<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34302463049.0" user="Evil_Thresh" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.

I don't think minimum wage is significant enough to do with losing the manufacturing industry. In the US minimum wage barely increased yet manufacturing jobs decreased dramatically. I don't think it's significant enough to pin it on increasing minimum wage. I think the lower cost of living and labor force outside of the US will lure the jobs away regardless.

Your workers will need $7/hr to be able to sell their labor. If you pay them $4/hr, they can't afford food, utility, etc and they will cease to exist so there will be a "natural" cost of living minimum wage even if we have no federal mandated minimum wage. Comparing this barrier, if you go to Thailand or Malaysia for manufacturing, they can live like kings with just $1/hr. There is no way US labor force \*can\* be competitive when the cost of living is just that much higher.

I think globalization is the sole/main reason. Anything else may contribute to the lost of manufacturing jobs, but it's not a determining factor.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
