<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928323372.0" user="Eh_Priori" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory.

Both of those societies practiced slavery, so why shouldn't we? Perhaps societies from centuries ago are not the place to look to for moral guidance.

&amp;gt; Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures.

I can't argue against this point in relations to world history (although I don't neccesarily think you are correct), however in relation to the conquest of the Americas this view doesn't hold water. Native American societies were more often annihilated than absorbed.

&amp;gt; Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn.

Europeans at this time were beginning to engage in trade on a global scale. There is no way that upon hearing of a new continent (or a westward route to the far east) they would have decided to never visit the continent again, even if they had no intention of conquest or colonisation. The Columbian exchange could have happened just as easily without conquest.

&amp;gt; The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world.

The New World would still have been used for trade, Western Europe would still be a trade hub considering the role of Western Europeans as global traders during this time period.

Also, why don't we try flipping the scales. Say that next week an advanced alien civilization discovers Earth. Would you agree that they are justified in conquering and colonising our planet? What about the specifics of the conquest? Are they allowed to encourage the spread of disease in our communities? Enslave us and work us to death? Tear down our cities and burn our books? Are they allowed to force us to resettle away from the fertile areas they have taken for their colonies? If you accept the conquest of the Americas as justified then surely you must accept this justified.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
