<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34711662046.0" user="Plonque" delta="True">
    <text>Wow, well there’s a (really well written) argument for civility and balance in modern discourse, and I absolutely agree with you in principle; **but not in practice, not right now**.

America's democracy was founded on raging debates, name-calling, smears, and sabotaging of opposing ideas, and we’ve withstood almost 240 years of push and pull without completely unraveling the thread that binds us as a society. I wish we could have heated debates without the nastiness of trolls, doxxers and general ugliness found on Twitter/Facebook/Reddit, but the ‘high road’ progressives have taken for the past couple of generations have lost out to modern media, especially in the echo chambers of cable news and bespoke content on social media. This is where push comes to shove.

Everyone now has a microphone and platform to broadcast from, and our conversations have turned from heated arguments over traditional things like taxation and healthcare to systemic crises like equality, civil/social rights, and science denial. Marches, protests and published opinions are much less effective than they were, and now encourage flame wars and shout-downs from the opposition. It’s fair to call out and shame anyone attempting to drag us back into Jim Crow or endanger the whole of society for small inconveniences at a personal level. I love seeing someone being shamed after throwing a tantrum in a Target over their mask display, coughing on folks who observe social distancing or calling cops on a bird-watcher for the crime of being Black. If outing these folks creates a ripple effect where their employer decides actions don’t match their values and people lose their jobs, well, too bad. These would be the same folks who call for strong, hard justice coming down on people breaking our laws or tenets of their faith. It makes me queasy to see families and (especially) kids dragged into this. and I don’t have an answer for that.

For decades we all shared the same sources for information — courtesy of airwaves licensed by our government, and required to provide news in a neutral way in exchange — and as result, we were debating from a common starting point. That no longer exists and we have to find better ways to come back to the middle and resolve our differences. Until then though, this deeply liberal, middle-aged, and privileged white guy will celebrate anyone who turns weapons so effectively, brilliantly used by the extreme right against them. I may like it, but I support it.

\[note: I’m the dad of the author of this CMV and couldn’t be prouder. We don’t always agree, but the measured, thoughtful argument here may have shifted my position a bit.\]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
