<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34768394825.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="True">
    <text>First, if Barack Obama didn’t take concrete steps toward fascism by killing US citizens with drone strikes without due process on purpose, not much Trump did moves the needle. 

Trump can’t even get $5 billion for a stupid wall, he can’t force a state to open or close, he can’t send in the national guard without a governor requesting it, and he will face legal challenges for the actions of federal officers recently. He doesn’t get to do whatever he wants, and if you think concrete steps have been taken you are welcome to list them, I would be happy to discuss them.


Second, his acceptance of the outcome is ceremonial, it has nothing to do with the transfer of power.


The USA has robust checks and balances in place, and the reality is that there isn’t any way for him to try to stay in power after noon on January 20, 2021 if he loses, or January 20, 2025 if he wins.

* If he loses, at the moment the new President is sworn in he has no more authority. The secret service don’t work for him anymore, and the US Marines on grounds are constitutionally obliged to ignore illegal orders.

He doesn’t have a choice and he isn’t stupid, our constitution was written by anti-government crazies who hated tyranny more than anything. 

His people will be very clear with him if he has any doubts. Trump may leave threatening legal action, he may leave pouting and crying, but it is highly unlikely force is required to remove him.


* If he tried to delay the election on some COVID19 nonsense, and the electors could not be seated in time, he would still stop being President on January 20th at noon, we would have President Pelosi, should she still be speaker of the house.

And his people have already probably told him that.

* If he wins, we will hear this same argument in four years, that Trump wants to stay in office, and that will not happen. I would go so far as to say constitutional changes cannot happen in today’s divided political environment, getting enough votes is currently impossible. Getting enough states to agree is currently impossible.

China and Russia just extended or removed their term limits for example, in rubber stamp near unanimous votes. With the USA that wouldn’t happen. If republicans tried it between 2020 and 2024 (if Trump won) democrats would throw the biggest tantrum in history and there would be mass riots. If democrats tried it while a democrat were in office republicans would throw the same tantrum, and there would be mass riots.

There would be no near unanimous vote, it would be the ugliest political fight in our lives and it would fail.  No matter who tried or how much of government they controlled.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
