<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34897162603.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="True">
    <text>That’s not true.

There are very few schools (comparatively) who make millions of dollars off their athletes. Big 10, SEC (the best conference), ACC (second best conference), Big 12 &amp;amp; the other 3/4 big ones do make millions. 

There are **thousands** of schools out there. Division 2 &amp;amp; 3 schools that do not make money off of athletics. A vast majority of sports don’t make money. Football and basketball are the main ones. Female sports don’t make money... unless if your UConn women’s basketball team or Duke. Most will not make money to pay for their operation cost. Collegiate gymnastics, swimming, climbing, rowing, track &amp;amp; field, golf, trap, polo, lacrosse &amp;amp; so on are not televised events that take in money like men’s basketball and football. I’m not sure how man’s hockey, soccer and baseball do. I know it isn’t as profitable as the other big two though. 

For most schools, having successful alumni is where they will get a lot of donations.


Look at the schools with the largest endowments... they mostly are not the schools that get prime time game slots or televised bowl games. They don’t have the top picks in the draft.


Their profit generators are their graduates that go out and make money. The ones that make the education at their school look great and want others to come to their institution.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
