<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112092849.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1uqje9/m23_i_refuse_to_flirt_before_the_first_date_of_a/">
    <title>M23 I refuse to flirt before the first date of a serious relationship CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwawaytrex</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL;DR: Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator.  Furthermore, any incompatibilities can often times be worked out with open and honest communication.  

I don't do casual dating, hookups, etc.  When I date, it's to find an entire life partner: that is what I'm looking for.  Because that's what I want, I accumulated a lot of advice on what makes a successful long term relationship, and it is a combination of compatibility, communication, and compromise, among others.  

Getting to the point: flirting is about turning each other on sexually.  In a open and honest relationship, both partners will communicate to one another their desires, and depending on that sexual compatibility, and other things, the relationship will or will not work out.  It doesn't make sense for "blind" flirting to occur, before both parties know what each other honestly wants, and then based on how lucky you are at guessing the other person's flirting strategies, succeed and win the first date.  

Problems with this approach: My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.  The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.  

Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants.  To me, seduction is like acting out a role.  And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27002704878.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>I understand you are trying to assure that you have only genuine relationships, and that is laudable. But your understanding of flirting and relationship-building is misguided.

Flirting is an act of communication, not just a sexual game. It is a way of demonstrating interest -- sexual and/or otherwise -- to a potential partner. This has the benefit of allowing the relationship to progress organically rather than trying to make a sudden hard turn into a romantic relationship with someone to whom you have shown no interest. 

&amp;gt;Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator. 

No, sex assesses sexual compatibility. Flirting doesn't tell you anything about what turns a person on. Flirting is opening the door just a little bit. It may give you hints, but that's kind of the point. But it's well-established that sexual compatibility is a big factor in long-term relationship success for most people. 

&amp;gt;The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.

The problem with this approach is that you're trying to take the relationship from zero to sixty with no warning. Flirting is a way to gradually break down social barriers so the relationship can grow closer. Most people don't respond to a sudden, "Hey I'm into you!" Even if they're interested back.

You are trying to manipulate the process of building a relationship rather than participating in the social norm. You're welcome to follow a different set of social norms, but you will have limited success because most people are expecting relationships to develop in a certain way, and in most cases flirting is a part of that.

&amp;gt;My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.

Understand: What you are doing is communicating that you are not interested. You are placing yourself firmly in the friend zone.

&amp;gt;Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants. To me, seduction is like acting out a role. And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.

This has nothing to do with a genuine relationship, which is ostensibly what you want. You need to learn how not to act, how to be an authentic human being who responds to other human beings in the moment rather than trying to read and calculate.

You need to learn how to build a romantic relationship because....

&amp;gt;The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out,

...it's not just a switch you can turn on. Actors get laid really easily but they have a bad track record for relationship success.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
