<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1127710637.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iner3h/cmv_the_root_of_the_us_healthcare_crisis_could/">
    <title>CMV: The "root" of the US healthcare crisis could simply be the food we eat.</title>
    <original_poster>godlike_hikikomori</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, we do have a crisis with healthcare costs/medical bills. Insurance and pharmaceutical companies are major players. However, I believe the root of the "health crisis" in America is in our food/diet. Many peer reviewed studies have shown that the US population's obesity, diabetes,and cancer rates are at multi decade highs, compared to other countries. Policy experts must focus on making the whole medical system more cost efficient and more focused on functional/holistic health. Enforcing food and environmental regulations are a must. Also, many low income communities do not have the money to afford healthier foods, and some of them live in food deserts. Society should encourage people to avoid and overcome chronic illness so that they can avoid the hospital beds in the first place. This system may allow Americans to actually rely less on healthcare, and this could decrease the amount that taxpayers have to pay for Medicare. Heck, the life expectancies in Korea, Japan,and Singapore are much higher than in the states. Their cultures all promote good diet and exercise. The conversation of reforming healthcare should boil down to this question: Would you want to live a life where you constantly have to rely on pills and hospital visits, instead of improving your overall, long term health?

You can disagree with me on this view,and I may be wrong. However, no one can deny that there are many studies that support the claim that US leads the world in chronic illnesses, and something has to be done about this eventually. In my own spare time, I have studied deeply about how the advent of fast food/junk food actually came about. The history of fast food in the states actually spans from gaining mid- Western farmlands during Manifest Destiny, to the gov't allowing more food to be produced from more acres of land during the post WW2 period, to Big Agra and Food constantly lobbying the gov't, and to the rise of fast food joints in all 50 states. If you study the effects that junk food and food additives have on the body, you would come to understand that it's really not a pretty picture. I just believe that we should be more focused in actually making people healthier in the long-term. To be frank, I strongly disagree with many of the policies put forth by virtually every politician with regard to healthcare. They all seem to ignore how the food we eat can impact our long term health, even though they all have their own merits when discussing the other aspects of the healthcare crisis.

What are your thoughts on how we solve our health crisis?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35082417411.0" user="thethoughtexperiment" delta="True">
    <text>Eating habits are definitely a major issue when it comes to public health in the U.S.

But to modify your view here:

&amp;gt;CMV: The "root" of the US healthcare crisis could simply be the food we eat.

I'd say that the "root" is deeper, and has more to do with economics, which strongly impact people's choices about what they eat.

In particular, relative to many other advanced countries, the U.S. *massively* subsidizes sugar. A candy bar in many Western European countries will cost you 2-3x what it does in the U.S., and that is majorly down to U.S. sugar subsidies.

Beyond sugar:

"Writing in the 2004 *Annual Review of Nutrition*, James Tillotson, a professor of food policy and international business at Tufts University, argues that U.S public policy encourages obesity at the expense of sound nutritional practices. “You have a whole régime here that’s worked to increase agricultural efficiency,” Tillotson says. And what U.S. farmers are most efficient at producing, he says, are just a few highly subsidized crops—wheat, soybeans, and especially corn.

Support for these few crops, critics say, has compelled farmers to ignore other crops such as fruits, vegetables, and other grains. The market is flooded with products made from the highly subsidized crops, including sweeteners in the form of high-fructose corn syrup (HFCS), fats in the form of hydrogenated fats made from soybeans, and feed for cattle and pigs. This flood, in turn, drives down the prices of fattening fare such as prepackaged snacks, ready-to-eat meals, fast food, corn-fed beef and pork, and soft drinks. Worse yet, some scientists say, paltry support for foods other than these staples increases the contrast between prices of fat-laden, oversweetened foods and those of healthier alternatives, offering poor folks little choice but to stock their pantries with less nutritious foods." \[[source](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1247588/)\]

So, consider that unhealthy eating is a consequence of economic policies (the root cause).

*Edit: An alternative would be subsidies for healthy foods.*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
