<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199878026.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/judjt6/cmv_losing_your_virginity_as_an_adult_andor/">
    <title>Cmv: Losing your virginity as an adult and/or pursing/having sexual and romantic relationships as a grown adult is worthless and absolutely crummy and nothing to be happy or excited about compared to having the same experiences as a teenager</title>
    <original_poster>Ruka_ushibaru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a male virgin who will be a legal adult soon (18 years old)  

I have had some thoughts and concerns that have been lingering me for a while. 

As people know, teenagers have raging hormones and are easily aroused (especially teenage boys) 
But adults don't have the same raging hormones and sexual desires and drive that teenagers have. 

Adults also aren't innocent or ignorant to sex. Because of this, sex isn't as exciting or seen as something... to be mesmerised by. However teenagers on the other hand have a extremely strong desire to have sex and "explore"  

Because those experiences are new and mysterious they can be more exciting and thrilling especially because its it's something you shouldn't be doing unless you're older. 

I mean adults need all of these fucking sex enhancing drugs and techniques and information to improve their sex life and "spice" shit up. Adults also need to be "in the mood" for sex But adolescents don't need any of that bullshit.
Most are horny as shit and ready for sex all the time  

Also sex seems easier to find as a teenager because teens are around the same horny people of the same age all the time so it's easier to build relationships and find someone who is willing to have sex. 

Whenever teenagers display the desire for sex adults often chuckle and say oh Its just their raging hormones and "they're still so young"

All of this makes me absolutely angry and bitter because i never had the the opportunity to have sex as  teenager and now I'm out of high school and never will return, thus my chances of experiences sex as a teen are gone. 

I've been feeling extremely bitter as i said before and it's made me develop misogynistic views and some incel views as well. I'm not a misogynist or incel but If i continue this path i surely will become both of those things. 

With that being said, i am extremely ambitious, resilient and determined. I'm very hard working and have other qualities about myself that i am proud of. 
 
I have a lot of goals and desires i plan to purse. One of them being that i wanna become a person i am proud and confident to be. I wanna grow and learn and become successful. 

Some of my goals require me to social a lot. 
I plan to build my social skills further and learn to be more charismatic. 

I highly doubt i will ever find any sexual relationships with women when I'm older but... if i ever do why should i bother having sex with them?
If for one reason or another women find me attractive (money, or my success or some other quality i have) 

Why the fuck should i bother having sex and losing my virginity if i am a grown ass man? 

If beautiful women ever threw themselves at me should i be happy? Should i even play with their feelings and hurt them? 

Having Sex and relationships isn't exciting as a man compared to doing it as a boy. 

Worst of all, i feel even more bitter and angrier when i see stories of beautiful adult women having sex with teenage boys who are still in highschool. 

Thess stories make me feel inferior and frustrated that i will never have the same experiences. 

These boys are even considered lucky by most people including me. They're more lucky than adult men having sex the same women. 

I fucking hate sexually active teenagers, especially teenage boys who have sex with attractive adult women. 

I hate them. I hate them i hate them i hate them i. Fucking HATE them. 

If i am still a virgin by my 20s or even 30s I'd rather never have sex at all  

Also most people in America and other places lose their Virginities when they're still im highschool. 

Having sex as a grown adult for the first time means that you are late and other people who have had the same experiences at a younger age are superior and better and enjoyable for the reasons i mentioned before. 

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35573687074.0" user="JohnCrichtonsCousin" delta="True">
    <text>Stop thinking so much about it all. You're not away from the hormone riddled existence of teen years, this impetus lasts on into mid 20s, indeed there is a great deal more sexual learning and experimenting going on in college than high-school. Its not bad to still be a virgin, but having no sexual experience at all is worth taking note of and working on. That being said, a lot of what you said reveals that you know nothing about it and are making all sorts of assumptions. 'If I found a partner as an adult, why would I want to have sex with her?' Trust me when you're in that scenario you will *not* have to ask that question.

Furthermore, it sounds like you're hinting that you're lacking sexual desire, or feel like you won't be able to perform. Stop watching porn, it totally fucks your sexual programming up and will absolutely drain you of sexual drive, leading one to question why women and sex are even appealing to everyone else, because your brain isn't sending you horny hormones since it thinks you just got laid the previous however-many-nights you've wacked off. Maybe you're not watching any porn but just in case, don't, because it causes the very problem you're afraid of.

You're too far removed from the scenario of sexual interaction to have a clear view on it, and I'm betting your shame/fear about being an adult virgin is getting to your head, both of them. I just got through a very short, very intense interaction with what was a brand new acquaintance. She threw herself at me, no feeling involved, and was probably trying to manipulate me for her own reasons, but I could smell it and guarded against it while trying to enjoy her graciousness. I've had the same thoughts you've put here before, and felt like I might be slipping away from my hormones, from my virility as a man. She proved me wrong given how many boners I got from mere touching and kissing, and the fire it lit in me I had forgotten existed. I didn't even like her and actively knew she was trying to dominate me, which was fun to allow her to think, but that would usually cancel out sexual attraction for me. I don't like evil people, I don't like sex being manipulative. Still, my hormones had me ready to bat. I guarantee if you find someone you actually love and find attractive, you won't have a hard time finding yourself. Stop thinking about it so much and go live life. You're a virgin at 18, you have some catching up to do. Go mess around with some people and try not to hurt anyone and watch your feelings but don't be surprised if they get hurt anyway. Life is messy. But sex is great and don't let yourself forget it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
