<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36519399950.0" user="VenousMallard46" delta="True">
    <text>"The people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism" this is a very good point; i'd say in real-life terms this translates often to those in power - the church, powerful businessmen, powerful politicians, influential cultural leaders, etc - are more likely to choose a "fascist" regime  


However where i would disagree with you is on two points: a) whether or not the kind of regime they would choose would really be definitively a "fascist" one, and b) whether or not fascism or communism presents more danger to a society  


For my first point, i would argue that in all intents and purposes, "fascism" as a political ideology is all but dead.  the people who genuinely agitate for it are hyper-marginal, and more often its used as a political epithet against people deemed to be authoritarian than an actual descriptive tool with any connection with the fascism of interwar europe.  for example, politicians like Marine le Pen, Donald Trump and Matteo Salvini, three people often called "fascists" today, I'd say have both different ideologies, and are nevertheless much more in the middle than genuine fascists were.  All three I'd argue are better called "national conservatives", who are basically pro-capitalism and pro-status quo, but want less immigrants, more sovereignty over their affairs, and are less committed to traditional allies (but still generally committed).  Le Pen is more anti-laissez faire than the other two are, and someone like Jair Bolsonaro, another person I'd include in this category, is more socially conservative.  But I'd still say they're not fascists; they're basically a kind of conservative.   


Now, if those with power were to be seriously threatened again, there could be a resurgence of fascism, or something similar.  My guess would be it would be the kinds of societies they would create would be the same, but the actual ideology itself would be  a lot different, just because of how much fascism is despised today.  But who knows.  


  


For my second point, I'd say that genuine fascism, real fascism, is far more dangerous than Communism.  By "Communism", i'm assuming you are and I will be referring to Marxist Leninist states that followed the Soviet model.  Those states, while repressive and tolerant of mass starvation for economic goals, did not advocate for the enslavement or extermination of huge swathes of Earth's population through conquest.  The Soviets did not embark on the most cataclysmic war the world has ever seen in order to slaughter "subhumans".  Communist aggression was typically defensive in nature; Stalinist ideology spoke of the need to build "socialism in one country" while the world proletariat inevitably rose up against capitalism elsewhere, which would be aided by the Soviets.  Therefore, what aggression they and the Chinese undertook was generally taking territory in their immediate vicinity to PREVENT a greater war, not cause one.  The Soviets and Chinese invaded Finland, Vietnam, the Baltic states, etc. when they were all but positive that a greater war would not break out, and that they would not have to conquer huge amounts of land, and when they felt threatened by another power.  Fascism by its very nature encourages conquest, especially Nazism.  With conquest comes an enormous new population to exploit, and the fascists were eager to do so.  The Nazis went even further, and outright wanted to kill most of the population in its occupied territories to pave the way for German settlement in those areas.  That's what the Generalplan Ost planned for.    


Fascism sought to re-establish earlier forms of European imperialism onto other countries in Europe for nationalistic purposes; European imperialism in Africa, the British settler colonies, all of those would be reborn by fascist Italy and Nazi Germany and took to new levels and heights with as much of the surrounding peoples they could conquer.    


Lastly, I'd say that Communism's fall was so devastating to some countries just because of the way the transition was handled.  Compare the transition to capitalism in Russia to the transition in China; Russia's was called "shock therapy", and was coordinated by western free-marketeer economists who wanted to test their theories further like they did in Chile in the previous decades.  It was a disaster; Russia saw a catastrophic decrease in economic output and quality of life that it has taken decades to recover from.  China, on the other hand, took a very gradualist approach and introduced reforms slowly, to the point where now China is in competition with the US to be the world's biggest economy.  Reforming society post-Communism isn't always a disaster like it was in many of the post-Communist states.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
