<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696623575.0" user="hungryCantelope" delta="True">
    <text>so there is a lot of things we could talk about here but I am going to stick to 1 point for now because I think it hits the heart of your position.

**It is possible to objectify  people in ways other than sexual.**

(before getting into this I just want to clarify the topic of objectivation is a lot more complicated than most people make it out to be, people freak out about the idea which means that the word comes with a lot of negative connotations, the reason I mention this is because I am not using this word as an attack against you but rather because the use of the term is needed to deconstruct your feelings about women so you can understand them better.) anyway back to the main point

**It is possible to objectify people in ways other than sexual.**

you are using women as a metric to evaluate your sense of self-worth.  This doesn't feel like objectivation to you because it isn't sexual as illustrated by your statement here.

&amp;gt;while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much

Regardless it is still objectivation , instead of being on object of sex you are thinking about women in terms of them being a tool to measure your value.  We can see this in a number of ways. One, the very fact that you identify as an incel, the fact that you are particular focused on virginity, the use of words that are intrinsically about ranking people according to sexual status.

&amp;gt;they don’t want to talk to me, because women see anyone who isn’t chad or a clown as subhuman  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Yay, so I can get women when they are old, ugly, and used up? That makes me soooo happy :/  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers

all of these things are about framing relationships as a metric by which to rank yourself not about the relationship itself.

So why is this a problem? well like I said it's still a from of objectivation which means that instead focusing on actual specific people and actual relationships you are focused on an imaginary relationship with a people you don't know but have projected a personality onto.

By your own admission you haven't talked to these women, and your reasoning for wanting to be with them isn't based on anything personal about them or even based on what the actual real world relationship would be, you just like the idea of them validating you as a partner in some way.  Ask yourself this if you asked one of these women out and they said yes what would happen next? do you actually have something specific you want to do with them?  My guess is not really, and the reason for that is because your desire to be with them isn't personal.  Your not looking at your options and evaluating which women would best connect with you personally your imposing onto women ideas about which one would best validate you if they choose to date you.  Things like are they hot? are they socially valued by my peers?  In this way you treat them as objects, imagined versions of themselves.(notice how none of these things are actually descriptions of their personalities.)  In short you have convinced yourself that your attraction to them is personal and then vilify them as being shallow, in reality your approach is just as shallow.

To clarify being attracted to people in this way doesn't make you bad, everyone does it.  The problem you are having is that you pretend that you don't do it, which makes you resentful towards others and will prevent you from interacting and getting to know women personally because the personality you project onto them stops you from realizing who little you know about them in reality.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

a quick fix for this is to stop thinking about interacting with people as a way to win them over but rather as a way to see if the 2 of you are compatible, this works with romantic and plutonic relationships.  Doing this will make you interaction revolve around what you actually have in common and how compatible you are instead a vaguely defined game of social interaction that can be won and lost, which is both un productive andtypically very awkward.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
