<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332232441.0" user="dumboy" delta="True">
    <text>People who don't even bother with *paragraphs* shouldn't expect citations from volunteer content contributors trying to indulge them. You arn't assigning a task, your trying to entice peoples sense of curiosity. 

Also what are your benchmarks for "productivity"? How do you *really* know whose productive?

Your view, as you've laid it out, contradicts psychology, biology, Blue-Chip companies' hiring practices, and in the absence of real data. So I'd beseech you with an appeal to expert opinion &amp;amp; earnings statements. 

While you might say women are unproductive at software development, someone might point out that Nursing or Project Management - where women *don't* tend to report the glass ceiling nearly as often - not only do women dominate, but the benchmarks (hours, physical activity, years of education involving 'hard' science in addition to raw math) are often *more* rigorous. 

tl;dr: Capitalism moved *away* from segregation, and at the same time our national productivity increased. A historic analysis of profits &amp;amp; productivity seems to refute your claim. According to conventional wisdom, at least. I'm not going to go cite the obvious. But maybe you should do some googling. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
