<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422372444.0" user="kyril99" delta="True">
    <text>I think the Nordic model has been romanticized to an extent greater than is really justifiable. As others have pointed out, there's a strong argument to be made that culture is a major factor in your success. I think that if we're going to look for a "best" socioeconomic model, we should look for one that's more generally applicable - one that isn't tightly tied to a particular culture and a cohesive, homogeneous national identity.

It turns out that there's a model that fits that description quite well. [Canada](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada) looks a lot like the Scandinavian countries on measures of [happiness](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report), [education](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Education_Index), [life expectancy](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_life_expectancy), [economic mobility](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_mobility), and [GDP per capita](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_GDP_%28PPP%29_per_capita), and is [relatively close on income inequality](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_income_equality). It's also an aggressively [multicultural](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiculturalism_in_Canada) nation of [immigrants](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immigration_to_Canada) which specifically [rejects the need for homogeneity](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cultural_mosaic). Because of this, the Canadian economic, educational, and legal systems aren't built on shared identity and trust, but rather on a sort of consequentialist pragmatism. Canada tends - in general terms, over a multi-decadal time scale - to adopt policies that work and discard ones that don't. In this it contrasts sharply not only with its idealistic southern neighbours, but also with the differently-idealistic political culture of Scandinavia.

So I think you should consider Canada's model as a more generally-applicable candidate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
