<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422297986.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>I like a number of aspects of the Nordic model but there are a few things you are not considering;

&amp;gt; reduces poverty which benefits everyone.

Reduced poverty does indeed benefit everyone but when poverty rates are calculated the same way between advanced economies they are largely indistinguishable from one another, there is a fairly good analysis including some history [here](https://www.chapman.edu/research-and-institutions/economic-science-institute/_files/ifree-papers-and-photos/PriceFishback.pdf).

Largely where the US differs from other advanced economies is that our programs tend to be non-universal other then for old age transfers (which is the reverse of the rest of the world as it is universal where it generally isn't elsewhere), programs like public health are means tested where they are not elsewhere.

&amp;gt; High level of education

The US actually has an identical tertiary enrollment rate to all the Nordic countries.

A fairly persistent problem in the US (its existed since the 80's) and to a lesser extent elsewhere is that even with a rise in education skills acquisition has been relatively flat, while people are entering and graduating from tertiary education at increased rates their marketable skills are not increasing. The problem here is caused by insufficient information being available to those embarking on tertiary education, they don't understand what the future value of their skills will be so make poor choices regarding which skills to acquire.

&amp;gt; highly efficient administration

They are efficient due to their size, states of the same size are similarly efficient.

&amp;gt; effectively invests into the society

You would have a hard time justifying the US doesn't also do so but just in different ways. Public science &amp;amp; healthcare R&amp;amp;D spending in the US is extraordinarily high compared to every other advanced economy (EG - The vast majority, nearly 90%, of worldwide public vaccine research spending is in the US), NiH and NSF actually fund research in the Nordic countries too.

&amp;gt; providing multiple incentives

Which often fail. One of the reasons why Sweden went in a different direction in the 90's is due to their persistently high structural unemployment, having double digit unemployment even in a boom is a significant problem and poses a very significant mobility issue. In many of the countries today they are finding similar problems in education, people are becoming perpetual students obtaining degrees because they can rather then there is actually any value to them doing so.

&amp;gt; angles of growth

Growth in Nordic countries is certainly below potential but more significant globalization creates a great deal of interaction between countries economies such that high growth countries with significant trade will necessarily increase growth in other countries. There is a good paper on the Nordic vs US models from this perspective [here](http://scholar.harvard.edu/files/jrobinson/files/varieties_of_capitalism_april_9_2013.pdf).

&amp;gt; Low level of income inequality

Beyond the moral case its hard to make a case for inequality being bad, its simply not causal with any negative economic outcomes. Poverty &amp;amp; mobility are the issues which actually do impact outcomes but always seem to take a back seat.

&amp;gt; low crime

Check out Northern New England. US national figures are biased by a couple of places (DC particularly) which have very high crime rates.

&amp;gt; good healthcare

Different healthcare then the US, better accessibility but lower quality of care; it largely depends on how you consider healthcare issues.

Beyond political reports we really don't rank healthcare systems of advanced economies, they all have good quality of care and all respond to local lifestyle &amp;amp; political factors. The US is expensive but offers a wider array of treatment options then other countries, there are simply too many points of bias for any ranking to be useful so they are largely considered to be equivalent.

&amp;gt; great education

Agreed, we spend the 2nd highest per child in the world and perform shockingly badly. K-12 is in desperate need of reform.

&amp;gt; But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing

This is does do, nearly half of total world capital is available in the US. Net capital flows in advanced economies is towards to the US rather then away from it. As a good example even the European pharma's perform the majority of their R&amp;amp;D in the US (EG - Most of GSK's R&amp;amp;D is in MA). Capital created in the Nordic countries will typically end up in the UK or US.

&amp;gt; sustainable economic growth.

As a quibble there is no such thing, all non-artificial growth is good for everyone. If we had a magic wand which would add 5% to growth immediate we should wave it, higher wages, reduced prices relative to incomes etc.

A better intermediate model which largely accomplishes what you are likely looking for would be the German system. Their healthcare system is incredible, the works council system is incredible (but currently illegal in the US) and while I don't think we need to legislate it in the same way the shared prosperity principles are really interesting. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
