<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1606602557.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qkj2gt/cmv_i_am_not_very_religious/">
    <title>CMV: I Am Not Very Religious</title>
    <original_poster>AbiLovesTheology</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I'm Hindu. I started following this path around age 14 after some serious mental health issues and it helps me cope in life and helps me to stay calm (I have an anxiety disorder and various other disabilities, so life can get tough sometimes.

My best friend Morgan  (an atheist) says I am very religious, but I currently don't think so. I do (or at least try to do) the following things daily:

Chant mantras

Wear bindi

Sing devotional songs

Perform pujas (this is where as well as chanting mantras and singing songs, we light incense, give offerings to deities, meditate, light candles) etc in front of an image of a deity.

Wear rudraksha (a form of prayer bead) I wear 4 daily. I also sometimes wear bangles.

Meditate (without all the other things mentioned in the puja section)

Do yoga

Spend time thinking about The Divine. I try to think about the Divine in everything I do.

Ponder over scriptural verses and the thoughts of Hindu philosophers.

I also celebrate Hindu festivals at the temple,and, and spend time thinking about what I am grateful for, I don't eat beef and I have traditional clothes to wear during rituals.

Now, if I was very religious, as Morgan claims, I would most likely be vegetarian completely, do occasional fasting, live in an ashram (monastery), I would meditate and pray for a lot longer than I do, I would know a lot more mantras from memory, I probably wouldn't have many possessions and I wouldn't be a student. I wouldn't go to concerts or talk as much as I do.

What do you think? Do you think I am very religious despite not doing the things in the bottom paragraph? If so, why? Please change my view so I can agree with Morgan.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38148586291.0" user="overhardeggs" delta="True">
    <text>There are many Americans that consider themselves religious because they go to a religious service every week but outside that, religious activities or thoughts rarely or never cross their minds because it's more of a cultural thing for them than a spiritual thing. 

So by comparison, you are very religious in contrast to many "religious" Americans. You do daily things rather frequently to enhance your spirituality, and this is coming from someone who is religious</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
