<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1606602557.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qkj2gt/cmv_i_am_not_very_religious/">
    <title>CMV: I Am Not Very Religious</title>
    <original_poster>AbiLovesTheology</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I'm Hindu. I started following this path around age 14 after some serious mental health issues and it helps me cope in life and helps me to stay calm (I have an anxiety disorder and various other disabilities, so life can get tough sometimes.

My best friend Morgan  (an atheist) says I am very religious, but I currently don't think so. I do (or at least try to do) the following things daily:

Chant mantras

Wear bindi

Sing devotional songs

Perform pujas (this is where as well as chanting mantras and singing songs, we light incense, give offerings to deities, meditate, light candles) etc in front of an image of a deity.

Wear rudraksha (a form of prayer bead) I wear 4 daily. I also sometimes wear bangles.

Meditate (without all the other things mentioned in the puja section)

Do yoga

Spend time thinking about The Divine. I try to think about the Divine in everything I do.

Ponder over scriptural verses and the thoughts of Hindu philosophers.

I also celebrate Hindu festivals at the temple,and, and spend time thinking about what I am grateful for, I don't eat beef and I have traditional clothes to wear during rituals.

Now, if I was very religious, as Morgan claims, I would most likely be vegetarian completely, do occasional fasting, live in an ashram (monastery), I would meditate and pray for a lot longer than I do, I would know a lot more mantras from memory, I probably wouldn't have many possessions and I wouldn't be a student. I wouldn't go to concerts or talk as much as I do.

What do you think? Do you think I am very religious despite not doing the things in the bottom paragraph? If so, why? Please change my view so I can agree with Morgan.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38150112371.0" user="Crayshack" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Chant mantras

&amp;gt;Sing devotional songs

&amp;gt;Perform pujas in front of an image of a deity

&amp;gt;Wear rudraksha (a form of prayer bead) I wear 4 daily. I also sometimes wear bangles.

&amp;gt;Spend time thinking about The Divine. I try to think about the Divine in everything I do.

&amp;gt;I also celebrate Hindu festivals at the temple,and, and spend time thinking about what I am grateful for, I don't eat beef and I have traditional clothes to wear during rituals.

Each of these things on its own would be something that would qualify you as very religious to me.  The fact that you do all of them puts you very firmly into the "very religious" camp.

However, this just gets into the vagueness of the term "very religious".  It's a spectrum of varying degrees of religiousness.  Where we draw the line between "somewhat religious" and "very religious" is arbitrary.  To someone who isn't religious at all, anything more than a token participation in religion might feel "very religious".  However, someone who is following every tenet of their religion might view that same level of just more than token involvement to be not religious at all.

For perspective, I was raised Reform Jewish and I left the religion.  I consider the Modern Orthodox sect of Judaism to be extremely religious to the point that calling them "very religious" is an understatement.  However, I'm also active on /r/ex-jew and have had a lot of conversations with people with other backgrounds on that sub.  For some of the people there, switching to Modern Orthodox represents a drop in how religious they are.  As a result, there are groups that I consider "very religious" that they consider "not religious".  It's a matter of perspective.

Thinking about it that way, I'm sure there are people who wouldn't call you religious at all.  But it would also be fair for someone who is less religious than you to call you very religious.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
