<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1606602557.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qkj2gt/cmv_i_am_not_very_religious/">
    <title>CMV: I Am Not Very Religious</title>
    <original_poster>AbiLovesTheology</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I'm Hindu. I started following this path around age 14 after some serious mental health issues and it helps me cope in life and helps me to stay calm (I have an anxiety disorder and various other disabilities, so life can get tough sometimes.

My best friend Morgan  (an atheist) says I am very religious, but I currently don't think so. I do (or at least try to do) the following things daily:

Chant mantras

Wear bindi

Sing devotional songs

Perform pujas (this is where as well as chanting mantras and singing songs, we light incense, give offerings to deities, meditate, light candles) etc in front of an image of a deity.

Wear rudraksha (a form of prayer bead) I wear 4 daily. I also sometimes wear bangles.

Meditate (without all the other things mentioned in the puja section)

Do yoga

Spend time thinking about The Divine. I try to think about the Divine in everything I do.

Ponder over scriptural verses and the thoughts of Hindu philosophers.

I also celebrate Hindu festivals at the temple,and, and spend time thinking about what I am grateful for, I don't eat beef and I have traditional clothes to wear during rituals.

Now, if I was very religious, as Morgan claims, I would most likely be vegetarian completely, do occasional fasting, live in an ashram (monastery), I would meditate and pray for a lot longer than I do, I would know a lot more mantras from memory, I probably wouldn't have many possessions and I wouldn't be a student. I wouldn't go to concerts or talk as much as I do.

What do you think? Do you think I am very religious despite not doing the things in the bottom paragraph? If so, why? Please change my view so I can agree with Morgan.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38148991979.0" user="ytzi13" delta="True">
    <text>I'm sure this has already been addressed in other comments you've gotten, but...

You seem to be defining "very religious" from your own perspective versus that of an atheist, which is going to be difficult. Why? Because each individual will have their own definition of "very religious" and they'll define it according to their own personal scale. For example, as an agonistic atheist myself, if you had to ask me to define some sort of "how religious are you" scale, I'd do so in the following way:

* **Not Religious**: a person who does not believe in any religion.
* **Kind of Religious**: A person who unconvincingly follows a religion because it might be all they've really known and are part of the community, and may or may not really believe in what the religion says.
* **Religious**: Believes in a religion and willingly participates in religious activities.
* **Very Religious**: Believes in a religion and willingly participates in public religious activities as well as private practicing (strict about praying; abides by dietary restrictions; does not waiver in faith; etc.).
* **Extremist Religious**: Believes so much in a religion that it completely consumes them and leads to irrational tendencies.

This isn't going to be perfect because it's off the top of my head, but you get the point. To me, you would probably be classified as "Very Religious" because it's something that you consider in every aspect of your life: you chant, you dress the part, you give offerings, you think about it when you make decisions... The diet thing isn't really a disqualifier for me in this scenario because you check off so many boxes and every religion is open to interpretation by the individual to the point at which they'll disagree on some major and minor points. Even if that may not be the case, it's almost always the case that individuals will pick and choose the aspects of the religion they follow, often out of personal convenience or due to some other reason.

Now, take your perspective as a religious individual as part of a community of other religious individuals. You're going to have your own scale because you're exposed to, and can recognize, other individuals who may be obviously more devout than yourself. Your atheist friend might not be capable of recognizing the nuances within that group. This is a common pattern when you don't understand, or haven't been exposed to, something. For example, if I were to watch a chess match, I might not be able to tell who's better between two players because I'm unfamiliar with high level chess, whereas someone experienced would be able to follow and criticize. To me, both players may be really good chess players, but that might not be true to the experienced chess player because the scales are different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
