<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38698622550.0" user="deep_sea2" delta="True">
    <text>Every sport has its own charm, so to say. The charm of basketball is constant back and forth scoring, where soccer is the opposite where a single goal could win the game. The charm baseball and football is that they are turn-based sports in a sense, while soccer is free flowing. The charm of hockey is that it is a super fast game dialed up to 11 the whole time, while soccer is a more patient and energy efficient game (hockey is a sprinter, soccer is a marathoner).

What I am trying to say is that the endurance elements of soccer, where you only have a handful of subs, is part of what makes soccer soccer. That is why extra time soccer is so interesting. You can see that the players are absolutely gassed, and yet they keep on pushing. Yes, you could have unlimited subs, but then soccer would simply turn into hockey on grass. Yes, the offense could be more explosive and then there would be a lot more goals, but then it would become basketball played with your feet.

So yes, substitution would improve certain components of soccer, but perhaps that would change soccer to a point where it becomes something else. To me, this sound like making the hurdles shorter to allow sprinters to run faster. If the shot put were lighter, you could throw it further. If long jumpers could jump off a springboard, they could jump further. If target shooters could use a computer programed rig, they would shoot more accurately. All these things would make their respective sports "better," but they would change it to the point where the spirit of the sport is no longer the same. I believe that making soccer faster and more intense would ruin the spirit of soccer in a similar fashion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
