<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589670624.0" user="stevegcook" delta="True">
    <text>It seems like you're implicitly arguing that we should select our drinkware based solely on the criteria of breakability and spill probability, is this true?  

If so, would you also agree that we should only ever drink things out of sippy cups or Contigo travel mugs?  

But aside from that, here are some things to consider:

* The wide base of a wine glass makes more of a difference than you'd think.  Objects tip over once their centre of gravity is no longer directly above part of the base.  This angle is pretty much the same as many other glasses.  Obviously mugs are more stable, but aside from that there isn't that much difference.  [Here's what I mean](http://imgur.com/a/49p26) - the angle from this point to the edge of the base is equal to the angle you'd need to tip the glass before it fell over.

* I have successfully cleaned thousands of wine glasses and never had a single problem with breakage. 
* Because the top lip of the glass curves inwards, spills from the liquid sloshing around is less likely.  
* The thin glass of a wine glass makes it lighter and easier to carry around for long periods of time, which is good for times when one is socializing at cocktail parties and whatnot.
* Wine glasses can be held at the top of the stem without using the entire hand.  Again, good for social events where one might be holding a plate of food, shaking someone's hand, and accepting a business card all at the same time.
* Wine glasses look elegant.
* The curvature of the glass is more conducive to sipping, and makes it easier to savour the wine.  This allows for a fuller appreciation of the wine's flavours and allows the aromas to collect right under your nose.  This sipping motion also makes moderation easier.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
