<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173157689.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2v3dbt/cmvthe_media_turns_us_into_what_we_consume/">
    <title>CMV:The media turns us into what we consume</title>
    <original_poster>ExploreMeDora</original_poster>
    <original_post>Marshall McLuhan coined the term "the medium is the message." This means that the form of a medium (cell phone vs newspaper) embeds itself in the message, creating a symbiotic relationship by which the medium influences how the message is perceived. McLuhan proposes that a medium itself, not the content it carries, should be the focus of study. He said that a medium affects the society in which it plays a role not only by the content delivered over the medium, but also by the characteristics of the medium itself.


With this concept in mind I ask that you challenge these statements:


1. Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.
2. Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.
3. Watching television makes us less social.
4. Life online gives us popcorn brain.


Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.


I welcome you to come up with other statements to challenge or to develop other counterarguments. Essentially, I believe that our media consumption strongly affects our identity. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27597534993.0" user="hashtag_bad_advice" delta="True">
    <text>I think you are misunderstanding what McLuhan was saying.

What he means by that statement is that ideas do not exist in a void. For example, take this comment. You are reading the words I've typed into a comment on this post in the change my view section of the larger reddit website. Presumably you are reading it in a web browser on some type on internet enabled electronic device. Each step of the process modifies how you perceive the content and imposes additional meaning on my message. 

If you took this discussion and transplanted it to another website, your perception of it would be altered based on how you perceive the website. For McLuhan it was more than simply the physical form the content takes. The publisher matters, the author matters, the typeface matters, the supporting art matters.

If this thread was on 4chan, how would you evaluate it? What if it was in the online edition of the Wall Street Journal? How about Vox, The Daily Mail, or Yahoo News? Each of these sources color our perception of the content and that is what McLuhan means by the "medium is the message".

With that in mind I have to take issue with each of your statements.

&amp;gt; Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.

To apply McLuhan's lense to this situation you would have to be more specific. If two people read the same article, one digitally and the other in print, neither would be more educated than the other. They would have different perceptions of the significance of what they've read but both would have the same information.

&amp;gt; Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.

For every study saying that statement is true, there is an equal and opposite study saying it's false. The fact is when you zoom out, humans have become less violent as a whole.

&amp;gt; Watching television makes us less social.

It makes it easier to be anti-social but watching television does not require us to be less social. Many times discussing television gives people who would not have otherwise interacted a common ground they can build relationships on. Social groups also form around television and can be a great way for people who otherwise find it difficult to meet people to socialize.

&amp;gt; Life online gives us popcorn brain

The internet has forced us to reevaluate how we value our time.

Ultimately I think your premise is backwards; What we wish to consume changes our media.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
