<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173814707.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vhgab/cmv_focusing_too_narrowly_on_the_plot_of_movies/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing too narrowly on the plot of movies is a shallow way of experiencing and critiquing them</title>
    <original_poster>sloggz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often when I see movie criticism, either on Reddit or in person, I see people focusing on critiquing the plot of films. They'll say things like "the story was great, up until *blank* and then it totally ruined it for me". There is also a general focus on spoilers, plot holes, etc.


Now, I don't think there is necessarily anything wrong with people viewing film this way, I just think it's shallow. And I don't mean shallow in a wholly negative way, I just mean it as exactly as it is, shallow, close to the surface, without depth.


Films, as an art-form are an immensely complex and intriguing form of entertainment. They combine all the aspects of music, photography, writing, performing, digital effects and art, set design and sound production into an end result that can often be greater than the sum of its parts. To reduce all of these aspects of film to just the narrative of the story and the literal events of the movie is to ignore and not appreciate a massive part of the experience.


Not that plot isn't an important part of movies. I love movies with complex, interesting plots, but I also love movies without them. A complex narrative is in no way, a pre-requisit to a good movie. Just as it's not a requirement for a good novel or anything. It helps, and it can add to or make a good film even great, but it is not all there is.


Basically, my view is that modern mainstream critiquing of movies - what your family members discuss after leaving the cinema, or what people say around the water-cooler at work, (or what is often said in discussion posts of films at /r/movies, is far too focused on the plot of movies. Movie fans everywhere are doing themselves a disservice and would enjoy the movies they watch more if they changed the way they thought about them.


I equate it to people judging music solely on the lyrics.


So! please, try to change my view, as I am clearly in the minority. Why would it not be better for general audiences in general to be more well-rounded film viewers?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27602508715.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="True">
    <text>Plot points are certainly the easiest part of a film to criticize, and that's because in most movies, that's the first level that the film works on.  Most movies, the main point is: this is what's happening.  It's hard to enjoy the second or third level of a film if the first level fails.  Why should I care about the symbolism or cinematography or soundtrack or whatever of a film if it's occurring against the backdrop of "a bunch of shit is happening that I don't care about?"

And granted, this isn't true for *every* film.  I can think of a large handful of movies where the plot isn't the first level you're supposed to enjoy: *Across the Universe* is about listening to new versions of Beatles songs; *Avatar* is about seeing groundbreaking 3D visual effects.  But I think that the plot is the first level that *most* films operate on, so that's where the first criticism (either positive or negative) should occur.

It doesn't matter how the story is told if it's not a story worth telling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
