<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564864312.0" user="heartBreak1879" delta="True">
    <text>Yes. I concur that this change in hands over the control of Twitter does not bode well at all given Musk's history.

But, the problem is Twitter, like other social media sites, is already a dangerous echo chamber where bigotry festers unchecked. The core issue is not ownership at all.

Rather, the business model social media platform uses. Under this business model, we are not the actual customers. Advertisers are. So without getting into all the nitty gritty details, keeping customers engaged through morally dubious means and using underhanded ways to ~~use~~ abuse private user information to attain engagement in order to maximize ad revenue is the source of the issue.

For a better treatment of this thesis, check out *Ten Arguments for Deleting Social Media Accounts Right Now* by Jaron Lanier, a computer scientist who is close to the tech scene at Silicon Valley.

Therefore, while I fear Musk's ownership, it is not the main problem at all.

Also, your statement implies social media platform favors progressive voice when that is far from the truth. The belief that social media platform actually represents the left to me is more of right wing statement, designed to fabricate baseless outrage.

Social media is too right leaning in all the wrong ways, and whatever element of progressive value there is too superficial and lightweight. 

Thus, your view misses the forest, the innate issues with social media, for a tree, or perhaps, an tree thar will soon get nastier and more infected.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
