<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39891518682.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="True">
    <text>I think there are various elements at work here. It depends on the context really. 

For some, the idea is sort of just uninspiring. It's like, instead of exploring space to make discoveries or help humanity, it's just another way for corporations to make money. 

For others, the idea is foolish. This is along the lines of those, like Musk, who view space colonization as a way to escape a dying Earth. The obvious question is "if we can create a civilization on a barren moon, then why wouldn't we just do that but on the barren Earth." A variation of this is also just the criticism that we are spending resources on moving off of Earth instead of fixing it. Or the fear that this is just a way for rich people to escape the problems they've helped create. 

Finally, the reason to care about the environment in space is actually really about conserving it for future generations. If we can't survive in space sustainably, then all we are doing is making it that much harder for people in the future. If we are relying on mining or using up natural resources then eventually those will dry up and future generations will be forced to travel even further or work harder or solve these problems. You know, the same exact issue that is happening on Earth now. It's like we aren't learning from our past.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
