<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1919527693.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vqu51p/cmv_downfall_of_news_networks_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing</title>
    <original_poster>mindtug</original_poster>
    <original_post>News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors. It’s important to know what’s happening but global networks such as CNN and Fox are too sensational for me to support. Should I feel sad they’re dying?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40074793060.0" user="GinoMidnight" delta="True">
    <text>I totally understand where you are coming from on this, especially when you factor in the opinionated anchors who go on an emotional rant that a liberal or conservative to be did wrong.

However, I think relying on news with social media is much worse because the facts, conspiracy theories, and false information blend together. The only time I think it’s useful is for certain clips that need to be viral to wake people up, such as the clip of that officer kneeing George Floyd’s neck.

The other thing too is I like to hear the opinions of the left and right cause sometimes their view on something could be totally different than mine and I don’t get their side and some can explain that well. Many can’t explain it well, but some do.

Tl;dr: I agree to an extent. It’s good to hear both sides of the story but relying on social media for news 100% doesn’t work due to disinformation, true facts, and conspiracy theories blending together which is causing a lot of issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
