<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197802628.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39rlhg/cmv_killing_baby_cows_for_food_is_no_more_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Killing baby cows for food is no more immoral than killing adult cows for food.</title>
    <original_poster>Arandur</original_poster>
    <original_post>Cows are neither sentient nor intelligent. They don't anticipate the future, they don't make plans, they're not moved to tears by bringing a new little cow life into the world. Given that killing animals for food is not generally immoral^1 ,  there is not such a great difference between the experience of a baby cow and an adult cow that one will experience death any differently than the other; neither is the life of a cow so rich and fulfilling^2 that it's immoral to deprive a baby cow of it before it dies.

Therefore, I should not feel any worse eating veal than I do eating a hamburger.

^1 If you disagree with this, that's a different argument entirely; I'm glad to hear your opinion on the matter, but you won't change my view unless your argument assumes this point.

^2 Just the opposite, presently; the lives of cows are full of pain and discomfort, because our (American) food-raising process is horrifying. I *do* think that this is unethical, just based on the principle that pain is a bad thing, but it's not a massive priority for me because I think the amount of human suffering is significantly greater at this time than the amount of animal suffering (due to the greater capacity of a human to experience suffering). Again, this isn't the topic of my CMV, but if you want to give your opinion on the matter I'd be glad to hear it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27824601458.0" user="friendlyelephant" delta="True">
    <text>I actually had this [exact debate yesterday](https://www.reddit.com/r/vegan/comments/39khuv/my_least_favorite_thing_about_australia_is_their/cs4srum) over on /r/vegan, I'm curious if you were motivated by that to post this? I'll take on your argument here though. I've been meaning to look into this more in depth anyway.

So I disagree with you that (1) does not matter. The only way for me to say that it is worse to kill a baby cow than an adult cow is to say that there are degrees of badness in killing animals, and that requires me to be able to say that it can be bad to kill an animal, otherwise I could only say that it is not bad to kill animals, and there could be no degree of immorality in that scenario. And I think you must admit that there are degrees of such, as my neighbor's pet dog is clearly much happier than a calf in a veal crate, and you have said that happiness and suffering does matter in animals. The question is then, does the calf suffer more than your average beef cow?

Now while I think you under-estimate the cow's ability to feel pain, I don't think I need to press this point so much as the difference between a veal calf's reality and a standard beef cow's. Beef cows do spend time outside. Here's an [EPA article](http://www.epa.gov/agriculture/ag101/beefphases.html) on the subject. However, the outside they spend time in often does not have grass, and is only a feedlot. During winter they can be confined inside, and also confined a few months before slaughter to help fatten them up. They are most often dehorned as well, without anesthetic. However, veal calves not only experience all this, (94% of dairy calves are dehorned, while about 17% of those calves are given anesthetic. [Page 109](http://www.aphis.usda.gov/animal_health/nahms/dairy/downloads/dairy07/Dairy07_ir_CalfHealth.pdf). There's no debate that dehorning causes pain.) but must do so *while being starved and confined in a crate for the entirety of their life.* So I think we can say that veal calves suffer at least twice as much as your average beef cow.

Duration of suffering matters too though. So how long is that miserable calf's existence? The MSPCA says veal calves suffer [for about 18 weeks](http://www.mspca.org/programs/animal-protection-legislation/animal-welfare/farm-animal-welfare/factory-farming/cows/veal-calves-on-a-factory-farm.html), or 4.5 months before slaughter, and since the age of veal calves is such a contentious issue, pretty much all sources have the same number. I couldn't find any official data on beef cows, (or steers), but scouring around forums gives me about 18 months for commercially raised, non-grass fed beef. ([1](http://www.homesteadingtoday.com/livestock-forums/cattle/235359-age-slaughter-steer.html),[2](http://www.teara.govt.nz/en/beef-farming/page-7),[3](http://www.grass-fed-solutions.com/feeding-cattle.html)).

So the numbers add up quite nicely, 18/4.5 = 4, meaning steers suffer for 4 times as long as veal calves before slaughter. So the suffering of 1 veal calf is 1 unit, and a steer is 4 units. However, (and there is official USDA data on this, thank god), we get about [880 lbs](http://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/results/BD7FAEF0-CFC8-3E27-A0EB-67C04E8FB488) of edible meat per beef cow, and only about [175 lbs](http://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/results/4D51FF2B-04BC-3312-8D46-ED424F7C2D01) per veal calf. 880/175 = ~5, meaning per lb of meat you eat, you cause a 5x longer duration of suffering for veal calves. do the math and we have 5 units of suffering per lb of veal eaten, and 4 units per lb of beef. This is purely on a basis of duration, not intensity, of suffering... even though as I've argued above, we have good reason to believe that veal calves suffer more. So you would have to actually argue not only that veal calves don't suffer more, but that they actually *suffer less*, in order to justify the view that eating veal is no worse than eating beef.

On top of that, every purchase of veal covers a negative expense of the dairy industry. If we stopped paying for veal, not only would the dairy industry lose its profits, but it would actually suffer, as it would still be producing calves, simply not selling them. Whereas if we were to stop buying burgers, the beef industry would stop raising cattle, and would lose profits, but not actually go into debt.

And finally, there's a great practical reason to consider veal worse than beef, once again, *even if the suffering is the same.* Imagine I give you the opportunity to live in two societies. One in which it is considered just as bad to kill an adult as it is a baby, and one in which it is considered worse to kill a baby than an adult. I think it's clear that a society that considers cruelty to adults not as bad as cruelty to children would be a better society, for indirect reasons such as the need to protect children more, and the moral innocence of children, and by saying that there's nothing worse in killing a baby for food than there is in killing an adult, you're supporting a worse society, however rational your view may seem at surface.

All things considered, I think there's very good reason to find killing baby cows for food more immoral than killing adult cows, even though both are clearly immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
