<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27843100025.0" user="Futchkuk" delta="True">
    <text>First of all your premise eliminates the main reason why people have a problem with the festival, but I'll play along as best I can. 

The dog was domesticated somewhere between 15,000 and 30,000 years ago while man existed as a hunter gatherer, by comparison the cow, sheep, and pig was domesticated around 8,000 years ago and are tied with man's development of agriculture. So we have had a relationship with dogs for at least twice as long as any of the animals we use as a food source. This also shows that we never intended them as a livestock animal since we literally had not developed that concept at the time.


15,000 years ago man and wolves filled much the same niche and had many similarities, both traveled in nomadic packs hunting much the same animals, even our social structures are remarkably similar. It has been theorized that the domestication of wolves was not some thing we actively did but rather a gradual symbiosis. Wolves fed on our scraps and wolves less aggressive to us thrived while more aggressive ones failed. Wolves following our tribes served as a deterrent to larger predators and a free alarm system notifying us of any approaching threat. Eventually we began to work together to bring down prey. Wolves became dogs and we welcomed them into our huts and our families.

 At no point is there evidence of us using them directly as a food source except when no other sources were available. In fact meat eaters like dogs are terrible animals to use as direct food animals, every time you move up the food chain a step the amount of meat for resources required to create it diminishes dramatically. Essentially it takes a given amount of energy to grow grass which comes from the sun, a pig eating that grass can only convert a small portion of that total energy into meat, and a dog eating that pig can only convert a even smaller portion of the energy from that meat into its own meat. Carnivores are just not designed to put on weight like herbivores. For this reason actual farming of dogs is horribly inefficient and completely uneconomical. This  is why so many of the dogs for this festival are kidnapped instead of farmed, it's the only truly viable way to provide that much meat. What is the purpose of growing perfectly edible meat to feed to dogs which will produce exponentially less meat than you originally fed them for a product (dog meat) that from everything I've heard is not exponentially better.

 Since dogs make for terrible livestock instead we bred them to depend on us emotionally and to see us as members of their pack. Dogs have several abilities which uniquely augment our own such as speed, loyalty, intelligence, sharper senses, and hunting ability. Dogs and humans are the only animals that use visual cues to communicate, it certainly was not inherent in them before domestication and is not in any other domesticated animal showing that we viewed them as closer to equals to be communicated with than livestock to be slaughtered. We used these dogs to help us survive in a very harsh world by aiding us in hunting and protection. Dogs literally put food on our table and watched over us while we slept for thousands of years. In recent years dogs have been much less critical to our success as a species but still provide many valuable functions. In a very real sense our species and theirs are for no better word "married" we have developed an bond, depended on, and provided for each other in a symbiotic relationship that goes far deeper than any other domesticated animal for tens of thousands of years. 


TL:DR
Essentially Dogs were never intended to be livestock like pigs and cows. They would be horribly inefficient if we used them that way due to their carnivore nature, which means if a ready supply of pets to be stolen did not exist it's likely this festival would also not exist for lack of supply.  A tradition of eating dog can only ever thrive on the immorality of stealing dogs or incredibly uneconomical waste of resources farming them. We also have a deep and inherent debt to them for protecting, feeding, and loving us for far longer than recorded human history. All of these things are unique to dogs and show why eating dog is not the same as eating pig, but rather a betrayal of all that they have done for us over the last 15-30 thousand years. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
