<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40699667845.0" user="3xtheredcomet" delta="True">
    <text>OP,

From my reading, your entire post is presented as if from the rich person's point of view. The angle I'm going to attempt here won't necessarily invalidate your stance, but I want to broaden the scope a bit. Lemmessplain:

It is not *just* that the poor covet the rich; we all ultimately covet what we do not have. The rich covet the rich. The poor covet the slightly less poor. "The grass is always greener", envy being one of the seven deadly sins, and all that jazz. 

How many rich people play their ridiculous games of one-upmanship? They're already rich, so what does it matter? And yet, they do it anyway. I just got an 8:30 rez at Dorsia, great sea-urchin ceviche. How many poor people flex, buying something outside of their budget for their momentary status? Hell, how many upper middle class people blow their cost of living way out of proportion in order to keep up with the Joneses?

The rich sometimes (actually often) *even covet the poor*. How many Black genres of music were co-opted throughout the decades? Why are pre-distressed, pre-ripped jeans more expensive than fully intact jeans? Why did all the cheap cuts of beef, oxtail, hanger steak, get expensive all of a sudden? 

**People covet**, not just the poor. Rich vs. poor is merely the most visible form of have and have-nots. Rich vs. poor is ultimately an arbitrary categorization.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
