<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="207157398.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fc3o6/cmv_people_who_give_their_kids_two_last_names_are/">
    <title>CMV: People who give their kids two last names are inconsiderate</title>
    <original_poster>NeoshadowXC</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a lot of fun at the expense of people with two last names. This is a tough one, because I do believe a woman shouldn't be socially pressured into taking her's husband's last name, and gay spouses also have a conundrum of their own. 

However, I think that a family should have a family name, because otherwise you are choosing to make everyone else's life difficult. One small example is if you work in an industry where you deal with a lot of names and families and meeting people blind (like I do). It's helpful to know in advance who is related to who by just looking at a piece of paper.

BUT, if the wife and the husband choose not to share a last name, please God settle on one name for your kid. Just flip a coin for which last name your kid takes if that's what you need to do. Don't make everyone around him have to deal with saying and writing out Reginald Henry Lieberman-Montgomery. 

A metaphor I would make for this would be gender pronouns. You have the right to tell me whether you identify as a man or a woman, but I swear to God if you insist that everyone around you refer to you strictly with the gender neutral pronouns Ni, Nem and Nir, I will be having none of it. 

As a counterpoint, I will say that I can't ever imagine myself taking my wife's last name. And if she chose not to take mine, I think I would feel a little disappointed. Further, I can't imagine feeling comfortable with my kid not taking my last name. So I already recognize a bit of the hypocrisy. In that way, I see that I am posing a problem without an apparent solution. On top of your rebuttals, I would also be curious to hear alternative ideas/social structures that could work to level the playing field, AND prevent me from having to say a mouthful. 

**EDIT:**

Apologies for the day long delay-- car emergency took all night and all morning.

Thanks for all your responses! Here are some of my views you've changed. 

Spain &amp;gt; 'Murica. There's a clear system in place in Spanish countries that actually speaks to my "one family name" point. People consistently take the fathers, then mother's surname. Then the kid's kids will do the same. Gives you family history and also something to put on your mailbox. 

What I personally like about this is that it's uniform. If two last names were adopted country-wide in America, I would have much less of a problem with it. 

I also want to clarify: My problem with the "mouthful" of hyphenated last names does not mean that I would also suggest gentrifying the Krzyzewskis and the Chevaprevadumrongs of the world. To shorten your family name is to bastardize it. No ill feelings to those with shortened last names of course-- my last name was actually gentrified two generations ago. 

Finally, here is a post that very well summarizes my American sentiments: 

&amp;gt; While this drifts from your true argument, these lines of thinking quickly move into the larger name-choice debate, which in my experience usually boils down to “People who name their kids something I like or understand are exercising reasonable freedom of choice. People who name their kids something I dislike or don’t understand are selfish and stupid.” You have not said this, but I think it is worth pointing out that are cultural biases about names are deep-seated.

&amp;gt; You want people to have choices about identity labels - - - as long as every choice is based on what you find easiest and most comfortable. If a stranger's choice is not based on your preference, they are selfish and inconsiderate. When a family you do not know fills out a birth certificate, you ask that the FIRST priority be guessing your experience if you meet their child at work in twenty years, and the SECOND priority be articulating their identity as a family in a way that feels personally appropriate.

My American sensibilities that shorter is better are deeply ingrained and will probably be there 'til I die. That said, at least I can recognize them so that I know to keep them in check. 

While I will continue to make fun of people who have two last names, it will be with the same conviction that I make fun of everyone else. No hostility here.

Thanks guys!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27915086079.0" user="ChristopherMarlowe" delta="True">
    <text>I think you already know you are rationally incorrect, but you are trying to justify an instinctive preference for the naming system that   "feels" right in your gut. The single-last-name-of-father system likely feels most correct to you because it (a) is most familiar and (b) gives you the most benefits while asking the fewest concessions. First, you know that you have an ingrained and biased preference about names: you prefer your wife and children take your name, but would feel uncomfortable or disappointed by the opposite. This is not a topic on which you are neutral and simply trying to find the easiest universal system.

As a measure of clarity – who is related to whom – hyphenating provides *more* information. The single-last-name system obscures familial relationships in comparison.

As a measure of legal identity – how many people share your name – hyphenating makes each name more distinct. 

I too work in an industry where I deal with thousands of names and families. The single last name system does not allow me to know “who is related to who” at anything better than an educated guess. I know dozens of families who share last names but no close relation. I know dozens of blended families. I know dozens of guardians who don’t share names with children, and committed couples who are not married. I also know siblings who get mistaken for spouses, and spouses who have been mistaken for siblings. Helping strangers make assumptions based on a single last name seems like the weakest possible defense. 

As a matter of personal identity – the right of a couple to determine family identity and choose names that are appropriate, representative, and meaningful – having a range of possibilities means couples can make a decision about how they understand their family construction. Group labeling and identity are incredibly strong sociological forces. 

As a measure of ease – spelling, length – that consideration does not exist in any other naming context, and it becomes absurd to try to impose the ease standard universally. If your wife had a much shorter last name than you, would it be inconsiderate to give your own name to your children? Is it unnecessarily complicated to give children a first name with more than one syllable? Is it unacceptable to name your child after your French mother if the name may be difficult for American businesses? 

Maybe more to he point, though, the difference in ease between the most complex and most simple names I have *ever* written has been minor - a dozen letters, a double-check on spelling, a confirmation. Literally a difference of a few seconds. 

While this drifts from your true argument, these lines of thinking quickly move into the larger name-choice debate, which in my experience usually boils down to “People who name their kids something I like or understand are exercising reasonable freedom of choice. People who name their kids something I dislike or don’t understand are selfish and stupid.” You have not said this, but I think it is worth pointing out that are cultural biases about names are deep-seated.

I do see nods to individual choice in your post, but only if you never have to interact with a world where people choose differently than you. 

Women should not have to take their husband’s name, but you only want to marry a woman who will. Men should have the option to take their wife’s name, but you'll never consider it. Children can have either parent's name, as long as yours have *only* their father's. Gay couples need ways to build family identity, but only if you don't have to see a hyphenated name.

You want people to have choices about identity labels - - - as long as every choice is based on what you find easiest and most comfortable. If a stranger's choice is not based on your preference, they are selfish and inconsiderate. When a family you do not know fills out a birth certificate, you ask that the FIRST priority be guessing your experience if you meet their child at work in twenty years, and the SECOND priority be articulating their identity as a family in a way that feels personally appropriate. 

Also, as a side-note, it is a pretty well-documented phenomenon that people are less likely to change a position after taking a public stance. You begin by saying you have “had a lot of fun at the expense of people with two last names.” If you have expressed “joking” superiority or derision towards people who do not like the same names you like, then you may feel compelled to justify that you were just smarter all along, rather than arbitrarily judgmental or dickish. 

Edit: Formatting

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
