<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922414024.0" user="Tarediiran" delta="True">
    <text>Although you personally do not like tipping, the custom exists for good reason. If people did not tip and servers had to earn their living from only wages, food prices would increase to compensate the additional cost required to sustain the servers.  In addition to this, not tipping is typically frowned upon because the stiff is disregarding the server's humanity.

Eliminating the tip would not save money for anyone in the long run because restaurants will simply up the price of their food. Imagine a scenario in which one had to pay $10 + at least 20% tips, thus raising the price to $12. If tipping ceased, the restaurant would simply raise the initial price of the food to $12. The consumer still has to pay the same amount. However, under the tip system, servers can try to provide better service because they have an incentive for doing so. Tipping helps both the consumer and the server, and as such, it is more preferrable to tip than provide a base wage.

The server is paid a base wage of +/- $2/hour to ensure that they walk home with at least something. It's a protection of their income stability, much like how many salespeople of supermarkets like Walmart are paid much lower than what the skill demands because salespeople make commission. The base wage for a server is not meant to sustain the server. It is only meant to be used as a backup if income from tips is too low. Servers actually earn their money from providing and enhancing a good service by taking away plates and bringing food to the customer. Keep in mind that when consumers pay the price tag for the meal, they are paying only for the cook's labor and the cost of the ingredients. Tips are not factored in because they provide an incentive for servers to give giving a better service. While you may argue that cooks should be tipped too under this logic because then cooks have an incentive to cook better, the action is simply unrealistic to implement because a cook spends most of his or her time optimizing efficiency in the kitchen. To have to deal with tips is to immediately handicap the maximum achievement the cooks can accomplish.

People who serve are doing so to sustain their families. They try to provide the best service because they need something from you: money. A person who does not tip goves everyone else around him or her that he or she is rich, but chooses to spend cheaply anyway. It's a rude gesture, especially when someone else (the server) is expending a reasonable effort to provide the consumer with a better environment surrounding a meal. Tipping shows some respect to the server, which is arguably more important than saving $2 here and there. It's common knowledge that people didn't pay for the service up front and that stiffing the server results in making the server's life harder to live.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
