<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209099690.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ghqcq/cmv_the_tactics_used_at_the_bernie_sanders_rally/">
    <title>CMV: The tactics used at the Bernie Sanders rally interruption did not consider the primary and most effective mechanism of enacting change via direct action</title>
    <original_poster>uoaei</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people today don't understand how protest and action actually lead to change. 

It doesn't work by shouting down the person who has the power to do things about it until they relent to the power moves and aggressive posturing. It succeeds when the minds of the general populace are changed at a high rate toward the verbalized cause. Through the witnessing of such actions and protests, suddenly the people turn their gaze toward those in power, who feel the stare of everyone looking at them, oppressing them with genuine and widespread mistrust of their stances. The people display a collective "what are you going to do about it now?" and the power of those at the top is actually threatened by the people who support them from below. 

This is the moment when those in the comfortable seat of power relent, and no sooner. 

It is public shaming via conversion, not force. Those at the top hate to be hated by the majority: it translates to mutiny. 

And I don't mean conversion from 'against' to 'with' the movement. Instead, I mean conversion from 'passive' to 'active'. Calling an entire crowd of 15000+ people "racists" does not change a people's minds, it puts them on the defensive. This is basic psychology. It helps no one when it's one voice at a time that's angry, it helps a lot when everyone's angry at the same person, at the same time. The boos at the rally in question did not start en masse until the entire crowd felt attacked by the name-calling (why does everyone overlook this? Why have absolutely none of the thoughtpieces I've read so far reference this blatant and obvious fact?). The people in the crowd were not against the movement to begin with, and they still aren't. You can hear the cheers yourself. 

I understand these people are not representative of the entire movement. This is not an attack on the movement in general (which I am a supporter of, though not an active player due to my expatriation), this is a critique of a particular tactic that I think ignores medium- and long-term consequences of short-term actions. Especially shrieking "WE ARE REASONABLE!!!!" quite unreasonably and name-calling those from whom you demand respect and silence.

P.S. Please direct me somewhere I can have an intellectual discussion about this, without it being interjected with people agreeing with me simply because they're racist and have their own agenda to push, running their mouths and distracting the conversation from my original points. That keeps happening to me and it delegitimates my statements when they are associated with such vitriol.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27932652230.0" user="lolylolerton" delta="True">
    <text>So, I think your argument can be split into two parts.

**I. This method is not effective**

I think the most convincing argument in favor of the BLM protesters is that it worked. Sanders was forced/convinced to release a more comprehensive platform on racial violence in this country due to the vast amount of flack he has been given by BLM, both recently and at netroots. 

Secondly, you say

&amp;gt;It succeeds when the minds of the general populace are changed at a high rate toward the verbalized cause. Through the witnessing of such actions and protests, suddenly the people turn their gaze toward those in power, who feel the stare of everyone looking at them, oppressing them with genuine and widespread mistrust of their stances. The people display a collective "what are you going to do about it now?" and the power of those at the top is actually threatened by the people who support them from below.

But I think we are already at that point. Most people recognize that there is a systemic problem in the way policing works that makes excessive force more likely to occur and to go without punishment, and most people also recognize that police violence is disproportionately focused on people of color, specifically black bodies.

What we are lacking is concrete policy proposals by those in power to alleviate the distress of the population, and that is what the BLM protesters accomplished.

**II. This method is targeting the wrong people**

I think you are wrong to say Sander's supporters are pro-BLM. The huge backlash on reddit has shown, not only to this event but also to the shooting yesterday in Ferguson, judging by top comments in large/default subs such as /r/news, has been overwhelmingly anti-black, and anti-BLM. You may say this was because of the specific tactic, but more often then not the criticism was leveled at the movement itself with this incident being the trigger for the anger, not the cause.

Secondly, Bernie Sanders has come to represent the new "champion of liberalism/ progressivism" in America, and as such needs to be held to a high standard. His comments at netroots and his whole platform of worker solidarity are seen by many to push racial issues under the rug of income inequality or the fight against "capitalism." To many, this is not seen as an adequate response, and because of these tactics, Bernie has clarified his views and updated his platform.

The biggest obstacle for Sanders to win a nomination is outreach to minorities, a demographic with which he currently polls very poorly with (I think in large part due to the attitude of his supporters). These incidents and his response have shown to help both sides, appeasing BLM and helping hammer out a better platform on police violence.

**III. These are not mutually exclusive**

Finally, your view states that they did not take certain avenues of action into consideration, however, there is no reason you cannot do both as one does not sacrifice the other. You can raise awareness and confront leaders. BLM has consistently done both and through these policies has made a real difference on the way politicians are talking about police violence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
