<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881150229.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. 

This is a very bold claim.

&amp;gt;They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

This is not mutually exclusive with your initial, bold claim. 

My primary argument is against your initial, bold claim. It is bold because it is implicitly an accusation of bad faith. I was raised in an evangelical fundamentalist household. Until I was ~14 (honestly I can't pinpoint when I started questioning but by the time I was a young adult I was not religious) I fully believed Hell was real, God smote the evil, and the righteous will prosper.

*Let me just call out that there is simply no reason for a person to do some of the things believers do unless they are true believers.* In evangelicalism this is well above 50% of people (we're pushing 80% at least). One thing you don't state but what I strongly believe (and you may very well agree with) is that people project their beliefs onto god as a way of insulating their beliefs from self-reflection and finding similarly-minded people. It's this insulation that prevents them from realizing they are projecting in the first place. It also allows them to avoid cognitive dissonance while maintaining genuine, contradictory beliefs in some cases. 

As a ancillary argument I want to state that there is a high probability that someone inherits the beliefs of their parents. It's not 100% though! It's not even close.

https://geneticliteracyproject.org/2015/11/17/are-religious-convictions-heritable/#:~:text=Religiosity%20is%20moderately%20heritable%E2%80%9425,Lewis%20and%20Bates%2C%202013).

I've seen studies where the heritability is as high as 65%. The source above states 25-45% which is much weaker.

So the answer to your question of whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents followed a different religion is at best *probably* but also very likely not.

My first argument should dispel this idea that religious people generally do not believe what they say they believe.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
