<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42344071744.0" user="recurrenTopology" delta="True">
    <text>Roads do not generally (given a long enough time span) decrease traffic on account of induced demand. Roads do, however, move people around. Consider adding a third lane to a two lane highway. In a few years congestion will return to the roughly the level it was prior to the road expansion, however that road will now be carrying approximately 50% more people. Those will be people going to work, to see friends, to recreation, etc. Increased traffic represents an increase in the number of people getting from where they are to where they want to be.

In essentially all US cities (with the exception of maybe NYC) the road network is the most important means of civilian transportation. Land use patterns have developed which reflect the capacity of the built road network (this is what creates the induced demand), so severely restricting the capacity of that network without providing an alternative would be a disaster for mobility in urban areas.

A policy of this sort would have worked had it been in place from the beginning, with city development occurring in response to a more limited road network. American cities would have undoubtably had better public transit and walkability. However, this is an instance where you can't unbreak the egg: American cities have developed with their road networks, and those road networks now represent an essential component of how those cities function. I support road diet programs, but the process has to be gradual to allow public transportation and development patterns to evolve to reflect the changing transportation paradigm. An immediate change as you are proposing wouldn't just be a rough transition, it would render cities completely inoperable.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
