<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442637028.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>How do you create any word problems for STEM when you arent teaching reading comprehension, basic literacy, grammar, etc?

I dont want to have to teach a group of high schoolers how basic puncutation works for a lab report.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
