<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2454551757.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14ldk99/cmv_most_communities_are_echo_chambers_its_not/">
    <title>CMV: Most communities are echo chambers. It's not echo chambers that are inherently harmful, it's echo chambers that echo world-shaping ideas that are.</title>
    <original_poster>ivyinthewait</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most communities are echo chambers in order to create a civil environment. Racism, homophobia, ableism etc. tend to be filtered out of communities in order to protect the mental health of community members who are apart of these marginalised groups while also upholding a civil and non-toxic environment. This is an echo chamber because it causes a lack of exposure to alternative viewpoints. This specific type of echo chamber is the most popular form of echo chamber we see on the internet today and can be seen in places like music communities, gaming communities, art communities etc. I classify this form of echo chamber as harmless. An etiquette is required to form a community which considers the mental health of the members within it.  


The actual issue we have with "echo chambers" are the ideas they are echoing. Political echo chambers, conspiracy echo chambers, hate groups, pseudo-science or anti-science echo chambers, etc. These echo chambers are harmful due to the inherent world-shaping views that come with them. There is a difference between an echo chamber with a focus on creating a civil environment and an echo chamber that tries to pull you into a specific way to view the world and how the world should work. Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.   


&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42923691367.0" user="RodeoBob" delta="True">
    <text>So, in order to have this discussion, the first thing we need to do is define "echo chamber", or at least come to an agreement on what the meaningful traits are.

An echo chamber is **not** simply a community. It is not merely a community that censors intolerant views, or moderates conversations to keep things on-topic. 

Echo chambers have at least two distinct, key features. 

One of those is a pattern of manipulating members into increasing closeness by methodically discrediting all outside sources. This sort of "You can't trust anyone but us, because everyone else is lying" approach looks and feels very cultish. This 'us versus the world' framing is key feature of an echo chamber. This is above-and-beyond the typical sense of a community. 

The other key feature of an echo chamber is the sequencing of having ideas, gathering evidence, and discussion. A typical approach towards new ideas is for an individual to be exposed to and/or gather information, form an opinion or explanation, and then seek to have that opinion challenged by others through logical analysis and/or additional information. In an echo chamber, the opinion comes *first*, and then others provide information that supports the opinion and excludes and discredits anything that challenges it. 

To illustrate these features, imagine the following claim being made in a given community:

"I see a lot of crime and homelessness in my city. I think it's because people are lazy bums, and a lot of them are minorities."

How would our imaginary community act? 

Would this community *agree* with this assertion, and follow that agreement with pre-emptive criticism of conflicting evidence? "Oh yeah, and the city government just loves to waste taxpayer money on stupid projects like giving junkies free needles and making the cops be more sensitive instead of kicking those freeloaders off the sidewalk!"

Or does this imaginary community challenge some aspect of the view? "Well, the police blotter and crime statistics actually show we're at a 5 year low on a lot of those things. Maybe you're just noticing it more, or maybe it's because people have been pushed out of where they used to camp and you're seeing them in your neighborhood for the first time..."

&gt;Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.

The problem I have with this claim is that there's no exception for ideas that are factually incorrect and/or objectively false. There's no distinction made between other perspectives that are grounded in reality and distorted perspectives formed by rhetoric over reason. 

You see this a lot with folks who like to talk about "the marketplace of ideas", too. Yes, there's a marketplace for ideas, but the market has repeatedly, definitively rejected some ideas, and pretending like we should keep allowing those ideas to re-circulate with the same standing and legitimacy as new ideas is absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
