<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2454551757.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14ldk99/cmv_most_communities_are_echo_chambers_its_not/">
    <title>CMV: Most communities are echo chambers. It's not echo chambers that are inherently harmful, it's echo chambers that echo world-shaping ideas that are.</title>
    <original_poster>ivyinthewait</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most communities are echo chambers in order to create a civil environment. Racism, homophobia, ableism etc. tend to be filtered out of communities in order to protect the mental health of community members who are apart of these marginalised groups while also upholding a civil and non-toxic environment. This is an echo chamber because it causes a lack of exposure to alternative viewpoints. This specific type of echo chamber is the most popular form of echo chamber we see on the internet today and can be seen in places like music communities, gaming communities, art communities etc. I classify this form of echo chamber as harmless. An etiquette is required to form a community which considers the mental health of the members within it.  


The actual issue we have with "echo chambers" are the ideas they are echoing. Political echo chambers, conspiracy echo chambers, hate groups, pseudo-science or anti-science echo chambers, etc. These echo chambers are harmful due to the inherent world-shaping views that come with them. There is a difference between an echo chamber with a focus on creating a civil environment and an echo chamber that tries to pull you into a specific way to view the world and how the world should work. Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.   


&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42924992265.0" user="Soft_Marionberry_221" delta="True">
    <text>While your argument presents a compassionate and empathetic viewpoint, it's important to consider that labeling all communities that protect marginalized groups as "echo chambers" can oversimplify the complexities of these spaces and their dynamics. Furthermore, even though there is a clear distinction between communities that foster respect and those that promote harmful beliefs, it might not be accurate or fair to classify one as inherently "harmless."  
  
Firstly, the term "echo chamber" often carries negative connotations, suggesting that members of such a community are uncritically repeating the same views without considering alternative perspectives. However, communities that support marginalized groups often do not blindly echo the same ideas. Instead, they aim to provide safe spaces for people who may face discrimination, harassment, or misunderstanding in other areas of their lives. Such communities often actively encourage open dialogue and understanding, rather than merely echoing the same points.  
  
Secondly, even communities that create a civil environment can have unintended consequences. For instance, they might inadvertently exclude individuals who hold different views but are willing to engage in respectful conversation and learn. This can lead to a lack of diversity in thought and even isolate the community from broader societal discourse, which is not entirely harmless.  
  
Thirdly, while it's important to create communities that prioritize the mental health of their members, these communities should also strive to educate and enlighten others about the issues they focus on. If they turn into echo chambers that do not engage with outside perspectives, they may lose opportunities to raise awareness and foster understanding among a broader audience.  
  
Lastly, the dichotomy between 'harmless' and 'harmful' echo chambers can be misleading. Any community that discourages critical thinking, open dialogue, and exposure to diverse perspectives can potentially lead to an insular mindset, even if its intentions are noble.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
