<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43066677560.0" user="rollingForInitiative" delta="True">
    <text>The mutually assured destruction of nuclear weapons works (or has so far) because that's more of a "alright we're now going to die because Russia launched all their nukes on so, so let's take out Russia and we'll both be annihilated".

But in your case here, it's only Canada that suffers. Let's say that Russia is in a desperate situation, and they think the best solution is to invade Canada and take the water. They think Canada is bluffing and won't detonate the nukes. Canada gets in invaded. There are now two scenarios:

1) Canada doesn't detonate the nukes. The Canadian may or may not be in a very tough situation, but they survive. They can potentially drive the Russians out. Or maybe they get integrated into Russia and keeping living that way.

2) Canada detonates the nukes. Russia withdraws, is no worse off than before. Canada is a disaster zone with not drinkable water. Lots of people die from radiation poisoning, from the blasts themselves, or from thirst.

Russia doesn't really lose that much either way, so why would it deter them if they're very very desperate?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
