<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28275005989.0" user="TechJesus" delta="True">
    <text>It strikes me that you've exaggerated one view (conservatism) and taken that as the norm whilst using a moderate version of the other (progressivism*) as a point of comparison. As below:

&amp;gt; Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. [...] Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Most conservatives accept change is inevitable, but feel that it should be managed to protect the existing positive aspects of society. Indeed this is outlined thoroughly in the writings of the British politician Edmund Burke, who is often cited as the father of Anglocentric conservatism. 

Progressives may not usually want change for its own sake, but they're often more willing to risk existing strengths in pursuit their goals. Partly this is because progressives often see existing structures as the cause of problems, without acknowledging their positives. For instance, many progressives would point to capitalism as the cause of inequality (a fair point) but would not acknowledge capitalism is superb at generating wealth (in the sense of products and services).

To take your next point:

&amp;gt; This to me seems like they [conservatives] are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. 

At the far end of conservatism you have the view that society is very fragile, and that institutions built up over centuries can be shattered in a short space of time. This is why conservatives have taboos around criticising traditions, though they may not articulate it as such.

To some degree it's arguable the progressive/conservative spectrum is defined by one characteristic: risk appetite. Progressives tend to be willing to gamble to improve society, conservatives tend not to be.

PS. If you're interested in this I recommend looking up Thomas Sowell, an American economist who has written widely on conservatism compared to progressivism, especially in *A Conflict of Visions*. 

*I've used "progressives" throughout this, but to my mind the proper counterpoint would be "radicals", even allowing that one can have conservative radicals (reactionaries).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
