<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28275170465.0" user="Nepene" delta="True">
    <text>I have a lot of sympathy for change and social welfare. Most people do. George Bush, under the ideology of compassionate conservatism, worked with Ted Kennedy, a Democrat, to improve the American education system, massively increased healthcare with medicare part D, increased the federal workforce, increased federal spending on each household, did the PEPFAR program to help AIDs victims in Africa. He did a huge amount to increase social welfare for people and change society.

Many liberals are extremely non open to change. Both of the democrat presidential candidates are opposed to nuclear power, school choice, they're widely against GMO food,

http://voices.washingtonpost.com/fact-checker/2008/04/dr_obama_and_dr_mccain.html

Obama has claimed that vaccines cause autism, like many members of the democrat party, and pushed against change like people not dying from diseases. 

http://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704335904574497324151841690

And that had immediate consequences, with the US not having as many swine flu shots because they refused to use adjuvants which quadruple the effectiveness of vaccines but which anti science people think cause autism. 

Lots of people are dead because liberals don't embrace change when they see a problem with the current system. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
