<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248893922.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/446ns2/cmv_the_middle_east_will_be_consumed_by_chaos_for/">
    <title>CMV: The Middle East will be consumed by chaos for the rest of the 21st Century</title>
    <original_poster>AssFaceKillaaa</original_poster>
    <original_post>Change takes a long time. Things happen overnight, but we don't see true effects until removed by a generation or two. There have been myriad of conflicts in the middle east for the entirety of my life, as well as most of the last century. Over the course of the last Century, The Middle East was thrown into Chaos due to many factors: 

-The redrawing of borders which effectively isolated portions of ethnic or religious groups into minority/majority regions that would form the basis of targeted persecution for regimes at later times (disbanding the Ottoman Empire/reshaping political landscape of the region).

-The discovery of massive oil reserves across the region which would turn some states into the massive economic powers (Saudi Arabia/Iran/Qatar/UAE... and on and on) that would drastically effect their relation to the rest of the world.

 -The formation of the State of Israel, and subsequent dissimilation of Palestine (this one should be obvious..)

-The growth of what would become an endemic trend of militia groups backed by states foreign or otherwise for purposes of fighting Proxy-Wars or affecting regional influence. (i.e. Mujahideen turned into Taliban turned into Al-Qeadea turned into ISIS...)

Because of these and many other reasons, I believe that the region as a whole will continue to see failing Nation States, massive civilian casualties, continued violent confrontations between Nations, Rebel groups, and civilians, and systemic corruption for *at least* the next 85 years. **I don't believe through supporting Regime Change, or diplomatically informed policy decisions will affect meaningful change in the region in this century.**

 Or to put it another way: *The damage has been done.* 

PLEASE CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28277892302.0" user="lameth" delta="True">
    <text>Within the next century we could very well see, due to rising global temperatures, the middle east becoming every more inhospitable to life. What I expect to see by 2060 is mass migration out of the region, as temperatures will finally become unbearable for those living in the area. A less hospitable area with less people then becomes less caustic, which will kill the incentives for much of the hostility.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
