<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="250195022.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/44yjpq/cmv_nuclear_power_should_be_widely_adopted/">
    <title>CMV: Nuclear power should be widely adopted until/unless renewable energy sources can catch up</title>
    <original_poster>LostInRiverview</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've had numerous debates with other self-described liberals (in the American sense of the word) regarding nuclear power's place in energy production and in combating climate change. During these discussions, I've held that nuclear power plants should be aggressively built in order to meet current and future electricity needs. We have agreed that non-renewable energy is a detriment to the planet, and that an ideal solution would be non-nuclear as well (e.g. solar, wind, and other as-yet-unknown methods of power generation), but they have argued that nuclear power in itself is inherently dangerous, devastating, and should not be part of our "energy portfolio" moving forward. I feel this view is based mostly on an emotional reaction to the idea of nuclear power, rather than one based in science and reason. I have pointed out that modern methods of nuclear power generation are much safer and more efficient than those developed in the mid-20th century, and many times safer than continuing to burn fossil fuels for energy. Additionally, while we are making strides towards improving our power generation through renewables, there's no guarantee that we'll ever be able to provide all the energy we need through those methods, especially if/when we transition from gas-powered to electric vehicles. Transitioning to modern nuclear reactors for electricity seems the most level-headed long-term solution to our energy problems, at least until such time as we can find better ways to generate green electricity. 

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28288281144.0" user="Recognizant" delta="True">
    <text>Nuclear energy isn't feasible to power the world, even with salts, even with breeding reactors.

* [It takes a ridiculous amount of capital and time to build a nuclear power plant.](https://www.oecd-nea.org/news/press-kits/economics-FAQ.html) It takes five to seven years to build a plant - aside from zoning concerns and planning, and can run costs of five to six billion dollars before they're finished and you can start to get anything approaching a return on investment - which means that the taxpayers would have to make a long-term investment themselves, because businesses aren't even interested with the normal capitalistic incentives.
* Fissile material is unfortunately a negative point in a world involving [terror attacks](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radiological_weapon). It's a decidedly low risk, but it's a big point against public opinion, and it can obviously be catastrophic in case of an issue. Similarly, safety is a concern in the event of natural disasters (Such as Fukushima).
* It requires a tremendous amount of water to use nuclear power generation. Fresh water is protected, Coastal places (Like Fukushima) run the risk of waves/tsunamis and similar difficulties.
* [We still don't know what to do with the end result radioactive material.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yucca_Mountain_nuclear_waste_repository#Earthquakes) Keeping it on-site is a temporary solution, but isn't viable for long-term goals.
* It's centralized. Coming back to the terrorism angle, it works too heavily against us in the way that it would allow a small break to have a wide impact. This also goes back to uranium/plutonium concerns. Fluoride salts are an option, but then it goes back to the water issues. From an economic angle, decentralization (Assuming we can manage appropriate storage) is cheaper to maintain and manage, and reduces loss due to transportation.
* No one wants a Nuclear plant anywhere near them, but solar and wind are much more acceptable to public opinion.

France, in particular, has a very nuclear-driven energy program, whose [details you can read about here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclear_power_in_France). Their water use is severe, and generation is limited during heat waves because of the temperature restrictions on the water of the inland plants. In desert environments, it's pretty unfeasible.  In areas that grow warm (particularly near rivers), it's impractical.  And the use of the water in this method can have significant problems with agriculture (Imagine justifying this level of fresh water use in California, for instance).

Some nuclear is okay, mass nuclear will probably not be a viable option for years - we would need significantly better material science, or build locations.

Solar and wind are far more viable long-term solutions than mass nuclear. Nuclear is better than fossil fuels, but we still don't have portable storage for things like transportation (Since oil is so energy dense).  If we have enough battery capability for viable electric cars and diesel trucks, then we have enough for home energy generation and storage, and we might as well go backyard solar/wind anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
