<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450321058.0" user="KnightOfThirteen" delta="True">
    <text>My understanding is that ACAB specifically means that the institution has such deep and complete corruption of its purpose and standards that while individual cops may not be directly responsible for unacceptable actions, they are by way of working in the field, contributing to the continuation of those that are.

I am personally a little torn. On one hand, there are absolutely cops who are just in it to help their own tiny sphere of influence and know that they don't have to power to change the whole system, so they choose their battles and do what good they can rather than try in futility to combat corruption, and i am a big proponent of "its okay to want to do your job and go home, not save the world". On the otherhand, public service is something that needs more people willing to die on the right hill and save the world. I know I personally could never live that life, so I give them the same respect I do a cashier or table server.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
