<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513618735.0" user="Foolhardyrunner" delta="True">
    <text>A lot of elections are primary only, the candidates aren't really competing against the other party because their seat is in a very blue or red district. 

If you are trying to win an election against an incumbent in one of these districts you have to appeal to the base because they make up a huge percent of who is voting.

&amp;#x200B;

In short its not just R vs D but also R vs R and D vs D and ideological purity can help a politician primary their opponent.

&amp;#x200B;

For the biggest election, the presidential election, you have to keep in mind that winning is not the only goal, you also have issue candidates who use the platform of presidential debates and election hype to sway the public's opinion. For examples look at Bernie and Yang, Bernie had Medicare for all and Yang had UBI.

&amp;#x200B;

They both succeeded in their elections because they increased the popularity of their issue. This doesn't push people out of the party either because, in a presidential election, after the primary the people who lost endorse the winner anyway. Even back in 2016 with Hillary Clinton who was hated by the left only about 10% of the people who voted for the "ideologically pure" candidate Bernie Sanders switched to voting for Trump in the general.

&amp;#x200B;

[https://www.npr.org/2017/08/24/545812242/1-in-10-sanders-primary-voters-ended-up-supporting-trump-survey-finds](https://www.npr.org/2017/08/24/545812242/1-in-10-sanders-primary-voters-ended-up-supporting-trump-survey-finds)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
