<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43509449739.0" user="page0rz" delta="True">
    <text>&gt;To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

Let's look at the real world, then. In the USA, the democrats had basically unbroken control of the house of representatives (and almost as much control of the senate) for like 70 years. Didn't matter who the president was, what party was in power. It was just a truism that the democrats controlled the house and senate. During that time, they were the labour party, and that helped them keep that solid control, because they had the unions

In the 80s, the democrats got stomped by Reagan. As a response, the new leadership in the 90s sprinted to the right, because they believed that's what they had to do. Reagan had been crushing unions, and instead of reinforcing that position that had kept them in power for most of the century, the democrats abandoned all positions of workers rights and became "Reagan democrats." Reagan won, so that was the smart move. Staying with the unions and workers, which the older Dems wanted to do, was just being too ideologically pure. It was virtue signalling


Ever since that flip, the democrats have been out of control of the house and senate both for the majority of terms, to the point where someone like Trump could even make a very easy and obvious political play by saying he gives any sort of fuck about workers. The unions are all gone. The democrats can never get that back. They 100% fucked themselves over to do the "smart" move of tacking to the right, permanently, because anything less would have been purity testing. And they have been losing ever since (See also: the labour party)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
