<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43523589843.0" user="918AmazingAsian" delta="True">
    <text>I feel like the subject line of this topic is making one argument whereas the argument you are making is a completely separate one.

The statement "It is illogical to not believe in Free Will" implies that there is a logical inconsistency or some logical leap that must be made in order to come to the conclusion that Free Will does not exist.

The argument stated, however, establishes a tertiary value judgement of "being right", delineates a specific definition for it, and states that "being right' is a desirable quality only within this definition.

By your stated argument "being right" does not mean that a belief accurately describes the state of the universe at large.

Instead, the stated argument begs the question and presupposes that in order for a person to be right, "free will" must first exist.

According to your argumnent, without the existence of free will, even if a person's description of the universe is free of logical contradiction or fully accurate in describing the universe, because they did not "freely" make the choice to believe it, it is not valuable.

This is an argument, but not one for the stated subject line.  In other words, it does not argue that Hard Determinism or Compatibilism is illogical.  Instead it argues the following:

- "Making a choice" requires free will.
- "Making the right choice" therefore requires free will.
- "Making the right choice" within this narrow definition that requires free will, is an inherently valuable thing.
- A description with no logical contradictions, that accurately describes the universe, if made without free will is not a choice and therefore is not valuable.
- Thus, within the parameters defined in this premise, "making the choice to believe in free will" is the only opinion that has value (value as defined within the premise itself).

Again, there's an argument to be had there, but it isn't whether or not "There is no free will" is a logical statement, for which you provide no arguments against.

Instead, the stated subject line should be something along the lines of "Whether or not free will exists, it is more personally beneficial to live with the belief that it does because if you are right, then that's good, and if not, who cares because nothing matters."

In order to argue that Hard Determinism or Compatibilisim is *illogical*, you must provide a logical contradiction/argument against it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
