<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43758485727.0" user="GCSS-MC" delta="True">
    <text>there are FAR more things to support than just this small list. Your sample size is far too small to make this claim. Here are just a few other things he did that are a reason to support him:

"His tariff threats forced Mexico to crack down on illegal immigration. Mexico is for the first time in recent history enforcing its own immigration laws — sending thousands of National Guard forces to its southern border to stop caravans of Central American migrants. Plus, Congress is poised to approve the U.S.-Mexico-Canada free-trade agreement, which would not have been possible without the threat of tariffs.

He worked toward and enforced the FDA to approve more affordable generic drugs than ever before in history. And because of that, many drug companies are freezing or reversing planned price increases.

He reformed the Medicare program to stop hospitals from overcharging low-income seniors on their drugs—saving seniors hundreds of millions of dollars \[in 2020\].  
  
Trump signed a law ending the gag orders on Pharmacists that prevented them from sharing money-saving information.

Trump signed an executive order \[in 2020\] that forces all healthcare providers to disclose the cost of their services so that Americans can comparison shop and know how much less providers charge insurance companies. When signing that bill he said no American should be blindsided by bills for medical services they never agreed to in advance. Hospitals will now be required to post their standard charges for services, which include the discounted price a hospital is willing to accept.

Trump signed 3 bills to benefit Native people. One gives compensation to the Spokane tribe for loss of their lands in the mid-1900's, one funds Native language programs, and the third gives federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians in Montana.  
  
He signed a law to make cruelty to animals a federal felony so that animal abusers face tougher consequences.

He also signed a bill to require airports to provide spaces for breastfeeding Moms."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
