<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743957896.0" user="Euphoric-Beat-7206" delta="True">
    <text> Family values: While it is true that Trump has made some questionable remarks about women, it is important to remember that he is a product of his time. He grew up in a different era, and his views on family may not be the same as those of younger conservatives. Additionally, it is important to note that Trump is a successful businessman who has created many jobs. This suggests that he is a strong leader who is capable of making tough decisions.  


Religion: While Trump may not be a religious scholar, he has spoken about the importance of faith in his life. He has also appointed conservative judges to the Supreme Court, which is a key issue for many religious conservatives.  


Managerial competence: Trump's business success is evidence of his managerial competence. He has also been able to achieve a number of policy goals since taking office, such as tax cuts and deregulation.  
   

Honest dealing: It is true that Trump has filed for bankruptcy several times. However, this is not necessarily a sign of dishonesty. In many cases, bankruptcy is a legitimate business strategy that can be used to save a company. Additionally, Trump has released more financial information than any other presidential candidate in history.  


Promises kept: Trump has kept many of his campaign promises, such as appointing conservative judges to the Supreme Court and withdrawing the United States from the Iran nuclear deal. However, he has not been able to keep all of his promises, such as building a wall on the border with Mexico.  


Decorum: Trump's demeanor is certainly different from that of previous presidents. However, his supporters see this as a sign of authenticity and strength. They believe that he is not afraid to speak his mind, even if it means ruffling feathers.  


Democracy: Trump has never said that he would not accept the results of the election if he lost. He has simply said that he wants to make sure that the election is fair. This is a legitimate concern, given the widespread voter fraud that took place in the 2020 election.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
