<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2660036271.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17zpt4f/cmv_rape_victims_have_a_harder_time_processing/">
    <title>CMV: Rape Victims Have a Harder Time Processing Their Rape Because Society Expects Them To Have the Expected Feeling of Being Raped.</title>
    <original_poster>DayOk2</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the main reason why rape victims have a harder time processing their rape is because society expects them to feel like how a rape victim is supposed to view. For example, society expects rape victims to have a particular reaction to being raped like they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

My conclusion is that rape victims would have an easier time processing their rape if society explicitly tells them to feel whatever they want to feel like. Change my view about why society does not necessarily make it harder for rape victims to process their rape.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44142972635.0" user="Relevant_Maybe6747" delta="True">
    <text>&gt;they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

has it not occurred to you that being numb, crying, being scared and embarrassed, that these are ways of processing what occurred? Not all rape is identical. Honestly I'd say the main reason rape victims have a hard time processing is a lack of sex education from a young age means plenty of children might be raped before they even know what sex is, worsening the inherent trauma of The Talk. And the entire rest of adolescence really, once you know that you've done the thing everyone talks about wanting to do and if you talk about it, you're pitied. Not to mention how people love to fantasize about violently hurting rapists, so if your rapist was a family member or friend, someone you don't necessarily want torn apart, you have every incentive to just never tell anyone and try to diminish what happened even to yourself

Then there's the shame and sense that nobody ever wants you to talk about it is another problem - you're only supposed to process in therapy so if you don't have therapy you alienate all your friends. People don't want to hear it, when they're going around at university sharing stories of when they lost their virginities, so then the victim either ruins the mood or silently is reminded of how different their experience of sex is from everyone else's.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
