<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229567485.0" user="scarab456" delta="True">
    <text>You can not like either front runner from either party, but anyone who has been following the candidate pool will understand who the most popular candidates are for the two major US parties. Campaigning for a different candidate that the most popular is a massive uphill battle.  

Just look at [the lead Biden](https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-primary-d/2024/national/) has.     

Looking at [Trumps numbers](https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-primary-d/2024/national/) he's dominating, that's in spite of there being more room for challengers.    

These are realities that you can't just ignore. Sure you can advocate for another candidate, but at this point it's almost impossible to build up another candidate in time for the election. The US has a never ending election cycle; making moves, promotion, and campaign is necessary to some degree at every point and in this cycle making a new front runner is slim. It's not there's not another candidate out there, I'm sure there's a better person. But that person needs more than just an education, they need a record, they a platform, they need experience, they need staff, they need fundraising, they need grass root support, they need to tour battle ground states, they need to secure help from major party leadership, endorsements, the list goes on.   

The worst part is that a new candidate introduces division in one party that the other will try and exploit. So it's in both parties interests to sideline internal conflicts to focus on keeping the opposition back. In the Democrats case it's an incumbent president, meaning it make makes no sense politically to not support Biden for a second term. In the Republicans case it's the sheer influence Trump has because of both his rhetoric, popularity, and the years the party has spent courting the far right end of their base. The mechanisms of politics aren't immutable, just that change is slow and needs to start much earlier than now to make a difference in **this** impending presidential election.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
