<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44438592417.0" user="Evening-Chapter3521" delta="True">
    <text>Competitive (natural) bodybuilder here.

&gt; On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing

I respect this view, and I think you may be thinking of open bodybuilding— the mass monsters in thongs. Nowadays there are other divisions that fit certain looks. For example, the Classic Physique division is arguably the most popular division with the current Mr. Olympia in the division, Chris Bumstead, having a larger following than many A-list celebrities. The Classic Physique look is more "attainable" and replicates the golden era aesthetic (think Arnold Schwarzenegger) that not only popularized the sport in the 60s but also has much greater mass appeal.

&gt; What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it.

The same reason why people think any sport is worth it: to reach the extremes of what humans are capable of. Elite bodybuilders are just like any other athlete, whether it's a sprinter, swimmer, tennis player, etc. They each have a rigorous and disciplined training, eating, sleeping, and pharmaceutical routine. The only difference is what it is within the human body that they are pushing.

Also, for some, bodybuilding is an art. Don't get me wrong, it oftentimes *is* meatheads vainly posing, but for others there is a creative and artistic aspect. It's like you're treating your own body like a slab of marble and sculpting it to an aesthetically presentable form. Regardless of what you find attractive, it's not a beauty pageant, nor is it a muscle arms race; judges look for a fine balance of proportion, shape, symmetry, and detail. No two physiques look the same even if they do the same workouts, eat the same foods, take the same drugs, and these differences allow bodybuilders to sculpt their physiques in their unique ways.

There's also an extremely creative and skillful aspect of posing. It's much more difficult than just flexing your muscles— many people including myself will say a posing session is more tiring than a workout. There is skill and practice in twisting, contorting, and tensing certain parts of your body in the right positions and angles that simultaneously *highlight* your strengths and *hide* your weaknesses. Individual routines also highlight unique styles; Kai Greene incorporated elements of hip hop and dance in his posing. In the way I described above, sounds a little like gymnastics, figure skating, or diving, huh?

&gt;  I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.

Bodybuilding appeals to me mainly because, out of any of my life pursuits, it has provided the most profound sense of "enjoying the process" rather than "the destination." Muscle gain and fat loss are physiological processes that inherently occur over time, no matter how gifted you are. What I do with my training, sleep, or diet in an hour, day, or even a week won't do anything; it's the accrual of these hours, days, and weeks of training, eating, and sleeping over several years that allow for meaningful change. For better or for worse, there is never a single climactic moment in time in the sport, because the destiny of one's competitive pursuits were determined in the preparation behind the scenes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
