<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579633186.0" user="evilgenius815" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Supported the war in Iraq

She did not "support" the war in Iraq. She voted for the Iraq war authorization measure that Bush asked for, because he said that he war authorization would be the leverage he needed with the UN and Saddam Hussein. On the floor of the Senate, while explaining her vote, she said, "A vote for [this resolution] is **not a vote to rush to war**; it is a vote that puts awesome responsibility in the hands of our President and we say to him, use these powers wisely and as a last resort." Bush was supposed to allow UN inspectors to finish their work and report, but he didn't. War was not used as a last resort but as a first and only resort, plunging the country into a decade-long ground war he had no ability to run. 

&amp;gt;Against universal health care

That depends on what "universal health care" means. She is and has always been in support of every American having health care. [She was an important figure in the creation of CHIP](http://www.politifact.com/colorado/statements/2016/feb/17/hillary-clinton/hillary-clinton-wrong-sanders-claim/). She wants to expand the ACA, CHIP, and Medicaid programs. And she still supports a public option for health care -- she just intent on fighting for it at the state level. It says so on her website: "As she did in her 2008 campaign health plan, and consistently since then, Hillary supports a “public option” to reduce costs and broaden the choices of insurance coverage for every American. To make immediate progress toward that goal, Hillary will work with interested governors, using current flexibility under the Affordable Care Act, to empower states to establish a public option choice."

&amp;gt;For the 2001 Bankruptcy Bill/Against the same 2005 Bankruptcy Bill

Yeah, that wasn't great. Can't say I agree with her on that one. But the difference between her two stances isn't a flip-flop -- according to her, she voted for the 2001 bill (which did not become law) because she had engineered certain compromises with Republicans on the structure of the bill. She voted for it, but was happy when it didn't pass the House. Because that's how politics works in the real world -- you have to compromise sometimes and vote for things you don't like in order to make sure an even worse thing doesn't pass.

In 2005, the "same" bill wasn't the same. The bill had rewritten, her concerns in 2001 weren't a factor any longer, so she opposed it. (She talks about it [here](http://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2016/02/07/clinton_accuses_sanders_and_warren_of_smear_campaign.html).)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
