<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613301464.0" user="Christopher312" delta="True">
    <text>James Rolfe posted a [video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hz8X2A7wHyQ) on his youtube channel back in May explaining why he didn't plan to watch or review the movie based on all the reasons he didn't think it would be any good.

Things he didn't mention or complain about in the video:

 * Feminism
 * The all-female cast (he skimmed on this when saying that people were referring to the movie as "the female ghostbusters," but that was just to make a point that Hollywood likes to milk popular franchises with remakes)
 * Political correctness

Things he did criticize in the video:

 * Based on the trailer, the jokes are lame
 * The effects are lame
 * It's not consistent with the lore of the original movie
 * It doesn't use the original characters in any way
 * It's a lazy remake
 * It piggybacks off the original by not at least modifying the name, which means anytime anyone searches "ghostbusters," both movies come up

You can agree or disagree with his criticisms, evaluation of the movie, or decision not to watch or review it. But I certainly don't see the case that his dislike of the movie is motivated by misogyny or even dislike of feminism.

That didn't stop all of these people from labeling him a misogynist: 

 * [Ty Burr of Boston Globe](https://www.bostonglobe.com/arts/2016/05/19/who-you-gonna-call-anyone-but-ghostbusters-fans/pYDa39Q7mB9TfoaUGDWpFM/story.html)
 * [Jen Yamato of the Daily Beast](http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/05/19/donald-trump-s-sexist-anti-ghostbusters-crusade-goes-mainstream.html)
 * [Miles Klee of the Daily Dot](http://www.dailydot.com/unclick/ghostbusters-reboot-movie-critic-refuses-to-review/)
 * [Walt Hickey of 538](http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/men-are-sabotaging-the-online-reviews-of-tv-shows-aimed-at-women/)
 * [~~Maggie Serota of Death and Taxes~~](http://www.deathandtaxesmag.com/291025/ghostbusters-james-rolfe-cinemassacre/?utm_source=share-tw&amp;amp;utm_medium=button), this one was a mistake. As a bonus, try [Devin Faraci of Birth Movies Death](http://birthmoviesdeath.com/2016/05/18/the-soft-sexism-of-hating-on-the-new-ghostbusters) instead.
 * [David Sims of The Atlantic](http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2016/05/the-sexist-outcry-against-the-ghostbusters-remake-gets-louder/483270/)
 * [Vikram Murthi of Indie Wire](http://www.indiewire.com/2016/05/ghostbusters-reboot-cinemassacre-youtube-critic-refuses-to-see-the-film-for-dumb-reasons-290290/)


I could dump even more links on you, but I think you get the idea. It's definitely not a myth that non-gendered criticism of this movie gets unfairly labeled as misogyny.

Edit: grammar

Edit 2: fixed links</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
