<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884325985.0" user="tunaonrye" delta="True">
    <text>There is a giant caveat to this, namely that I have no idea if it is true. But given that it will be a long time before the full details come out, here is the best defense that I have heard - that is at least consistent with (if not slightly supported by) public reports on the matter.

Comey was between a rock and a hard place regarding the initial letter. There was a large enough (or committed enough) cadre of FBI agents angry about the initial decision not to indict that this new development (described only in the abstract) would (likely) be leaked during the election, making the FBI look bad and raising the issue as a speculative unsubstantiated October surprise. So: suppose the leak happens. If Comey followed DOJ policy, he could have clamped down on his agents very hard to minimize the possibility of a leak and stall/not answer - which would lead to attacks on the FBI and complaints from within. Bad for FBI/Public confused/Hearings after election drag out the issue (for FBI/Comey).

Suppose the leak doesn't happen: Then you get angry agents and you WILL get congressional hearings after the fact - that would make the FBI look bad and Comey doesn't want that.

In the case of (DOJ policy-violating) disclosure, the FBI itself just has to live with the political consequences, but isn't dragged into the "corruption" or "rigged" worries anywhere near as much as they would be in the other cases. Comey and the FBI take less political heat compared to not disclosing, in the long run, despite the disclosure being a stupid STUPID thing to do.

So, while he went against DOJ policy, it wasn't against the letter of the law, he knows that firing him would shift the story away from the mess that lead to this situation (and would be bigger political news than as an indictment - pun intended - against Comey as a leader), and if he isn't fired he must (implicitly at least) have the trust and support of the president.

So, on point 1, the situation within the FBI made particular knowledge moot - it was simply about managing the leak/anger situation. On point 2, he didn't violate any particular law, just advice (as a side note, the DOJ, if they wanted to, presumably could have stopped this and didn't... so it was either within the law or they are also culpable). And on point 3, that's true, but it only would be a firable offense if 3 alone is sufficient to warrant firing, and that seems too strong.

I don't like this, I think Comey ought to resign, and that this was so dumb dumb dumb, but it still might be dumber to fire Comey until this is entirely sorted out, given the mess at the FBI (so... like 2018).

Oh, and why I think this description is at least consistent with reality is Spencer Ackerman in the [Guardian](https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/nov/03/fbi-leaks-hillary-clinton-james-comey-donald-trump?CMP=share_btn_tw)
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
