<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884330442.0" user="RustyRook" delta="True">
    <text>Pardon the nitpicky answer, but I'll try to change your view on a minor point and then the proper one. 

It would *look* awfully partisan if Obama fired Comey right now. It would seem like he was trying to help Hillary win the election and it would also look like there was some sort of cover up taking place. While it may not be true, it would look that way and it may provide Trump's supporters and disgruntled Republicans something to rally around. In the interest of not getting Trump elected I think Comey should stay on until some time after the election. 

Now I do think that there's a slightly sympathetic case to be made when it comes to Comey's recent actions. There were reports that some people in the FBI were planning to leak information that made it look like there was something on Weiner's computer(s) that made Hillary look bad. I think that Comey, by writing a completely vacuous letter to Congress, successfully reduced the damage that may have occurred if some low-level leaks made it seem like there was something there. Had there been a leak he could not have said that there was nothing there since it would require an investigation to prove it and it would have made him look bad if something came out of it in the future. His letter had its own drawbacks and seems to have affected Hillary's position but think of what could have happened and it doesn't look as bad.

The guy needs to go but I think that given what his subordinates were planning he handled the situation as well as he could. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
