<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28898628417.0" user="lindypenguin" delta="True">
    <text>Yes, a Trump presidency is certainly a setback for effective climate mitigation action. But the Republican Congress is probably the larger setback, given that Obama has pretty much already done what little is possible through executive action. Yet giving up is literally the worst thing to do for a number of reasons:

Firstly: Every. Tonne. Counts. Certainly the 3 to 4 degrees Celsius track that we appear to be on at the moment (with present national commitments) is worse than 1.5 to 2 degrees that the Paris Agreement "committed" to, but it's a damn sight better than 7 to 9 degrees under a more lax approach or the 9 to 11 degrees under a 'burn it all' scenario that would likely bring civilisation-ending consequences. 

Secondly, there are many city and state governments that are taking more robust action. This number can and must go up,  and local lobbying can make a substantial difference here. Even with strong action at the federal level the commitment of state and local actors would be required, so it's more than possible for them to go it alone. 

Thirdly, it would take more than American intransigence to blow up the Paris Agreement. There's plenty of countries on board and already talimg stronger action than the USA. One could even make the argument that China is taking stronger action, in terms of emissions intensity reductions (which measure CO2 emissions against economic growth). As mentioned elsewhere, the USA is hardly a world leader on climate change so a Republican victory is not really a global setback. 

So (like with the rest of the Trump platform) there's still plenty worth fighting for, writing letters, donating and protesting for, and making incentives with your own wallet for. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
