<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28898292309.0" user="Five_Decades" delta="True">
    <text>The US is not the world leader on addressing climate change, China is. China will still be fighting climate change no matter what the US does. 

Also, private markets and state governments will still combat climate change. When W Bush rejected climate change, many states including california passed laws to combat climate change and abide by Kyoto. 

Also renewable energy keeps dropping in cost. Some of the biggest investments in renewable energy have been in deeply red states and counties because it is financially profitable. So people will keep pushing for renewables due to economics. 

Solar may drop to $2 per installed watt by 2020 or so. Hopefully. That'll mean a 5kw system is 10k and will provide a house with power for 20-30 years. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
