<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337048102.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ko3za/cmv_some_people_want_companies_to_pay_a_carbon/">
    <title>CMV: Some people want companies to pay a carbon tax, others do not. I believe the best compromise is an optional carbon tax.</title>
    <original_poster>antilisterine</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are people who care about climate change who want companies to pay a carbon tax - well they can pressure companies to prove that they're environmentally friendly and they can do that by paying the optional carbon tax. It's like they're saying, hey, we care so much about the environment, that we're willing to pay a tax that we don't even have to pay.

However those who don't care about climate change can remain unaffected by it - they can buy products and use services from companies that refused to pay the optional carbon tax. Also, as I've mentioned before, I don't believe that disadvantaged people should be forced to thank society for treating them like shit or be forced to help people with good lives whilst their lives are miserable - in this scenario, they have a choice. These people can choose not to support companies that pay the optional carbon tax so that way they're not thanking society, they're not helping people with good lives and they can remain completely unaffected by it.

It just seems like a win-win situation to me. So why can't we fight for an optional carbon tax instead? I see literally no problems with it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29005957379.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="True">
    <text>That's not the point of carbon taxes.  A company that cares about the environment just takes steps to reduce their carbon footprint.  That can cost more money than using fossil fuels, but that is fundamentally different from a carbon tax.  A lot of co2 emissions come from industries that don't sell directly to the public.  Things like steel mills and energy production, that go towards other manufacturing processes. Steel is traded like a commodity, that is, 1 kg of x grade steel is worth $1.70 USD, for example. Regardless of who made it.  There's not enough financial/market incentive for steel producers, mines, or most primary and secondary goods producers, to significantly reduce their carbon footprint if it increases the cost of production.  

Carbon taxes attempt to alter market forces to tip scales in favor of greener practices and alternatives.  First it gives companies, products and services that use fewer fossil fuels a leg up against dirtier alternatives.  So let's say a carbon tax makes concrete and steel more expensive, while bamboo and pine are unaffected, which may tip the scales to use greener products in certain situations that used to favor dirtier products.  

Second, it provides a greater financial incentive for companies to innovate and retrofit their factories to be cleaner.  What translates to better environmental outcomes doesn't necessarily translate to good marketing, and vice versa.  A Steel mill switches to passive intercooling, hotspot welding, and yransphonic drifting and a half dozen other small changes that all cost money, but put together add up to significant carbon reductions. These are expensive to implement, so It's really hard to make these investments worthwhile on a commodity product.  Carbon taxes put all industries and factories at the same disadvantage, so they all have to implement changes to their processes, or pay higher taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
