<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29200225943.0" user="Crayshack" delta="True">
    <text>Here is another realistic scenario where self defense with a gun is a viable option.  You live in the woods pretty far from any sort of law enforcement and a bear breaks into your house and starts rummaging through your kitchen.  If you don't have a gun, you have pretty much no options in this situation besides hoping the bear doesn't come after you, but with a gun the result is [a dead bear](http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/grizzly-bear-shot-dead-inside-kimberley-home-1.3185310).

&amp;gt;If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

The sort of scenario most people picture where they would be dealing with a human usually does not have the good guy with the gun as the primary target.  A common scenario that is brought up are a house break in where the people breaking in are seeking to steal valuables and be gone before being noticed but the [homeowner getting the drop on them](http://www.oregonlive.com/portland/index.ssf/2016/07/cleared_of_criminal_wrongdoing.html) either because they don't know he is home/awake or just because he knows the way around his own house better than them.  Another scenario often brought up is when someone else is being held at gunpoint and a [third party comes in to solve the situation.](http://www.easttexasmatters.com/news/local-news/police-good-samaritan-stops-robbery-at-cumberland-park-mall/670679572).

&amp;gt;If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

This is where it gets a bit confusing.  Yes, self defense is a commonly listed reason for gun ownership and the people that have this as their primary reason tend to be the loudest, but that is far from the only reason for owning guns.  A much more common reason is people wanting to own guns simply because they intend to use them for hunting or the sport of target shooting.  Each of those on their own are major hobbies in the US that millions of people partake in to some extent.  These people want ease of access to their guns because in is a major part of their culture and leisure time.  In some cases (such as on farms), having guns can be pretty crucial to preventing damage to crops and livestock and in some cases they are used for slaughtering livestock.  Even if you completely take away a self defense scenario from the argument, there would still be many people pretty firm in their stance that guns should be legal.  In my case, I do not ever expect to use a gun in self defense, but I own three guns because target shooting is a major hobby of mine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
