<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="372786470.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/65y3vq/cmv_kids_today_are_losing_the_ability_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Kids today are losing the ability to express themselves effectively</title>
    <original_poster>rewdd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Since writing is an important tool of communication it is important to learn the process without the help of paraphrasing from the writings of others and arriving at ideas naturally. most kids don't write using their own ideas, they search the internet and arrange the writings of other people into an essay. The effect of this method of writing papers is harmful because if they don't arrive at ideas naturally and write them in their own words they will not be able to write or know proper grammar without the help of technology. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29289306850.0" user="bawiddah" delta="True">
    <text>Few ideas are original. Those who create truly original things are greatly celebrated, but they are rare. Can you name a single friend who created something truly original? 

In art it is now nearly impossible to create an original work. Plots are well trod. Characterizations reused. Vantages repeatedly drawn. There is not a single unique idea in the world of engineering. The entire field is simply the application of already known scientific principals. Perhaps the only field of originality is mathematics, as they can continually parse the details of their abstract objects.

As for expression? That never stops. Kids these days, they consume all this regurgitated content and spit out pastiche. Their stroke of brilliance was not creating a new culture of their own, but simply adopting every culture possible, mixing it up, filtering out the interesting bits, and gluing it all together.

Wearing your grandpa's clothing and thinking it's cool? That's pretty original, if you ask me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
