<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377703481.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68vhvd/cmvstalin_was_a_bad_leader/">
    <title>CMV:Stalin was a bad leader</title>
    <original_poster>BRINGITSISTA</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I have recently become a communist, or more specific a marxist leninist. But that is not what you will be changing today.

I hear many leftists and communists proclaim that Stalin was actually a really good leader and his negatives are exaggerated or fake....

Despite this, I still seem to have a somewhat negative view of Stalin

Yes, my image of Stalin has been improved by some communists I have encountered, but int quite there yet...

Instead of small one liners, I would like someone to write me a good, well rounded summary of why I should like Stalin

I know this might be controversial, so lets keep it to just communists and pro-Stalin people to answer this one...

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29328884029.0" user="rocaralonso" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;When we consider Stalin's facts and figures, it becomes clear that we are witnessing the most concentrated economic advance ever recorded--greater even than those of the Industrial Revolution. Within 10 years a primarily feudal society had been changed into an industrialized one. And for the first time in history such an advance was due not to capitalism but to socialism.

Cameron, Kenneth Neill. Stalin, Man of Contradiction. Toronto: NC Press, c1987, p. 75

&amp;gt;Between the poverty stricken year of 1924, when Lenin died, and the relatively abundant year of 1940, the cultivated area of USSR expanded by 74 percent; grain crops increased 11 percent; coal production was multiplied by 10; steel output by 18; engineering and metal industries by 150; total national income by 10; industrial output by 24; annual capital investment by 57. During the First Five-year Plan, 51 billion rubles were invested; during the Second, 114; and during the Third, 192. Factory and office workers grew from 7,300,000 to 30,800,000 and school and college students from 7,900,000 to 36,600,000. Between 1913 and 1940, oil production increased from nine to 35 million tons; coal from 29 to 164; pig iron from 4 to 15; steel from 4 to 18; machine tools from 1000 to 48,000 units, tractors from 0 to over 500,000; harvestor combines from 0 to 153,500; electrical power output from two billion kWh to 50 billion; and the value of industrial output from 11 billion rubles to more than 100 billion by 1938. If the estimated volume of total industrial production in 1913 be taken as 100, the corresponding indices for 1938 are 93.2 for France; 113.3 for England, 120 United States; 131.6 for Germany, and 908.8 for the Soviet Union.

Schuman, Frederick L. Soviet Politics. New York: A.A. Knopf, 1946, p. 212

Most people who lived during Stalin say it was a time of rapid growth of healthcare, education, infastructure, and living standards. Healthcare was extended into remote villages for the first time in Russian history. Diseases like typhus, endemic in the countryside, were virtually eliminated. Illiteracy was eradicated, and living standards rose drastically. 


The Soviet population under Stalin Government wasn't slaves. The workers ran their own newspapers, had the power to elect their own factory managers, and had guaranteed vacation time, privileges unknown in the economically depressed Western world at the time. The Communist government, and Stalin, enjoyed mass support among the population. In about fifteen years, illiterate peasants living in borderline medieval conditions with a 50% infant mortality rate (the majority of the Zarist Russia population) saw a great quantity of their sons and daughters, becoming scientists, doctors, or engineers.

Today, Stalin remains popular in the former USSR. A recent poll put him as the third greatest Russian in history.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
