<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397999908.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kyip0/cmv_students_who_excel_in_sports_should_not_have/">
    <title>CMV: Students who excel in sports should not have their sporting achievements weighed the same as someone with strong academic achievements in terms of being admitted into high-schools and universities.</title>
    <original_poster>sourmilky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Firstly, let me start by setting some context for my CMV.

The universities I know have specific criteria in which they can admit for points for someone who is trying to get into a degree. Hypothetically speaking, if Person A and Person B got the same final mark and is both trying to get into a degree - Person A would have an numerical advantage as they would be awarded with additional points/marks on their total mark due to their excellence in sports in an university, but does not have any relevance to their degree.

While I understand there maybe benefit in increasing notable alumni or their yearning for well-rounded students, I believe if they want to admit people for their strengths in extra-curriculars - they much either admit everybody that excels in acting/dance/music/acting, or none at all. It's incredibly unfair that certain students get an advantage over others because they know how to kick a ball, especially since it's irrelevant to the degree they pursue. In saying this, the odds of having sporting alumni 'making it' onto a team is very small. While it's nice to have an athletic person represent to school and dominate every game - it doesn't seem like a wise long-term investment for some short-term gain. Unlike disciplines which have a high employment rate, I don't understand how there are aspects like sporting scholarships which is on par with academic scholarships, when there doesn't seem to be a lot of jobs. 

The purpose of academia scholarships is to provide a financial cushion to bright students in hopes for their long-term contribution into society. I don't see how sports provide the same effect (and when I talk about long-term contribution into society, I mean the ability to provide essential help as a community). The purpose of sports I see is collectively as a form of entertainment which helps bind society and enjoying together - but isn't this concept also applicable to other extra-curriculars?

Due to this, I presume schools do this in order to increase school's image and gambling on the hopes for famous sporting alumni. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29490310935.0" user="cdb03b" delta="True">
    <text>1) High schools you are admitted automatically. They are not something you try out or apply for save for some rare specialty schools. 

2) They are not weighed the same and I am not sure why you think they would be. Sports achievements are weighed at a high priority by the sports faculty at the University when they are determining who to try and recruit and offer their allotments of scholarships to. But the physics or English departments do not really give any weight to those activities for who they try and recruit and give their scholarships to. So far as general admittance is concerned they simply want you to be active in some kind of activity other than pure academics so as to show that you are capable of functioning outside of just academia.  

Edit: Also universities give a lot of scholarships for music, acting, art, and every other subject that they teach. Every department gets budgets for them to use for scholarships, in addition to the general academic scholarships that the University gives out separate from departments, and there are also a lot of private scholarships funded by alumni and fundraising. 

Edit2: Also the purpose of scholarships is to attract high performing students, in whatever field the scholarship is focused in supporting or department supplying the funds. It is not to provide a financial cushion for students. The financial cushions as you put it are grants. These tend to be based on financial need, though there are some tied to specifics like degree choice (often offered for teachers) and other factors. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
