<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="401821196.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6n8f7w/cmv_lord_of_the_rings_are_great_films_but_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: Lord of the Rings are great films, but it is not a good trilogy</title>
    <original_poster>This_The_Last_Time</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is inspired by a recent Movie Fight debate about what is the best movie trilogy (check it out from YouTube). 

I'd argue, that even though I LOVE Lord of the Rings movies, and have seen them dozens of times, it is not a good movie trilogy. For one simple reason: the movies do not work separately. 

I think for a movie trilogy to be good or better than most, the parts of the trilogy have to work both individually as single movies and as pieces of a greater whole. 

LOTR does not work as individual films. None of the themes or storylines are resolved within a single film, with the exception of characters who are both introduced and killed within one film (Boromir, Shelob). 

LOTR films are individual films only in technical sense: they all have their separate release dates, each one ends with ending credits, etc. But the story contained in these films does not work when viewed as a single piece, because you do not get to see the big picture. LOTR films are really a single film, single story, released in three separate parts. 

I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. Story cannot be truly great if it does not end. Imagine if Fellowship of the Ring was a box-office bomb, and the two others films were never released. Who would call Fellowship a self-contained, resolved film? It would still be a good film, just without resolution. Audiences would think, what then, only to be answered, nothing. A good story does not ask questions it does not try to answer. 

Then look at Godfather. If Godfather Part 2 was never released, Godfather 1 would still work perfectly on its own. Part 2 enchances the first one, and vice versa, but neither requires the other.  And no one needs the third one. 

Lord of the Rings films are great. But in reality they are a trilogy only in technical terms, as the story within is one single story, not three complementing ones. If you only watch one of the films, but not the others, story is flawed and incomplete. If you watch the films out of chronological order, nothing makes sense. All the plot threads and all the character archs in the trilogy take multiple films to reach their conclusions, with the aforementioned exception of characters who are introduced and killed within a single movie. 

An exceptional trilogy of films should work both individually, where you only see one of them (not necessarily even the first one), and still feel like you got everything you needed and wanted, and as parts of a bigger whole. Lord of the Rings films do not work without the other parts of the trilogy. Without them, story is incomplete, unresolved, and the character archs unfinished. 

CMV. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29521096543.0" user="CosmoDanger" delta="True">
    <text>I would argue each film does have a unique identity.  It's not so much about plot, but about character development.  Several characters evolve over the trilogy, but each film also has its mini character arcs. 

FOTR - It's all about Frodo wrestling with the shitty reality of having to be the Ring Bearer even though he'd rather live in peace and obscurity: "I wish none of this had happened."  So Gandalf says, "So do all who live to see such times, but that is not for them to decide.  All you have to decide is what to do with the time that is given to you."

Thematically and for Frodo's character, FOTR is about accepting a major responsibility and sacrificing your personal desires for a greater good.  In the end, that also means sacrificing friendships (the Fellowship).  Sam sticks around because Frodo also learns he can't do everything by himself.

TTT - This one is about hope, and the dangers of losing it during tough times.  This is the darkest part of the trilogy because everything is turning against the heroes.  Some would argue Aragorn is the "main" character of TTT because he has the most screen time.  But I would argue his arc doesn't change much in this one (we'll get to him later).  Here are the characters who best represent the theme of TTT, in my opinion:

* Theoden - He's lost hope not just in his country, but in himself.  In the end, he realizes that victory is still possible.

* Legolas/Elrond - They've lost hope in Men (to use Tolkien's word and capitalization scheme).  They think they're weak, which leads to Legolas' conflict with Aragorn.  But then they make up and Elrond sends the Elves come to help Men and stand against evil together.  

* Sam - He has no hope in Gollum to begin with, while Frodo does.  Over the course of the film, and somewhat begrudgingly, Sam eventually wants to establish an understanding with Gollum.  Sam talks about the film's main themes in a great monologue in Osgiliath.  He realizes he's being a dick and it's hurting the Mission, so he extends the olive branch to Gollum.  Little does he know, Gollum is going to totally sell them out.  But Sam's arc was still completed.

* Faramir - He's an extension of Boromir in that he's the personification of "Man" - greedy, wants the easy way out, etc.  He's lost hope in himself too, if he ever had any.  The Ring is his way of rising above his shitty station in life.  But he realizes that he needs to trust Frodo and have faith in the Mission.  He rights Boromir's wrongs.

In the end, all the characters lose hope and then gain it back again, even if it's only a little bit or if there's still danger ahead.

And ROTK is about a whole bunch of these characters coming to the end of their arcs.  This film is about how underdogs can be heroes too.  Again I see a few "main" ones at the forefront:

* Aragorn - We get teased about his returning to the throne and all that, but that's never a real possibility until Elrond shows up and offers him Anduril.  Aragorn is such a badass that he doesn't seem like an underdog, but in the context of the story he very much is.  He leads Men on a suicide mission and eventually becomes King.  He never had faith in himself, but everyone else did.  Eventually, he believes in himself too (except a troll nearly kills him which was fucking lame).

* Merry/Pippin/Eowyn - These guys get shit on for most of the movie but each prove to be big heroes.  We've already seen Legolas/Gimli prove themselves so that's just fun.  But watching these characters come into their own is really satisfying.  You don't need to have seen the previous two versions to understand and empathize with them - especially Eowyn and Merry.  

I'm missing a whole bunch of stuff.  But I think the films stand on their own as 

* (1) I get by with a little help from my friends
* (2) Never give up hope; and
* (3) "Even the smallest person can change the course of the future"

EDIT Sorry for formatting - I'll fix it later, promise!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
