<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="403343304.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6o51oo/cmv_retard_is_not_an_offensive_or_ableist_word/">
    <title>CMV: "Retard" is not an offensive or ableist word because the connotation has changed from referring to mentally handicapped people to referring to stupid people, much like how the meaning of other words like "dumb" and "lame" have also changed meanings dramatically.</title>
    <original_poster>Dillon-psm</original_poster>
    <original_post>So a lot of people find the word "Retard" used as an insult to be incredibly offensive, akin to saying the n-word to a black person. They say that this is because historically the word means mentally handicapped person and it was used in a patronizing and derogatory way during a time when there was a massive cultural stigma and disgust with mental disabilities. 

Yet, many words over the course of history change. Hell, a lot of the words we use today to refer to someone as an idiot - including the word idiot - were historically used to describe mentally ill/handicapped people. 

To this day, words like Imbecile, Moron and Cretin are used to describe stupid people (or troublemakers, in the case of cretin), yet these words actually mean the exact same thing as "retard". 

So why is retard singled out as "ableist"? Are people who take offence to the word simply being resistant to the natural evolution of language, or does their anger have merit? 

EDIT: Everyone made very good points. I'm considering them, but based on the fact that for the most part I had *nothing* to fire back with, I'd say my views have been thoroughly changed and I'm going to phase this word out of my vocabulary. I'm guilty of frequent use - it's easy to just turn to a buddy and say that in good fun without even thinking, but I'll be mindful in the future. 

Thanks people. Also You get a delta, you get a delta, and you get a delta, everyone gets a delta!!!!!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29532140282.0" user="matt2000224" delta="True">
    <text>I try to refrain from saying retard just because I know it offends some and not others, and I'd rather not needlessly piss someone off when I can use different words to get my message across without rustling any jimmies.

That being said, I think conversations like this often break down due to what people view as "racist" or "ableist" or "sexist". Some people think racist = the kkk, or ableist = throwing the mentally challenged in wards where they have experiments done on them. These people obviously would balk at being called ableist or racist, because the image they have in their mind of a racist is so horrible.

Rather, think about Avenue Q. If you don't know what that is, you're welcome: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RovF1zsDoeM

Everyone's a little bit racist. Everyone's a little bit ableist. There are tiny little things we all do which just are. It's not the end of the world to say "retard", but it is ableist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
