<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="408864224.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6rfdnk/cmv_impeaching_donald_trump_is_actually_not_a/">
    <title>CMV: Impeaching Donald Trump is actually not a very good idea</title>
    <original_poster>Shanghai1943</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress and the DOJ are investigating the collusion between the Trump campaign and the Russian government in the 2016 Russian election. Robert Muller has been appointed as special counsel to investigate this matter, and today he has [impaneled a grand jury.](http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-a-grand-jury-robert-mueller-trump-russia-2017-8). Which could ultimately result in the impeachment of Donald Trump.        

For the most part since the Trump presidency, Vice President Mike Pence has been kept away from the spotlight. This may be a move by the party in the case of an impeachment that the new president would start from a clean slate. Although Pence is a much much more presentable president for America, he serves a similar agenda to Donald Trump and the current Republican leadership, not to mention he has a very poor track record on abortion, LGBT rights, climate change, education, among others.       

In the case of a Trump impeachment, Mike Pence becomes the new president. In my view, he is just a more competent version of Donald Trump that is presentable to the public, but at the same time perhaps much better than Trump at pushing the same type of Republican backed bills through congress. Lets not forget that the skinny repeal was only 1 vote short from passing.        

America might look silly with Trump as the president, this is manly due to his personality and unstable nature. But because of his unstable nature, people in congress, even in his party bound to oppose him. In the 6 months he has been president, he has gotten almost nothing done. Since Trump has been so awful, all Pence has to do is a little good and he would seem like a saint, which would prolong the Republican run, and at the current state of Republican leadership, this is no good. Thus in my view, keeping an idiot running things for the next 3.5 years would be better for America in the long run than putting Mike Pence in the driver's seat as he is just a more competent Donald Trump.

Edit: Thanks guys, my views have been changed, I have ignored his foreign policies in this thread as well as the precedence he sets if we accept his behavior.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29575742762.0" user="ghdghsahdgjdgf" delta="True">
    <text>Think about the entire administration, rather than just the president. The firing of Priebus and Spicer is being seen as a huge blow to the 'GOP establishment' in the Trump administration. (Priebus is personal friends with Paul Ryan, and is a bridge to House members)

This is highly problematic for a few reasons:

-The GOP establishment, while maybe not the greatest statesmen in history, are an important counterweight to the... how do you say... nativist wing of the GOP, within the Trump administration. Granted the GOP administration is not the only counter weight, there are I would argue two others, the generals, and Jared/Ivanka. Now, I think most people (including you, I gather from your post) would like to see as many checks on the Bannon wing as possible, these two both have major issues. Trump's reliance on generals is a huge breach of the norms of civil/military relations, and with Jared/Ivanka you have problems with charges of nepotism. So my basic thesis is that both of these important checks on the ethnic nationalists in the administration are somewhat precarious, if the heat against the number of generals, or nepotism increase, we could see these groups sidelined. So a president would stregthen the GOP establishment, which while unexciting for a progressive, is much better than the Bannon wing. 

-Better foreign relations, no twitter diplomacy

-Much lower chance of winning re-election. People who say Trump will never win re-election need to look at base rates, a large majority of presidents of run for a second term win, however Pence seems to lack the political ability and support from the Trump base necessary to win 2020. 

-May encourage bipartisanship in the legislative. Most people, I think, would agree that the legislative works best when parties work together, compare GOP legislative under Clinton, to Debt ceiling incident under Obama. Right now, working with the Trump administration is a poisoned chalice for democrats, they'd get flayed in the media for any 'pro trump' voting, even if the bill had nothing to do with trump (see the thing on 538 that tries to measure which senators are more pro trump than expected). If the GOP manage to distance themselves from Trump, then the legislature can finally start to work again. 

-My last, and I think the biggest point: It will be a fundamental discrediting of Trump style politics. The accusation of any candidate being 'Trump-like' will be a death knell for their political viability, if Trump is vilified like Nixon was after Watergate. The GOP will lose 2020, as discussed above, and they will have to have a serious rethink of the direction their party has been going. 

Or Trump either wins, or comes sufficiently close to winning in 2020 (remember base rates), and it appears as though appealing to nativist tribalism is still a viable (or, worse *the viable*) political strategy for the GOP.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
