<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584765967.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>Well Peter Singer's argument, he is a pretty hardcore utilitarian, is that for something the have rights, the sufficient prerequisite is that they must have preferences between states. So a pig would prefer that I not stab it, rather than I stab it. He argues that if you have the proviso, then you derive rights for animals from a utilitarian perspective. What is wrong with that argument? It seems like you just take animals not having rights as some axiom. Where do rights come from? It turns out to be really hard to explain rights without stumbling on some metaphysical view (like utilitarianism) that accidentally justifies animal rights as well. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
