<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699441796.0" user="huadpe" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view.

This is in fact the case.

[This article gives a nice summary](https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2014/08/13/the-best-way-to-fight-inequality-in-cities-is-through-zoning/?utm_term=.d5dd58bd8fa6) but basically, the reason rents are so high is that it's illegal to build dense housing.  And the reason it's illegal to build dense housing is to keep out poor people and minorities who are perceived as the people who would move into new apartment buildings.

The restrictions on new apartment construction are extreme and nearly nationwide.  For example, in [Manhattan, 40% of the buildings would be illegal to build today.](https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/05/19/upshot/forty-percent-of-manhattans-buildings-could-not-be-built-today.html)
 That's not the most extreme.  Somerville MA is almost entirely illegal, with only [22 legal buildings in a city of 80,000 people.](http://cityobservatory.org/the-illegal-city-of-somerville/)

The price of rent is not a supply and demand issue, because the law bans adding new supply at anything close to the rate needed to meet demand.  [Same issue in San Francisco.](https://www.citylab.com/equity/2015/07/whats-the-matter-with-san-francisco/399506/)

So with highly inelastic supply, relatively small changes in demand can produce enormous price spikes.  And supply inelasticity is a product of government policy banning density, not market forces.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
