<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="427286909.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/72e8ot/cmv_advertisements_data_mining_and_targeted/">
    <title>CMV : advertisements, data mining and targeted marketing isn’t unethical</title>
    <original_poster>The_IOvOI</original_poster>
    <original_post>With all these posts on the front page and comments on the measures people undergo to avoid targeted advertisements and data mining I was curious as to why there is such a strong opposition to this. The way I’ve always seen it is that google / amazon etc are providing a service, and instead of paying 20 cents every google search you let google use your data so that they can be profitable. I’m curious as to why people seem so against this as opposed to paying every time to use the service. 

Also as a sidenote, aren’t targeted advertisements a good thing? Instead of being shown silly ads that don’t do anything good for you your getting things that are actually relevant towards your interests. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29718841496.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="True">
    <text>The reason people have problems with data mining is NOT targeted advertising.  Personally, I prefer seeing an ad for something I'd actually consider buying like a new video card or movie coming out.

The scary parts are when that data is linked to your name (or someone could eventually figure out how to link it to your name) and could be used against you in unknown ways.  Things that privacy experts DO have a problem with:

* The data is lost to hackers and because the company never purges old data, the hackers have access to your entire history.
* The data is sold to employers who use it to decide to hire you or not
* The data is used to blackmail political rivals that aren't favorable to your particular business.

So you might say, my employer isn't using data mining for hiring decisions currently.  But the fact that all these companies are collecting data continually and holding onto it should be scary.  Yes, they may only be using it for targeted advertising NOW, and it may not even be linked to your actual name NOW, but they intend to hold onto it for a long long time and may not properly secure it from hackers or may simply sell it to the highest bidder if the business fails or is starting to fail and they get desperate for cash.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
