<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431133293.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/74ookt/cmv_i_should_turn_my_car_off_at_stop_lights/">
    <title>CMV: I should turn my car off at stop lights</title>
    <original_poster>Sleeper_in_the_code</original_poster>
    <original_post>I currently do not have a job, and will not be able to get a good one for a few years (I am in school and a bad student, so I need as few distractions as I can afford), and want to save money where I can. My commute has two (sometimes three) lights where I might have to wait for up to about two and a half minutes to get moving again, idling for that whole time. Seems to me that that is wasted gas, since I am not going anywhere but my engine is running. 

However, I have never seen anyone do this, so I can not help but feel like I am missing something obvious as to why I should not do this. 

I want to save gas, and therefore money, but I also want to avoid doing anything dangerous or illegal. 

Maybe this is a question for a different sub, but I have no idea where else I should go, and this seems like something that could be discussed. 

Edit: yep, I’m convinced. Saving money by not idling isn’t really worth the drawbacks, and if I’m really concerned, I should look into a car that is supposed to do this (a few years from now when I hopefully have more money). </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29749287241.0" user="down42roads" delta="True">
    <text>Point one:

Idling consumes a [negligible amount of fuel](https://energy.gov/eere/vehicles/fact-861-february-23-2015-idle-fuel-consumption-selected-gasoline-and-diesel-vehicles). If you drive a large sedan, you are looking at about .4 gallons per hour. Assuming that you spend 5 minutes idling per trip, so 10 minutes per day, that means you "waste" a gallon of gas every 15 work days. Assuming $2.50 a gallon and 250 work days per year (50 weeks, 5 days per), that $41.67 per year idling.

Point 2: 

Turned off cars don't have heat, A/C, or radio. Creature comforts are worth a certain amount of money, and $42 per year seems like a good price.

Point 3:

Its not safe. A turned off car can't move. If there is an emergency vehicle or an accident or something that you need to respond to quickly, you can't. You are effectively leaving an inoperable vehicle in the middle of the road.

Point 5:

People are gonna be pissed.

The light turns green, you notice it, you start your car, you put it in drive, you go. That's what, 5 seconds? Every car behind you has been waiting as well, and they are gonna be mad at you if you don't respond quickly to the green.

Point 6: 

In a real winter (one with snow) a car takes about 10 miles to warm up. When the temperatures above freezing, a car takes about 5 miles to warm up. If you turn and engine off and one before it's warmed up, you run the risk of very seriously damaging it (over time) and the engine won't heat up as fast which means it will return a much lower milage when you are driving it (since heating an engine up takes a lot of gas).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
