<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907897138.0" user="gster50" delta="True">
    <text>I think morally repugnant is a bit extreme if we consider the cases that do not quality as harassment, and are reasonable.

In order for something to be morally wrong, the standard I use is that it has to harm someone, either directly or indirectly, and I don't think a poorly executed flirtation harms any one significantly. Realistically the worst case scenario is mild social discomfort for whoever is being approached, and to me there's nothing wrong with that.

The extreme edge cases you mention of panic attacks or flash backs, you're not really morally obligated to consider. Consider if we used that standard for all behavior. Talking to anybody you don't know would be prohibited, because they might have social anxiety and you might trigger a panic attacks. Fireworks would be prohibited because they might trigger flashbacks in war veterans, etc. It's an unreasonable standard that's being selectively applied.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
