<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907786503.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="True">
    <text>I think you really have to define creepy in this situation.

For me, a person should look at their actions and decide if a _reasonable_ person would be made uncomfortable by those actions - if yes, then don't do it; if no, then go ahead.  If I am in a bar and a woman is sitting alone so I walk up and offer to buy her a drink I don't think a reasonable person would find that action creepy (so long as I respect her decision if she says no).  True, may be that particular woman might find that action undesirable, but we are in a place where it is socially acceptable for men to approach women and I have done so in a socially acceptable way.  If we are limited to actions that we are _certain_ no one would be upset by, then no one can do anything at all since you can never be certain how any given person will react.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
