<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451763485.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gyuxp/cmvmoral_objection_to_infidelity_is_probably_only/">
    <title>CMV:Moral objection to infidelity is probably only superficial</title>
    <original_poster>amalopectin</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT-Infidelity isn't really an appropriate word to use here, so to avoid confusion I will clarify that it is more a question of the act of polygamy than of going behind someones back necessarily. 

 I'd like to preface this by saying I don't especially condone anything that will upset or destroy a relationship, nor have I experienced infidelity from either end (though I have seen family go through it.) but from a practical point of view, I don't really understand what is 'wrong' about. Firstly, Monogamy and promiscuity are fairly widespread in society. They are supposedly linked to testosterone levels in both men and women, because of this scientists often debate that it is to difficult to classify humans into monogamy or promiscuity. However they also agree that monogamy is a recent occurrence (Within a few thousand years). This suggests that it is driven by the emergence of society and changing views of religion. (Though as we know even the 'devoutly religious' could get away with promiscuity. King Henry eight is an unfortunate example.)

Of course, monogamy has obvious benefits, that is, two parents are better than one for raising a child, and compared to r select animals, humans are very helpless when they are born and take a lot of energy to raise, definitely k select. However I use the word infidelity in the title because I'm not referring to those who would have children then move on to a new sexual partner. More the secret act people take in of sleeping with another partner, hidden because of the moral view against it.

Humans for one, don't actually value children as the prime goal of sex anywhere near as much as they used to, but more importantly I think is that promiscuity in human relationships doesn't seem to constitute moving on or 'breaking up' by any necessary means. There's even examples of families quite honest and accepting of polygamy, or just relationships. These are of course uncommon and I am not promoting them, simply pointing out that they are quite possible.

 So what is the harm done then by sleeping outside of a relationship? Pride is the clearest answer, people feel as though it means they are less loved or aren't providing for their partner. But that's not a particularly good reason to think your partner doesn't love you if this behavior is natural to some and not to others.In fact it's also suggested that promiscuity can be inherited from a parent. So in that case, it's not so much a matter of values and not loving ones partner as a natural urge. It would be better if this was discussed with openness instead of men or women going behind their partners backs. This would erase a lot of the dishonesty paired with it, and with a shift in views might actually save a lot of relationships. So my question is, why do we view infidelity as amoral? Would it not be better to accept it as natural and discuss it properly with a partner? After all if someone still felt uncomfortable even without the weight of pride, society, or religion they would simply know sooner than if their partner had lied.


(I hope this isn't to sensitive for anyone and clarify that it's only a theoretical discussion.)
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29909802285.0" user="Nicolasv2" delta="True">
    <text>My piece of mind on that case. For information, I'm someone which is against monogamy, but also against infidelity.

Just googled a bit, and I saw that infidelity primary definition is different in french and english. In english, it's quite simple, it's having sex with someone who is not your husband / wife / regular partner. In french, it's the "Lack of respect for a given commitment". 

&amp;gt; It would be better if this was discussed with openness instead of men or women going behind their partners backs

Given my definition, only the "behind their back" is a case of infidelity, as in the 1st case, you can do whatever you want in your relationship as long as both partners agree on it.

Anyway, that was for in introducting a bit what I understand of the word "infidelity". As for the reasons why these are seen as really bad, I think that's because : 

* It break trust.

A couple is "normally" based on honnesty and discussions to take the better decisions and compromise for a good life together. When cheating, you're telling your partner "Ok, but when something is not good for me, I'll do whatever I want behind your back and not talk to you". This is quite a heavy blow on the other partner for its expectations toward the relationship future.

* It make the cheated partner take sexual risks he wasn't aware of.

When you have sex, there is always a risk of STD, that you can control if you are in a exclusive relationship, but can't if one have extra conjugal relationship. Even with protections, you can catch something, and you're putting your partner at risk without telling him/her, what is pretty jerkish toward someone you're engaged and supposed to love.

* Social stigmata

Finally, most communities are seeing infidelity as a stigmata. Sometimes, it can be even worse for the one that has been cheated on, that for the cheater. Cheating on your partner put him/her in a position where he/she can suffer for a big social stigmata, and you did that only for your carnal pleasure. Once more, pretty jerkish move.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
