<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="454805894.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7is2h2/cmv_superhero_movies_would_be_better_as_animated/">
    <title>CMV: Superhero movies would be better as animated films, and the only reason animated superhero movies aren't made more often is the Western belief that animation is for kids</title>
    <original_poster>wiibiiz</original_poster>
    <original_post>[The new Spider-man trailer](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ii3n7hYQOl4) just dropped, and it looks amazing. Watching this trailer got me thinking, and I now believe that live action superhero movies as a genre have a lot of problems that could be resolved by simply going down a route that includes animation. I'll list a couple of them:

1) **Art direction.** Great comics feature great art. Often how a comic is drawn says just as much about a story's theme as the actual narrative itself, and can contribute a great deal to a tone or sense of style. As a result, comics as a medium rely on their art just as much as their text to convey story, and many of the best aspects of superhero stories get lost in translation onto the big screen. Marvel produces comics that feel unique and distinct from one another, but their movies feel remarkably generic and often fail to set themselves apart. On top of that, **no** studio has successfully captured the bright, engaging color palette of comics in their live action films: technical constraints aside (I'll discuss those later), these things simply don't look as cool or engaging in real life as they do when slightly stylized. As a result of all of this, the resulting movies have a weak art direction. I believe a move to animation would help solve this problem, but I'd also point out that the tone problem in comic book movies is caused by a lot more than just their art style. To fully understand the problem, we also have to look at...

2) **The influence of big budgets on Hollywood blockbusters.** As a general rule of thumb, the more money goes into a movie the more your investors will want creative control of the project. The result is that high-budget movies often take very few risks and rarely achieve a unique vision, mostly preferring to stick to a proven formula. (This is why Hollywood is cranking out all the sequels and reboots you see these days: New IPs are seen as a sucker's game). DC makes animated movies with much less reach then their live-action films. They reportedly cost around 3 mil to produce according to industry figures I've talked to. Now, some of these movies are terrible and *none* of them have the quality to be mainstream smash hits, but I'd say that even the middling entries in their animated franchise are better than something like Suicide Squad. At lower price points animation is pricier than live-action, but as you approach the most expensive movies the needle swings in the opposite direction. For instance, Frozen reportedly cost 150 mil to make (including marketing) while Age of Ultron cost 250 mil (not including marketing). By moving to animation, Marvel and DC could emulate Disney proper and Pixar by making varied films while still playing it safe enough to rake in the cash.

3) **technical constraints.** Simply put, the action and aesthetic of superheroes simply fits animation better than live action. In order to "fit" modern special effects into live action movies, everything has to be *just so.* The constraints of these sfx affects everything from lighting to cinematography, and the result undermines the artistic quality of these films. If you need a reason for why Marvel movies are grey and DC movies are dark, look no further. Look at scenes like [this,](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TbpR2Oli3pg) and realize that they were done almost 20 years ago with hugely outdated technology. Yet the movement, color, framing, etc. are all miles ahead of what we can achieve even today with live action. This sort of fluidity would really make the action in superhero movies more lively and entertaining.

4) **Continuity of character.** Let's not beat about the bush here, the shareholders who own the Marvel and DC movie rights love money. Yet actors are mercurial and want to stretch their repertoire: very few A list actors intend on spending their entire careers in the cape world. If superhero movies were animated, this would present no obstacle. Both Marvel and DC are running into this problem, with iconic characters forced out of play because of real-world actor fatigue. In Marvel's case this isn't a huge deal because we've grown to know these characters well enough that a story about their departure works on an emotional level, but how the hell is DC going to explain Batman leaving the big screen when Affleck walks away? Issues like this completely disappear with animation.

5) **Distancing these stories from reality.** This might sound counter-intuitive as a strength, but hear me out. Superhero stories feature larger-than-life figures, doing larger-than-life things. By portraying these events in a photo-realistic medium, these movies ultimately make even the most outlandish heroics feel small and hollow. It's no accident that the best superhero movies like The Dark Knight Rises and Logan work with this effect rather than against it. Both movies deal in real-world themes, and while the *characters* and *plots* may be outlandish the *emotions* and *stakes* hit very close to home. These are movies that benefit from real, grounded performances and refuse to rely on high fantasy, sfx-heavy spectacle to thrill or engage the audience. That's fine, but not every film can be Logan. If you want to make a Thor or Superman movie, I'd argue the best way to deliver on that promise is with animation.

Anyways, these are just the top 5 advantages I thought of off the top of my head. Go ahead and CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29932474989.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="True">
    <text>I think there are a few advantages to live action for these movies, other than just the fact animation is seen as directed at kids:

 * Distancing characters from comic books. Comics have a reputation of being complicated to buy into - you have to track down old stories to get the full continuity, fans tend not to be very casual, plots are complex and span weeks, etc. The new movies are designed so that even if you've never heard of a franchise you can watch any of them and you're usually fine. Breaking from the comic-book aesthetics is a way to signal this to potential audiences.

 * Live action action scenes inherently look better to most. While you can achieve better expressiveness, extravagance and precision with animation, there's something more appealing in live action, because you can more easily place yourself in the building that's being destroyed or on the street being flooded with lava.

 * Many modern superhero films attempt (to varying degrees of success) to make their characters human. I think this is also done to widen the appeal of the characters to people who'd rather view superpowers as a metaphor, or who are more interested in a human story. This is obviously easier to do when people are live shot.

I generally agree with you that by shifting to animated superhero films, studios could focus more of their time and money on story, character and aesthetics, and we'd end up with a potentially better result, but I think this has many drawbacks for the non-comic-literate general public, and that's why they don't choose this path.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
