<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="464135371.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7oc157/cmv_people_who_hang_around_in_a_group_are_all/">
    <title>CMV: People who hang around in a group are all similar to each other and people who prefer being alone are too different from the them (the former)</title>
    <original_poster>zer0_snot</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Background:**

I've seen that we have two kinds of people in life. Those who prefer to hang out in groups - no matter where they go they end up being part of a group (almost always). And those that are always alone. They tend to be alone most of the time (most of the time).

**Belief 1 that needs to be changed:**

Let me elaborate on these points. For example, in the workplace your whole department might be divided into 5 groups. Then in each of those 5 groups the people are all similar to each other. You could say that group 1 has people of type A qualities, group 2 has people of type B qualities. If group 1 has 5 people then those 5 people are more or less similar to each other. I would say 70% similar in terms of life opinions, behaviors, attitudes etc.

CMV1: This is the reason why the group people get along with each other. It's because they're all similar to each other. They're just lucky that they were born with/absorbed such common behaviors that they always find similar people, no matter where they go.

**Belief 2 that needs to be changed:**

People who prefer being alone are very different from these group-guys. Such people usually end up being alone because they are too different. Their sense of humor is different, behaviors, perceptions, opinions, tastes are all too unique. So when they hang out in a group of people they cannot relate to the conversation or behaviors - because they are too different.

CMV2: No matter how much they try, the people who prefer hanging out alone can never be part of a group. It's because they're too different to fit in. The group-guys will never understand, appreciate or respect the loner-guys. Even when they're all hanging out together. It's only a matter of time before the group-guys start belittling the loner-guys for their lack of group-socializing-skills and making judgements on their whole personalities. It's just unfortunate that the loner-guys were born/developed into tastes that were just way too unique. Group-guys will never accept loner-guys.

**In other words:** 

We all fit into 2 kinds of people. 

The group-guys - who get similar people like them no matter where they go. I'm not saying a 100% similar, but like 70% similar. You all share the same tastes across movies, songs, discussions of the workplace, attitudes towards friends and acquaintances, mannerism of talking, eating/drinking/smoking preferences, hangout location preferences. They understand each other very well and become quick-friends.

The loner-guys - who are way too unique. There's like 1 in 30 guys who are similar to them. They mostly remain alone because they cannot fit in with the group guys. They will never get to be part of any group because of this. The group guys are all similar and loner-guys are way too different.

Please help me CMV!


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30005349639.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="True">
    <text>There are well-studied ideas in psychology about personality types that are related to a well-known pop-psych thing called the [Meyers-Briggs Type Indicator](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myers%E2%80%93Briggs_Type_Indicator). Since this latter one is better defined and more widely known than the detailed ideas in the field of psychology, I'll use it to illustrate. 

MBTI says that people can be characterized on 4 axes (text copied from the MB website). 

There's a lot of controversy about the usefulness of these *specific* four axes... but the point remains that people are different in more ways than liking to be alone or not. 

&amp;gt;Favorite world: Do you prefer to focus on the outer world or on your own inner world? This is called Extraversion (E) or Introversion (I).

This is basically the axis that you focus on in your view. Yes, some people are energized by being in groups, while other people prefer to rest by themselves. 

But it's important to note that this is an *axis* not a binary. You can be in the middle, and in fact, most people are not at the extremes of this axis, but prefer some alone time and some time with people, with only the *amounts* varying. 

But there are other personality type axes that you can recognize if you really look at people and try to understand them: 

&amp;gt;Information: Do you prefer to focus on the basic information you take in or do you prefer to interpret and add meaning? This is called Sensing (S) or Intuition (N).

Surely you have met some people who are "just the facts Ma'am" types, vs. people that don't care that much about facts but like to go on intuition. An example would be scientific people vs. some kinds of religious people, for example. These are huge differences in world view and personality. 


&amp;gt;Decisions: When making decisions, do you prefer to first look at logic and consistency or first look at the people and special circumstances? This is called Thinking (T) or Feeling (F).

Again, I'm sure that you've found that some people are more interested in logic, and that some other people are more interested in feelings. Stereotypically, this is a divide between men and women, but of course both sexes have these focii to different degrees even if there might be a cultural reason for a statistical difference. 

&amp;gt;Structure: In dealing with the outside world, do you prefer to get things decided or do you prefer to stay open to new information and options? This is called Judging (J) or Perceiving (P).

Again, surely you've seen that some people like to plan things out, and other people like to be spur of the moment... and that this is true both for loners and in-group types. 

Often, in groups, such people will take charge, and organize the group activity, for example... 

Ultimate, look at all the differences between people, not just introversion. Don't get hung up on whether this particular framework is "correct". Think about it more generally.

For example: if you think that men and women are different, then this pretty much refutes your idea that "in group" people are "all the same"... unless you think that all groups are solely male or female, but I'm sure you can find many counterexamples. 

Or take another example: intelligence. Surely you don't think that everyone is the same degree of being smart... and that's a pretty big difference between people. I can assure you that not all smart people are loners. 

Etc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
