<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084650289.0" user="John_Farrier" delta="True">
    <text>I'm a community college librarian, so I have quite a bit of experience on this subject.

&amp;gt;It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online.

I'm very glad to hear that your book searching skills are up to shape. I wish that I could say that the students I work with on a daily basis are there. 

It is very common for me to encounter students who have not searched for a book since elementary school, if at all. The catalog is a fairly complex instrument. I would think that a call number is not, but I've helped about a dozen students so far this week who thought that a call number should be read from right to left or from the middle outward. They were lost in the stacks as a result. Once they get the books, the work has just begun. I have to introduce them to the table of contents and the index. Although most students know what a table of contents is, a subject index is often a new concept.

These students are, I should emphasize, not stupid. They're just not familiar with these tools.

For most students that I work with, their first instinct is to go to Google. The job of us librarians is to make searching the catalog and subscription databases (where they can find periodicals and full-text ebooks) as straightforward as possible. A professor requiring a certain number of books, both print and electronic, and periodical articles from the databases, helps us teach students how to use these tools. Otherwise, most will go straight to Google and never learn how much information is not available on the World Wide Web.

It's possible that some of your classmates are not as ready for book searching as you are. They may need this opportunity to learn. Hopefully your library print collection provides better sources than drug policy texts from 1993.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
