<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084636398.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="True">
    <text>I'll give it a go. Your argument is, the books can be unreliable or outdated, more so than articles online. Reading or looking up books isn't really a skill you need anymore, and even if you do it's not hard. And, you aren't even given enough time to read the book, encouraging you to just cherry pick quotes.

On your first point, the issue isn't that you're required to read books, it's that there should be some standard used for which source you use, whether it's online or a book.

Your second point, I think looking up books, reading them, knowing what to find and where, is definitely valuable. It may not seem too useful or difficult, but having students explore that aspect of research is important. If students do go into a profession where research is required, they may not have everything available online and will have to dig through books and be comfortable doing that.

Also, the internet isn't always as good about citing sources, providing accurate information, as books. Even Wikipedia sometimes leads to dead ends with [citations needed] or weird sources. It depends on what you are looking for, I suppose. 

Finally, the internet is still relatively young. There may be stuff in books in libraries that just hasn't been uploaded onto the internet. Especially on things that don't exist or aren't widely used anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
