<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106488577.0" user="-paperbrain-" delta="True">
    <text>I'm myself not very convinced by the various rebuttals to the problem of evil. But I do think taken together they at least leave a bi-omni (or indeed tri-omni) god as a possibility.

First we have to break down omnibenevolence and omnipotence.

When we talk about benevolence in more general terms, we're talking about an interest in what's best in a broader scope. A parent may make their child eat vegetables they don't like, or get a painful innoculation because the temporary and minor unpleasantness is dwarfed by the downsides of malnourishment or deadly disease. It is considered benevolent to create discomfort or even pain when the long term effects are bigger. And since most religions with a tri-omni god believe in an eternal afterlife, then any pain felt in our finite lives is dwarfed if it is necessary to avoid infinite negative consequences.

The obvious rebuttal is that inflicting temporary pain for greater good is only a necessity for a parent because that parent is not omnipotent. If a parent could make their kid grow up strong eating only things they loved, they probably would. If a parent could wipe out infectious disease, or make a child's tastebuds love veggies, they probably would.

So here we get into a definition of omnipotence. It can't be the ability to do anything we can state, because that would include things like creating a square with three sides, logical contradictions. If our bar for omnipotence included that ability, then omnipotence would be an illogical quality and we wouldn't need a problem of evil to challenge it.

So taking as our bar logical possibility, could there be a logical necessity, unseen by us within the vastness and complexity of the universe which makes eternal happiness impossible without temporary suffering on earth? I'm not asking if such a thing is likely, or if you believe that such a thing exists. Since we're overall talking about whether the idea of an omnibenevolent and omniscient god is POSSIBLE, then we only need to agree that such a logical necessity could POSSIBLY exist. Unless you know of a reason that it can't, it follows that the tri-omni god could be constrained by such a logical necessity and that the current world is the least amount of suffering such a god could logically allow to achieve a much greater payoff for humans.

Personally, I don't believe in such a necessity or such a god, but there is no reason they couldn't possibly exist. They're just incredibly unlikely from the available evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
