<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503104193.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bj9oh/cmv_having_children_should_not_be_a_fundamental/">
    <title>CMV: Having Children Should not be a Fundamental Human Right</title>
    <original_poster>BioTheRaider</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've come across this interesting concept in some personal conversations, and I find myself continuously returning to it and thinking, "Huh, that might be something."

My view is that people should not be entitled to having children; that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child. 

A quick disclaimer before the argument: I do not believe this is a view that can be effectively legislated for, and I am not advocating for any program to enable this. I am posing a more philosophical and ethical argument. I fully understand the dangers of giving a group of people the power to artificially select those who can and can't have children, and I don't pose to be any kind of expert in any area related to such things. I will not discuss selection processes, nor preventative processes, except in the broadest of possible senses.

Now, my points. It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence. I think this is a principle many people feel in situations outside of human children. For example, I have asked several people a question along the lines of "Is it moral to, assuming they are conscious, farm instantiations of artificial intelligence?" Let's take this to a large real-world scale, and say we have a thousand servers each storing a thousand AI, and these AI are sufficiently intelligent that, while it is unknowable, there is a possibility that the AI are conscious entities. Imagine that a company is trying to create a specialized AI for some problem they're trying to solve, and so they set their servers to work evolutionarily testing the AI until they produce one which solves the problem sufficiently. In essence, a million possibly conscious entities are being evaluated on their ability to solve a problem, and then discarded for a newer, better generation of a million AI. These servers are creating and destroying millions of instantiations of an AI which is possibly conscious in some way. Is this morally acceptable? I think not. These entities are being forced into existence and, to a first degree approximation, somewhat arbitrarily destroyed. I think that is something equivalent to a digital Holocaust, and I am not using that phrase lightly. Were those AI human brains, there is no doubt that we would find some practice of subjecting humans to a similar process to be hugely immoral. The principle here is that we are, essentially, exerting control over the life and death of a conscious entity. We don't find slavery or murder acceptable, so why would this be?

We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life. 

I am aware that we have children in order to continue the species, we are biologically designed to have children. But just because it's the natural course of things does not make it moral. I'm not of the inclination that the perpetuation of the species is an inherently good goal.

Human life is frought with suffering and hardship. It is, until we somehow become all-powerful, unavoidable. Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. Why would it be alright to enable suffering through the creation of the capacity for suffering as having a child does? Why is it okay to force people to live? If someone is already alive, then of course we should allow them agency over their body and life, and provide alleviation of suffering, but why should we be allowed to force something into a position where it must encounter suffering?What right does anyone have to do this?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30305651637.0" user="HeWhoShitsWithPhone" delta="True">
    <text>The body of your post does not actually line up with your title. It is possible that it is a person can have a right to have kids, yet the choice to have kids is immoral. For instance people have a right to free speech? However often what we say is immoral even if it is still protected. The body of your post only seeks to establish the immorality of birth, but you are missing the arguments that would establish the relevance of this immorality.


That being said I would agree with you that having children is not a basic human right, and that seeking to contol that is a violation of your rights. Strictly speaking rights are more philosophical not practical. Functionally they are more or less the same though. People also do not have the right to breath, however any thing you do to prevent someone from breathing would be a violation of their rights. 


As to the morality of having kids, that comes up in CMV a lot and I would encourage you to search old posts. 
To address your anology specifically, 

&amp;gt; We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life.

I don't think I follow this part. The goal of most parebts is to have their child become and independent adult, not to live a life of slavery only to then by killed the parent. If you only seek to use your kid for personal gain then kill it, I think everyone would agree that your being immoral. Would you feel it is immoral to make AI with the intent that they grow and learn then eventually take control of their life and find success and happiness.


&amp;gt; Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. 

We generally accept that it can be moral to cause suffering or allow them to happen at certain time. For instance when the suffering will bring about something good. An example would be a coach. Their job is basically to make their team suffer so that they can get better and win games. if all suffering ass immoral then coaches would be Hitler. Obviously this can be taken too far, for example Hitler. 

Most people mostly enjoy their life so havig a kid tends to add happyness to the world.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
