<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306940032.0" user="weirds3xstuff" delta="True">
    <text>/u/BraapLord has the right idea here. I will try to elaborate on the same point.

(For the following, I will assume both that there are no practical impediments to your prohibition and that it would be accepted as legal by the relevant parties. FWIW, I'm an atheist.)

At heart, religion is a set of non-empirical statements. "God exists", "After you die, you will go to heaven", "Jesus rose from the dead", "If someone strikes you on the cheek, do not retaliate, instead, let them strike the other cheek," etc. are all religious statements that cannot be verified as true. In claiming that we should prohibit children from being taught religion, the axiom of your action appears to be, "We should not teach children that statements which have not been verified to be true are true." This sounds perfectly defensible. Until you remember the [is-ought problem](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Is%E2%80%93ought_problem).

In brief, the problem is that *no ought-statements, whether secular or religious, can be verified to be true*. I can empirically say that, "Shooting someone in the head will kill them." I cannot empirically say that, "Shooting someone in the head is wrong unless they are putting you in mortal danger."

So, if we are to both prohibit the indoctrination of religious creeds to children and be intellectually consistent, we must also prohibit the indoctrination of secular value systems. That outcome is unacceptable for reasons that I hope are self-evident, therefore we must permit the religious indoctrination of children.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
