<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503594194.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8btrrm/cmv_america_doesnt_need_more_stem_majors/">
    <title>CMV: America doesn't need more STEM majors.</title>
    <original_poster>brotherhood4232</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to follow the Reddit consensus that STEM = good and "basket weaving" majors = bad. I graduated with an electrical engineering degree myself. But after looking for a job myself, it doesn't seem like the job market could support a ton of more STEM majors.

I've seem very few job postings that said Entry Level. Most want 3\-5 years of experience and a host of qualifications that no new graduate will have. This means you are not only competing against other new graduates, but you are also competing against Mid\-Level STEM professionals. I think a flood of new STEM graduates would exacerbate this problem and a lot of those new engineers would be working at Starbucks. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30309803612.0" user="superbluelobster" delta="True">
    <text>I have noticed an uptick in advertisements aimed at getting more people into STEM, which confused me at first until I watched a video by in a nutshell on Egoistic Altruism. Basically, the video argues that the world's economy is no longer based on land, but on the about of people working in, and contributing to the advancement of, STEM. the world has moved from a zero-sum gain to a positive-sum gain due to industrial advancement. In order for countries to survive in this new economy, they need more people in STEM that can contribute innovative solutions to problems that we face and will face. Innovation is lead by supply and demand. as more individuals can contribute to supply, they increase their personal gains and can contribute to the demand in other areas, leading more people to study in that area. unfortunately, we are in the early stages of this process still, meaning that you might be stuck waiting for the supply of jobs to reach the same level as the demand for jobs. but this process will eventually work its self out as we find more problems, which lead to more jobs, which will bring more solutions and problems.
I hope that make sense, and I recommend checking out the video.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
