<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503594194.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8btrrm/cmv_america_doesnt_need_more_stem_majors/">
    <title>CMV: America doesn't need more STEM majors.</title>
    <original_poster>brotherhood4232</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to follow the Reddit consensus that STEM = good and "basket weaving" majors = bad. I graduated with an electrical engineering degree myself. But after looking for a job myself, it doesn't seem like the job market could support a ton of more STEM majors.

I've seem very few job postings that said Entry Level. Most want 3\-5 years of experience and a host of qualifications that no new graduate will have. This means you are not only competing against other new graduates, but you are also competing against Mid\-Level STEM professionals. I think a flood of new STEM graduates would exacerbate this problem and a lot of those new engineers would be working at Starbucks. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30309786542.0" user="Extraneous-thoughts" delta="True">
    <text>America doesn't need more JUST STEM majors.

My experience with STEM majors is that they're very one-track about the value of their degree. They believe that just having their degree with their 4.0 GPA is enough. I go to a school with a lot of pre-med students, and everything they do is for their dream--more likely their parents' dream--of being a doctor. Specific to medicine, the standard student has a high GPA in a biology/chemistry degree that was going to cover all their pre-requisites anyways, some half-hearted lab experience, and affiliation with one of the many pre-med associations on their campus. They aren't well-rounded, or doing something that shows creative thinking or skill with hands or people.

The way the world is going, we're going to need more STEM proficient people. But that can't be the only thing going for them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
