<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="510392670.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8fvhi6/cmv_ocd_doesnt_have_to_be_debilitating/">
    <title>CMV: OCD doesn't have to be debilitating</title>
    <original_poster>lookslikeamirac</original_poster>
    <original_post>A lot of people get ticked off a bit when someone says something like "I'm OCD about _____" because they don't think it's legitimate and they see it as undermining what people with 'real' OCD go through.

I understand that maybe it seems insignificant to someone who has to wash his or her hands 20 times before bed, but it doesn't mean it's not some degree of OCD.

A hypothetical situation:

There's a guy who always leaves the volume on an even number when he changes it. When he turns on the TV though, he doesn't check to make sure it's an even number. So if it's already odd when he turns it on, then it's fine.

He changes the volume and sets it to an even number. Then, his friend changes it to odd and steals the remote. It doesn't prevent the man from watching TV, but it makes him slightly uncomfortable because he knows it's odd and he asks for the other guy to change the volume to an even number. The man refuses, and both men go on watching TV leaving the first man a little uneasy. After a while, the friend goes to the bathroom and forgets about the remote/volume, and the first guy steals the remote back to change it back to even.

My claim is that the guy may still have OCD since it makes him feel uncomfortable. It doesn't mean he *has to* change the volume back but he'd greatly prefer it be on an even number and gives some small anxiety when he knows that's not the case. It's enough that the friend forgot about it, but he remembered and immediately changed it on the first opportunity. 

To change my mind please provide evidence that my situation or a similar one *can't* be OCD. There may be no way around a semantic argument since we're dealing with medical terms, but try to avoid it if possible. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30365485258.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="True">
    <text>As /u/lekanto/ has said, OCD is a diagnosis of a mental illness - a defined medical disorder. Feeling compulsions and/or being somewhat obsessed about something does not, by itself allow for a diagnosis of the condition.  Only a significant amount of distress, impairment and/or loss of functionality, when diagnosed by a trained professional (psychiatrist), represents actual OCD.  I'm afraid your example is trivial and fails to meet the definition in the DSM.  While the man feels 'uncomfortable', or 'small anxiety' is is able to to continue the activity, continue interacting with his friend, and is not compelled to complete a ritualistic behaviour.  Bluntly speaking, our hypothetical man does not meet the clinical definition of OCD, and thus, does not have the disorder.  This is the key distinction.   

&amp;amp;nbsp;
To explain the source of displeasure created by the expression "I'm OCD about ____", those of us with diagnosed with OCD have often endured years worth of time lost to irrational compulsions in response to obsessive thought patterns we are unable control (without treatment).   Our schooling, our careers, our relationships and families have been damaged (perhaps beyond repair) by extended periods of non-functionality.  A comparison to a circumstance when someone feels a little 'ill at ease' when their desk is not clear, or their books are not neatly lined up on the shelf, demonstrates both ignorance and a lack of perspective/empathy.    A similar comparison might be comparing a minor, low-speed 'nudging' of a barrier in a parking lot to a collision at highway speeds; the first may create the need for a minor repair, the other renders the car unusable without suitable repairs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
