<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="510392670.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8fvhi6/cmv_ocd_doesnt_have_to_be_debilitating/">
    <title>CMV: OCD doesn't have to be debilitating</title>
    <original_poster>lookslikeamirac</original_poster>
    <original_post>A lot of people get ticked off a bit when someone says something like "I'm OCD about _____" because they don't think it's legitimate and they see it as undermining what people with 'real' OCD go through.

I understand that maybe it seems insignificant to someone who has to wash his or her hands 20 times before bed, but it doesn't mean it's not some degree of OCD.

A hypothetical situation:

There's a guy who always leaves the volume on an even number when he changes it. When he turns on the TV though, he doesn't check to make sure it's an even number. So if it's already odd when he turns it on, then it's fine.

He changes the volume and sets it to an even number. Then, his friend changes it to odd and steals the remote. It doesn't prevent the man from watching TV, but it makes him slightly uncomfortable because he knows it's odd and he asks for the other guy to change the volume to an even number. The man refuses, and both men go on watching TV leaving the first man a little uneasy. After a while, the friend goes to the bathroom and forgets about the remote/volume, and the first guy steals the remote back to change it back to even.

My claim is that the guy may still have OCD since it makes him feel uncomfortable. It doesn't mean he *has to* change the volume back but he'd greatly prefer it be on an even number and gives some small anxiety when he knows that's not the case. It's enough that the friend forgot about it, but he remembered and immediately changed it on the first opportunity. 

To change my mind please provide evidence that my situation or a similar one *can't* be OCD. There may be no way around a semantic argument since we're dealing with medical terms, but try to avoid it if possible. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30365458119.0" user="ThomasEdmund84" delta="True">
    <text>Well firstly by definition you only have OCD or any other diagnosis if your life isn't significantly impaired by it, so mild discomfort and preference around volume doesn't officially meet criteria.

More philosophically however this means we aren't sure whether OCD is a "thing" or its a description of a pattern of challenges we've observed. By being a "thing" I mean that if OCD exists as some sort of specific condition a person could well have it but for whatever reason not suffer significantly, however if OCD is just what we call a particular set of difficulties we've observed but not a condition on its own then this guy does not technically have OCD.

That probably sounds a bit gibbery - compare to having a bacterial infection, a person can have an infection and feel fine OR feel all sorts of symptoms and this can be confirmed or denied by testing for that bacteria. We don't just define medical diseases by their symptoms but also the underlying causes.

For mental health we define diagnosis by their symptoms and still have much to learn about underlying causes. Therefore no symptoms or rather no significant symptoms no diagnosis</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
