<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="522076006.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8mtwfa/cmv_parrots_dont_make_good_pets/">
    <title>CMV: Parrots don't make good pets.</title>
    <original_poster>KnightWhoSaysNi1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just to be clear, I'm not in a place in my life to get a parrot, nor do I want one, as you can tell from the title of my post. But I want to find out why people find them to be good pets.

Here's why I don't think they make good pets:

1. From what I've read about them, they're on the emotional level of toddlers. And while human children are toddlers for a few years, parrots can live around eighty years. So you're dealing with a toddler for eighty years.

2. To add onto the previous point, they can live eighty to ninety effing years! Cats and dogs can live around twenty years, and that's a reasonable time commitment, but for a pet with the kind of lifespan that a parrot has, even if they have the very best outcome and have an owner who makes a lifelong commitment to them, there's still a good chance that they'll be uprooted from their home at the very end of their life.

3. From everything I hear and read, they require a ton of work! They seem to be messier and more expensive to take care of than dogs and cats, and after all that work, you can't cuddle them like dogs and cats. It also seems like it's hard to find a vet for them, and I'm guessing it would be way more expensive once you do find a vet.

4. They're loud and neurotic. If you don't devote a huge amount of attention to them, they screech all the time, pluck their feathers out, and attack people. I've heard a cockatoo screech, and I think I'd go insane if I had to listen to that sound in my house constantly.

With all this out of the way, I'm not going to pretend that I don't think that they're cool animals. They're really beautiful and seem pretty intelligent. It's neat that they can talk, and maybe for people who are not me, the novelty of them talking wouldn't wear off after ten minutes. I just think they'd be better off at zoos or wildlife sanctuaries where they have enough space to fly around and have a team of dedicated people than as pets in people's homes. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30458723931.0" user="7nkedocye" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;To add onto the previous point, they can live eighty to ninety effing years! Cats and dogs can live around twenty years, and that's a reasonable time commitment, but for a pet with the kind of lifespan that a parrot has, even if they have the very best outcome and have an owner who makes a lifelong commitment to them, there's still a good chance that they'll be uprooted from their home at the very end of their life.

Well most dog and cat owners don't get one in their lifetime and call it done. It's arguably beneficial that they live so long as you can train them longer and build a better connection. If people don't want the parrot after a while there are human and inhumane ways to get rid of them.

&amp;gt;From everything I hear and read, they require a ton of work! They seem to be messier and more expensive to take care of than dogs and cats, and after all that work, you can't cuddle them like dogs and cats. It also seems like it's hard to find a vet for them, and I'm guessing it would be way more expensive once you do find a vet.

Sure, but this is known by responsible parrot owners before purchase yet they still find them to be worth the effort. You can absolutely be affectionate with a parrot.

&amp;gt;They're loud and neurotic. If you don't devote a huge amount of attention to them, they screech all the time, pluck their feathers out, and attack people. I've heard a cockatoo screech, and I think I'd go insane if I had to listen to that sound in my house constantly.

Properly trained birds don't screech outside of set times during the day, but yes they are very loud animals.

&amp;gt;It's neat that they can talk, and maybe for people who are not me, the novelty of them talking wouldn't wear off after ten minutes.

A lot of parrot owners have a love for birds that you and I probably don't have or understand. But that doesn't mean they can't be good pets to people who have a passion for them. I completely agree that they should not be an impulse purchase, but I apply that standard to all pets.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
