<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483314812.0" user="misscheeky123" delta="True">
    <text>It is possible for it to be a place for families AND for sexual openness. 

Im from the Caribbean, and carnival is a big thing in my culture. You could definitely say its sexually open \- we dress up in masquerade costumes \(kind of like bikinis with a lot of extra decorations\) and wine on each other all day long. It doesn't matter if you're big or small, you can wear mas costumes and wine and no\-one will judge. It's just what we do, and many see it as very sexually provocative. But its also a place for families. We bring our kids and parents and uncles. Ive been to carnival with my aunts and little cousins before. Its a celebration of culture.

I think Pride could be like that too. I shit you not, I went to Pride in Amsterdam with both of my parents and my little sister, and we had an amazing time dancing \(my mum especially loved it\). Not long later, my sister came out to us because she finally had the courage to do so. I think theres something for everyone at Pride in the same way as carnival, it doesn't have to revolve around sex if you don't want it to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
