<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483288354.0" user="Benjamminmiller" delta="True">
    <text>Straight guy here.

While being public about your sexuality may not be important to you, expression of sexuality is central to both historic oppression and modern repression. Pride is the bounce back from a world that hasn't (and doesn't) want you to be gay, and especially doesn't want you to wear it on your sleeve. Pride is a celebration of finally reaching a point where there's freedom of expression for a historically (and currently) marginalized people, without fear of judgement or backlash.

Pride is not a recruitment festival or educational movement.  Pride is not about catering to other people. Pride is a celebration of freedom.

For many people in the gay community getting to express their sexuality publicly, on ones own terms, is the whole point.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
