<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30612789699.0" user="SpicyIguana" delta="True">
    <text>The niqab is oppressive because it seriously limits a woman's ability to interact socially and participate as a member of society. It covers up the most expressive part of her body – her face – and hinders her ability to show emotion. A huge amount of communication is done through nonverbal cues, but a woman wearing a niqab isn't able to convey these cues and therefore her ability to participate in public life is limited. Imagine listening to a presentation at a meeting at work - who do you think would be the more compelling speaker, someone whose face and hands are free to be expressive and interesting, or someone who is muffled by a sheet and a veil and whose face you can't see? Almost certainly the former, which gives a tremendous advantage to men in a society where women are expected to wear the niqab. 

Additionally, the niqab forces anonymity on a woman. It steals a woman's individuality, dehumanizes her, and turns her into a faceless figure. When you look at her, you don't see a person - you see a dark ghost with eyes peeking through a slit. This stands in contrast to men, who just look like human beings. All women wearing a niqab look more or less the same, with the result that they can easily all be treated the same and lumped into one single faceless and insignificant category by men. 

A niqab is also a constant reminder that, in the view of the oppressive societies that expect them to be worn, women and men must be kept fundamentally apart. The niqab is a barrier between the woman who wears it and the outside world. Men, however, don't need such a barrier because they FORM the outside world. The outside world is a place for men, and women who enter it must hide themselves to avoid disrupting or tempting the men to whom it belongs. I would argue that nearly all women who choose to wear the niqab are doing so because they've absorbed this oppressive ideology, so the fact that they technically choose to wear it doesn't mean it's not oppressive. (Others wear it because they're in a place where they will face harrassment, shaming, and physical danger if they don't.)

Heels, on the other hand, don't hinder a woman's ability to interact in public, either socially or professionally. They don't separate her from the outside world and they don't set her apart as some "other" who must be kept hidden. Like neckties for men, heels for women are a gender-specific part of professional or formal clothing. (And [heels have historically been worn by men](https://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-21151350); they weren't invented to damage women's backs.) 

You mention throughout this thread that you worked at a place where women were required to wear heels. That's sexist, because as you point out that forces a health risk on women. But it's nowhere near as fundamentally oppressive as the niqab, because the heels aren't designed to limit how effectively a woman can participate in a public/professional sphere, or to force her into faceless anonymity. A woman in heels is able to take part in a board meeting just as easily as if she weren't wearing heels (and heels actually sometimes lend an air of power or professionalism). But a woman in a niqab isn't able to show visible reactions or facial expressions, and is wearing clothing that makes her seem less significant and less present than men whose faces are bare; and the niqab also serves as a constant reminder to everyone in the room that she's a woman and that women are in a fundamentally different social class and category from men.

The physical damage from heels occurs over the long term and isn't visible to or desired by employers who require heels (many probably aren't even aware that this damage occurs, or don't think their employees walk enough to develop this damage). Like I said earlier, that's absolutely sexist and I would either sue my employer or quit in protest if they started requiring heels. But heels at work don't prevent a woman from participating equally in society, nor do they dehumanize her and turn her into a faceless figure, so they're not "oppressive" in the same way as a niqab.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
