<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611234226.0" user="ralph-j" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.

While I agree that high heels are a sexist expectation in some parts of society (e.g. certain jobs), you don't generally hear about families where the husband won't let the wife leave the house without wearing high heels.

Some examples of forced niqab use:

* [Her husband is forcing her to wear niqaab and she wants advice](https://islamqa.info/en/20910)
* ['Hell' for wife forced to wear a niqab by husband](https://www.dailystar.co.uk/news/latest-news/341449/Hell-for-wife-forced-to-wear-a-niqab-by-husband) 
* [My New Husband is Forcing Me To Wear Niqab. Must I?](http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:https%3A//aboutislam.net/counseling/ask-about-islam/husband-forcing-niqab/)

In Saudi Arabia, women have even been called on to wear a [niqab that only reveals one eye](http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/middle_east/7651231.stm). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
