<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="556141362.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9741f6/cmv_fines_should_scale_according_to_the_persons/">
    <title>CMV: Fines should scale according to the person's wealth</title>
    <original_poster>onlyfoolandhorse</original_poster>
    <original_post>...or some other punishment should be included. The punishment should be worse depending on how much money people have.  


Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.  
For a deterrent to work the accused must want to avoid the penalty i.e. the fine.  
A billionaire hardly minds if he gets a £200 fine!

Notes:  
 \- Sometimes this wouldn't be possible, but when it is possible the extra admin would be well worth it.   
 \- Additional punishments could include some sort of public shaming, more driving licence points deducted, etc. I don't know, just anything which puts wealthier people off commiting crimes. It doesn't necessarily have to be money, although money makes sense as it could go towards helping victims of the crime (e.g. helping victims of speeding motorists).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30726271242.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="True">
    <text>There is a lot wrong with this poison.

Firstly, the fine itself isn't what deter people from speeding most of the time. Rich or poor they will take your license away. The rich cant get away with continually speeding and paying fines.

Secondly, it creates warped incentives, small towns already use speeding tickets to raise money. By doing tins you making it an even more attractive way of raining money, one pulled over billionaire would net millions.

Thirdly, should prison sentences scale like this as well? should a healthy person serve a longer sentence than a morbidly obese person? One person is expected to live another 40 years, so is given 20 years, the other who never exercises gets 10 for the same crime. Does that sound fair to you?

Also money form fines doest go into helping victims at all. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
