<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="567468370.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9dutea/cmv_album_art_that_solely_consists_of_a_portrait/">
    <title>CMV: Album art that solely consists of a portrait photograph of the artist's or artists' face(s) without any interesting makeup is boring, lazy, and uninteresting.</title>
    <original_poster>Zalmoxis_1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples: Phil Collins's [*Face Value*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c9/Phil_Collins_-_Face_Value.png/220px-Phil_Collins_-_Face_Value.png), [*No Jacket Required*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/2f/Phil_Collins_-_No_Jacket_Required.png), [*...But Seriously*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f5/Phil_Collins-But_Seriously.jpg)


Taylor Swift's entire discography




Album art serves important functions- to draw a newcomer in and to be aesthetically pleasing. A good album cover ought to tantalize a listener and make them listen to the record.  It can  convey the tone and content of the album "loudly" with blunt and bold symbolism, or it can be mysterious and subtly hint at the content with a minimalist design.


 Additionally, it should be aesthetically appealing to some degree. This is important if you own a physical copy of the album, whether it be vinyl or cd, as it encourages you to preserve the quality of the casing. Additionally, it can be appreciated as you would appreciate any other piece of art. It also makes the band look more serious and professional about their work.



In my opinion, the portrait album covers I provided as examples have none of these qualities. First of all, they don't necessarily stick out. If it wasn't for Collins's and Swift's fame, these records could easily be passed over in a record store. They don't have any unique or noteworthy qualities to them- they're quite vanilla and inoffensive. It's just someone's face without any particular unique makeup or costume. Additionally, they're quite boring to look at. 


Secondly, it's hard to discern the tone and content of the album. Phil Collins seems to be donning a neutral expression in many of the album covers. This obviously makes it hard to determine what kind of music is going to be in the album.



I added the "makeup" caveat as it actually can make portrait covers interesting. Just look at Bowie's *Hunky Dory* and *Aladdin Sane*


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30811163163.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="True">
    <text>We're psychologically drawn to faces. If we see a picture of a face, there's generally a desire to infer the subject's thoughts and emotions. Take the cover of Face Value, for example. The extreme close-up with Phil Collins looking you right in the eye suggests that the album will be an intimate one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
