<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31002786262.0" user="MindlessFlatworm" delta="True">
    <text>You are correct that it is a mental disorder. However, at the current time, the causes are unknown and it may not be fixable through hormone replacement (of the kind you are imagining). While I certainly think it is VASTLY overused and that many otherwise normal people with mild gender dysphoria that they might eventually grow out of are pushed into more extreme treatments than are necessary, it certainly seems to be that gender hormone replacement therapy and sex reassignment surgery ARE the best form of treatment that we have available for the most extreme cases. Until we figure out what causes this and if there is a cure for that cause, there's nothing wrong with transitioning. (Again though, we should take the Jewish approach and actively discourage transitioning. Only the most persistent cases should go through that)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
