<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31003769484.0" user="han_dies_01" delta="True">
    <text>Based on the following quote, /u/armdrag2youback, I gather that this post is focused on the idea of **cultural relativism**. 

&amp;gt;I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". 

This actually reflects a popular misunderstanding of the concept of cultural relativism as it was devised.

Cultural relativism was a philosophy developed by the anthropologist Franz Boas in the early 20th century to guide cultural anthropologists in studying, describing, and analyzing other cultures. It actually has nothing to say about "respecting all cultures."

It was pushback to earlier anthropologists' approaches, in which non-Western cultures-- and cultural practices / beliefs / norms / values-- were typically described in direct contrast to Western cultural norms and ideas. And usually they were depicted as somehow lacking.

Boas proposed a cultural relativistic view. Not that other cultures' practices "should be respected," but that in describing and writing about a culture, those practices should be viewed from *within* the cultural and historical context in which they developed and exist, rather than holding them to the moral / ethical standards of another culture.

That's all.

In fact, most cultural anthropologists today readily acknowledge that there are practices in *every* culture that are maladaptive, dysfunctional, and harmful. One of the things anthropologists do is work to understand the social processes and history of those practices, because if you don't know how and why a "bad" practice develops (the context-- the part that cultural relativism is really useful for), it's very difficult to actually develop a solution. Today, many anthropologists are actively engaged in working with community members to develop effective and constructive solutions that can be implemented within communities to address those practices (e.g, FGM). These solutions include (among other things) social engagement and education.

**tl;dr:** The people who actually adhere to "cultural relativism" don't hold the view that you're attributing to them. I don't know whether this changes your mind or not, but hopefully maybe it better explains what the term actually means. (**source: I am a professional anthropologist**)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
