<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593993382.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tnc86/cmv_schools_should_place_as_much_emphasis_on/">
    <title>CMV: Schools should place as much emphasis on developing children's mental health as they do on academic learning.</title>
    <original_poster>Starrcade87</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the goal of the education system should be to help children grow into healthy adults. 

Academic learning is good, but I would argue that it's actually less important than learning how to take care of yourself and your mental health.  For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

How should this be achieved?  I don't know exactly, but a few ideas:

\- Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

\- Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day.  Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

\- Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults.  Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed.  This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

In other words, school shouldn't just about math, reading, and science.  Spend time and effort developing kids as people and not only will they be healthier, they'll learn better too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31015190799.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="True">
    <text>So let's say the average school week is 40 hrs. That means a single therapist can see at the very most 40 students per week and certainly less due to breaks and things. My class, a fairly average suburban class, had ~500 students. Which means we'd need at least 13 just for my one class, and that's assuming 40 students per week and no extra hrs. So once we add those in 15-20 therapists per class. In a high school with 4 grades in it that's 60-80 therapists. That's insanity. There's just not enough therapists for every school to do what you want them to. And even if there were no way schools would have the budget for that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
