<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31139661285.0" user="fugutaboutit" delta="True">
    <text>I'm not for punishing anyone more than anyone else.  Why should a prosecutor's speeding ticket cost more than anyone else?    

Even if you disagree with that, you simply can't codify "overpunishment" into law.  You can, however, create new laws and statues.     

If a state were to create a new law, specifically punishing criminal action taken ["under color of law"](https://legal-dictionary.thefreedictionary.com/Color+of+Law), then I would be 100% on board.  For example, (keeping with the above speeding ticket) lets say the prosecutor attempted to justify her speeding by saying "I was headed to some emergency 'prosecutor' meeting", and it turned out to not be, then the fine should be doubled.  In the same way, a police officer tried for rape ought to be sentenced as such for Rape, but if he used his position to execute such rape, he should be face a punishment twice as bad. 
     
Basically, instead of advocating for harsher punishments, (which by itself is considerably difficult to actually carry out) create a new statute that punishes those in power from abusing their powers. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
