<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159098578.0" user="IYELLALLTHETIME" delta="True">
    <text>Employee retention matters. People with more years of experience at a company are always better employees. If you replaced a $70,000 / year employee with a $50,000 / year employee and then that employee sucks at his job, he could very easily cost the company much more than $20k. It is by no means a guaranteed good financial decision and seems like a pretty poor one.

Plus, companies do have reputations. Imagine considering applying for a company with a reputation for letting people go after 2-3 years. Do you think you’ll follow through with that application? Hell no. And a company is well aware of that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
