<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159046280.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="True">
    <text>In a competitive market, businesses compete for top talent.  If you are a high performer, multiple businesses should want you to work for them because, logically, your talents will help them earn more money (or spend less money, which amounts to the same thing at the end of the day).

A business may want to squeeze you and have your work for the least amount possible, but if they do that then you are likely to get poached by another company who is willing to offer you X% more money because your talents are valuable.  In order to prevent that, and prevent the disruption that having to replace you would cause the business, it is logical to offer the employee Y% more money every year, where Y is _just enough_ to keep the employee from looking for another job.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
