<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159326944.0" user="gloria_monday" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages"

First of all, 'good review' != 'higher wages'. Giving a good review is absolutely easier than replacing an employee. It costs nothing, other than 10 minutes of the manager's time.

Even in the event that giving a good review necessarily leads to a raise, it's not like we're talking about doubling someone's salary. Say you have to give them a 10% raise.  I think you're underestimating how easy it is to hire decent people. Of course it will vary depending on the complexity of the job, but it seems very conservative to say that it would easily take a month or more to hire someone new *and* train them to the point that they were as productive as the previous (good) employee - particularly when you factor in the fact that some percentage of new employees will be terrible. Ok, so that's a month or more of lost productivity. That will cost the company at least the 10% pay raise that they didn't want to give, since 1 month is about 10% of a year and the value that the employee generates for the company is definitionally greater than their salary (otherwise the company wouldn't hire for the position).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
