<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159173337.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="True">
    <text>- I have to review employees and the purpose is to communicate strength and weakness and no always about money.

- I would also point out many companies may do review differently but the objective is to asses the employee.  If your boss is just checking boxes on a form then I dont think that is helpful.  Your boss should meet with employees one on one at least once a year.  go over expectations for improvement and what they feel you are doing well.  It does make a difference to hear that as an employee vs a boss who never gives reviews.  everyone has different perspectives on how they view themselves vs how others see them.

- a review can be used as a record of improvements or failings over time.

- If an employee is a super employee and does everything well then  a review is an opportunity to keep setting the bar higher and suggest new goals for them to achieve

- positive feedback is good for the employee even if the company has no money for a raise.

- it is also an opportunity to hear from the employee themselves.  use that as a tool to improve the business or employee relationships</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
