<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644178994.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anizoy/cmv_the_government_doesnt_have_any_special_rights/">
    <title>CMV: The government doesn't have any special rights to products that make use of publicly-funded research.</title>
    <original_poster>kuriousgoomba</original_poster>
    <original_post>I typically consider myself fairly fiscally liberal, but I saw two reddit posts in recent days I don't really agree with that garnered a lot of support from other redditors. 

1) [If Software Is Funded from a Public Source, Its Code Should Be Open Source](https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/an43i7/if_software_is_funded_from_a_public_source_its/)

(Note- I don't disagree with the main point of the article, I am all for open standards. I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

2) [Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Calls Out Sexism As Her Big Pharma Knowledge Is Labeled 'Inadequate'](https://www.reddit.com/r/AlexandriaOcasio/comments/anebj0/alexandria_ocasiocortez_calls_out_sexism_as_her/)

(Note- I don't disagree with AOC's claim that her treatment by the media and the op-ed in question is sexist, because it is. Rather, I disagree with her claim during the hearing that government funding justifies public ownership of the final product.)

Both these articles seem to be getting at an idea that because the government initially funds certain ventures, they have a right to mandate public access to the product at either reduced cost (pharma) or for free (open-source code).

I think that I fundamentally disagree with some of the redditors commenting on these posts when I think about the purpose of government research funding. In general, I think the government's role is to fund basic research projects and produce novel ideas that private industry can then use to benefit people in a wide variety of ways. This includes pharmaceuticals, advances in alternative energy, novel algorithms, etc. etc.

In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. Taxpayers don't fund research because they expect a direct financial payout. They finance research because they expect a preponderance of high-quality and creative research programs to lead to welfare-improving products in the end (such as new medicines). There may be other reasons to mandate reduced prices, such as the elasticity of demand when it comes to medicine. But to say that companies are obligated to lower prices because it was initially public-domain research doesn't seem correct to me. 

There are other viable economic systems where the government can, for example, produce energy at cost. But because we live in a capitalist system we ought to use the power of the free market to soak up the innovative ideas that public universities and research programs produce and put them to work developing products people will purchase because they see value in them. 

Is this the correct way to view public-private research relationships? Please, change my view! 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31432216655.0" user="McKoijion" delta="True">
    <text>Private property, and intellectual property are both somewhat manufactured concepts. If I bury a million dollars somewhere such that only I know where it is, it's pretty safely mine. On the IP side, if I am the only person that knows the recipe for Coke or KFC, then it's also mine. Aside from that, private property is based on what you can defend, or convince others to defend on your behalf.

We can layer in growing ideas of private ownership. We can say that people can own land. We can say people can own factories. We can say that people can own businesses. We can say that people can own arbitrary concepts of value like cash, bonds, derivatives, etc. We can say people can own patents. We can say people own entertainment content. But the further you get down this path, the weirder things get. 

For example, who owns [this embarrassing photo of Beyonce](https://www.sbnation.com/lookit/2017/2/5/14514466/beyonce-super-bowl-halftime-how-photos-lmao-never-forget) from the Super Bowl? Does Beyonce? Does the NFL? What about the photographer? How about the people who created memes online of it? What about the people that took those memes and put them on for-profit Instagram pages? Does it belong to the general public?

At a base level, the entire concept of ownership is meaningless. After humanity goes extinct, my property is no longer mine. In 100 years, my property is no longer mine. That means that property only exists temporarily. And the real basis for property is whether I have special access or am willing to use violence to enforce it. Then when we create a society/government, it's really just us coming to an agreement on how to maximize the benefit for all people.

Patents exist because we want to incentivize individuals to invent things. That improves society. But today, patents are used to find ways to block other companies from competing. It's more-cost effective to extend the patent on a drug than to invent a new one. Disney used a lot of characters (e.g., Aladin, Rapunzel) in the public domain without paying the estates of the people who created them (e.g., the Brothers Grimm, Hans Christian Andersen.) Meanwhile, they fiercely guard their trademarks (e.g., Mickey Mouse) even though they are almost a century old.

Most people are willing to abide by laws that protect content creators, but they aren't willing to do so for people who aren't actively generating any new value. People were happy to praise billionaires when they were creating far more value than they took for society, but are unhappy when they feel that the wealthy are taking more than they are returning.

Jonas Salk took public money to invent the polio vaccine, and then made the patent available to the public. As such, Americans have been willing to fund research without getting a direct profit because they believe that the drugs alone are worth it. Now that the research has become much more valuable, but the public isn't getting the value they expect out of it, they want to see a greater return. Namely, they want a direct return on investment. A cure for a deadly disease is worth funding no strings attached. But if public funding is going to be used to fund profitable baldness treatments, the public wants some of that money back. 

Ultimately, even if you start with the premise that property rights are invaluable, we are layering in providing extra government funding to certain people, not just protecting existing rights. At that point, the public can structure that extra service however they want.

Ultimately, you have the right to do whatever you want. But if you want me to help you, you have to be willing to do it my way. And I'm going to find the balance that grows the overall pie the most while still giving me a large slice. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
