<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449930568.0" user="xxFactFinder" delta="True">
    <text>"It is . . . the heartiest hope of the Soviet Government that the United States will become involved in war with Japan. . . . The final conviction of the leaders of the Soviet Union with regard to the war they desire so ardently between the United States and Japan is that Japan would be defeated, that a Communist Government would then be set up in Japan, and Japan and the Soviet Union would then move happily hand in hand to establish communism in China. "

Foreign relations of the United States. Diplomatic papers. The Soviet Union, 1933-1939. (pp.227)

[https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/006255778](https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/006255778)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

"There will never be so good a time to stop the shipment of oil to Japan as we now have. . . . There might develop from embargoing of oil such a situation as would make it, not only possible but easy, to get into this war in an effective way. And if we should thus indirectly be brought in, we would avoid the criticism that we had gone in as an ally of communistic Russia."

Harold Ickes to Franklin D. Roosevelt, 23 June 1941

[http://www.sscnet.ucla.edu/polisci/faculty/trachtenberg/methbk/ickes.pdf](http://www.sscnet.ucla.edu/polisci/faculty/trachtenberg/methbk/ickes.pdf)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

"6. If the Republic of China had received effective military aid from the United States they might have defeated the Communists"

"7. The propaganda campaign against the Republic of China was vicious"

"15. It is difficult to secure information from an administration which is determined to keep the facts from the Congress and the people"

"16. The problem of Communist infiltration in our Government is still unresolved"

Military situation in the Far East. Washington, U. S. Govt. Print. Off., 1951. (PART 4, pp.3595\~)

[https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/001606736](https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/001606736)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

"The strategy of world conquest of the Soviet Union springs from the premise that it is not yet strong enough to risk war with the United States but must build up its domestic war potential and bring new strategic areas, resources, and peoples under its control before attacking us. In preparation for attack on the United States, it is, therefore, consolidating its hold on the 130,000,000 Europeans it has dominated since 1939; striving to seize France and Italy by action of its fifth columns; pressing on Greece, Turkey, and Iran; and—using the Chinese Communists as its instruments-attempting by war to conquer China. Communist conquest of China would lead rapidly to Communist victory in Indochina, which is the extension of south China; and Communist control of Indochina would almost inevitably be followed by Communist subjugation of Thailand and the Malay Peninsula."

U.S. Foreign Policy for a Post-War Recovery Program. : hearings before the United States House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Eightieth Congress, first session and Eightieth Congress, second session. (PART 2. pp.1897)

[https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/100667492](https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/100667492)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
