<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449913359.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh

How? Germany's blank check started the whole conflict and had wrecked half of northern France to the point scars can still be seen today. It makes sense they should pay for what they broke.

[Just look at this](https://brilliantmaps.com/zone-rouge/), there are places of France so badly damaged nobody is allowed to live there to this day, after over a century of attempted clean up.

&amp;gt;The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty

The hyper inflation was caused by the great depression, almost a decade after the treaty came into effect.

&amp;gt;caused the German economy to collapse.

[They still had one of the highest GDP/capitas or western Europe](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_regions_by_past_GDP_(PPP)_per_capita#Europe_1830%E2%80%931938_(Bairoch)).

&amp;gt;The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke.

The Germans should have been glad the allies had been so kind after all the millions of deaths they caused. Instead of dividing up Germany into nice manageable puppets and getting rid of east Germany all together they made them a fee independent state, only took away a tiny sliver of land (that had been polish majority anyway) and asked them to pay for the land they wrecked.

In my opinion Versailles was far to lenient. A unified Germany was far to powerful, think of how many lives could have been saved if they where split up into four or five more manageable chunks.

&amp;gt;and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies.

What? Germany wasn't over populated by any measure and their economy was the largest in mainland Europe when they started invading stuff.

And what do you mean bullied by the allies? Ask the Indians or any of the other colonies, they knew what being bullied was like. If Germany was being bullied by the allies they would never have gotten the chance to build an army. Saying Germany had any idea what being bullied was like is the peak of a first world problem.

&amp;gt;The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans.

The fact that Germany had enough resources to fight world war two showed they did have options. The resources that went into making so much as a single panzer could have fed a family for more than a year. The metal in the Tirpitz alone could have built enough factories to employ hundreds of thousands of people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
