<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449940546.0" user="Barnst" delta="True">
    <text>Under the circumstances, the Treaty of Versailles was not significantly worse than the [indemnity](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_indemnity) that Prussia imposed on France after the Franco-Prussian War, which was itself modeled after the indemnity imposed on Prussia by Napoleon in 1807.  So France and Germany had a history of trading harsh penalties for losing a war against the other.

And you know what?  The French dug in and paid their indemnity off in a couple of years, even though people worried it would cripple France for a generation.

So why did the Germany economy tank under Versailles?   Because the Germans horribly mismanaged their own economy.  They paid for the war entirely with debt, anticipating they would pay it off with the vast riches that would come with winning.  When that didn’t turn out so well, they started printing even more money to pay for reparations, rather than, you know, tapping into their relatively unscathed economic might.  When they eventually failed to make a payment, France responded by occupying the Ruhr.  The German government responded by calling a general strike and then print the even *more* cash to support the strikers.  So it was German choices about responding to the treaty rather than the treaty itself that was drove the hyperinflation of the ‘20s.

All of which was more or less under control by the end of the decade.  Then, *bang!*, Great Depression!   Which had some roots in the war but wasn’t caused by the treaty.   

Of course, Germany still had reparations due, and the western powers recognized paying them would be a problem.  So what did they do?  Suspended payments [in 1931](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hoover_Moratorium) and then cancelled them all together [in 1932.](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lausanne_Conference_of_1932)

So by the time Hitler is rising to power in 1933, Germany isn’t paying anything.  In the end, they only paid 1/8 of what they owed under the treaty.   

The Germans weren’t bitter about Versailles because it was so harsh, they were bitter they lost the war.  The war was all in France, so the average German experienced no particular immediate consequence during it.  They had beaten the Russians and almost beaten the western powers during their last great offensive.  And then it all falls apart within months and the whole country collapses.  

So who is to blame for that?   Well, certainly not themselves, everything had been going great!    It must have been those [damn politicians and their devious Jewish masters,](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stab-in-the-back_myth) and those evil vindictive foreign powers and their unreasonable treaty.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
