<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="654650438.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atrfie/cmv_the_no_one_is_illegal_response_is_unjustified/">
    <title>CMV: The "no one is illegal" response is unjustified virtue signaling and the term "undocumented immigrant" is misleading.</title>
    <original_poster>snogo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand that there are sensitivities that need to be taken when referring to people who built their entire lives around an illegal act, but nobody cares when we characterize other people as "illegal" due to other illegal acts.

If I illegally dump toxic waste in the local river, I may very well be referred to as an illegal dumper. If I illegally sell cigarettes in the park, I may very well be referred to as an illegal seller. If I illegally grow marijuana in a legal state where a distinction is necessary, I may very well be referred to as an illegal grower.

The only time referring to someone as an "illegal X" gets people riled up is when you are referring to people who immigrated illegally.

This leads to whitewashed terms like "undocumented immigrant" which sounds like there was no illegal act performed. The term "undocumented immigrant" sounds to the uninformed observer like someone who is just like any other legal immigrant but whose immigration was undocumented due to a mishap in paperwork.

It wasn't simply an "undocumented immigration", it was an unauthorized, or illegal immigration.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31508069652.0" user="palacesofparagraphs" delta="True">
    <text>The problem with 'illegal immigrant' as a term is primarily that it gets shortened just to 'illegal'. If someone says, "All the jobs are going to illegals," you know they don't mean illegal dumpers or illegal sellers, they mean illegal immigrants. While from a technical standpoint all of those examples should be equivalent, when it comes to how we actually use the language, they're not used the same way. 'Illegal immigrant' is the one that's morphing in a way that makes us flag it and say hey, be careful with that. And the reason we need to be careful with it is that throughout history, the first step to genocide/oppression/ethnic cleansing has been to declare certain people's existence illegal. It's not a far jump from "this person's existence here is illegal" to "it's okay to do horrible things to this person." We need to recognize that all people, regardless of how they got here, have human rights, and labelling people illegal is often the first step to infringing upon those rights.

The term 'undocumented' points to the fact that immigrating illegally is a crime because of the system in place, not because it's inherently wrong. Some things are inherently wrong: theft, murder, assault, abuse, rape. Other things are wrong only because we've decided we want society to work a different way: jaywalking, speeding, tax evasion, forgery. These things are crimes, and may be immoral in certain situations (some of them even in all situations) but they're different from the previous category because they don't infringe directly on the rights of others, but rather go against systems we've created and agreed upon as a society. Tax evasion is wrong because it's unfair to benefit from everyone else's contributions without contributing yourself, but if we had a different way of funding the government then tax evasion wouldn't even be a thing that existed to be wrong.

Similarly, entering the country illegally isn't inherently wrong, it's just a violation of the system we've put in place. Calling someone 'undocumented' emphasizes the fact that what they did is come into the country without telling the government. That places the emphasis on the system and the avoidance of it, which thereby invites us to examine that system. Do we think it's a good system? Do we believe the person's actions were immoral given that the system exists? Is there some other action we believe they should've taken instead? Even if the answer to all those questions is yes, it's still worth asking them. It's worth recognizing that the crime of an undocumented immigrant is an avoidance of the system, not an assault on another person's rights.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
