<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31699266899.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="True">
    <text>Let me introduce you to the world of video game remixes!

[Magical Sound Shower - Original](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yzsqx5uXmpA)

[Magical Sound Shower - Euro Mix](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o02DbIF9yQo&amp;amp;list=PL_FcypE3heh-U1NUqH2--WnRBDYWU6-FT&amp;amp;index=5&amp;amp;t=0s)

[Lavender Town - Original](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-sOadAaGiq4)

[Lavender Town - Solkrieg's Dream Eater Dub Step Remix](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CGVDLxa_3rI&amp;amp;list=PL_FcypE3heh-U1NUqH2--WnRBDYWU6-FT&amp;amp;index=5)

[Toejam Jammin - Original](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=301acFz0a_A)

[Toejam Jammin - OC Remix](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F-DKr3HBnwU&amp;amp;list=PL_FcypE3heh-U1NUqH2--WnRBDYWU6-FT&amp;amp;index=20)

[Basilisk Run - original](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OZLXcCe7GgA)

[Basilisk Run - Ninja Gaiden Arrangement](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OoZoqEdvt28&amp;amp;list=PL_FcypE3heh-U1NUqH2--WnRBDYWU6-FT&amp;amp;index=24)

So, obviously, these remixes offer better sound quality since they are not limited by the old hardware of retro games, but I think there's more to it than that. Many of these remixes bring a new style to the song that people, like myself, may enjoy more (especially the Latin feel to Basilisk run). 

I would also like to bring up the musical concept of theme and variation. "Remixing" isn't really a new concept. Classical music would often introduce a melody and then play several variants of it throughout the piece. This is effectively a remix. Modern pieces tend to be much shorter than classical ones, but when somebody does a remix, haven't they really just executed a variation on a theme? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
