<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31699027215.0" user="arkonum" delta="True">
    <text>I would argue that in many cases, the point of a remix is not to be better but to be recreated to appeal to a different/ wider audience. 

For example, many remixes are done so as rap remixes or techno/ dance remixes. The intention isn’t for people to go “hey this one is way better than the original, I am going to listen to this version instead”, but the intention is for that good song and tune to be reconditioned for a different environment such as a night club, as a more appropriate basis for dance routines, or simply to attract people to the song who didn’t like the original style. I would even argue that by doing so it can really only ever be a good thing as the original still exists in its entirety, and is fully accessible to anyone who wants to only listen to the original. By the remix existing and appealing to a wider audience, it only ever broadens the appeal of the song and inherently makes it better in the process. 

TLDR; remixes aren’t designed to be better, they are designed to create a situation where the song can appeal to a wider audience or environment. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
