<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945499264.0" user="Eltotsira" delta="True">
    <text>So, I have some thoughts that I'm just gonna put out there. I actually think you're right, in a sense, tbh. 

But, what I think is important about the way History tends to be taught currently is that it contextualizes a lot of things that people learn in later high school and college, and it sort of creates a shared framework for everyone to at least have a minimum level of understanding, if that makes sense. Like, providing a rough, chronological timeline with basically memorizing dates, and briefly talking about how the events relate to each other creates a sort of metaphorical framework on a metaphorical canvas, for people to fill in at their own pace l, whether it be through higher education, or independent research, social and cultural events, etc. That said, I do agree that it's not the best at teaching kids to critically think, but I'm not sure (not a teacher or admin) that that's the point?

As for literature, I think it's something similar. I think it's more about showing kids what well constructed syntax looks like in a fun way, as well as fostering creativity, and shaping peoples writing and reading skills. I dont think the opinion that they dont exactly foster critical thinking is wrong, tbh, but again, i don't necessarily think that's the point. Kindergarten through HS is designed to make successful people. It's designed to give people the tools they'll need to succeed in life. I'd argue that most math and science teaches critical thinking, as well as sports, and foreign languages, and even some history and English classes. I dont think critical thinking is the goal of any specific class unless its stated as such. I think that's what exercises are for. The classes themselves should be more focused on making sure that everyone at least has an option to access the tools for success. 

And seeing as how most developed countries have literacy rates of around at least 90%, and most people know about past major world events and probably also the ones that are significant to their own country, I'd say that the purpose is being served. Does that make sense? 

TL;DR- I agree with you, but I dont know if that's actually the point. I also dont know if it's not, but those are just my thoughts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
