<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945596852.0" user="HoneyBadger9527" delta="True">
    <text>The problem is with*how*  history and literature are being taught and how it is being assessed, not with the content. I will start by saying that there is a lot wrong with the educational system. I am finishing up my masters in social studies education (I’ll be mainly focusing on history in my argument since that is my background) and have some experience teaching both middle and high school history classes. I will be the first to agree with some of your points; history has a horrible reputation (deservedly so in some cases) for its focus on memorization and there a TON of terrible teachers that do not focus on critical thinking. However, your and my issue with education is solely with how it is being taught, not with what is being taught (i.e. pedagogy). I do want to say that my views of education might be considered “radical” from mainstream educators, however, I believe that mainstream education is not reaching many of our students, especially our students of color. For example, MN (the state I live and plan on teaching in) has the highest academic achievement gap between white students and students of color. While my views are probably not mainstream, there are many educators who will agree with me and the points I make. Anyway, back to your argument. 

Your argument is that because of the focus on memorization, history and literature offer little or educational benefit and little opportunity to develop critical thinking. The focus on memorization isn’t unique to history or literature; in math you need to memorize basic multiplication and equations, in science you need to memorize basic principals. However, history often gets assessed through multiple choice questions where you need to memorize facts, dates, events, and people. Pablo Freire describes this as the “banking” model of education where students are “containers” that educators “deposit” information into, only to have students regurgitate that information verbatim on tests. This is not a good pedagogy. It forces students to be passive in their learning and encourages memorization of facts instead of critical analysis. Unfortunately, high level history classes, especially AP Histories, favor this model because they are teaching for the test.

Freire offers another approach to teaching. He argues that a teacher should instead collectivize learning and structure the classroom as a learning community. In this scenario, the students are made the center of the classroom and are actively shaping and guiding their learning while the teacher de-centers themselves form the center of the classroom, serving more as a guide that provides structure and support for the class instead of being that “all knowing individual” that is there to dispense knowledge into students. In this classroom, students are active participants in creating knowledge and have a say in their own learning (I am summarizing the points of Freire’s book *Pedagogy of the Oppressed* so I somewhat simplifying his view). 

This model requires the use of inquiry to work; i.e. students are given a problem or issue and must use their skills to find answers and solutions. History is a great space to do inquiry based research and projects. A simple question like “Why was the the I-94 highway in Minneapolis built where it was?” or “Why is there a group called Black Lives Matter?” provide opportunity to learn about the past and make modern connections to the future. 

Furthermore, history need to focus on teaching skills, not content. I would argue that learning anything that can be googled is a waste of time in the classroom. History should focus on teaching reading, writing, and speaking skills. To start, since the academic gap between white students and students of color is with reading and writing and speaking, that should be a point of emphasis in class. Next, these skills are required to do well in a history class (reading primary sources, writing about those sources, talking about those sources), so students need these skills just to do well in the class. Lastly, these skills translate over to other subjects as every academic subject, most jobs and careers, and everyday life will require some reading, writing, and speaking.

Students should then be assessed on these skills over time. Their reading, writing, and speaking skills should be monitored over the year to see how they have improved and note areas of strength and areas that need growth. Multiple choice tests do not adequately assess these skills. Instead, assessments must be more open and accessible. Things like Socratic seminars can be used to assess speaking and Document based essays (students are given 5-10 primary sources and must create a short paper with a thesis based on the documents) for reading and writing, etc. Additionally, project based assessments allow for critical analysis to develop and be assessed as well.

The content we use to teach these skills is also equally important. It is hard to develop the skill critical analysis if the content you look at isn’t critical of history. Content cannot focus on the whitewashed and Eurocentric version of history that is often taught. We must bring in counter-narratives and opposing viewpoints to critically examine history. For example, what did African-American, Latinx, and Native American people think about the Declaration of Independence. How did the Great Depression impact already marginalized groups? We need to incorporate stories or resistance and triumph of people of color and those who have been historically disenfranchised into our content. The MN Social Studies State Standards are broad enough that incorporating these stories into the classroom is fairly easy.

To summarize; History (and all of social studies) has as much educational value as STEM subjects when taught using good pedagogy (I would argue memorization is not good pedagogy).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
