<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944081792.0" user="THE_RMB" delta="True">
    <text>I know a bit about history and next to nothing about literature so I'll just talk about history. If you're saying that learning about historical facts, which is mostly memorization, doesn't do much to advance a student's critical thinking then sure. But understanding one's historical context offers plenty of educational value. Understanding how things played out in the past teaches a lot about how and why things are the way they are in the present. You seem to only value critical thinking but was that ever the purpose of high school history classes? I don't think so. There isn't much critical thinking involved in learning basic facts like the alphabet, or grammar, or the multiplication table right? And that's fine. Likewise I think history - at least at the highschool level - can be seen similarly as a survey of the necessary base set of historical facts to learn that makes one culturally literate.

If you want to become a historian then yes there's lots of critical analysis of texts and arguments for what the actual historical facts are but people can devote their entire lives to analyzing a single event. To think there's enough time in high school to go through that exercise that while also building a baseline of knowledge of historical facts is unrealistic. I wouldn't be against adding a semester on "how we decide on historical facts" outlining the methods that academic historians use but I also understand that they have a very limited amount of time to cover a whole lot of ground.

Again, I'm not as well versed in literature but I imagine the situations are similar with lots of ground to cover and not very much time to cover the more advanced and more critical thinking heavy aspects of literature.

I think the solution that would address the core of the very warranted concerns that you raised is to add a mandatory philosophy class in high schools. Every student should at the very least learn formal logic and the classical arguments. I don't think the solution is to cast aspersions on history classes or literature classes because they don't meet an ideal that is supposed to be addressed by a philosophy class.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
