<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946336864.0" user="Ixolich" delta="True">
    <text>I would argue that they do the same job that high school STEM classes do, as well as they do it. I think it's just that, as you said, your career is in STEM so you didn't get the chance to see how further education builds on the high school classes.

What is the point of a high school chemistry class? To give everyone a base level understanding about how the stuff that makes up our world works, and lay the groundwork for those students who want to go on further. Is there "value" in all students learning how to work through stoichiometry problems? Probably not, as 99% of people will never use it again, but it's part of the base knowledge for people who WILL go on in the field. And, if nothing else, it adds some level of understanding about why chemistry is the way it is.

What's the point of a high school history class? Same deal, only more people will be directly affected by what they learn. Establish a baseline of knowledge, set up the building blocks for people who want to delve deeper, and give an understanding of why history is the way it is.

It's that last part that I want to focus on. Why is history the way it is? Well, because of the history that came before it. In your OP, you said 

&amp;gt; I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understanding society, culture, and history that still affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s.

Name a piece of history covered in high school that hasn't seen its effects propagate to the modern day. I'll wait.

It's those details that make history understandable. Imagine trying to teach programming without bothering to teach about the difference between ints and doubles or how IF AND and OR work, instead just jumping directly into functions. Ignore the rest, that's just details, you can learn more about them in college if you want. It wouldn't work. And history is no different.

The Battle of Gettysburg was July 1-3 1863. Why then? How does it fit in to the larger narrative? It's no coincidence that the largest Confederate push northward happened the spring and summer after Lincoln signed the Emancipation Proclamation (January 1 1863). Suddenly it was explicitly a nation opposed to slavery fighting rebels who approved of slavery - the Confederacy suddenly saw their support from England trickle and stop. They were running out of options, couldn't keep up with Union manufacturing, and needed to push hard to win. When it happened is an important part of the narrative.

The politics of the early 1800s aren't important today? Don't make me laugh. We're literally having the same arguments today that the Federalists and Anti-Federalists were having in the late 1790s to early 1800s. Should we have a big government or a small government? What is and isn't the government allowed to do and pay for - and even if they're allowed to, do we want them to? The exact issues were different, sure, but the argument over a national bank in the 1790s is fundamentally the same as our current argument over national healthcare. What were the arguments made back then? How valid were they? How valid are they today? 

We need to know where we came from. Those who do not study history are doomed to repeat it, and all that jazz. And there's really no way to even start to look at how we got to where we are without some level of digging through the weeds and the details of history. Otherwise we end up in a world where fully half of Americans think the Civil War wasn't mainly about slavery.

It may be possible to go with a more generalized view of history in some areas, but there are a lot where the details are important for everyone to know. For example Reconstruction shouldn't be glossed over, as many of the policies set in place during that era led directly to Jim Crow laws and the current systemic racial inequalities we see today. Sure, we *could* just say "And then we helped the South rebuild after the civil war, but it wasn't really equal for everyone"..... But does that really teach anything? In order for it to have value, the details are necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
