<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="78227727.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1akowf/i_think_that_black_people_in_america_are_often_a/">
    <title>I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tomjoad76</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: I say black, not African-American. Many black people possibly have a longer history of ancestry in the U.S. than I do, and I never ask to be called a European-American.

I know this sounds terribly racist, and I apologize for offending people because I really do understand that people are often going to meet what expectations you set for them and not much more.

I am an open-minded and liberal white Southerner who has grown up with little exposure to black culture. However, what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior. This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

Hip-hop, the predominant choice of music for many black Americans, often promotes organized crime, prostitution, gun use, drug use, etc.

Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

Granted I do not know many black people, but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all). I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college. Unemployment rates are much higher among blacks than any other race. Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). There is a large black population on my campus, and anytime I have a class with a group of black students, it seems like those students will be very disrespectful to the professor or other students, e.g. interrupting class, coming in late, listening to music so loud on their headphones that everybody in the room can hear it. It's such an unfailing stereotype for me that I've come to dread anytime I see a large group of black students in my classes.

I know there are bad apples and good apples in every orchard. I feel bad because I often have these kinds of thoughts, and I am honestly no quicker to judge a black person I meet as a bad person than any other race. It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26662856802.0" user="NewQuisitor" delta="True">
    <text>I'm going to talk about two people I know, KC and Marv.

For whatever reason, there are lots of Nigerians at my school. They're the most sexist bunch of dudes I have ever met (used to have a Nigerian roommate, and he and his friends were always making horribly sexist statements) and they basically did the stereotypical stuff you were talking about up there. I also saw him hold a knife to an Asian kid's throat for "disrespecting" him and had to talk him out of beating the kid up multiple times. KC's entire culture seemed to be built on "flashiness", on conspicuous consumption, violence, and sexism.

BUT one of my best friends here, Marv, is black, and he isn't like that at all. Two of his roommates are also Nigerian, and they bug the hell out of him, too. So... I guess what I'm getting at is that race does not equal culture. I'm not particularly fond of the Nigerian culture I saw, but that doesn't mean that *all* Nigerians or *all* black folks are part of that culture. For all I know, the Nigerians I have met could all be Igbo, or Yoruba, and that's just what's sticking out in my brain (confirmation bias).

Marvin likes cars, and so does KC. However, while KC puts shiny things on his car and lets it fall to pieces (my parents will get me another one, so it's a'ight), Marvin enjoys working underneath the car-- he changes his own oil and brakes, and his old car was pretty heavily customized under the hood, though you couldn't tell from the outside. KC blasts loud rap music everywhere he goes. Marv likes classical and blues. KC parties almost every night and aggressively hits on girls. Marv prefers to study or go to a movie and the only reason he isn't in a long-term relationship is because he's so shy and quiet.

What I'm getting at is that culture doesn't account for individual preference (some people are just douchebags) and that you're only seeing partial aspects of a culture. Motley Crue, one of my favorite bands, was pretty heavily into sex and drugs too... but they have attained the respectability of age. AC/DC had a lot of songs about fighting and killing, but because they've been around so long, they have become more mainstream and less perceived as in-your-face and aggressive. Also note that normal, quiet, nice people tend to stick out in your brain less than assholes because either A) you just didn't notice them, or B) they didn't make an impression in your brain.

Now, I do think that there are parts of what you're calling "black culture" (although I would, conversely, call it "poverty culture") that *are* extremely harmful to the community as a whole. However, as a fellow southerner, I have seen the effect of meth on white communities and the effect of smuggling corridors on the border. **Black communities are not the only ones that have problems; all poor communities are suffering right now.** The guy out there listening to rap in a beat-up Caprice and shooting a dude in a tenement over crack isn't that different than the guy listening to Lamb of God in his beat-up F-150 and shooting up the trailer over meth.

If you can't get a job because you're black and uneducated, or you can't get a job because you're white and uneducated, what difference does it make? If your culture is built on violence, white or black (I'm looking at you, so-called 'outlaws' and 'proud rebels'), how does the end outcome differ? It's still an unsustainable model.

Finally, I think that certain political groups have historically utilized white-versus-black (or, where I'm from, white-vs-black-vs-Indian-vs-Hispanic) to create a wedge between **haves** and **have-nots** to sustain their own power structure. Our system, a democracy, means that there is a vote for every person, rich or poor. Well, there are a lot more poor folk out there than rich, so to be able to sustain their policies, certain people have found it politically expedient to exploit racial tension to create a divide in the poorest element of society to prevent it creating a powerful voting block. If you don't believe me, look at the history of Texas. Johnson was from Texas, and Texas was solidly Democratic until Johnson's Civil Rights act went through. Texas has been Republican ever since. Oklahoma, similarly, was once a progressive state. Race was used to drive a wedge into that voting block and break it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
