<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="795564867.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d5nps3/cmv_teenage_climate_change_protestations_are/">
    <title>CMV : Teenage Climate Change Protestations are Useless</title>
    <original_poster>AsteroidSnowsuit</original_poster>
    <original_post>So around the world, there are a lot of protestations by teenagers that want to fight climate change. 

While this is a good cause I believe in (and that I try to fight for), is it really that useful ? You get thousand of students to block major roads in big city, pissing off a lot of people on the way. You can scream all you want at the leaders, but the real power to make a change is with your vote. 

Instead of spending hours outside, skipping school for no real good reason (hell, some students lie saying that they go to the protest, but they just go home instead), pissing off a lot of people on the way, why don't all of these students organize to pick up trash around their school, convince their parents to vote for people who are more green.

If every student that came to these manifestations spent all this time trying to make a change locally, the impact would have been bigger. When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

The people who deny climate change won't tell themselves that climate change is real, they will only opposite strongly to the whole thing (because of the inconvenience caused by the protests).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

TL;DR : I don't get why people protest when there are way easier ways to make a change.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32690380777.0" user="iamasecretthrowaway" delta="True">
    <text>So only people that are old enough to vote are allowed to have an opinion and care about a cause?

&amp;gt;When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

Maybe they're concerned that, by the time they grow up, the world will be in a worse position than it could have otherwise been.

Your argument is really that protests are useless, rather than teenaged protests.  But are they really?  Is there no cause that was brought to your attention because of a protest?  Is there no one in your life whose first exposure to an issue might have been a protest?  

Do protests in and of themselves change anything?  No, probably not.  But they might get everyone who passes by to think about an issue that they maybe wouldn't have considered that day.  Protests make causes visible.  And that can be incredibly powerful.  It's easy to disregard an abstract concept.  It's a lot harder to ignore when you're face to face with people who are affected by it.  When you can literally *see* it in your community.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
