<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32702477630.0" user="letstrythisagain30" delta="True">
    <text>I think the better view is, capitalism, ***as it exists now*** has no place in the world.

Capitalism in the world has changed a lot though since it first started to be used. Regulations and social programs are proof that capitalism has some failings. Its why anti-trust laws were created after companies destroyed all competition and gouged customers. Its why labor laws were created after employees were nothing but wage slaves and kids were forced to work in horrible conditions. Its why environmental laws were created when companies found it cheaper to pollute and poison an unsuspecting populace because it was cheaper than proper disposal. Its why social welfare was created that protects those that were fired to increase profits and protect against another great depression.

Today, the wage gap is growing. Young people are being priced out of owning homes. Climate change is approaching its point of no return. Globalization making the world smaller changed the whole landscape for manufacturing employment. All of these things mean that we can't continue on the same path and things must change like they always do.

That doesn't mean blowing up capitalism though. For all the talks about actual socialism and communism, not the stupid bullshit people claim it is, being a better system by their proponents, I have yet to hear a convincing argument about how it would make current problems better or how they can overcome the potential issues that come with abandoning our economic system when we can make changes to address its failings like we always have.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
