<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99329272.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4yyg/i_believe_the_rich_should_be_more_heavily_taxed/">
    <title>I believe the rich should be more heavily taxed, and that wealth redistribution may be necessary, CMV</title>
    <original_poster>JonWood007</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay, I've come to this conclusion rather recently, looking at how things in this country have been working, and while redistribution is not my first choice, I am beginning to feel it is a last resort.

So a little bit of background on my views. When I was younger (teen years), I used to be a republican believe it or not. I used to think that social programs were bad, wealth redistribution was unfair and punished the successful while rewarding the unsuccessful. 

However, in college, my views changed. I began to realize the system was stacked against some people, that the rich are gatekeepers when it comes to wages and all, and that it's not necessarily peoples' fault for being poor. I realized capitalism had some very serious flaws, and that without government intervention peoples' needs don't get taken care of. Wages are low, hours are long, people can't pay for their needs, people are exploited. I then still believed redistribution was immoral, but believed that government should at times regulate the economy to ensure fair treatment of workers. We should have minimum wage, I was behind Obamacare, etc.

However, I'm beginning to change my mind to favor wealth redistribution. It's not because I like it in principle, but I am beginning to feel it's the only way to take care of peoples needs. You see, if you regulate business by making them pay for good wages, they'll just hire fewer people. If you try to make them pay for health insurance, they'll cut peoples' hours and people will once again suffer. While I like Obama's policies, I am beginning to see them as ineffective because he's relying on these free market solutions through regulation. I am beginning to think wealth should be redistributed to the poor to supplement their poor wages if we can't ensure good wages AND good employment, and we should have a single payer healthcare system like Europe does if a law like Obamacare actually harms the people its supposed to benefit. In short, if the rich are going to retaliate against plans to make sure the wealth actually trickles down by further harming the people the law is supposed to benefit, the rich should instead be taxed along the lines of pre Reagan tax rates and that wealth should benefit those.

As for benefits:

1) In a more extreme form, it gets rid of the labor surplus we have. In the past, the problem with needing people to work hard is that if they do not, society would not have enough to take care of itself. However, now the problem is that we have excess, it's just very poorly distributed, and has been getting worse since lowering the tax rates during Reagan's presidency. This also leads to higher wages among those who want to work, since companies will need to give more incentive. It also removes people who don't want to work from the labor pool, ensuring those who remain are higher quality and increase productivity. 

2) Raising taxes should fix the deficit, yada yada. Heck, the reason we have a deficit is because Reagan lowered the tax rates to unsustainable levels.

3) it should actually be a tide that raises all boats. It should do what trickle down is supposed to do. If more people have more money, they can spend more, giving the companies even bigger profits.

I know I'm kind of hazy as far as the specifics go for the kinds of plans I'm actually for. This has been a decision I've only reached in the last few weeks, and I'm still trying to work out the downsides of my views, which is why I'm here. I have toyed with basic income, but think that would be too expensive and unsustainable, so that may have problems. Negative income tax is another solution. Or maybe just expansions of current programs, both in benefits themselves, and the scope of who they affect (a major problem is that the second you get over the poverty line you suddenly have to work for everything....rather it should be gradually toned down, where only those who make above average income pay more than they benefit). There should also maybe some benefits/tax breaks for employers that actually do provide such things to employees. After all, since I'm inciting a failure in the free market system as grounds for such an extreme solution, I also think that if employers do decide to provide such things via the free market system, they should get a break.

Again, I know this is disorganized, I have ideas flying around in my head. I just know before we had this current paradigm of gutting social programs and lowering taxes on the rich, the lower and middle classes were much better off than they were now financially.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26872992969.0" user="redox000" delta="True">
    <text>The problem with raising taxes on the rich is that they'll just take their money somewhere else. If California tries to raise their taxes, the rich will move to Nevada or Texas. If the US tries to raise taxes, the rich will go to another country with lower taxes. Corporations and the rich also have access to many loopholes like carried interest or hiding money in overseas accounts.

The biggest hurdle to taxing the rich is that the rich and corporations by definition have lots of money and can buy their way to lower taxes by paying off politicians, running endless commercials, and creating a 24/7 news network to broadcast their agenda.

tl;dr: Raising taxes on the rich sounds great in theory but doesn't work well in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
