<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34234783636.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="True">
    <text>Creation in the ex nihilo sense is impossible, the only interesting conceptions of God are those that aren't anthropomorphized hypostatizations of conflated concepts.

God also can't want things, otherwise God is limited and not God insofar as God is supposed to be perfect or complete in any sense which theological accounts presuppose or explicitly assert. Wanting is tied to lacking. 

It seems like you're dealing with some exoteric watered down Christianity that's been oversimplified and reduced into absurdities. Complete waste of time. Some Christians understood what I said, others did not. You want to focus on the ones who understood, because they're the ones articulate enough to explain their positions reasonably as opposed to reciting scripture at you and/or just appealing to faith or revelation or whatever. 

I am not a Christian but I think if you want to deal with the matters of freedom and God, you shouldn't be concerned with summations of material that are mostly aimed at the unphilosophical general public and need to look into Aquinas, Augustine, or Kant - or comparable philosophers or secondary works on these sorts of philosophers. And I say that not as an Aquinian, Augustinian, or Kantian either - their work on these matters is valuable however even if they aren't the "end of the story" so to speak. 

Right now you're likely just dealing with several degrees of seperation from the works that inspired these kinds of watered down summaries, and you won't get anywhere in understanding why people relate freedom to God or why they think there is free will by doing that.

I am not so much aiming to change your title view here, but just saying you are looking completely in the wrong places if you want to understand "Christian perspective" or "God" or "free will" or their relation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
