<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34235499698.0" user="SFnomel" delta="True">
    <text>This biggest problem with this logic is that it presupposes a lot of thing about who God is and what his plans are. It's like a kid asking a parent why they don't just quit their job if they're unhappy. The logic seems flawless but it's a nuanced and complex situation that requires a much deeper understanding of desire, money, capitalism, love, taxes, life in general, etc. So while it's a fair point to ask "why wouldn't God just do ___?" you have to at least acknowledge that it's coming from a place of extremely little knowledge of an infinitely complex issue. 

Secondly, if all God wanted were entities to worship him endlessly and without resistance, he would have never needed to create humans, or the universe even. Angels fill the role much better than humans ever could. Granted they don't fit the role perfectly as they did have a chance to disobey, but they were given one chance instead of endless chances like humans.

So we can assume that humans were created with a different purpose in mind than being programmed robots that sing his praises day in and day out. Most theologically savy people would tell you he created us to love him and love others. Love by definition is a choice, so at the very root of the why we were created revolves around choosing to love or hate. Having a choice creates a true relationship, one that actually means something and isn't a Furby repeating how much it loves you. 

Lastly, determinism is a big part of certain Christian theologies. Predestination is the term that's used more frequently. This creates a whole new argument about whether it's fair or just for God to determine your life choices for you, but God and determinism don't conflict as much as a lot of people assume.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
