<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34310489631.0" user="jackstrad2020" delta="False">
    <text>The problem here is the Australian government never looked out for the countries best interests and put a dollar in front of the Australian people. 
We allowed all these cheaply made or not even cheaply made but un australian made items into our country to be sold cheaply undercutting the local markets. 

I’ve seen it in many other countries, for example Asian market protect their car sales and manufacturing by hitting non locally made cars with super tax. Keeps the local factories pumping gout cars. Locals can afford them and so on. 

Australians were betrayed by those who were trusted to keep them from harm all for a quick buck. 

Imagine how many more fords, holdens and Toyota’s would have been locally made and sold if they put a premium on Honda, bmw and Audi’s and the like? 

Everywhere we look we can see it. 

I get it that it’s all relative, pay the workers more and charge more for products/services. That’s fine. But when we paying the workers less and still charge an arm and a leg for things, the whole system falls out of whack. And that difference, the lost monies if you will. Has to be going somewhere. Where is it all going ??</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
