<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34302441865.0" user="1917fuckordie" delta="False">
    <text>Labor has always been cheaper in Asia and other developing countries, wages in places like Australia or the US has always been higher.

What made outsourcing possible were things like NAFTA and other trade deals that make offshore production cheaper and flood our markets with cheap consumer goods that our local manufacturing can't compete with.

So minimum wage isn't that much of a factor. "Globalisation" can mean a lot of things but if you mean free trade arrangements and developing countries trying to attract manufacturing then yes that's part of the problem.

What does need to be kept in mind though is that "typical manufacturing jobs" from the post war era (1940s-1970s) wasn't typical at all. The long consistent growth of the economy created incredibly good jobs for lots of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34304510976.0" user="thetasigma4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What made outsourcing possible were things like NAFTA and other trade deals that make offshore production cheaper and flood our markets with cheap consumer goods that our local manufacturing can't compete with.

There's definitely more to it than just the law. Logistics technologies have played a huge part in enabling this expansion such as containerisation which allowed for a huge increase in imports and exports and reduced losses. The issue isn't just neoliberal deregulation but the general structure of the economy that favours profit over actual QoL improvements or robust supply chains.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
