<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34302433853.0" user="stewshi" delta="False">
    <text>I think the minimum wage had less to do with it and more to do with people from the West expect more for their labor. If a person offered me the same wages as a Chinese laborer 1 I wouldn't be able to afford to live in the US so my time would be better spent doing something else. 2 I value my labor more than that. The minimum wage didn't push wages up. Wages were already going up because people were demanding more for their labor.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
