<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34302681075.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.

So this is very widely established fact.  However, it wasn't a result of increasing minimum wages, it was the result of investment in overseas manufacturing.  Shit just cost proportionally more in the 1950s when everything was made in the West.

[Here's a catalog](http://www.thepeoplehistory.com/50selectrical.html)
of various home appliances.  There's  which according to this [inflation calculator](https://www.in2013dollars.com/us/inflation/1951?amount=20) would be about $200 today.  Nowadays, you can get a toaster from Walmart for under $20.

Apples to apples comparisons are harder to come by, but Kitchenaid stand mixers are still manufactured in the US.  The premium [1959s model](https://www.ebay.com/itm/311568295718) would set you back about 135, whib translates to about $1100 in 2020 currency.  You can get a 2020 classic model for $250, or an artisan model for $400.   This cost savings can be attributed to better manufacturing processes and automation, as well as greater competition among retailers.  Let me emphasize that these are *still made* in the USA, and likely made by people with higher wages.

  Meanwjilez you can get a Hamilton Beach stand mixer, (likely of Chinese origin,) for $90, which is *less* than the cost of a Kitchenaid un 1959. 

Heres the thing.  Kitchenaids are one of the few Made In USA goods that have survived.  Most other small kitchen appliances have been completely lost to overseas manufacturing, because it's simply cheaper and easier to buy a $20 toaster and replace it every 5 years than it is to buy a $100 toaster that will last you 10 to 15.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
