<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1010113416.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gpe8i0/cmvvillains_in_pop_culture_from_comic_books_box/">
    <title>CMV:Villains in pop culture from comic books box TV shows movies are all the good guys.</title>
    <original_poster>ComfortableBrick3</original_poster>
    <original_post>When it comes to pop-culture in movies I see the fact that people always view the villains to be bad guys and I just don’t understand why because everything they’re doing is right and the heroes are always mostly wrong. They talk about how they wanna rule The entire world and take over the universe and if you think about it are we humans in real life trying to do the same thing and stuff like destroying humanity is actually a good thing human race is pretty much a fucked up species we deserve and they don’t believe in love compassion and friendship and I’ll a lot of that is just bullshit meaningless concepts, power in the end is what’s important  and a whole bunch of other crimes it’s just made up stuff that we may have considered to be wrong.If There is a way to convince me if you guys can give me a better argument why I’m wrong.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34321854825.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34324413577.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Shlomo_Maistre – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Shlomo_Maistre&amp;amp;message=Shlomo_Maistre+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/gpe8i0/-/frmcgo9/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
