<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1010113416.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gpe8i0/cmvvillains_in_pop_culture_from_comic_books_box/">
    <title>CMV:Villains in pop culture from comic books box TV shows movies are all the good guys.</title>
    <original_poster>ComfortableBrick3</original_poster>
    <original_post>When it comes to pop-culture in movies I see the fact that people always view the villains to be bad guys and I just don’t understand why because everything they’re doing is right and the heroes are always mostly wrong. They talk about how they wanna rule The entire world and take over the universe and if you think about it are we humans in real life trying to do the same thing and stuff like destroying humanity is actually a good thing human race is pretty much a fucked up species we deserve and they don’t believe in love compassion and friendship and I’ll a lot of that is just bullshit meaningless concepts, power in the end is what’s important  and a whole bunch of other crimes it’s just made up stuff that we may have considered to be wrong.If There is a way to convince me if you guys can give me a better argument why I’m wrong.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34320843669.0" user="syd-malicious" delta="False">
    <text>You're gonna have to be way more specific if anyone here is gonna tackle this. Are you saying:

Humanity is fucked up and deserves to be destroyed. Protagonists are generally trying to save humanity, while villains are generally trying to destroy it. Therefore the villains are the good guys?

Or are you saying:

Villains display the same characteristics as ordinary humans. Therefore we should empathize with them more?

Or are you saying:

Darwin was right. Villains are smart for realizing that only the strong survive, whereas protagonists are dumb for believing in other more 'virtuous' motivations. Therefore villains are the more worthy or surviving?

Or something else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34321527515.0" user="ComfortableBrick3" delta="False">
    <text> Number one about humanity we are kind a messed up we do a lot of things that I think we deserve to be destroy those people wish we would be destroyed in real life given what we do to the planet 
 Number two well yes I wanna rule the world and take over the universe really what is the wrong about that there's nothing illegal about that better off because it would stop all the wars progress at a better pace and we also trying to take over the universe or try to colonize  space my goals as most villains 
Finally villains  are right it is the strong that survive but heroes try to make it to the week somehow fight against a strong and be better than them that's the wrong idea and in real life usually that doesn't work. So love compassion and friendship is all bullshit meaningless concepts so Villians all right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34324509392.0" user="Man_of_Average" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, punctuation would help.

Second of all, I think they meant specific examples. Such as a certain super hero or a certain movie/comic/story. You're being too general to really argue against.

Third of all, just because the good guys make mistakes or slip up doesn't mean they are now the bad guys. And just because the bad guys may recognize a real problem or went through a real struggle doesn't justify the evil they go on to do. Thanos isn't a hero for trying to kill half of all life just because he recognized that overconsumption is a real problem. Tony Stark isn't a bad guy just because in an honest effort to create a defense system for Earth he accidently created a villain in Ultron. I feel like you're neglecting a lot of nuance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34325088317.0" user="ComfortableBrick3" delta="False">
    <text>Villians in general most of them are like i wanna take over universe and world we in real are trying to do same thing but it take a really long time.also what is wrong with Villians taking over the world it would be better since all humans do is fight against each other.
Fantasy Villians usually don't believe in love and only care about power that is true and love compassion friendship themes I see in hero journey is just bullshit concepts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
