<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1026594069.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/cmv_america_should_not_be_able_to_claim_that_it/">
    <title>CMV: America should not be able to claim that it has abolished slavery</title>
    <original_poster>rrea436</original_poster>
    <original_post>The abolishion of slavery is normally claimed modernly to be through two separate documents. 

[Emancipation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emancipation_Proclamation) and the [13th amendment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution#Text)

However I don't think that these documents provide a substancial enough basis to claim that slavery is abolished within the USA.

The Emancipation Proclamation, was in effect largely symbolic, It is estimated that it freed 2% slaves in the USA when it was made, and indeed it helped many more over the coming years. The country being at civil war made it unenforceable and it did not apply to the 500,000 slaves within Union territory. I feel that the Emancipation Proclamation was more important in building to the 13th rather than holding any real abolishment itself.

the 13th amendment is the real crux of the issue. I'll post it here directly.

Section 1.

Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, **except  as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly  convicted,** shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to  their jurisdiction.

Section 2.

Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation.

Personally section 2 is fine the problem is in section 1 that I have in bold

I do not think slavery is abolished because it is explicitly legal for certain persons. and many of the earliest prisons where in fact just plantations, [1.](https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations) [2.](https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/)  Not going to Lie thing like the Black laws, the Jim crow era and the war on drugs, have all in my opinion targeted this enslavement at black people in the USA. I probably would not have posted this without the current BLM protests, however I have held these opinions for years. when people (I) say systemic racism this is what they (I) mean.

The 13th Amendment does not stop slavery, it just changes who slaves are. That's not abolishment, no where near it, and it's no where near good enough.

Believe it or not [There has been progress](https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-08-26/slave-trade-roots-us-private-prisons) on removing the prison system from private ownership, but even then slaves owned by the state doesn't inspire me with confidence that America is anywhere near the end.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34429855565.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>Who and where are the current slaves and\or laborers in the US?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34429900599.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>1. [In depth study of areas such as California](https://confluence.gallatin.nyu.edu/context/interdisciplinary-seminar/prison-labor-in-the-united-states) (fire camps)
2. [Modern day plantation farm](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mississippi_State_Penitentiary) Mississippi
3. [Texas is th largest by numbers](https://truthout.org/articles/unpaid-labor-in-texas-prisons-is-modern-day-slavery/) 

All slaves in the USA are in prisons. these are just a few examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34429941925.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp; is legal under the 13th amendment. Those people have gone through due process and have been convicted of a crime. 

Regardless, they still do have several more rights than actual slaves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34429957428.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>my argument is that the 13th amendment is flawed in that is can not claim to make slavery illegal if it simply changes the rules of enslavement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430014467.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>The amendment is not claiming anything, it is setting the frame work on what rights individuals have in the US. 

Are you not aware that other rights can be bypassed **after due process** in which the amendment clearly states.

You have the right to own firearms in the US, but after due process and you are a felon you can no longer have that right.

Same with searches and seizures... if you are a felon your PO can search you at their discretion.

Come on guy...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430077547.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>you see my opinion is now that Americans cannot claim to have the right to own a firearm.

And Americans cannot claim to have the right to be protected from search and seizures.

How many of your rights do I have to rethink here.

I think that i dont give you a delta or because you have changed my views but not in relation to my view in question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430107707.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>It is an example dude... 

People can be placed into a situation **after due process.**

That’s is absolutely nothing like the slavery the US abolished because it doesn’t legally exist any more.

People (no matter the color) have rights. 

What do you not get about that. The **type** of slavery that the US seemed to get ride of is gone. That is no longer a legal viable option.

Do you agree with that? Yes or no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430195921.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the US abolished ONE type of slavery. 

I believe that America cannot claim the blanket statement " America abolished slavery"  until you abolish all of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430238165.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>The two documents you reference are in response to that one type of slavery.

So should any rational person conclude that that was specifically is what people talk about when referencing the abolishment of slavery in the US?

Are you really going to split hairs?

Many European nations stopped the Atlantic slave trade centuries ago, but if a single European smuggles an individual from Africa across the Atlantic does that mean the Atlantic slave trade is alive and active? It hasn’t been abolished?


Come on dude... you know exactly what people mean when they say slavery is abolished. They are talking about the legal ownership of African descendants in the US. People who had no standing as people in the US.

You want to play on words go ahead, but you know darn well what people mean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430363762.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>well obviously I don't hold the same view as you on this. I don't understand why you keep bring up things that are illegal as if those nation states support them?

And yes obviously I'm "splitting hairs" because those hair are important to my view on the subject. 

Your entire argument is why you think penal slavery is fine, mine is that it is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34431035310.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>Your whole argument is wrong.

You are misinterpreting the meaning when people say “ Slavery is/was abolished.”

They mean that particular type was no longer going to legally continue in the states.

That’s it, it was not replaced with anything. 

You are wrong in what you think people mean.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
