<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1026594069.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/cmv_america_should_not_be_able_to_claim_that_it/">
    <title>CMV: America should not be able to claim that it has abolished slavery</title>
    <original_poster>rrea436</original_poster>
    <original_post>The abolishion of slavery is normally claimed modernly to be through two separate documents. 

[Emancipation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emancipation_Proclamation) and the [13th amendment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution#Text)

However I don't think that these documents provide a substancial enough basis to claim that slavery is abolished within the USA.

The Emancipation Proclamation, was in effect largely symbolic, It is estimated that it freed 2% slaves in the USA when it was made, and indeed it helped many more over the coming years. The country being at civil war made it unenforceable and it did not apply to the 500,000 slaves within Union territory. I feel that the Emancipation Proclamation was more important in building to the 13th rather than holding any real abolishment itself.

the 13th amendment is the real crux of the issue. I'll post it here directly.

Section 1.

Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, **except  as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly  convicted,** shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to  their jurisdiction.

Section 2.

Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation.

Personally section 2 is fine the problem is in section 1 that I have in bold

I do not think slavery is abolished because it is explicitly legal for certain persons. and many of the earliest prisons where in fact just plantations, [1.](https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations) [2.](https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/)  Not going to Lie thing like the Black laws, the Jim crow era and the war on drugs, have all in my opinion targeted this enslavement at black people in the USA. I probably would not have posted this without the current BLM protests, however I have held these opinions for years. when people (I) say systemic racism this is what they (I) mean.

The 13th Amendment does not stop slavery, it just changes who slaves are. That's not abolishment, no where near it, and it's no where near good enough.

Believe it or not [There has been progress](https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-08-26/slave-trade-roots-us-private-prisons) on removing the prison system from private ownership, but even then slaves owned by the state doesn't inspire me with confidence that America is anywhere near the end.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34429855134.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>If you want to be anal about it no country has abolished slavery. I’m sure there are human traffickers operating in every country on earth. 

As far as it goes in America... the US abolished the legality to sale and the legality for people to own others. That is what it aimed to abolish and that is what was abolished. The US government passed legislation that outlawed slavery. 

**It abolished (made illegal) that particular slavery practice.**

Sure there are several other forms that go on... doesn’t mean what the emancipation proclamation did failed... the slaves were freed in the eyes of the law and citizens of the country. Equal citizens? No... of course not.


So yes they can claim they abolished the slavery in which they aimed to abolish. Can you come up with cases where people have **legally** sold individuals since? Kept them captive for their entire life? Pay them absolutely nothing and make all life choices for them? Breed them like live stock and claim ownership of the offspring? Do those captive individuals have no standing as a person in the US or rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34429943072.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the US abolished the legality to sale and the legality for people to own others. That is what it aimed to abolish and that is what was abolished.

But it is legal for business to do this, many prisons do exactly this when they rent out prison production lines to other companies.

The fact that you admit that several other forms go on means that I'm not convinced that Slavery can be claimed as abolished. 

Chattel slavery, is abolished but I don't think think that while other forms of slavery are existent, it cannot be claimed abolished in general.

much like how claiming "alcohol is illegal" in Ireland would be ridiculous since only a few select types are illegal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34429969431.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>You missed my point... they looked to abolish a certain kind of slavery. Where a large group of blacks were not technically even people in the eyes of US. That is no longer the case.

Prisoners still are considered people, they have rights. There rights were given when they had a trial that got them convicted to serve time. 

**I am saying that the specific type of slavery the US went out to abolish was.**


I am sure there were pimps and traffickers in 1700’s &amp;amp; 1800’s US who sold women as sex objects and they did so after the abolish of slavery as many are today. 

That is not the kind of slavery that brought about those changes you mentioned buddy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430042796.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt;  I am saying that the specific type of slavery the US went out to abolish was.

and my point is that replacing one system of slavery with another did not abolish slavery, and my statement stand America did not abolish slavery. 

For some reason your trying to Gotcha me; as if the fact America only wanted to remove chattel slavery is my point, but it's not, my point is that America has slaves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430076722.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn’t replacing anything.

As I said, human sex trafficking has been going on.

Indentured servitude has been going on.

So what exactly do you think was replaced?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430118224.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>the difference is that human trafficking is illegal and Indentured servitude is legal.
Chattel slavery was replaced by indentured servitude in Prisons, this is why you have so many private prisons built in old slave plantations, by the same slave owners.
Throughout the ages Black code / Jim crow/  war on drugs always fed into a for profit system of slavery</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430148827.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>Dude... it wasn’t replaced!

That was already a thing before and after.

Also with the constitutional requirement of **due process.**



The emancipation proclamation did not look to end indentured servitude. It didn’t look to end, sex trafficking, it didn’t look to end drugs, it didn’t look to end the use of drug mules.

It looked to make millions of humans beings free and humans in the eyes of the nation. 


That has ended. Those things are what it liked to stop and it legally did.

Yes there were other forms of slavery going on concurrently and after... those are **not** replacements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430177221.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so you agree with me?

Your last sentence is literately slavery continued after. Even with due process that is continuous ongoing slavery. 

I understand that the legal documents did what they set out to do.

I would argue that with a modern understanding those documents cannot be considered fit for purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430194151.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>Not the type of slavery the US looked to abolish. That did not continue.

Am I correct by saying that?

Yes or no</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430376548.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>Lets break this down because we are obviously going in circles.

yes, that statement is correct please continue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34431044880.0" user="Babou_FoxEarAHole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp; that is what people mean from a historical context of “Slavery was ended.”

No decently informed person believes that slavery as a whole has ended. It will probably never end.

What don’t you get about that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
