<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1026594069.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/cmv_america_should_not_be_able_to_claim_that_it/">
    <title>CMV: America should not be able to claim that it has abolished slavery</title>
    <original_poster>rrea436</original_poster>
    <original_post>The abolishion of slavery is normally claimed modernly to be through two separate documents. 

[Emancipation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emancipation_Proclamation) and the [13th amendment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution#Text)

However I don't think that these documents provide a substancial enough basis to claim that slavery is abolished within the USA.

The Emancipation Proclamation, was in effect largely symbolic, It is estimated that it freed 2% slaves in the USA when it was made, and indeed it helped many more over the coming years. The country being at civil war made it unenforceable and it did not apply to the 500,000 slaves within Union territory. I feel that the Emancipation Proclamation was more important in building to the 13th rather than holding any real abolishment itself.

the 13th amendment is the real crux of the issue. I'll post it here directly.

Section 1.

Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, **except  as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly  convicted,** shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to  their jurisdiction.

Section 2.

Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation.

Personally section 2 is fine the problem is in section 1 that I have in bold

I do not think slavery is abolished because it is explicitly legal for certain persons. and many of the earliest prisons where in fact just plantations, [1.](https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations) [2.](https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/)  Not going to Lie thing like the Black laws, the Jim crow era and the war on drugs, have all in my opinion targeted this enslavement at black people in the USA. I probably would not have posted this without the current BLM protests, however I have held these opinions for years. when people (I) say systemic racism this is what they (I) mean.

The 13th Amendment does not stop slavery, it just changes who slaves are. That's not abolishment, no where near it, and it's no where near good enough.

Believe it or not [There has been progress](https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-08-26/slave-trade-roots-us-private-prisons) on removing the prison system from private ownership, but even then slaves owned by the state doesn't inspire me with confidence that America is anywhere near the end.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34430334554.0" user="castor281" delta="False">
    <text>Prison labor is more akin to involuntary servitude than slavery. Even then, prison labor is a lot different than involuntary servitude. Subtle as the differences are, they are very different things. 

As far as slavery goes, nobody is born or sold into prison labor. Children who are born in prison don't become property of the prison. People aren't kidnapped from foreign lands and sold to the prisons. 15% of all prisoners don't die during the "voyage" to prison. Prisoners aren't whipped or killed for refusing to work. 

Comparing prison labor to slavery shows a complete lack of understanding of the cruelty of actual slavery. 

Comparing somebody that has to work in a field a couple days a week as punishment for a crime they committed to somebody that was kidnapped, shipped a couple thousand miles in horrific conditions, sold to another person, chained and beaten or abused daily, forced to live in squalor and work in fields, have their children taken from them and often sold and shipped away, often raped if they are women.... All with no end in site. That's a life sentence. No "release date" for when they get to go home. 

Do we need prison reform? Absolutely. Should prison labor be paid? Yes. Should we compare a couple days of manual labor every week to the horrifically inhumane savagery of slavery? Absolutely not. That comparison should be insulting to anybody whose ancestors were slaves.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
