<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1026594069.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/cmv_america_should_not_be_able_to_claim_that_it/">
    <title>CMV: America should not be able to claim that it has abolished slavery</title>
    <original_poster>rrea436</original_poster>
    <original_post>The abolishion of slavery is normally claimed modernly to be through two separate documents. 

[Emancipation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emancipation_Proclamation) and the [13th amendment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution#Text)

However I don't think that these documents provide a substancial enough basis to claim that slavery is abolished within the USA.

The Emancipation Proclamation, was in effect largely symbolic, It is estimated that it freed 2% slaves in the USA when it was made, and indeed it helped many more over the coming years. The country being at civil war made it unenforceable and it did not apply to the 500,000 slaves within Union territory. I feel that the Emancipation Proclamation was more important in building to the 13th rather than holding any real abolishment itself.

the 13th amendment is the real crux of the issue. I'll post it here directly.

Section 1.

Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, **except  as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly  convicted,** shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to  their jurisdiction.

Section 2.

Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation.

Personally section 2 is fine the problem is in section 1 that I have in bold

I do not think slavery is abolished because it is explicitly legal for certain persons. and many of the earliest prisons where in fact just plantations, [1.](https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations) [2.](https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/)  Not going to Lie thing like the Black laws, the Jim crow era and the war on drugs, have all in my opinion targeted this enslavement at black people in the USA. I probably would not have posted this without the current BLM protests, however I have held these opinions for years. when people (I) say systemic racism this is what they (I) mean.

The 13th Amendment does not stop slavery, it just changes who slaves are. That's not abolishment, no where near it, and it's no where near good enough.

Believe it or not [There has been progress](https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-08-26/slave-trade-roots-us-private-prisons) on removing the prison system from private ownership, but even then slaves owned by the state doesn't inspire me with confidence that America is anywhere near the end.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34430233147.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34432747832.0" user="TheRegen" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/AmbivalentAsshole – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+AmbivalentAsshole&amp;amp;message=AmbivalentAsshole+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/-/ftevdx7/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
