<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1026594069.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gz7h1x/cmv_america_should_not_be_able_to_claim_that_it/">
    <title>CMV: America should not be able to claim that it has abolished slavery</title>
    <original_poster>rrea436</original_poster>
    <original_post>The abolishion of slavery is normally claimed modernly to be through two separate documents. 

[Emancipation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emancipation_Proclamation) and the [13th amendment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirteenth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution#Text)

However I don't think that these documents provide a substancial enough basis to claim that slavery is abolished within the USA.

The Emancipation Proclamation, was in effect largely symbolic, It is estimated that it freed 2% slaves in the USA when it was made, and indeed it helped many more over the coming years. The country being at civil war made it unenforceable and it did not apply to the 500,000 slaves within Union territory. I feel that the Emancipation Proclamation was more important in building to the 13th rather than holding any real abolishment itself.

the 13th amendment is the real crux of the issue. I'll post it here directly.

Section 1.

Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, **except  as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly  convicted,** shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to  their jurisdiction.

Section 2.

Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation.

Personally section 2 is fine the problem is in section 1 that I have in bold

I do not think slavery is abolished because it is explicitly legal for certain persons. and many of the earliest prisons where in fact just plantations, [1.](https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations) [2.](https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/)  Not going to Lie thing like the Black laws, the Jim crow era and the war on drugs, have all in my opinion targeted this enslavement at black people in the USA. I probably would not have posted this without the current BLM protests, however I have held these opinions for years. when people (I) say systemic racism this is what they (I) mean.

The 13th Amendment does not stop slavery, it just changes who slaves are. That's not abolishment, no where near it, and it's no where near good enough.

Believe it or not [There has been progress](https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-08-26/slave-trade-roots-us-private-prisons) on removing the prison system from private ownership, but even then slaves owned by the state doesn't inspire me with confidence that America is anywhere near the end.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34429857913.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>It is generally accepted that here is an implied exception for a whole host of rights we have when it comes to people who have been convicted of a crime and imprisoned:

- You don't have freedom of speech or the press

- You don't have the right to own a firearm

- You are not protected from any search an seizure

- You have no freedom of movement or assembly

- Etc, etc, etc.

The point of incarceration is to take away some of your rights for a period of time as a part of your punishment, and our discussion of the rights that everyone should have is about those who are not subject to that punishment.  We don't say that the US lacks freedom of speech because prisoners can be silenced, nor do we say that we don't have the right to own firearms because prisoners cannot, nor do we say that we are protected from search because prisoners can have their cells tossed at any time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430015572.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>you see my problem here is that your not claiming it to have been abolished. your defending slavery as a punishment. 

I think that the point of disagreement is on whether legal enslavement as a punishment should count towards slavery being " Abolished" 

I think that my view is based on the fact that a country should not be allowed to claim anything as an immutable right if it reserves the ability to remove that right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430027818.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>No, that is not the argument I was making. The argument I was making is that our discussions about the immutable rights given to people - including the right not to be enslaved - is a discussion about those not currently convicted and incarcerated for crimes. Our fundamental freedoms have never universally applied to the incarcerated, so you are arguing a false premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34430147869.0" user="rrea436" delta="False">
    <text>I think my big misstep here was attributing what I consider a "right" to be to what Americans consider a "right" to be.

I am actually reading around as I go through these comments and need to learn more about the concepts of "Civic death" I think.

Thank you very much</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
