<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="103563615.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1pnq73/i_believe_free_markets_are_the_ultimate/">
    <title>I Believe Free Markets Are the Ultimate Determiner of Worth. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>matthedev</original_poster>
    <original_post>Markets, Americans like me love them. The idea of supply/demand curves is so enthralling that we can and do apply it to just about everything. Sadly, I fear many so-called free-market capitalists are nothing more than statists in disguise; they think the State should play a role in such things as enforcing the law and national security. They often take on interests that provide no tangible gain.

I say, though, free markets are the ultimate determiner of value because:

 * The law of supply and demand provides a fair and universal metric. One cannot say, "In my opinion, this has value, but nobody else cares"; instead we can experimentally and objectively measure the price the market will bear.
 * Markets enable a kind of direct democracy. We can "vote with our dollars" if we do not like the service being provided and take our money elsewhere. A business will hear the cry of the market or die, trampled by the competition.
 * Price changes with reality rather than being fixed by dogma. When it snows, the demand for rock salt goes up, and the supply begins to dwindle; the corresponding increase in price is a pointer to the world we live in rather than the whims of a sky-sprite whose existence has not yet been proven.
 * It corresponds better to our nature and is a more concise theory: Man is acquisitive, competitive, and selfish. Market theory does not have to assume otherwise.

To give an example, many—even the laissez-faire ones out there—will put some inestimable value on the relation of parent to child. "You can't put a price on a child's love." Rubbish! Let us instead weigh the opportunity cost instead of listening to these pieties. Assuming no artificial statist red tape has weighted the options, let us consider the cost of: (A) abandoning the child to the wilderness; (B) raising the child into adulthood; (C) selling the child's labor in the free market; or (D) selling the child itself. With A, there is the possibility, though remote, the child shall be raised by wolves, found a formidable city, and come back to strike revenge upon us; with B we are conforming to the dictates of current, non–market-based demands and perhaps assuming the ingrate will provide us some value in our elder years rather than selfishly choosing to pursue its own interest instead of that of the dying; with Options C and D, we have the benefit of a more immediate pay-off without the uncertain outcome that our adult child will be faithful and swayed by the fables of society.

If only market-based mechanisms were to prevail, Options C or D would win. The child would be carted off to some far-away land and *Pater Familias* would be healthier, wealthier, and wiser for it.

Next I look at productivity and work. It's cliché to say, "Do what you love!" Make art! Make music! Make love! Humbug! Your art won't pay the bills. Instead, "Make profit, not love!" While the artsy crowd can only afford to rent some dank, post-Apocalyptic studio in the blighted districts of town, if you weigh your options carefully, study hard, and relentlessly pursue the opportunities thrust upon you, you may be able to wind up in a mighty castle of a cubicle, updating a spreadsheet on a Friday night, wearing your Rolex and refined cologne, while the artsy kids are, who knows, huffing all that spray-paint and attending parties where they exchange mere "good vibes" or "fellow feeling." A society full of liberal artsy types will just stand around admiring each other's "works of art," endlessly debating hypothetical nonsense, and doing nothing productive and eventually be eaten alive by more virile civilizations who do the productive if sometimes boring work that cures sickness, fights back war, and grows. The work that the free market values is the work people should do.

Now what of those who cannot do? I mean the sick and the elderly, the disabled and diseased. Present socialistic values say it is "society's" duty to feed them, to tax me and hand out to them. If their labor has zero market value, then they should throw themselves unto the nearest market-magnate and ask mere scraps in exchange for their labor; if this too is too much, well, I refer you to [history](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_Potato_Famine) in decreasing market inefficiencies.

Now please see if you can change my view. I beg you refrain from references to your sky-god or your feel-good politics.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26921922183.0" user="matthedev" delta="False">
    <text>I am just now getting to replying to everyone's comments. I have been busy engaging in the quotidian transactions of the market.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
