<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1044801247.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ha1psv/cmv_local_suburban_detective_police_are_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: Local suburban detective police are pointless</title>
    <original_poster>jeffunity</original_poster>
    <original_post>I will admit i live in a low crime area of a low crime nation. However I recently interacted with the police on several occasions and each time left feeling like our tax dollars are wasted. Please note i am not talking about having detectives on call for a wide area (I would suggest one or two teams in my city of 3 million people spread widely), i admit that *some* detectives will always be necessary for murders and the like. Nor am i talking about traffic police/highway patrol, or general law and order uniformed police. These are all necessary as part of a normal society. But normal robberies seem to be a fact of life and are never solved, nor are any goods recovered.

In the past 3 months i have had the following occur:

\- I rented a forklift to a customer. I have previously rented to this customer, we require all renters to carry insurance for the forklift. The forklift was stolen because the customer didn't secure the site well. the police response was "check ebay and auction sites, you know forklifts better than i do." After 2 weeks he asked if i had found it, then said there wasn't anything else he could do.

\- the business next to me was robbed. The police asked for my security footage. I went through it, couldn't see anything and told them that. They didn't have any further follow ups after that.

\- My employers car was stolen. using local contacts he managed to get the names of some people who might be involved. he also tracked the use of a credit card from the car and located a shopping centre they were buying products in. The police refused to follow up on those leads provided.

I am not commenting on police brutality or discrimination. But I feel these police detectives that are dealing with local crime are not doing their job, or their job is no longer possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34526510613.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>Police detectives exist to try to solve crimes. The fact is most do go unsolved.

What did you realistically expect for the Forklift theft? It is insured, there were no witnesses, and there were no leads. They advised you that since you owned one, you were more likely than they were to know where a stolen one might end up trying to be sold. What more could they really do?

The second item, why would you have any more interaction? They needed one piece of evidence from you - interview/footage. You are not a party to this crime. 

On the last one. A car was reported stolen and a credit card was reported stolen. Two related but separate items. It is quite likely the police tried to follow up on it but got nowhere. 

If you think objectively. Names of people - is that enough probable cause - likely to drive by their house but not much more. Shopping center - maybe - if there is usable security footage of the people using the card. But if the car is not in the lot - what do you expect. Again, to be honest - the car is insured and the credit card should have been deactivated. 

Police do not tell victims what they find. This is due to many factors including the ability to actually prosecute them. 

What can happen is when they catch one person, they may be able to solve multiple crimes. Realize only 1 in 5 stolen cars is actually recovered. Not only that - the arrest rates are a lot closer to 1 in 10 auto thefts. 

I think you are having wildly greater expectations for police work than actually exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34529235051.0" user="jeffunity" delta="False">
    <text>I am not complaining that they could have done more. My argument is that since they cannot, why do they exist in the first place?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34529553709.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>They exist to take reports and provide investigations where they can. You are just expecting a better outcome than nationally is present. 

Without detectives - people specifically trained and tasked to investigate serious crimes, who would do it? Would the service improve or get worse? Do you want a 'beat cop' to handle a murder scene? To be responsible for investigating if the husband killed the wife?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
