<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1044801247.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ha1psv/cmv_local_suburban_detective_police_are_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: Local suburban detective police are pointless</title>
    <original_poster>jeffunity</original_poster>
    <original_post>I will admit i live in a low crime area of a low crime nation. However I recently interacted with the police on several occasions and each time left feeling like our tax dollars are wasted. Please note i am not talking about having detectives on call for a wide area (I would suggest one or two teams in my city of 3 million people spread widely), i admit that *some* detectives will always be necessary for murders and the like. Nor am i talking about traffic police/highway patrol, or general law and order uniformed police. These are all necessary as part of a normal society. But normal robberies seem to be a fact of life and are never solved, nor are any goods recovered.

In the past 3 months i have had the following occur:

\- I rented a forklift to a customer. I have previously rented to this customer, we require all renters to carry insurance for the forklift. The forklift was stolen because the customer didn't secure the site well. the police response was "check ebay and auction sites, you know forklifts better than i do." After 2 weeks he asked if i had found it, then said there wasn't anything else he could do.

\- the business next to me was robbed. The police asked for my security footage. I went through it, couldn't see anything and told them that. They didn't have any further follow ups after that.

\- My employers car was stolen. using local contacts he managed to get the names of some people who might be involved. he also tracked the use of a credit card from the car and located a shopping centre they were buying products in. The police refused to follow up on those leads provided.

I am not commenting on police brutality or discrimination. But I feel these police detectives that are dealing with local crime are not doing their job, or their job is no longer possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34526961996.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>None of that demonstrates that local detectives in general are pointless; it would only demonstrate that the detectives in your specific jurisdiction are incompetent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34529227975.0" user="jeffunity" delta="False">
    <text>This is a reasonable point, however I have never heard of any property crime being solved by the police (antecdotal I know) . Assuming you are right, why are they there at all then if they are that bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34529890766.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>It's hard to say for certain without a close look at the local community.  Nepotism perhaps?  Or some other family friend got them a cushy job?  Other corruption?  
Maybe they managed to make it up and noone wnats to/benefits from firing them, so they just stick around?  It's often pretty hard to fire government workers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
