<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928539378.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded?

This question seems to be conflating two seperate issues: *was it immoral for the Mongols to do what they did?* and *did the Mongols compensate the people they conquered and killed?*

The answer to the second question is clearly 'no': the Mongols didn't.

But the answer to the second question is *irrelevant* to the first question. You cannot reasonably assume that the fact that the Mongols didn't compensate their victims means that their conquest and slaughter wasn't immoral. 

&amp;gt; Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory.

Because the act of conquering someone, taking their land from them, breaking treaties with them so that we can take stuff we'd promised to leave in their hands, enslaving their populations, and killing them off with biological weapons *is contrary to our moral beliefs*.

The United States is a country which is based, in part, on a very strong ideological foundation. "All men are created equal", etc. But we're also a country which *only exists* because of actions that are completely contrary to our ideology and are violations of our ideals.

It seems completely predictable and natural that we'd have a hard time letting that go.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
