<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928205915.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>This is a utilitarian argument. You believe that the genocide of the Native American is justified because it brought advancements to European populations. 

How do you feel about colonialism and slavery? It brought great death and destruction to people in Africa, India, and China for the benefit of European powers. How about feudalism, which brought great status and profit to landowners, but screwed over peasants. Is it justified to murder a millionaire, and spend his money on healthcare, education, scientific research, etc.? His money would benefit society far more than what he would have spent it on, but is it morally acceptable?

On the flip side, is it morally wrong for a society to fight back? Is it wrong that Native Americans or the people dominated by the Mongols tried not to be killed? They hindered the progress of mankind, something that you consider justified and beneficial. So is it wrong to get in the way of that progress?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928215300.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're saying, but the benefit the American colonies provided was not my only reason. My main point was that without conquest and expansion, society would not have advanced as quickly and as efficiently as it did. It may not have even advanced at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928233877.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You just ignored his entire comment. Why did you post here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928469798.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>I ignored it becausec he selected only one part of my argument and then acted like it was my entire argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928245421.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Society doesn't advance due to conquest, it advances due to scientific research and learning. 

This is why the conquest years of the Crusades are called the Dark Ages, and the age afterwards is called the Renaissance. The Scientific Revolution, the Age of Enlightenment, and the Industrial Revolution were not brought about because of wars and conflict. In fact, most scholars cite the start of the Napoleonic Wars as the end of the Age of Enlightenment.

Yes, there are some scientific advances that are brought about due to wars, such as better quality firearms or nuclear weapons, but they are largely limited to military applications. Yes things like radar and military satellites have civilian applications too, but those peaceful scientific ages were significantly more efficient at progressing society.

Also, in addition to the military tech is the new access to resources that comes with conquest. Yet, conquering powers often destroy whatever progress is already occurring in the places they attack. For example, while Europe was living in the Dark Ages, the Middle East was in a golden era. They were inventing calculus and building an immaculate society until Crusaders and Mongols came and ruined it. Caesar's Civil War resulted in him destroying his own Library of Alexandria. This is likely more of a myth, but it still demonstrates the destruction that conquest causes. Who are you to say that Native Americans weren't on their way to a major progression of society. Places like India and China were already doing incredibly well, and would have likely progressed even further if Europeans hadn't come in and massacred and colonized them. There is no way to predict what would have happened otherwise, but it is possible/probable that many of our technological advancements would have come about anyways, and perhaps even faster than they would have in our own timeline.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928307278.0" user="Eh_Priori" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is why the conquest years of the Crusades are called the Dark Ages, and the age afterwards is called the Renaissance.

I don't agree with OP, but the idea of a medieval 'dark age' is widely discredited among historians and the Renaissance wasn't any less violent than the middle ages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928363644.0" user="Zorkolak" delta="False">
    <text>A couple of important things to note:

First off, I dislike the term progression of society. it implies that a previous state is inferior to the current one. For some things like scientific knowledge we can state this (as we know more and more we progress) but when it comes to society I think the most accurate term to use is societal change. It's more neutral.

&amp;gt; Society doesn't advance due to conquest, it advances due to scientific research and learning.

I would say that conquest of other cultures leads to scientific research and learning and vice versa. Advances through science allows for better weapons and armour, thus allowing more conquest. Conquests means contact with other cultures from which we can (not always do) learn. That said, learning from other cultures is not always a good thing to do from behind the barrel of a gun. Or it might be. Depending on what you wish to learn about them.

&amp;gt; This is why the conquest years of the Crusades are called the Dark Ages, and the age afterwards is called the Renaissance. The Scientific Revolution, the Age of Enlightenment, and the Industrial Revolution were not brought about because of wars and conflict. In fact, most scholars cite the start of the Napoleonic Wars as the end of the Age of Enlightenment.

"The Dark Ages" is a term coined by the philosophers and artists of the Renaissance as was the term "Renaissance" itself. They were deliberatly invented to mark the rediscovery of ancient ideas, literature, artforms etc and to mark the 1000ish year period in between the fall of the Western Roman Empire and the rediscovery of it's culture. However, that does not imply that nothing happened! Most historians nowadays will agree that the period of anarchy following the collapse of central roman administration was far more gradual than has otherwise been stated. The rise of the Catholic Church as a centralising power in Europe has vastly contributed to emergence of a different european civilisation but a civilisation nonetheless. The threat from the east ie Islam also "helped" in this regard and provided a unifying factor in an age where political strife and war often were the same thing.

The other terms you used, Age of Enlightenment, Scientific Revolution, Industrial Revolution, are also terms invented by the people behind them, all to better style themselves, to make them seem larger then life. In the end, it comes down to Marketing and self-promotion.

&amp;gt; Yes, there are some scientific advances that are brought about due to wars, such as better quality firearms or nuclear weapons, but they are largely limited to military applications. Yes things like radar and military satellites have civilian applications too, but those peaceful scientific ages were significantly more efficient at progressing society.

Weapons are used by Police forces to keep the peace. I agree that the civilian uses of military technologies like the Internet, satelite imagery etc have a large impact but what about a GPS signal that can guide a rocket to it's destination with a margin of error of just a few feet? It can take out a man that could have gone out and changed the course of their society, rallying people for or against a cause, an idea, ... Is that not in some way social change as well?

&amp;gt; Also, in addition to the military tech is the new access to resources that comes with conquest. Yet, conquering powers often destroy whatever progress is already occurring in the places they attack. For example, while Europe was living in the Dark Ages, the Middle East was in a golden era. They were inventing calculus and building an immaculate society until Crusaders and Mongols came and ruined it. Caesar's Civil War resulted in him destroying his own Library of Alexandria. This is likely more of a myth, but it still demonstrates the destruction that conquest causes. Who are you to say that Native Americans weren't on their way to a major progression of society.

The crusaders knew bloody well that the Arabians were a lot more advanced then they were. It's how inventions like magnifying glasses came to Europe, together with a lot of mathematical knowledge of Algebra (not Calculus; Calculus was invented by Newton and/or Leibniz, depending on your viewpoint) and medicine. Ruined Arabian society? Aside from the 1st Crusade, all others were either beaten or beaten back with the Kingdom of Jerusalem only surviving for about a hundred years. Arabian society was hardly ruined by it, in fact, the threat of Christian Crusades served as the same kind of unifying factor as the threat of Islam did for Christiany before 1096.

&amp;gt; Places like India and China were already doing incredibly well, and would have likely progressed even further if Europeans hadn't come in and massacred and colonized them. There is no way to predict what would have happened otherwise, but it is possible/probable that many of our technological advancements would have come about anyways, and perhaps even faster than they would have in our own timeline.

First of all, places like India and China were in a state of technological stagnation at the time. China for example had not seen the need for the uses of glass over ceramic, thus precluding it's use in Alchemy (as a beakers made from glass are chemically neutral), in lense grinding (thus no telescope or microscope for you!). European powers like the United Kingdom and France had, through the use of military science and technology achieved a technological superiority that allowed limited amounts of colonial troops to take over vast amounts of land all over the world. For this, they not only needed better guns, but better ships, logistics, better navigation methods, better food storage techniques,... all things that were possible through the lessons learned from conquering the Americas. Exploration of these new lands inspired the Age of Discovery as it was and is called with new and better techniques tried, tested and implemented. Better ways of telling time had to be invented to help with navigation. All because the states (England, France, Spain, Portugal,...) were behind this. They were not interested in these tales of new lands, no it's the trade opportunities, the resources, the gold and silver! that awaited them in heaps in the new world, resources that would allow them to compete with the other colonial powers. And with this Age of Conquest and Exploration came the realisation that world was a lot bigger then people realised. There were new lands to discover, new areas to explore, peoples and cultures to meet,... This sense of exploration and conquest did a lot to change western european societies. It allowed them to start thinking on a global scale. Trade routes that spanned the globe brought back herbs, spices, foods, knowledge, animals, all sorts of things that allowed for the broadening of minds and the advancement of knowledge and understanding. It's a drive that lasts for centuries and has shaped the world and world politics ever since.

Now, no one sane will reasonably argue that conquest is always a good thing, for starters it isn't for the people being conquered. Culture and knowledge are lost as well, sometimes whole peoples are killed in genocides, forcibly converted to a different religion, treated as second class if not as slaves alltogether,... But you have to remember that a lot of these things have to be seen in their proper context. Yes, these things were and are awful and we have the luxury but also the duty to look at these things ourselves and evaluate them again and again as we weigh them against our current cultural standards. 

Stating that the exploration and settlement of the Americas was wrong is a meaningless statement. Yes, horrible atrocities were committed, as they still are today as well in places like Iraq, Iran, Afghanistan, Guantanamo Bay, Russia and pretty much every civilized or uncilivized place when the stuation appears to "ask for it". But stating that therefor it was wrong to explore and settle the Americas because of it is just misguided. Better to learn the lessons from the past and to not repeat them. As a learning example in the very least, the conquest of the new world was a good thing.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928366274.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But stating that therefor it was wrong to explore and settle the Americas because of it is just misguided. Better to learn the lessons from the past and to not repeat them. As a learning example in the very least, the conquest of the new world was a good thing.

I liked your post up until this point, because where was this stated or implied as part of /u/McKoijion's attempt to change the OP's view?  That is, why is conquest a necessary condition to settlement and exploration, and who said that the latter two were, in themselves, wrong?  From here, it *sounds* like you might be conflating conquest with both.

/u/McKoijion's post simply tries to point out the flaws in OP's rather rigid analysis:  that the costs of the *kinds* of conquests that occurred are outweighed by the *supposed* benefits (often wrongly attributed) of the world in which we live today. I don't want to put words in his mouth, but that is presumably the reason why he argues that many of these technologies or cultural assimilations could have occurred with vastly different kinds of interactions between peoples.  When the *particular* mode of conquest chosen by various European agents isn't the sole "but for" cause of the developments we have, it begins discounting the utility and thus justification for OP's position.

This is, after all, a historical analysis, so "Let's learn from our mistakes," while a laudable goal, isn't much of a rebuttal even if we should acknowledge that we have the benefit of hindsight.  I obviously have my own, other qualms with the OP's posts and approach it from a different angle, but this paragraph stuck out to me as misplaced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928379035.0" user="Zorkolak" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the OP's analysis is too rigid but it seemed to me that /u/McKoijion's response was equally rigid in some regards and failed as well to take into account various subtleties. 

In all, I feel that my final statement is directed more towards the OP then /u/McKoijion. It's a delicate argument, weighing cultures and peoples against gains in resources for other cultures, one that reeks of supiority when made in favour of the culture that takes advantage. In that I agree with /u/McKoijion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928270257.0" user="Oberstleutnant88" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How do you feel about colonialism and slavery? It brought great death and destruction to people in Africa, India, and China for the benefit of European powers.

Certainly not the United States. They imported millions of them, and now look at how the foolish practice of slavery manifested itself in the present...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
