<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928390897.0" user="minerva_qw" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, there were many benefits for European explorers and settlers. They gained land, a profitable trade hub, vast natural resources, new crops and agricultural practices, freedom to try out new economic and political systems. Great. Good for them/us.

Native Americans have good reason not to see it that way, however. Before the arrival of Europeans, there were a great variety of complex societies throughout the Americas, with their own cities, trade structures, technologies, and cultures, many of which were *more* advanced than their European counterparts.

They were all but wiped out by disease and violence. Those that survived were driven from their lands and forced to go on thousand-mile death marches to live on reservations that no one else wanted to settle on anyway. Others were forced to labor in horrendous conditions to produce goods that they would never see the slightest profit from. They were lied to and cheated repeatedly by the government.

Then, they were forbidden from speaking their native languages and practicing their own cultures. Their children were taken from them and sent to boarding schools for this express purpose. When they returned home (if they returned home) they could no longer communicate with or take part in community life. At the same time, institutional racism prevented them from taking part in society at large.

The fallout of all this still effects what remains of these populations to this day. Poverty and alcoholism rampant. Native populations throughout the Americas are subject to terrible living conditions and exploitation. 

For these people, it is not at all clear that it was all for the greater good or that it all worked out okay in the end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928470322.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>I know it's not pretty, but suffering and loss of life is what happens in conquest. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26928688008.0" user="minerva_qw" delta="False">
    <text>If genocide and slavery don't make something wrong, I don't know what does. Your CMV is that the European conquest was not *wrong*. For the reasons stated above, it clearly was. 

The fact that it happened a long time ago doesn't make it any less wrong. The descendents of those in the way when the Europeans arrived in the Americas have experienced lasting negative effects of conquest to this day. For them, the "benefits" of conquest don't outweigh the suffering and loss of life.

The fact that you enjoy the society you live in today doesn't make it less wrong. Things being good for you today doesn't negate the suffering of others.

Saying that suffering and loss of life are what happens in a conquest don't justify it, any more than saying violence and loss of property are just what happens in an armed robbery.

Would you be okay with your country taking part in a conquest that resulted in similar levels of human suffering today? Would you feel comfortable taking part in such an undertaking yourself? If not, why not? If so, I hope I never run into you in a dark alley.

And if the European conquests were wrong, does that mean that you have to go around feeling bad about it all the time? No, it's not like you went out and did those things personally. But it is important to be aware that the things you enjoy today had and continue to have real human costs. You can't undo what's been done, but you can use an awareness of the sheer scale of the wrongness that was perpetrated to keep it from happening on your watch, and to foster a bit of empathy for the people who are still affected today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26929180752.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point. But what was Europe to do? Ignore half the planet?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26929252777.0" user="minerva_qw" delta="False">
    <text>There's a lot of middle ground between ignoring half the planet and decimating entire civilizations. 

They could have explored and then gone home and reported their findings. They could have built consensual and reciprocal cultural exchanges. They could have constructed mutually beneficial trade agreements. They could have collaborated with different cultures to advance technologically and societally.

In other words, conquest was not the only path to progress. But it's the one that was taken. There's not a lot we can do about that now except recognize that it was the wrong path so we can be certain not to be so callous with human lives from here on out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
