<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928290930.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement.

This is definitely a new spin on the Spanish Conquistadors' brutal annihilation of the entire Aztec civilization.  Besides, since when is what other countries do the measure of what a proper reaction is?

It bears mentioning that whatever money various tribes receive from *our* government isn't predicated on conquest by *European* nations so much as early reciprocal treaties that we're beholden to, or effectively breached and are paying something analogous to an equitable remedy in contract.  The rest is just a bona fide relationship between two (quasi) sovereigns that is a modern compromise stemming from those early interactions.

I think part of the issue is that you're forcing numerous indigenous people into a category of "Native American tribes," when interaction with each has (and still remains) different, namely because they were discrete groups with individualized political and social structures.  You're similarly framing Europe as this unified conglomerate when they were, for the most part, wholly separate nation-states who varied in how they interacted with indigenous people in the Americas.  There simply wasn't a singular European conquest or a blanket Native American experience with Europeans, not all of whom were traditional "conquerors."

For example, the English interactions were very different in Virginia than in the Massachusetts colony, which also differed from the Dutch interactions in New Amsterdam, and those differed from New Sweden, and those likewise differed from New France, and similarly so from the aforementioned Spanish conquest.  I'm sure the Iroquois Nation would have a different experience from that of the Algonquin and Cherokee.  The list goes on.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
