<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26928396381.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>Suppose that it would be possible to cure cancer provided that we subjected 100,000 randomly selected people to extremely painful and ultimately fatal  medical experiments, and that this is the only way to come up with a cure for cancer here and now, rather than pursuing alternative methods of research which may or may not eventually yield results.

It seems to me as though you ought to think that we should kill the 100,000 people, going by the sort of argument you have advanced above.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
