<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="104870418.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1qfqj6/i_dont_believe_that_the_conquest_of_the_americas/">
    <title>I don't believe that the conquest of the Americas by Europe was wrong. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Halfdrummer</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, most of the Native Americans died when the Europeans took over, but that's just a consequence of conquest. What makes this conquest different than other ones? Did the Ottoman Turks ever pay the Byzantines? Did the Mongols pay the hundreds of countries and cities that they invaded? Why can't our government and our society as a whole just let this go, like every other nation in the world did after they conquered a surrounding territory. Without conquest and military expansion, the world and civilization as a whole would not have expanded as quickly and efficiently as it did, and the cultures of different countries couldn't have mixed to inspire new ideas and methods of technological advancement. Yes you could argue that such a feat is achievable through trade, but the process would be much slower, and the full affects of some cultures may not be completely absorbed or even shared with other cultures. Had Columbus turned back at the first sign of inhabitants, Europe would not have benefitted from crops like potatoes(a crop that played a major role in the European 19th century population boom), and corn. The introduction of the New world as a trading hub also facilitated international trade, not only to the new world, but to places like Java and the Ottoman Empire. Western Europe was transformed from a somewhat economically isolated area, into a trading hub for the entire known world. All in all, I believe that the conquest of the Americas was not only justified, but beneficial, despite the incredible loss of Native American life. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26929117025.0" user="craznazn247" delta="False">
    <text>By a purely utilitarian view, yes, the ends justify the means.
Except for the fact that you overlook any alternative. You're saying "well we got the job done" and disregard what it took to get here, and the fact that the same could have been achieved without that cost.

All advancement leads to moving forward - development of technology, social and cultural progress, etc. It all moves in one direction, and any benefit will affect EVERYONE after that. Your argument is based on a fallacy because it is on an unlimited scale, where the benefits are for an unlimited amount of time and unlimited number of people in the future, while the negatives affect a limited number of people for a limited amount of time.

By your view, when scaled big enough - every single advancement and bit of progress is worth any cost far enough down the line. If you sacrifice half the human population now for the cure to cancer, maybe hundreds, or thousands of years down the line the benefits will outweigh the costs - More lives will EVENTUALLY be saved by this sacrifice. But that doesn't make it right or moral? I think the answer is obvious.

Additionally, if such an action is "right", then why do we have ethical limitations on how scientific research is done? There is a significant amount of research and development that could be done and yield lots of results in the fraction of the time that it takes us right now, if we were to eliminate said ethical limitations. An example of this are the [Nazi Human Experiments](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_human_experimentation) which made massive early contributions to what we know today about the limits of the human body - the scientific evidence generated from these experiments took decades and a lot more resources to be replicated in an ethical manner.

Since we, as a society, define what is "right" and "wrong" based on our present views and morals, you have to convince the general population to be okay with something before it is "right".
You can't be 100% Utilitarian and still be humane, because Utilitarianism can argue just about anything to be "right".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26929650343.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>Do I believe that the lives of European people who will actually contribute to a complex society are more valuable then naked tribal peoples playing in the sand and accomplishing nothing? Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26931926777.0" user="craznazn247" delta="False">
    <text>You're detracting from your original point. You said that you don't believe that the sacrifice of lives is "wrong".

Now you're arguing over if a life has increased value based on the results of an individual's actions during their life. That's a whole different debate in itself. I'm only going to discuss your original argument. Your argument is justification of torture, murder, and genocide of people who generally were peaceful, and often times provided aid that saved the lives of those very "conquerors". 

All this based on the assumption that our society has "advanced" as a result. Yes. I will acknowledge that it helped us advance faster than we would have otherwise. But what you are arguing is once again, absolute utilitarianism where the ends justify the means, no matter the cost. By such an argument we would throw out all ethics for the pure sake of advancements, and impose no limits on the negative impacts of our own actions on others, so long as something were to come out of it, even if it is as small as inconclusive experimental data that hints at beneficial future research.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26931943158.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>Good point. How would you propose the Europeans should have taken over the Americas then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26935868521.0" user="Halfdrummer" delta="False">
    <text>I guess you swayed me. I concede. Good argument</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
