<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1050605380.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hdi4as/cmv_social_media_is_ruining_political/">
    <title>CMV: social media is ruining political debates/conversations</title>
    <original_poster>_Goldy82_</original_poster>
    <original_post>Social media is an outlet for a lot of people to talk, tell stories, share experiences and news, etc. 
The problem I have with social media and politics is the rumoring and free reign for many to twist details and frame stories to fit their viewpoints. I see some examples of this and will link to some when i find more. 
I am young (younger teen), so are my friends/people I follow. And for my age there are some really strong views on recent events that lean heavily one way or the other, and therefore i see only what this person feels is the absolute. 
The reason I say that debates are ruined by social media is because these stories that I see heavily lean in either direction and people become extremely biased to one side or another and it makes it hard for people to open up to the other side of the debate
The experiences I have on social could be much different than others and I would love to hear some opinions that change my mind on this matter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34562546968.0" user="majesticmoose001" delta="False">
    <text>It is certainly difficult to have meaningful discussions over it. I would say it is not ruining debate, because it is not a platform for debate. The major social media are a place to say your own ideas and read the ideas of others while making comments/liking things (even the angry emoji isn't form of "like").

Debate, even informal, relies on consenting parties to  agree to certain rules at the start, present their arguments, then decide what was learned.

Social media is nothing like this. I think if you are looking to have constructive arguments on social media (which I do often with strangers as well as friends/family with variable levels of success) the thing I find that works best is finding common ground before differences. Also, use move conversations from posts, to DM's since it is hard to have a constructive conversation with a peanut gallery.

I hope you have a lot of future success with sharing ideas.

Keep in mind, people believe the usage of social media is all sorts of different things so they may gets mad at you for using social media differently than them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34562586645.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>I find all of these points interesting. Especially the common ground. I know and have been in arguments/ “debates” in which the topics are floated around and shots are taken like a free for all. I like using these platforms to talk to others and gather ideas to form an opinion. While this may not be the best way to do it. It is with peers and is usually not a huge argument. Usually. Thanks for the input!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34562609967.0" user="majesticmoose001" delta="False">
    <text>When it is a heated argument, try and find out why it was to avoid that in the future. Maybe they are just someone who doesn't like their ideas being challenged, maybe you came out the gate too fast and they felt attacked. One of the nice things about social media the record of things which have been said as easy to access as scrolling up.

In using social media to argue it has made me more sympathetic towards people. You can have some great interactions in deescalations of a hostile individual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34562635465.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>Using deescalation is something i need to work on, it depends on the person as well. Sometimes talking with friends vs a person that has issues with their ideas being challenged requires a different method of approach. 
I have also had experiences with empathy especially when talking with people who have a much different like than me and have different experiences. 
The experiences of others is mostly the reason i talk politics. I like to see how the bias, good or bad, changes how people view a topic. Thank you and I will keep this in mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566127232.0" user="kaldariaq" delta="False">
    <text>The think hard-core democrats and Republicans have is that they have allowed themselves to believe that their fellow citizen is the enemy, when in reality most avg people have more in common with each other than the leaders of the parties.

Anyone thats let themselves get so brainwashed into thinking they are right and everyone else is evil probably don't have anything meaningful to contribute to a conversation anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566649415.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, I believe that people who cannot see the other side of the argument and cant handle exchanging ideas with the opposite party may be too immature to speak on politics.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
