<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1050605380.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hdi4as/cmv_social_media_is_ruining_political/">
    <title>CMV: social media is ruining political debates/conversations</title>
    <original_poster>_Goldy82_</original_poster>
    <original_post>Social media is an outlet for a lot of people to talk, tell stories, share experiences and news, etc. 
The problem I have with social media and politics is the rumoring and free reign for many to twist details and frame stories to fit their viewpoints. I see some examples of this and will link to some when i find more. 
I am young (younger teen), so are my friends/people I follow. And for my age there are some really strong views on recent events that lean heavily one way or the other, and therefore i see only what this person feels is the absolute. 
The reason I say that debates are ruined by social media is because these stories that I see heavily lean in either direction and people become extremely biased to one side or another and it makes it hard for people to open up to the other side of the debate
The experiences I have on social could be much different than others and I would love to hear some opinions that change my mind on this matter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34566486189.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>It's definitely made things more complicated. Before, only the squeaky wheels got the grease, now everyone can squeak. 

However, that's not necessarily a bad thing, or even something we should be trying to avoid. The voices we're hearing are new to us, but they've been here the  entire time and are entitled to recognition. Yes, that makes things take longer as there are more people to consider when making any decisions. Choosing to ignore people for the purpose of making politics easier is at best, laziness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566639363.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>I see your points, I don’t want to denounce new voices or shut out people, the reason I use social media is to see the ideas and opinions of others. I believe everyone should be heard, but my issue is the people that want to be heard and don’t want to receive any sort of opinion or idea that challenges them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566687421.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>That's their right. Some people aren't interested in logical arguments. We can't make them change, and we can't keep them from voting, so we have to cross our fingers and hope they either lose or don't cause too much trouble if they win. 

Case in point: our president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566737591.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>Perfect example, I feel if he was not as involved on social media, some people would have less issues with him. I don’t lean either way, but twitter is not helping his cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566771858.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>But hey, that's good too, right? Exposing his true self on social media is making an impact that could shape the course of history. Who knows how politics would look at the moment if Trump hadn't been tweeting the entire time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566852737.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, seeing that side of him made an impression on many, some of them are pretty funny too, which is what I think he uses twitter for besides pushing his agenda, he wants to use it to gather a crowd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566883450.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>See, social media isn't ruining political discussion at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34566929618.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>Hey good job bro, thanks for responding!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
