<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1050605380.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hdi4as/cmv_social_media_is_ruining_political/">
    <title>CMV: social media is ruining political debates/conversations</title>
    <original_poster>_Goldy82_</original_poster>
    <original_post>Social media is an outlet for a lot of people to talk, tell stories, share experiences and news, etc. 
The problem I have with social media and politics is the rumoring and free reign for many to twist details and frame stories to fit their viewpoints. I see some examples of this and will link to some when i find more. 
I am young (younger teen), so are my friends/people I follow. And for my age there are some really strong views on recent events that lean heavily one way or the other, and therefore i see only what this person feels is the absolute. 
The reason I say that debates are ruined by social media is because these stories that I see heavily lean in either direction and people become extremely biased to one side or another and it makes it hard for people to open up to the other side of the debate
The experiences I have on social could be much different than others and I would love to hear some opinions that change my mind on this matter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34561967166.0" user="threeSJE" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think it's ruined political conversation because political conversations have mostly been trash from before the internet was conceived. It's why spouses have warned eachother not to discuss politics at the dinner table at Thanksgiving. Because it always dissolves into a bunch of ill informed nonsense screaming matches. Social media just makes it more visible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34561981195.0" user="_Goldy82_" delta="False">
    <text>That makes sense. I do think it is mostly a human problem that causes arguments and such. Social media does reach more of an audience. where large groups of people are seeing it at a time. I see exactly where you are coming from, though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
