<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1057425222.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hhkaiu/cmv_owning_fish_should_be_banned/">
    <title>CMV: Owning fish should be banned</title>
    <original_poster>BowenEdwards</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start by saying I'm not some kind of extreme animal activist I regularly eat meat but it seems to me that owning any fish is needlessly cruel. Your taking a living breathing animal that can think and feel, ripping it from its environment and putting it in a tiny box so you can have something pretty to look at. 

Goldfish normally have huge amounts of space to swim around in and people will keep them in actually bowls. They're like a house plant they just sit there you feed it and admire it but with a fish, they're more alive and aware they're in a tiny box and normally have a lot more space. I think that owning a dog is different since they actually enjoy being with you, you can walk them and let them see and smell new things. Nobody is taking their fish down to the lake for a little swim. If you locked a human in one small room it doesn't matter how good the room is, you could give them all the games, tv, internet they could ever want and it'd still be cruel. I don't see what a fish has, or doesn't have that makes it perfectly fine to do that exact thing to them. 

I'm all for people owning pets but it just seems like taking an animal that should have a huge amount of space and putting it in a bowl, just so we can look at the pretty colours, is a bit horrifically cruel on the animal and I don't really see any reason to not just outright ban it. That said, if a zoo can provide it as much space as it would normally have or if it's endangered and we want to stop it becoming extinct then they should be allowed to keep them. 

But individual people owning them in small tanks should be banned. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34748037212.0" user="TheBadDestroyer" delta="False">
    <text>Me with my tetras in a 10 gal with clean water, plants, wood, ground cover, water changes, a filter, snails, loaches (the fish) and fish food: TF you on mate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34748105448.0" user="BowenEdwards" delta="False">
    <text>They're supposed to have a massive amount of space and you're putting them in a box. It doesn't matter how clean and fancy the box is it's still a box with a fraction of the space they would normally have in the wild.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34748160733.0" user="TheBadDestroyer" delta="False">
    <text>A box that they are contempt with. Now I usually will not project human feelings onto non human animals ( that is what vegans do and I hate them), but I will say this. Imagine if I locked you inside a regular large apartment. You have medicine, food, running water, oxygen and shit. You have space to do your favorite hobbies. You have friends who stay there, but don't take up much space. The apartment will be magically cleaned and supplies will be restocked by god himself. You are happy and can not die (except for old age). You have an iq of 5 (fish can think and are pretty smart, but not as smart as us) and have no interest in going outside. That is how fish would feel imo. I could be wrong, but my fish are thriving. Same goes for zoo animals in good, AZA-ACCREDITED zoos. Hope this can change your mind for just a little bit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
