<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1057425222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hhkaiu/cmv_owning_fish_should_be_banned/">
    <title>CMV: Owning fish should be banned</title>
    <original_poster>BowenEdwards</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start by saying I'm not some kind of extreme animal activist I regularly eat meat but it seems to me that owning any fish is needlessly cruel. Your taking a living breathing animal that can think and feel, ripping it from its environment and putting it in a tiny box so you can have something pretty to look at. 

Goldfish normally have huge amounts of space to swim around in and people will keep them in actually bowls. They're like a house plant they just sit there you feed it and admire it but with a fish, they're more alive and aware they're in a tiny box and normally have a lot more space. I think that owning a dog is different since they actually enjoy being with you, you can walk them and let them see and smell new things. Nobody is taking their fish down to the lake for a little swim. If you locked a human in one small room it doesn't matter how good the room is, you could give them all the games, tv, internet they could ever want and it'd still be cruel. I don't see what a fish has, or doesn't have that makes it perfectly fine to do that exact thing to them. 

I'm all for people owning pets but it just seems like taking an animal that should have a huge amount of space and putting it in a bowl, just so we can look at the pretty colours, is a bit horrifically cruel on the animal and I don't really see any reason to not just outright ban it. That said, if a zoo can provide it as much space as it would normally have or if it's endangered and we want to stop it becoming extinct then they should be allowed to keep them. 

But individual people owning them in small tanks should be banned. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34604363411.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'll start by saying I'm not some kind of extreme animal activist I regularly eat meat but it seems to me that owning any fish is needlessly cruel.

Is your view that factory farming isn’t needlessly cruel, but that owning a fish is?  Given that fish are cognitively simple compared to, say, chickens, and usually not raised an environment that’s outright harmful to them, I don’t think these two positions are easy to reconcile.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604399755.0" user="BowenEdwards" delta="False">
    <text>It is pretty cruel but at least it serves a purpose and feeds people. People own fish for no other reason than to look at them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604445753.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>That *is* a purpose, though—people enjoy watching fish swim around in fish tanks.  Similarly, people enjoy eating meat because of the flavor.  Neither of these things are strictly necessary (at least in developed countries).  People don’t need to keep fish in their home or eat meat in order to live a complete and healthy life.  You could argue that people enjoy eating meat more than then enjoy watching fish, sure, but if you assign any nonzero value to animal welfare, you’re still going have to weigh that greater enjoyment against the much greater suffering that factory farmed animals experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604484296.0" user="BowenEdwards" delta="False">
    <text>You can farm animals for meat in a non-cruel way, we don't but you could. There's no way to own a fish in a fish bowl and it not be cruel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604527012.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>Well, someone in a comment chain above pointed out that you *can* keep fish in a bowl in a way that isn’t cruel.  (Although personally, I’m not sure how cruel ordinary bowls are; I’m not sure whether fish can get bored.)  And yes, you can farm animals in a way that isn’t cruel, but in the case of chickens, for instance, this doesn’t happen &amp;gt;90% of the time.  Why support additional regulations on fish tanks but not on factory farming?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604583618.0" user="BowenEdwards" delta="False">
    <text>If there was a convenient alternative (at least where I live) to factory farming and it didn't cost a ridiculous amount I would use it in a heartbeat but, unfortunately, there isn't. The alternative to owning fish is something anybody could do, give them enough space to not be cruel or don't own one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604746481.0" user="yeahbutforrealtho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;usually not raised an environment that’s outright harmful to them

I don't think that's fair to say. Even slight variations in water temperature or pH level could kill the fish. Keeping a land animal means you're only responsible for good and water and bedding. With a fish, you have to vigilantly manage their entire environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34605316662.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>Fair point—my younger self learned firsthand that it’s not always easy to keep fish alive.  I’m not sure what the conditions of the average fish are like, given how many end up dying.  That said, I wouldn’t say that keeping land animals in good conditions is as easy or as common as you seem to be implying, given that there’s large economic incentives to keep them in poor conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
