<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1057425222.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hhkaiu/cmv_owning_fish_should_be_banned/">
    <title>CMV: Owning fish should be banned</title>
    <original_poster>BowenEdwards</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start by saying I'm not some kind of extreme animal activist I regularly eat meat but it seems to me that owning any fish is needlessly cruel. Your taking a living breathing animal that can think and feel, ripping it from its environment and putting it in a tiny box so you can have something pretty to look at. 

Goldfish normally have huge amounts of space to swim around in and people will keep them in actually bowls. They're like a house plant they just sit there you feed it and admire it but with a fish, they're more alive and aware they're in a tiny box and normally have a lot more space. I think that owning a dog is different since they actually enjoy being with you, you can walk them and let them see and smell new things. Nobody is taking their fish down to the lake for a little swim. If you locked a human in one small room it doesn't matter how good the room is, you could give them all the games, tv, internet they could ever want and it'd still be cruel. I don't see what a fish has, or doesn't have that makes it perfectly fine to do that exact thing to them. 

I'm all for people owning pets but it just seems like taking an animal that should have a huge amount of space and putting it in a bowl, just so we can look at the pretty colours, is a bit horrifically cruel on the animal and I don't really see any reason to not just outright ban it. That said, if a zoo can provide it as much space as it would normally have or if it's endangered and we want to stop it becoming extinct then they should be allowed to keep them. 

But individual people owning them in small tanks should be banned. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34605174971.0" user="paratheking" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't exactly a controversial topic in the fishkeeping community. In the aquariums subreddit, if someone posts a picture of a fish too large for the aquarium it's in there are instantly 5 comments about it. 

Unfortunately there is a lot of misinformation though about what fish need to be happy. For example, a gold fish or betta fish in a bowl is inhumane in my opinion. Both fish need filters and bettas need a water heater. But I do think that basic fish stores (eg Petco) are at least trying to do a little more to provide information about what a fish needs.

I think it is possible to somewhat measure a fish's happiness by its behavior. Is it eating? Is it out and about and exploring? Is it socializing? Is it breeding? If it's exhibiting all its natural tendencies, and its habitat requirements are met, then I believe it is living a happy life. 

I don't agree with taking fish out of the wild, but if they are captive bred and I can give them a good home, then I am okay with doing that. However if I can't give a fish a good hom, then I will let someone else do it who can.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
