<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="106031697.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1r4mkx/i_believe_a_person_shouldnt_intervene_in_a/">
    <title>I believe a person shouldn’t intervene in a suicide, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Binarypunk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Suicide is sad and horrible and I think it is very selfish. It leaves the family and friends questioning everything. I say this because I understand very well the after effects of suicide and in my line of work; I have dealt with a lot of people who have wanted to commit suicide. Over the years I have had some success and some failures in this prevention of suicide. 


But then there are my personal beliefs. I believe in freedom/free will and for personal choice, completely. For the most part it seems as though most everyone believes in personal choice, personal accountability, and the whole concept of “let me be and I’ll let you be”, “I won’t bother you about choices you make as long as you don’t bother me about choices I make” as long as they aren’t illegal. Or at least some level thereof. Eventually the thought has crossed my mind on why is it that suicide is the one choice a person makes where we feel as a collective society we must get involved in that persons personal choice, so much so that we quickly hear about very personal details of their life while talking them out of the choice. How about a harder one? A person who doesn’t want to talk about it and has completely made up their mind to do it, no matter what. We then think it is completely ok to restrain the person and force them into some level of help against their will. 


I’d like to think that for the most part we as a society believe that we should never restrain a person against their will and hold them until we as a society think they are ok to be released, who hasn’t committed a crime.  Except it seems, in the case of suicide. 


One last thing, I think I am not saying we shouldn’t try to help the person. I think I am trying to say that we shouldn’t go out of our way to restrain and hold them against their will. We can talk to them and bring up things that are worth living for and help them see that perhaps the issue at hand isn’t as big as they think it is. But at the end of the day, you can’t be around them 24/7 and we shouldn’t take away their freedoms on a chance that they might take their own life. 


This is a thought in progress, so please be nice and help me change my view.


**EDIT**

A few things I believe for clarity:


-This is for Adults, not underage people, teenage angst is a mental disorder (j/k)


-You should see about talking them out of this choice, but not force them out of this choice


-Religion and culture should never be forced upon another human


-I am also for assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die


-As for mental disorders, just because you have a history of depression doesn’t mean anything to me, we all have been depressed before. If you are bi-polar and taking your meds, then have at it, if you have schizophrenia or personality disorders or have taken mind altering drugs …. I assume you cannot make a decision of your own accord so we should save you.  I will waiver a bit in the mental disorders area, but I do not believe you can say if you commit suicide or try to commit that you have a mental disorder 100% of the time. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26940252260.0" user="bassy7" delta="False">
    <text>This is an insanely complex topic. What about people that are on drugs, that you know will calm down in a few hours? What about 14 year old's having trouble in school? What about people who are recently paralyzed? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940271030.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>Very complex, yes!

 I'll say it like this then, once you are an adult you should be able to make up your mind on things like this to include a paralyzed person. Drugs....? I think I would then say they did break the law since most places don't legally sell drugs. Even in the few countries that do have legal mind altering drugs, I think I might waver and say it'd be ok to intervene.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940347911.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>terminal ill -&amp;gt; suicide ok

guilty of murder/child harm/torture -&amp;gt; suicide ok

over the age of 70 -&amp;gt; suicide ok

.

rules to kill yourself :

no other victims

no property damage

no postmortem hazards (affair in order)


anyone else should be detained till sanity returns or when proper medication can be administered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26941516474.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>I think there are huge problems with the 

&amp;gt;detained till sanity returns

idea. I don't like that. It is still against the persons will. And who makes that decision? That was one of the big issues America had 50+ years ago. People being detained in a mental ward indefinitely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26941674187.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>while it is against the persons will, at that point, it may not be against there will in the long run.

if you want more oversight on the process thats fine, but thats no reason to abandon the concept</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
