<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="106031697.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1r4mkx/i_believe_a_person_shouldnt_intervene_in_a/">
    <title>I believe a person shouldn’t intervene in a suicide, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Binarypunk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Suicide is sad and horrible and I think it is very selfish. It leaves the family and friends questioning everything. I say this because I understand very well the after effects of suicide and in my line of work; I have dealt with a lot of people who have wanted to commit suicide. Over the years I have had some success and some failures in this prevention of suicide. 


But then there are my personal beliefs. I believe in freedom/free will and for personal choice, completely. For the most part it seems as though most everyone believes in personal choice, personal accountability, and the whole concept of “let me be and I’ll let you be”, “I won’t bother you about choices you make as long as you don’t bother me about choices I make” as long as they aren’t illegal. Or at least some level thereof. Eventually the thought has crossed my mind on why is it that suicide is the one choice a person makes where we feel as a collective society we must get involved in that persons personal choice, so much so that we quickly hear about very personal details of their life while talking them out of the choice. How about a harder one? A person who doesn’t want to talk about it and has completely made up their mind to do it, no matter what. We then think it is completely ok to restrain the person and force them into some level of help against their will. 


I’d like to think that for the most part we as a society believe that we should never restrain a person against their will and hold them until we as a society think they are ok to be released, who hasn’t committed a crime.  Except it seems, in the case of suicide. 


One last thing, I think I am not saying we shouldn’t try to help the person. I think I am trying to say that we shouldn’t go out of our way to restrain and hold them against their will. We can talk to them and bring up things that are worth living for and help them see that perhaps the issue at hand isn’t as big as they think it is. But at the end of the day, you can’t be around them 24/7 and we shouldn’t take away their freedoms on a chance that they might take their own life. 


This is a thought in progress, so please be nice and help me change my view.


**EDIT**

A few things I believe for clarity:


-This is for Adults, not underage people, teenage angst is a mental disorder (j/k)


-You should see about talking them out of this choice, but not force them out of this choice


-Religion and culture should never be forced upon another human


-I am also for assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die


-As for mental disorders, just because you have a history of depression doesn’t mean anything to me, we all have been depressed before. If you are bi-polar and taking your meds, then have at it, if you have schizophrenia or personality disorders or have taken mind altering drugs …. I assume you cannot make a decision of your own accord so we should save you.  I will waiver a bit in the mental disorders area, but I do not believe you can say if you commit suicide or try to commit that you have a mental disorder 100% of the time. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26940320028.0" user="BMRMike" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think physically restraining someone from walking under a truck they don't see is wrong as well? The person committing suicide is making a poor decision, demonstrated by people changing their mind quite often. Just like you have no way of knowing whether the man walking under a truck is making a mistake, killing themselves, or actually a street magician doing a trick, you use your best judgement and assume they are making a mistake.  The same logic applies to suicides, if you kill yourself you are most likely making a mistake and so people around you decide to help.

Now I acknowledge the opposite, what about physician assisted suicide and people who we know almost conclusively are not making a mistake in committing suicide (I support this). So I acknowledge that people may have very valid and set decision to end their life, but we currently believe that a majority people committing suicide are making a mistake, either because they will change their mind if forced to consider, or didn't know about options available to them such as Prozac or whatever for schizophrenia. So we act to help them.  

If you believe that a person should be allowed to kill themselves if they can demonstrate that their decision is of their rational mind then I would agree but a person killing themselves in most likely in a condition that would qualify them to be considered unable to make decisions for them.  And saying that depression isn't a mental illness because it is common is the wrong way to look at it. Depression is an illness just like cold or allergies, but we don't do anything about it because you are not a threat to yourself or others. The moment your illness because dangerous that's when we step in. If you have schizophrenia that only resulted in a voice in your head that would compliment you and give you good advice, is that a mental illness? Yes, but we wouldn't do anything about it because it isn't a threat to yourself of others around you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26941525079.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>Good post, thanks. 

The issue I have with your truck analogy is the fact that a person does have a split second decision to make. If they choose to save the person and then the (possible) suicidial person goes to explain they want to kill them selves, then ok. I'd maybe tell them there are cleaner ways of doing it. This example is good to bring up though, because I wouldn't knock anyone for trying to do somethign they see as good when it comes to saving a life, you have two seconds to make a decision. Sometimes bad decisions are made in that amount of time and it's hard to judge people for that. Like that time the person fell in the subway tracks in New York (or where ever that was) and no one did anythign, in fact a photographer took pics. They all had about 10 seconds or less. Your brain has a lot to deal with in those seconds. 

I also like and have never thought of schizophrenia in a positive manner. But as far as depression... what if it's been years and years since your child died and you are still going to their grave every day and crying for an hour each day. People will say you can still get help, and as true as that might be, that person chooses to kill themselves then they can in my book. That sounds horrible now that I'm typing it, but I think I will still go that route. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
