<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="106031697.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1r4mkx/i_believe_a_person_shouldnt_intervene_in_a/">
    <title>I believe a person shouldn’t intervene in a suicide, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Binarypunk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Suicide is sad and horrible and I think it is very selfish. It leaves the family and friends questioning everything. I say this because I understand very well the after effects of suicide and in my line of work; I have dealt with a lot of people who have wanted to commit suicide. Over the years I have had some success and some failures in this prevention of suicide. 


But then there are my personal beliefs. I believe in freedom/free will and for personal choice, completely. For the most part it seems as though most everyone believes in personal choice, personal accountability, and the whole concept of “let me be and I’ll let you be”, “I won’t bother you about choices you make as long as you don’t bother me about choices I make” as long as they aren’t illegal. Or at least some level thereof. Eventually the thought has crossed my mind on why is it that suicide is the one choice a person makes where we feel as a collective society we must get involved in that persons personal choice, so much so that we quickly hear about very personal details of their life while talking them out of the choice. How about a harder one? A person who doesn’t want to talk about it and has completely made up their mind to do it, no matter what. We then think it is completely ok to restrain the person and force them into some level of help against their will. 


I’d like to think that for the most part we as a society believe that we should never restrain a person against their will and hold them until we as a society think they are ok to be released, who hasn’t committed a crime.  Except it seems, in the case of suicide. 


One last thing, I think I am not saying we shouldn’t try to help the person. I think I am trying to say that we shouldn’t go out of our way to restrain and hold them against their will. We can talk to them and bring up things that are worth living for and help them see that perhaps the issue at hand isn’t as big as they think it is. But at the end of the day, you can’t be around them 24/7 and we shouldn’t take away their freedoms on a chance that they might take their own life. 


This is a thought in progress, so please be nice and help me change my view.


**EDIT**

A few things I believe for clarity:


-This is for Adults, not underage people, teenage angst is a mental disorder (j/k)


-You should see about talking them out of this choice, but not force them out of this choice


-Religion and culture should never be forced upon another human


-I am also for assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die


-As for mental disorders, just because you have a history of depression doesn’t mean anything to me, we all have been depressed before. If you are bi-polar and taking your meds, then have at it, if you have schizophrenia or personality disorders or have taken mind altering drugs …. I assume you cannot make a decision of your own accord so we should save you.  I will waiver a bit in the mental disorders area, but I do not believe you can say if you commit suicide or try to commit that you have a mental disorder 100% of the time. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26940274774.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>The vast majority of the time, suicide is not a rational decision, but one made under the skewed judgement of mental illness. 

As such, standing by and letting someone die of it would be just as morally culpable as standing by and letting someone tripping on acid jump out a window because they thought they could fly, or letting someone drive when they're too drink to stand, or hell, letting someone die of anaphylactic shock from a surprise peanut.

If someone's body tries to kill them for no good reason, you do all you can to stop it, because what a tragic, pointless waste of life would that be?

If someone's brain tries to kill them for no good reason... same deal.

I'm all for assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die. I'm just not in favour of standing by and letting a biochemical *glitch* kill someone, just because it managed to compromise their volition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940298151.0" user="owightman" delta="False">
    <text>This is an extremely good point. Hope OP gets in a good reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940299173.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>I assume your stance with assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die is with physical harm a person can then make that choice; loss of legs, arms, cancer, AIDS etc. 

What if I just don't want to live anymore and I am 100% physically healthy? I do not want to live if I am not able to live with my wife who is now dead. or, I do not want to live if my multi-million dollar corporation is now under investigation, and well.... ya know.... I did some book fixing and I just don't want to go to jail. 

I understand your point, but I do not believe it is ALWAYS a mental illness. And to treat it as such, all the time isn't good either.

 I've had people tell me that they don't want to live out their entire life taking a 'happy pill' to help fix the biochemical *glitch*. They are only happy when taking meds that mess with their emotions making them happy. It's good but it's fake. I've had several people tell me that. Should we tell them, too bad. If I let you stop taking those meds and you get depressed and kill yourself its the same as if I had let you drive drunk?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940490921.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You make some good points, and I'll agree with you on one: it is potentially plausible for a perfectly rational person to make the choice to end their life.

The biggest thing I've noticed about this subreddit in general is that people have good thoughts and beliefs, but don't necessarily look at the overall societal benefits and costs of such an idea.  

My argument back to you is simple: While it's true this will allow the rational individuals to end their lives, that number is an extremely tiny minority, and this kind of social policy will necessarily lead to more people dying who don't need to or should die.

Basically, if I see someone about to commit suicide, it is better for everyone if I assume that they aren't behaving rationally and stop it than to assume they are being rational.  Most likely, they are being irrational, and by assuming they are, many more lives will end than need be.

If in a perfect world, we automatically knew everything about a person's internal mental state, than your social policy could work.  Unfortunately, we don't, and we must make assumptions.  There is much greater benefit than cost in assuming a person is behaving irrationally than rationally, and there is much greater cost than benefit for assuming someone is rational.

Also, I understand people tell you they don't want to live their life on "happy pills."  Unfortunately, I don't think these people actually have a complete understanding of what the pills do.  The pills don't make someone "happy."  They clear away the irrational biological fog of constant depression.  A person can be sad and upset when on anti-depressants, but the sadness is rational rather than irrational.  These people may feel like they're "happy drugs," but it's only because they've come to assume that unhappiness is the default, and living in a state that's not unhappiness is unnatural.  This is just an incorrect understanding about the human condition more than anything else.  These people need to talk to therapists so they can better understand that these drugs just balance out the chemicals in their brain so their emotions can be rational rather than purely biologically driven.  

It's good to have empathy for people suffering for depression, but I don't think it's fair to accept the "happy pills" discussion on its face.  They're not happy pills, that's not what they do for the body, that's not how they operate, and a person that thinks so simply does not understand how their brain and emotions are supposed to work as a default.  

Let me stress one more time: pills do **NOT** mess with your emotions.  They balance chemicals in your brain so that you are capable of actually feeling normal emotions that you can't otherwise have.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26941504056.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>I like this post the most... I will give this more thought and reply later. Thanks for a good post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
