<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="106031697.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1r4mkx/i_believe_a_person_shouldnt_intervene_in_a/">
    <title>I believe a person shouldn’t intervene in a suicide, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Binarypunk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Suicide is sad and horrible and I think it is very selfish. It leaves the family and friends questioning everything. I say this because I understand very well the after effects of suicide and in my line of work; I have dealt with a lot of people who have wanted to commit suicide. Over the years I have had some success and some failures in this prevention of suicide. 


But then there are my personal beliefs. I believe in freedom/free will and for personal choice, completely. For the most part it seems as though most everyone believes in personal choice, personal accountability, and the whole concept of “let me be and I’ll let you be”, “I won’t bother you about choices you make as long as you don’t bother me about choices I make” as long as they aren’t illegal. Or at least some level thereof. Eventually the thought has crossed my mind on why is it that suicide is the one choice a person makes where we feel as a collective society we must get involved in that persons personal choice, so much so that we quickly hear about very personal details of their life while talking them out of the choice. How about a harder one? A person who doesn’t want to talk about it and has completely made up their mind to do it, no matter what. We then think it is completely ok to restrain the person and force them into some level of help against their will. 


I’d like to think that for the most part we as a society believe that we should never restrain a person against their will and hold them until we as a society think they are ok to be released, who hasn’t committed a crime.  Except it seems, in the case of suicide. 


One last thing, I think I am not saying we shouldn’t try to help the person. I think I am trying to say that we shouldn’t go out of our way to restrain and hold them against their will. We can talk to them and bring up things that are worth living for and help them see that perhaps the issue at hand isn’t as big as they think it is. But at the end of the day, you can’t be around them 24/7 and we shouldn’t take away their freedoms on a chance that they might take their own life. 


This is a thought in progress, so please be nice and help me change my view.


**EDIT**

A few things I believe for clarity:


-This is for Adults, not underage people, teenage angst is a mental disorder (j/k)


-You should see about talking them out of this choice, but not force them out of this choice


-Religion and culture should never be forced upon another human


-I am also for assisted suicide, living wills, euthanasia and the right to die


-As for mental disorders, just because you have a history of depression doesn’t mean anything to me, we all have been depressed before. If you are bi-polar and taking your meds, then have at it, if you have schizophrenia or personality disorders or have taken mind altering drugs …. I assume you cannot make a decision of your own accord so we should save you.  I will waiver a bit in the mental disorders area, but I do not believe you can say if you commit suicide or try to commit that you have a mental disorder 100% of the time. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26940263173.0" user="owightman" delta="False">
    <text>In many countries and many cultural and religious traditions, suicide is actually against the law. Would you try to prevent a robbery? I guess legally and impartially without any consideration of the emotion this is the logic behind intervening. When you think about it, preventing someone from breaking the law on a broad spectrum can be considered the right thing to do. 

Possibly irrelevant, but it also happens that many people disagree with the need for suicide (think 'there's always help'), and so intervening is an extension of their own views, which helpfully tend to align with the rulings of common law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940273428.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>It's against the law to commit suicide? What is the punishment?

The same religious traditions may not be held by the person who is wanting to commit suicide. So you are imposing your religious/cultural belief on this person. I think that is wrong.

I'm not sure I understand this common law piece. But I would still say that intervening especially as an extension of a persons own views is wrong. You would then be applying your own version of right and wrong and morality on that person. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940278342.0" user="owightman" delta="False">
    <text>My apologies. I put a lot of useless arguments in there. 

Cultural/religious/ moral grounds should not matter. But legal grounds do. Yes, countries do prohibit suicide. Canada, for example ( on mobile, can't provide link, sorry). Obviously you cannot punish someone for it, but I would guess that one if the reasons it remains illegal may be to justify the prevention of suicide itself. Just my thoughts. 

Great question! Thanks for the good responding 

Edit: spellign</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940294901.0" user="Binarypunk" delta="False">
    <text>I guess my only actual response would be that it shouldn't be illegal.

Not to get too far off topic but several criminology studies show level of punishment doesn't deter crime. People will about always do a risk to cost analysis. It may be illegal to drive 5 MPH over the limit but there are times you do, because the risk of being caught isn't high enough for you to not do it. So risk to cost analysis of committing suicide isn't too bad. I'm not paying the fine if I'm dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940438554.0" user="CarnivorousGiraffe" delta="False">
    <text>I think making it illegal is just a way to permit immediate intervention if a person is currently attempting suicide.  It isn't about punishment or deterrence, it's just about legal justification for stopping that guy over there from jumping off the bridge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26940611906.0" user="jsmooth7" delta="False">
    <text>Not that I disagree with your overall point, but suicide is not illegal in Canada [anymore](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_legislation#Canada).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
