<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1062071645.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hkbvq5/cmv_youtube_was_right_in_agerestricting_prager_us/">
    <title>CMV: YouTube was right in age-restricting Prager U's videos because a significant portion of their audience were children that didn't know better.</title>
    <original_poster>AneurysmicKidney</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL:DR: &amp;gt;!PragerU was targeting a young audience that didn't understand what they were watching, and YouTube was right in age restricting PragerU's videos.!&amp;lt;

PragerU, a far right-wing media outlet popular on YouTube had it's videos age-restricted by YouTube so that only users &amp;gt;15 years old could watch them.

PragerU claimed that YouTube was censoring them and responded by suing YouTube on the grounds that they were behaving like a publisher while enjoying the protections of a platform.

(The following story should is and should be treated as an anecdote. Because the demographic data of PragerU's viewer base is not public information, this is all I have to go on.)

When I was younger (~9) I came across a video titled "[The] War on Boys". Being a boy myself, I had clicked on the video because of the title and the cartoonish graphics in the thumbnail. Being just over five minutes long, it was perfect for my young, short, attention span.

I have since forgotten the content of the video, but because videos from the same channel as the one you're currently watching are more likely to get suggested, I clicked on a few more blue-background cartoons.

I remember seeing Ben Shapiro, and through the next 3 years I would think of him as some sort of Genius who was always right, because of his childish argument strategies and constant insulting.

I have since disengrained the bullshit that PragerU puts out from my head, but I believe that they were targeting a younger audience with their cartoon drawings, short videos, and simple arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34633305419.0" user="Morasain" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say the same about a hypothetical similar left wing channel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34633325690.0" user="AneurysmicKidney" delta="False">
    <text>Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34634429254.0" user="Xakire" delta="False">
    <text>If it was hypothetically as false and misleading as PragerU, sure. For me at least the biggest Ed issue with PragerU is that it’s just a massive display of sophistry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636906772.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If it was hypothetically as false and misleading as PragerU, sure

If you think your average breadtube channel isn’t as much of a propaganda push I have a bridge in Russia to sell you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34637083840.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>Name a lefty channel you think is comparable to prager?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34637181641.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Xexizy, Tovarishch Endymion, ABCs of Communism, Socialist Education, Socialism Or Barbarism!. Are all legit Soviet Union apologists, something I’d consider far  worse than what prager does.

RichardDWolf, is  roughly parallel to Prague in terms of being skeevy propaganda with idiotic takes that get more respect than it deserves.

The Young Turks is less far left but still has blatant disregard for facts and a genocide denialist front man.

Secular Talk has absolutely brain dead takes on politics that deserve an honorable mention just for getting idiots to agree with em</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
