<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1062071645.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hkbvq5/cmv_youtube_was_right_in_agerestricting_prager_us/">
    <title>CMV: YouTube was right in age-restricting Prager U's videos because a significant portion of their audience were children that didn't know better.</title>
    <original_poster>AneurysmicKidney</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL:DR: &amp;gt;!PragerU was targeting a young audience that didn't understand what they were watching, and YouTube was right in age restricting PragerU's videos.!&amp;lt;

PragerU, a far right-wing media outlet popular on YouTube had it's videos age-restricted by YouTube so that only users &amp;gt;15 years old could watch them.

PragerU claimed that YouTube was censoring them and responded by suing YouTube on the grounds that they were behaving like a publisher while enjoying the protections of a platform.

(The following story should is and should be treated as an anecdote. Because the demographic data of PragerU's viewer base is not public information, this is all I have to go on.)

When I was younger (~9) I came across a video titled "[The] War on Boys". Being a boy myself, I had clicked on the video because of the title and the cartoonish graphics in the thumbnail. Being just over five minutes long, it was perfect for my young, short, attention span.

I have since forgotten the content of the video, but because videos from the same channel as the one you're currently watching are more likely to get suggested, I clicked on a few more blue-background cartoons.

I remember seeing Ben Shapiro, and through the next 3 years I would think of him as some sort of Genius who was always right, because of his childish argument strategies and constant insulting.

I have since disengrained the bullshit that PragerU puts out from my head, but I believe that they were targeting a younger audience with their cartoon drawings, short videos, and simple arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34633489214.0" user="BoyMeetsTheWorld" delta="False">
    <text>My argument would be that YouTube should not have the possibility to decide what to show on their platform. They should be classified as a public utility like a telephone company because they have a very dominant position in the market. As such they should only remove or restrict videos according to local laws.

While I have no sympathy for PragerU I find the current status of Google/Facebook/Apple/Amazon/Microsoft unacceptable and they have a point that those firms currently get the best of both worlds with little-to-none downsides for them.

For smaller sites I think we can leave the status quo atm. But for very dominant market players the system breaks down. I argue the same thing for banks or credit card companies that they should not be able to cut off Wikileaks for example unless they are ordered by law to do so.

Edit: I find it also really funny that PragerU sues YouTube because I would assume that PragerU usually is for a radical free market with free right of association? But while that would make them hypocrites it does not make YouTube correct.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
