<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34668802994.0" user="CozyAndToasty" delta="False">
    <text>Oh this is a fun one.

Let me preface this by saying that I am a scientist by practice but agnostic by belief.

Astrology is not necessarily non-sense. I should say not necessarily complete non-sense. It is a complicated system with a lot left to interpretation. It isn't impossible that one such interpretation can, by chance, accurately describe the causal relationships of the universe or at least some significant part of it.

Our universe's inner workings are unknown to us and the best we can do is make a guess or "model" based on the phenomenon we observe. Astrology, science, and many other religions are simply models explaining our observations. The model might be wrong and we will probably never arrive at the one true model of the universe, that is the unattainable objective truth described in philosophy.

A model produced by science isn't that much better than the model provided by astrology. Science just cheats a little by constantly rewriting itself. It'd be like changing the answer every time to make a mistake. There's also compelling reason for us to rule out the model provided by astrology to be coincidentally the objective truth.

Astrology's success can also itself be treated as an observable phenomenon that can be further explained by science. By being the observation, it can serve to better help us understand the nature of the universe even it doesn't completely explain the universe on its own.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
