<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34665834252.0" user="TheBigFish89" delta="False">
    <text>Not a defense of astrology but there's no smoke without fire: The Moon does have an indirect effect on some organisms behaviour, horseshoe crabs mating habits are affected by the Lunar cycle and it's effects on the tides for example.

I'm not sure when astrology was created, I'm not an expert, but Google informs me it was over 2400 years ago.

I don't think it's a stretch to imagine someone back then observing the lunar cycle having an affect on some animals and then making an assumption that it also affects humans, and then astrology just evolving from there to observing people's behaviour compared to the position of the objects in the sky, effectively becoming an ancient science. Maybe it happened a different way, but you understand my general point.

I realize this doesn't really refute your view, but it's just to make a point that it's likely originally based on an incorrect interpretation of a real phenomenon. 
And obviously there's always a section of the population that believes that because something is ancient, it must be true.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
