<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34661305972.0" user="plushiemancer" delta="False">
    <text>I found something

https://www.quora.com/How-do-zodiac-signs-affect-our-personality

tl;dr humans are made of combination of 5 elements, which affects the personality. Astral objects also have their own combination of elements. Their position when a person is born influence that person's elemental makeup, therefore influencing a person's personality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661484938.0" user="Evening_Resource" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;humans are made of combination of 5 elements

That's not true though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661524345.0" user="plushiemancer" delta="False">
    <text>I never said it is. OP is asking for astrology's justification to astrology. I gave it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661599138.0" user="GSGhostTrain" delta="False">
    <text>This is the exact point I was making, though. These aren't justifications, they are just claims. 

" Human also made of star dust or 5 basic element which is air, fire, water, earth, ether. so particular position of planet for example Mars is dominated by Fire element so it affects the person by its element and decide how can that person behave and how he develop his personality."

There's very clearly a missing step between the initial assertion and the stated outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661877178.0" user="plushiemancer" delta="False">
    <text>you are asking an unanswerable question.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MO0r930Sn_8

The example use magnets, but it applies to most things. The only reason you should think astrology is nonsensical is due to lack of evidence, NOT due to lack of complete understanding of "why does it work". otherwise it's going to lead to the false conclusion that "magnet is nonsensical"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34662442902.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>The justification is just more nonsense. So it counters nothing to OP's view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34662477259.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34665919409.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/Franks_Fluids_Inc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+Franks_Fluids_Inc&amp;amp;message=Franks_Fluids_Inc+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/-/fx956mj/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
