<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34662978619.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34671794593.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/alexjaness – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+alexjaness&amp;amp;message=alexjaness+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/-/fx9fxh7/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
