<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34661388857.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>This is this way. [Astrology is 2.2 billion dollar industry](https://www.google.com/search?sxsrf=ALeKk01-5ifuq8Gtijlw9YqjECWdUonBtw%3A1594149590454&amp;amp;ei=1soEX66dG43urgSQ9pTQCA&amp;amp;q=astrology+industry+worth&amp;amp;oq=astrology+industry+worth&amp;amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzIFCCEQoAE6BwgAEEcQsAM6AggAOgYIABAWEB46CAghEBYQHRAeUMUbWMwhYIwjaAFwAHgAgAF4iAGnBJIBAzYuMZgBAKABAaoBB2d3cy13aXq4AQI&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiu4LqA7rvqAhUNt4sKHRA7BYoQ4dUDCAw&amp;amp;uact=5). So while their predictions etc. are nonsense it's very convincing and good in selling itself. Marketers can learn a lot from astrology and it's not nonsensical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661398031.0" user="GSGhostTrain" delta="False">
    <text>This feels more like an argument that marketing isn't nonsensical. You can market the shit out of anything, regardless of whether it's logical. FWIW, I agree with you though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34664502398.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Let's thing astrology as a product. While the product don't have any scientific proof it works people still buy it. But it's not because of marketing. It's because product itself is so well designed that people buy it. I don't see ad campaigns for star maps but they sell very well. So good qualities are in the product itself and not in the marketing.

Basically astrology (as a product) is well designed to appeal to certain demographic that is willing to pay good money for it. This product design is something that can be learned from. Not the 50 cent adds in the news papers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
