<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1066588137.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hn0oo9/cmv_astrology_is_nonsensical/">
    <title>CMV: Astrology is nonsensical.</title>
    <original_poster>GSGhostTrain</original_poster>
    <original_post>To head off some initial arguments, I want to be clear that I understand many, many people engage in astrology as a sort of fun "horoscope only" type of activity. That's fine, and I don't begrudge anyone that. However, having encountered some people who buy further into it, including star charts for significant others being required, or making decisions based on astrological positions, I have always struggled to understand this belief. 

To date, I have never heard an explanation of *why* the position of the stars and planets would have any bearing on mood, personality, behavior, or anything else beyond potentially the weather -- only what the supposed effects *are*. I would like to better understand what the supposed causal chain is between the positioning of the planets and verifiable outcomes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34661307880.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Placebo effect, If you believe in it, it will work. 

As a concrete example, if you believe that you act more irrationally during a full moon, then you will. Similarly, if your care giver believes that the full moon causes you to act crazier, then they will report more instances of misbehavior during the full moon. 

As such, there are more incidents of violence in mental health institutions during the full moon, in some cultures, because either the patients believe they will be worse, or the nurses believe the patients will act worse. 

Lunacy is real, if you believe it. But the cause isn't the moon, it's your own belief in lunacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34661334727.0" user="GSGhostTrain" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the placebo effect is real. As to full moons, that's an interesting point -- my parents worked in mental hospitals, and they both attested to the full moon definitely being the worst time in the units. 

All of that said, it only shows that the placebo effect isn't nonsense. It doesn't combat the main view.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
