<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34712172042.0" user="AfricanToto" delta="False">
    <text>I'm obviously an outlier, but I think we should be able to say faggot, retarded, the N'word, ect., but ban using it in hateful ways. People always point out that it's hard to tell when people are being serious, but honestly it really isn't you can tell by their inflection, body language, who its directed at and the context it's used. If its used in art, conversation, or simply saying the word its unreasonable to say that person is hate filled or using it as such. 

Completely banning words or ostracizing people for using them just gives bigoted assholes a very flimsy argument that their rights are being restricted. Your rights end when they infringe on other peoples rights, that's the way it's supposed to work anyway. Idk why people don't see a difference in a racist using the N-word  to talk shit about black people and some stupid white kid singing along to a song. 

The communities of their respective slur have obviously taken back their words. I've heard gay people call themselves fags and do it proudly, which is good. Many gay people were obviously hurt by that word growing up. You know who else was, me as a straight male, I got called fag for 3 straight years, and it made me question my identity and made me depressed as hell. Even as a 12 year old I knew the difference as someone calling me that as a joke, and when someone meant it harmfully, its not hard to tell at all. If it is hard to tell and it hurts you, you should simply ask them to not say that, and if they don't stop you know it was meant harmfully. 

I guess what I'm saying is I kind of agree with you, but when people are straight up saying likes kill these N-words, then saying muh FrEe SPeeCh, its obviously meant with ill intent and should not be tolerated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34713121033.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
