<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34713248896.0" user="CocoSavege" delta="False">
    <text>What's your take on Google guy?

He was expressing controversial opinions (or however you might characterize them) and after such expression he was fired.

I'm curious because he's an example of opinions freely expressed and his opinions reflected poorly on him, at least from Google's POV.

I've definitely heard people opine that he was unfairly treated, and he should be allowed to express his opinions about workplace culture and negative consequences (such as getting fired) have a chilling effect on individual opinions and conscience.

I disagree 100% myself, AFAICT Google made the correct move. His opinions cast serious shadow on his ability to do his job, work with his team members, cast doubt on his rigour with respect to application of science and demonstrated poor discretion with representing the brand of Google.  

So, what are your thoughts on the context of a controversial opinion with respect to what, when, where, 
how etc?  

Another parallel example might be a pharmacist refusing to provide birth control because of religious convictions.

And of course Gay wedding cakes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34715974378.0" user="yunyun333" delta="False">
    <text>It was an internal memo, and the science is much less clear than anyone would like it to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720081223.0" user="CocoSavege" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure how it matters if it was (meant to be) an internal memo.  Google guy was speaking his mind to his co-workers.  I guess we should interpret the tone consistent with generalized expectations of internal memos @ Google but i wouldn't know where to start.

Re: Science.  It's not even that "the science" is fuzzy, it's his approach to sourcing and interpreting whatever science is available.  Google guy actually has a Masters in something sciencey and was pursuing a PhD before googling.

As such it's pretty poor form that his sciencing was lacking rigor.  I can't read his mind but it feels like he was post hoc appropriating "science" as scaffolding to support an ideology.

https://medium.com/@tweetingmouse/the-truth-has-got-its-boots-on-what-the-evidence-says-about-mr-damores-google-memo-bc93c8b2fdb9

Thats a long read and takes a while to get into the dirt.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
