<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34711332941.0" user="zeratul98" delta="False">
    <text>Cool, let's talk about "cancel culture"

At it's core, the idea here is to remove hateful people's power and platforms. I totally agree with you, there's limits to what's okay here, attacking innocent family members is usually too far. But what is cancel culture often doing?

One is trying to remove them from the platform they're using to spread hate. As you said, free speech is not freedom from consequences, but it's also not an obligation for others to provide someone with a platform. You wouldn't let a Nazi fly a flag on your house, why should Twitter allow them to spread hate on their platform? This is usually where the slippery slope or "where do you draw the line" arguments come in. It is a little tricky because Twitter is, in some regards, the equivalent to getting on a soapbox in the town square. But we can generally agree on some rules of what should not be allowed. In fact, we already have. You can express hate towards a group, but explicitly inciting violence towards them is illegal. It is not protected speech. Tweets calling for violence or explicitly expressing extreme forms of hate can and should be taken down. It's not as slippery of a slope as it seems. There's clear rules ("no violence, not hate speech"), clear reasons (protecting vulnerable groups), and clear limits. Almost all content will fall obviously on one side or the other. The gray bits will be rare, but can and should be challengeable by both sides. 

The other part of cancel culture is removing people from positions of power. Sometimes this is simple consequences. If you want to scream racial slurs at protestors, go ahead, but you'll be out a job. Equality and a better society is the carrot. Consequences and firings is the stick. This is even more important for those whose jobs involve power over people's lives. Politicians, professors, CEOs, police officers, etc. Their hateful views can and do manifest in their actions, and they will limit the growth of or actively hurt the people they have power over. Equality comes in part through removing barriers, sometimes those barriers are assholes in power. 

So it's not really that much of an infringement of liberties. Remember that you really can't give someone liberties without infringing on someone else's at least a little. The right to do whatever the hell you want also means taking away the right to be protected from other people. In order to have a free and open society, people need to be free from prejudicial abuses. That comes at the expense of some minor and reasonable checks on speech. Ones which we have already had for ages, and just not chosen to enforce when hate and violence is directed at vulnerable groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711444760.0" user="mslindqu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can express hate towards a group, but explicitly inciting violence towards them is illegal.

&amp;gt;or explicitly expressing extreme forms of hate

&amp;gt;chosen to enforce when hate and violence

You say one thing, but then slip in a contradiction a couple times.  I don't know the specifics of the laws, but it's frustrating when the description of the laws starts out by saying hate is allowed, and then injecting this idea that 'extreme hate' is impermissible.  I thought violence was the limit, not some arbitrary level of hate.  It's the arbitration people have a problem with I think.  It's hypocritical.  Now if the law defines some level of hate that is the limit fine, but that isn't what you said, and I'm not sure how they'd do that.  

No violence, no promoting violence.. Most people are gonna be good with that.  Now, let's talk about how hard it is to skew anything you like into 'promoting violence'.  (And vice versa, how easy it is to promote violence in a way that doesn't seem like it)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712084963.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>The latter two lines you quote weren't referring to the law. The second line was about Twitter policy and the third, I think, was about social norms.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
