<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34711183831.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm surprised with an absolutist view of free speech you don't mention exceptions. If I gave some situations where free expression should NOT be allowed and you agreed would that get a delta?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711226350.0" user="Dankletron" delta="False">
    <text>It would depend if the context is relevant. Do I believe it should be illegal to shout "fire!" in a crowded theater? Of course. But there are few if any situations where I would say someone should be forbidden from stating something publicly. I may vehemently disagree with them, but I respect their right to say it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711375524.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>They aren't forbidden from saying it though. You're advocating no social consequences though. Should I not have a right to state my opinion about someone I disagree with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711378450.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Ah dang so not quite absolutist.

What about, "It is my opinion that the /insert high ranking political figure/ should be murdered"?

I can think of several other calls to violence which I don't think should be legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711455974.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>It shouldn’t be illegal to yell fire in a theater.  Situations like that should be handled like libel laws.  If someone yells fire knowing there is not one, then they would be guilty of a similar thing to defaming someone when they know their statements to be false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711517692.0" user="3superfrank" delta="False">
    <text>The point I think is more of how your 'right' protects you from laws.

For example, if there's a law saying its illegal to critisize X, your freedom of speech should protect you from being prosecuted on that charge.

Its yelling fire in the theater, which is an exception to said rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711523730.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>So the crime would be inciting panic. Not yelling fire.  I tho k were saying the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711535755.0" user="3superfrank" delta="False">
    <text>That's my understanding of it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712220039.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But you incited panic with just words, so *absolute* free speech would protect you. The issue is free speech isn’t the *only* right, and often rights can overlap (in this case the right to free speech overlaps the right to safety in a public space, and most would agree the latter is more important to protect than the former)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712278558.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with that view is when people say, “well speech is violence”... Speech can be graphic and violent... it can never be actual violence.  So the problem with saying that rights overlap is that today’s world people are ridiculous, and a simple difference in opinion will cause people to claim it is violence toward them or that it makes them unsafe.  

The only time free speech should be supeceded as a right is if there is immediate physical harm that follows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712354304.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, that’s what I’m saying. You can go for either extreme by saying *all* speech is violent, or for the other and say *no* speech is violent, or you draw an arbitrary line. 

Even you did so at the end, by adding the “immediate physical harm” clause: to what extent do we assign blame? If a politician says how much a certain group is to blame for all the countries problems, and then immeadiately after there’s a surge in hate crimes, this would arguably fall under your definition. 

You may say that this doesn’t count, since the politician here didn’t actually order this violence, and it was the perpetrators fault for being morons and listening. But how far does our hypothetical politician need to go to be at fault? If he actually says: “we need to kill them all, today, at [location] at [time]”, then that would definitely fall under your caveat of “immeadiate physical harm” but how close to an explicit order do we need to go to be actually *at fault* and therefore no longer protected by free speech?

This isn’t to say your definition is necessarily wrong, but I’m saying we can still have free speech even if we have to draw an arbitrary line in the interest of a functioning society and the safety of the public, right?

(And addressing your point about a difference of opinion being classed as violence, this is a view held by a small minority, and definitely is not what the general public would class as hate speech)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712392799.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue the politician situation would not be immediate harm.  You could define immediacy as temporal and spatial.  So a politician saying something and then people doing something at a different location would not be ‘immediate’.

And the specific date and time example would be illegal not because of the words said, but because that is conspiracy to commit murder.  

But I do respect what you’re saying.  It’s a conundrum, which I why I think you should always err on the side of allowing the speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34712617181.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for considering that.

Expanding on your last paragraph, why *always* err on *allowing* speech? 

I mean there are certainly situations (such as the extreme example I gave) where it would be best to err against speech.

Not to say always, but I don’t think either route is correct even in the vast majority of cases, and such things need to be decided on a case by case basis (like almost everything)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34713026412.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree.  I honestly don’t think there are many situation when speech can actually do damage.  And I would rather have freedom win.

Take for example Shaun King.  He tweets out recently that Jesus is a manifestation of white supremacy.  Then you have that guy on the airplane going crazy and you have that statue of the Virgin Mary being burnt.  Both incidents are terrible. But I would not want Shaun kings speech to be limited.  If any legal action comes, is should be against the perpetrators of the violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34715531659.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, fair enough. But would you agree to *non-legal* consequences to such forms of speech? Such as being deplatformed from major social media, boycotts etc? I think that would be a fair solution, as it wouldn’t at all infringe on his rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34717034334.0" user="Muahd_Dib" delta="False">
    <text>People are free to boycott whatever they want.  Social media as a private company can do whatever they want. 

But I am slightly sympathetic to the idea that social media banning people for speech makes them a publisher not a platform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711266305.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>Remember for your examples, he's talking about statements of opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
