<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34711401286.0" user="stylusrose" delta="False">
    <text>[The paradox of tolerance states that if a society is tolerant without limit, its ability to be tolerant is eventually seized or destroyed by the intolerant.](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paradox_of_tolerance)

I'm all for protecting controversial opinions, if they're constructive. But, we can't be tolerant of people that use their opinions to hurt others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34713470468.0" user="Sililex" delta="False">
    <text>The paradox of tolerance is clever wordplay, but it breaks down if you just ask the question, "who decides who is intolerant?". If you'd had that standard of public discourse in the 40's, you would have never had the gay or civil rights movement. Like, it's a nice theoretical principle, but then so is eugenics or qualifying to vote, they're ruined by their implementation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34714660251.0" user="stylusrose" delta="False">
    <text>What you said is a good example of tolerating intolerance. Things got real bad because people were intolerant of black people and minorities, and the gay community, and now the trans community.

Every little bit of intolerance they face keeps them down, in a box, or even painted as degenerate criminals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34714728796.0" user="Sililex" delta="False">
    <text>But as per the social beliefs of someone in the 40's, being discriminatory against minorities isn't intolerance but pragmatism. These people *genuinely believed these behaviours/people were harmful*. There is no non-biased test for what is "intolerance". Intolerance is a word that's meaning is relative to societal norms. Lincoln was radically tolerant for his time, but would be a bigot today. Any dislike of anyone can be classed as an intolerance under the right framing. Giving the tools to people to decide what is and isn't intolerant speech isn't something I believe we should do. It locks us in a particular social framing, and gives too much power over public discourse to a minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34714894542.0" user="stylusrose" delta="False">
    <text>The intolerance lead to a lot more intolerance and pain though. Imagine the minorities trying to be tolerant of somebody who would not tolerate them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34719238685.0" user="Sililex" delta="False">
    <text>But my point is that sentence needs to be interpreted by human beings if we're making it a matter of policy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
