<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34713607536.0" user="The_PracticalOne" delta="False">
    <text>Here's the thing. Free speech is not what most people think it is, legally speaking. That constitutional amendment does one thing and one thing only. It stops the government, no one else, just the government; from persecuting you based on what you say, what you look like, and what you believe (as well as some other stuff like freedom of assembly). It does not stop individuals or private businesses from disagreeing with you, it does not stop them from firing you for your behavior, boycotting your business, etc. nor should it.

Even if we just talk about free speech in the non-legal way; Free speech shouldn't infringe on public health or rights. It does not give you, for example, the ability to yell at a grocery store clerk due to their anti mask rule. It should not harm a community, like saying all jews are evil, or that all people of color are dumb. These reinforce incorrect and negative stereotypes that harm communities and individuals. Free speech should not mean spreading misinformation.

It's so much easier to practice free speech now than it ever has been. Literally anybody can find like-minded people on the internet. Even illegal, and blatantly, morally, wrong forms of speech, like pedophilia find homes online. No one is being censored. It's not like they have no outlet to express these feelings. No one is going to be arrested for saying that a black man is a lesser life form (even if I wish upon them an eternity of squished, topping-less, pizza every time they order one, for having this view.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
