<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1073570521.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hr6cbd/cmv_free_speech_and_the_right_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Free speech and the right to express controversial opinions must be protected (and should be respected) in a free and open society.</title>
    <original_poster>Dankletron</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a touchy subject right now, but it's one I've been struggling with recently as a result. Let me start by fully acknowledging that freedom of speech does not equate freedom from consequences. 99% of the time, I fully stand behind that philosophy. That said, I believe that "cancel culture", doxxing, and the current intolerance amongst some on the left of any free speech deemed to be hateful, ignorant, or highly controversial is, at it's core, unproductive and antithetical to the very democratic ideals that allowed many of those movements arise and build consensus in the first place.

What is deemed an appropriate or "acceptable" opinion has always been defined by the culture and zeitgeist of the times, but opposition to such opinions should revolve around public debate and political and economic disengagement (i.e. boycotts, voting, removal of media platforms, etc). What it should not entail is a rage-fueled vendetta against someone with the explicit or implicit intent of inflicting suffering and lasting, personal harm (like, for example, having the private details of them and their family blasted across the internet).

This creates a culture where only some people get to decide what is an acceptable opinion and I worry that this a slippery slope. I'll be the first to admit that America is *far* from perfect, but what has often separated us from other countries is our shared belief in protected free speech and the right to express it. And there will always be consequences to such speech, but those consequences should  involve resistance to the content of the speech and the platforms that support it, not some spite-fueled attempt to ruin another person's life (deplorable as that person may be). This only fuels a devolving tit for tat that endangers (what I feel) are the very tenets of a free and open society.

I would love hear your thoughts. For the record, I'm a progressive and am very left-leaning myself. I believe we need systemic change in America and that speaking truth to power is how we get there. I just worry that the rhetoric and backlash on the left right now towards those who disagree is endangering some of the very values that progressive, liberal democracy stands for.

If my right to free speech is protected and celebrated, then so should yours.

\*EDIT: typo</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34711230997.0" user="probsgettingdownvote" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re disagreeing with human rights, if you’re saying racial slurs, or slurs in general to people in public, if you are coughing on people during a pandemic because you refuse to wear a mask, or any of the other things people have been doxxed for, you’re not just having a controversial opinion, you did the action. 

A huge example would be the Karen in the park lady from a few months ago. Her calling the cops on that black man wasn’t just a controversial opinion. She put that opinion into action by lying to the police and trying to intentionally get someone hurt or arrested. 

Another example would be the two high schoolers from Tik Tok who were using the n-word and saying a bunch of racial stereotypes. This lead to them being kicked out of school. And colleges taking back their letters of acceptance. There was no other way they could’ve been “punished” for their actions but that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711266824.0" user="forsakensleep" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear, what do you mean by disagreeing with human rights? Other examples make sense, but 'disagreeing with human right' is too vague. For example, most people do not consider those who advocate capital punishment having detrimental actions that need punishment just because they advocate violation of right to live.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711297041.0" user="probsgettingdownvote" delta="False">
    <text>“Systematic racism doesn’t exist” “Gay people have the same rights as everyone else” “Black people aren’t treated differently” “Racism doesn’t exist” “Saying the n-word isn’t that bad” 

People that say thinks like that are definitely against human rights as a whole. I don’t think I’ve ever seen someone say right out “I don’t agree with human rights” but it is always obvious with their argument points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711346962.0" user="forsakensleep" delta="False">
    <text>Why are those words against human right? They are of course false, but that doesn't mean they are denying the existence of human right. People can truly think there isn't any problem due to simple ignorance. "Racism against black people doesn't exist" and "Black people do not deserve equal right as white people" are entirely different sentences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711369539.0" user="probsgettingdownvote" delta="False">
    <text>It’s hard to explain and I wish I could tag specific examples. I’ve discussed with people here before and I said I had dreadlocks and could be fired because of it. They said my natural “messy ass” hair should be a reason for me to lose my job. I hope that explains it better. It’s hard to pull exact examples but every time I’ve had a discussion with someone and they say any of those things it always ends with black people and white people have the same opportunities or gay people aren’t discriminated against which isn’t true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711405916.0" user="forsakensleep" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry for hearing that, but I think people should assume the other side are arguing with good will unless there couldn't be any other interpretations like 'directly saying n-word to one'. You may need some rest for a while if your frustration is risen enough to consider generalizing certain people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711308983.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you’re disagreeing with human rights 

So we can arrest all the people in the gun control groups who would deny me my natural, human right to keep and bear arms?

&amp;gt; if you’re saying racial slurs, or slurs in general to people in public 

We arrest every black guy who uses the word "cracker." 

&amp;gt; if you are coughing on people during a pandemic 

That is an action more akin to assault, not speech. 

&amp;gt; She put that opinion into action by lying to the police and trying to intentionally get someone hurt or arrested. 

The moment you make a false statement to police, it's no longer just opinion. It's now a claimed statement of fact that is false. 

&amp;gt;And colleges taking back their letters of acceptance. 

Freedom from government prosecution for speech does not mean freedom from general social consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711338271.0" user="probsgettingdownvote" delta="False">
    <text>I never said anything about governmental or law enforcement consequences. Not once in my response. Nor am I making an argument for them. I said it doesn’t need to be respected or protected because you made a choice and that doesn’t keep people from doxxing you or getting you kicked out of school or fired from your job. 

Cracker isn’t a slur....

Read OPs post before responding. He’s arguing speech and expression should be protected regardless of what is seen a favorable or not. I’m disagreeing. I don’t even understand your response to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711536644.0" user="DarwinianDemon58" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by ‘protected’. Sounds like you are talking about law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711357061.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>That last one might be a bit trickier. While attending a public university is a privilege, the government can’t condition privileges (in the US at least) based on protected speech. Would it be all right if all 18 year olds who tweeted in favor of BLM had their admission revoked?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34711370970.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>Good question, when it comes to a public university.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
