<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34723276489.0" user="jow253" delta="False">
    <text>Are you equally outspoken about compliments for every other trait?

Overweight people probably already know it's unhealthy. that's the life they live. Telling someone they look hot when they're trying on a new outfit is not going to convince them they are at their optimal health level. They already know. It's so ridiculously unhelpful to withhold compliments until they lose some weight. You're not their coach. If you want to be their friend, be kind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724024499.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>I find that everything you said can be aplied to drug addicts, why do we have rules for those ? And in case you say, obesity doesn t produce addiction,,think again, body fat wants more body fat, leptines are affected in obese people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724407701.0" user="jow253" delta="False">
    <text>It's not healthy for people to run on cement. It's not healthy to eat bacon. It's not healthy to follow fad diets. It's not healthy to drink beer. It's not healthy to sit for long periods of time. How often do you scold people for exercising too much or enjoying a traditional breakfast or being productive in a cubicle.

Some people think overweight people are attractive. Studies suggest confidence and encouragement are more healing of the underlying causes of obesity than shame. These are all reasons to compliment someone.

What is the point of saying they shouldn't be complimented? What is the function of the maxim? What are you trying to accomplish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724449425.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, a person is not mono-dimensional. Fat people aren't defined by the fact they are fat. They can be praised for so many things, what they are, who they are, what they've done. But I think we as a society should take the position that Fat=bad and don't overlook it. Look, for example I've been a gifted child but I had a complete disregard towards authority and elderly. People always praised me for being smart but never for the other one. We can do the same for fat people. Do we argue that fat people shouldn't be complimented at all or if they shouldn't be complimented on their fat-ness(sorry, couldn't find another word) ?  Bad behaviour is bad behaviour.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
