<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34720608791.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720615782.0" user="Livves25" delta="False">
    <text>Anyone who is more than slightly over weight without trying to improve themselves healthier</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722883255.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MediocreMuffin8 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+MediocreMuffin8&amp;amp;message=MediocreMuffin8+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/-/fy7r57b/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
