<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34720729791.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Who praises an obese person for being obese? I see praise for their confidence, their courage, or their appearance, but I never see someone praise an obese person for their size.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720830452.0" user="Livves25" delta="False">
    <text>It’s always about “body positivity” and people are always especially online being like “your beautiful and don’t need to change, I wish I looked like you” and other comments like that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720885061.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>That's not praising an obese person for being obese, it's about praising obese people for looking good despite being obese.

Making people feel better about their bodies does more to make them want to change than calling them ugly and fat ever will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722086137.0" user="TheRapistsFor800" delta="False">
    <text>When have you ever been complimented and then sought to change the thing you were complimented on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722366583.0" user="Haruko_MISK" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, but I think the goal is to make someone feel worthwhile enough to *want* to help themselves. One of the biggest factors in obesity is depression and low self esteem. The aim of body positivity is to counteract the negative self talk people suffering from depression often have, and replace it with one that's motivating and positive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722374785.0" user="TheRapistsFor800" delta="False">
    <text>Then compliment their personality, work ethic, anything else. Body positivity should also be about solidifying that your body image isn’t a representative of you as a person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722438215.0" user="Haruko_MISK" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I think you're absolutely right! The issue is that the compliments are aimed toward the person's insecurity. It misses its intention when the obese person ends up comfortable being obese. 

It's one of those catch 22's, 'cause if you're a stranger who doesn't know the person, you don't know what will make them feel good. Empty compliments don't improve anyone's self image, after all. Then the only thing you can compliment them on even somewhat genuinely is their appearance, which sometimes defeats the purpose. 


Not to mention body positivity is about more than obesity. Obesity has taken the limelight because of it's frequency, but at one point it was also a movement to help (mainly) young women to be comfortable in their own bodies despite features they're unable to change. The ones that come to mind are amputees, folks with skin disorders or large birthmarks. These things don't fit the traditional idea of beauty, so people were crucifying themselves in their own mind without ever knowing that they are beautiful in their own way. 


The issue is the disconnect between something changeable and something permanent. Obesity is a matter of mental health more so than physical, and while body positivity is important, I personally think that "self positivity" should be the name of the movement. Accepting yourself is just one piece of a larger puzzle for some people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722552074.0" user="avdoli" delta="False">
    <text>All the time, when people tell me I'm good at art I don't go. Well I must be the best ever. I say thank you and keep trying to improve</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722563820.0" user="TheRapistsFor800" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but they probably know you are working on your art. If I know someone is actively trying to improve their health through diet and exercise I will definitely compliment them and tell them that it looks like what they’re doing seems to be working and to keep it up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722770673.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>That is praicing them for obesity when you imply that everything is great and "don't need to change".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722697252.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It’s always about “body positivity” and people are 

Do you accept that some individuals are motivated more with positive perspective about themselves and some are motivated more with a negative perspective about themselves?

While it seems counter-intuitive for many, there are a lot of people who won't better themselves when they dislike\hate themselves now.  They're too far depressed and believe there is no hope for them now.  They need to be in a more positive mindset about themselves to allow them to focus on bettering themselves.  

One can be positive about their about their body but still have a desire to do better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722791010.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>True but they can't better themselves until they admit they have a problem. And empty compliments about their looks certainly won't help. While shaming people doesn't help, neither does sticking your head into the sand and pretending there is no problem. Like it or not, desire for change usually comes from dissatisfaction. What's the point of hiding the effects obesity? It doesn't make it go away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722837399.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; True but they can't better themselves until they admit they have a problem.

This is exactly what I am describing.  NOT anything about empty compliments.  People often need to feel positive in order to acknowledge points they need to get better at.  How is that not understood by my comment above?  Is it that it's so counter-intuitive for you that you assume it is for everyone else too?  If so, you're making assumptions about what you think it is vs what it factually is.  Presenting your perspective as truth with-out truly understanding it is a great example of the Dunning-Kruger Effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723011083.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>Cool ad-hominems there. 

People(generally) don't change if there's not some kind of pressure(internal or external) to change. If you tell people everything is great and they don't need to change. Well, they don't. It's become pretty clear that the current trend is not working and things don't change until they are pressured to in some way. And yes, the whole "body positivity" movement has caused the fact that many people see obesity as something totally normal and not dangerous. And that the world should cater to them because they are obese. Now, we need to treat obesity(not obese people) as a problem that needs to be treated but I don't see the way to do this while holding people's hands and telling everything is allright.

How is this done? I don't know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723054361.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Cool ad-hominems there. 

Where?  If you took the comment about the Dunning-Kruger Effect as one, that's unfortunate.  Cognitive biases exist and should not be assumed or taken as an insult \ character attack.  But, perceiving it as one shows a level of defensiveness towards it being possible.

&amp;gt;People(generally) don't change if there's not some kind of pressure(internal or external) to change.

Notice how you even specified it with *generally*.  So you acknowledge it is not always the case?

&amp;gt;If you tell people everything is great and they don't need to change.

Again, you're making a claim about how you perceive it that does not align with the objective facts here.  

Body Positivity =! `tell people everything is great`.

I ask again:

&amp;gt; Is it that it's so counter-intuitive for you that you assume it is for everyone else too?

Please address this question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723094277.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>Here you go again, attacking me and not my arguments. 🤷‍♂️

People sometime change their opinion with age or other factors yes. Still for the majority of cases, and when talking about populations on national scale it's not really important. The most effective way to change population behavior is through taxation.

And you're not the person who gets to define what "body positivity" means. It's not an official movement with official websites and such. There are people in the body positivity sphere with varied opinions, some with likes the one I stated, some not. It's not unlike feminism where a subset of that movement actively hate men.

Also I don't understand what you're referring to as "counter-intuitive" please elaborate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723131302.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Here you go again, attacking me and not my arguments. 🤷‍♂️

Please address that I did in fact inquire exactly what you are referring to.  Pointing out a possible fallacy is not in an way an attack on a person.

&amp;gt;People sometime change their opinion with age or other factors yes. Still for the majority of cases, and when talking about populations on national scale it's not really important. The most effective way to change population behavior is through taxation.

Citation, specifically with Positive vs Negative reinforcement?

&amp;gt;And you're not the person who gets to define what "body positivity" means. It's not an official movement with official websites and such. There are people in the body positivity sphere with varied opinions, some with likes the one I stated, some not. It's not unlike feminism where a subset of that movement actively hate men.

You again make assumtions here.  Here is what I base it off of:

&amp;gt;The Body Positivity Movement has been groundbreaking because of the effect it has on the psychology of a person. The movement encourages the partakers view self-acceptance and self-love as traits that dignify the person. The movement is based on the image basing their sense of self-worth heavily on their physical appearance, and how good they perceive themselves to look. **This is referred to in the field of psychology as appearance-contingent self-worth, and can be highly detrimental to an individual's body image. The degree to which one feels proud of their physical appearance is referred to as appearance self-esteem. People who fall under the appearance-contingent self-worth umbrella put great effort into looking their best so that they feel their best. This is only good when an individual feels that they look good, but is extremely negative and anxiety-inducing when they do not.**

&amp;gt;The psychology of the movement goes beyond feeling good. **The movement is also recognized as an important part of physical and mental well being as it has been found that having a negative body image or otherwise known as body dissatisfaction has been linked to a range of physical and mental health problems like disordered eating, depression, body dysmorphic disorder, and more. The movement started spreading to create awareness around the difficult illnesses that some suffer like Anorexia and Bulimia; the movement is shedding light on subjects that brands and bigger companies refused to talk about.** Big retailers like Aerie are acknowledging the power of influence they have on behavioral advertising and the positive impact this could have for a new generation. 

-----

&amp;gt;Also I don't understand what you're referring to as "counter-intuitive" please elaborate.

Let me quote what I had stated:

&amp;gt;While it seems counter-intuitive for many, **there are a lot of people who won't better themselves when they dislike\hate themselves now.** They're too far depressed and believe there is no hope for them now. They need to be in a more positive mindset about themselves to allow them to focus on bettering themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723446468.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>Any economic textbook. It's very well known in economics that taxation effects consumer behaviour.

Source for the quote? 


Also I agree with that, many people won't change when they hate themselves while some do. Many simply don't want to change. I still don't think the current body positivity movement is the answer, no matter how good ones intentions are. Normalizing obesity will likely cause more harm than good in the long run and won't cause people to change willingly.  If there's an effective way I don't see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722832238.0" user="littleghostwhowalks" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're confusing support with praise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722856566.0" user="Livves25" delta="False">
    <text>I mean praise, I see people all the time literally looking like they are praising them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722872594.0" user="littleghostwhowalks" delta="False">
    <text>The example you gave? The one I replied to? That is not an example of praise. So no, you do not mean praise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
