<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34722111265.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722726180.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/khabadami – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+khabadami&amp;amp;message=khabadami+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/-/fy8ncip/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
