<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34722509571.0" user="sakthi38311" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody is really compliment for their weight. They are shamed for it tho. I assume you're talking about their body shape. 

A normal weight person can get complimented for their body? The reasons someone compliments a normal weight person for their appearance:

1. Sexual Attractiveness

2. Presumed good health

3. Appreciation of beauty

Anyone could get complimented for one or more of the above reason. This can apply to an overweight person. People can find beauty in an overweight person. They can find them sexually attractive. 
To each their own - that is everyone has their own personal yardstick. 

What you are particularly talking about is the comments section (presumably Instagram) of an overweight person. They are also appreciating for another reason added to the above. That is the courage it took for the person show their body to the world which is very harsh towards them. And their courage inspires people. It's like a representation. Looking someone fat being bold, being happy, makes other fat people feel they are worthy of happiness too. 

Is being obese unhealthy? To an extent.

Does that give anyone any right to bully them? No.

Should that prevent anyone from appreciating their beauty? No.

Are unhealthy people undeserving to live a happy life? Ofc not! 

Are unhealthy people undeserving of compliments, appreciation and gratitude? You decide. (No!) 

Side note : many obese, and overweight people are denied of medical care because doctors tend to assume some conditions are result of their obesity while most cases it isn't so. My friend wasn't treated for PCOS for a long time because the doctor said that she didn't have a serious issue and it's just her obesity. 

**The predisposition that Obesity == unhealthy is harmful.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722821917.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>Obesity is unhealthy and has been proven by science. Are you against science?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723187239.0" user="sakthi38311" delta="False">
    <text>Obesity is measured using BMI but BMI isn't a universal yardstick of health. We can see that many Obese people are heart healthy while normal weight people are not. BMI can just be a correlation with heart health in many cases. When I said deeming obesity as the only reason for every health issues is unscientific.

Nevertheless, fat obese people are people and they deserve appreciation of beauty. It is simple.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723477348.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>BMI is not necessarily a good measure on individuals but it is concidered good measure for larger populations. Also source for the heart health study.

Also beauty is subjective. They deserve basic respect and decency. Like any other human.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724662365.0" user="sakthi38311" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Decency is fundamental. OP is talking bout compliments on fat people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724016117.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>Every single file in medical literature will have the disclaimer " BMI " is not a good measurement for obesity. Every single one. We use it because it s the fastest cheapest</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
