<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34720896154.0" user="SatanicOnion" delta="False">
    <text>Or how about you stop trying to dictate how people live their lives? 

If they want to be over weight, let them. It's their right. 

If they want to feel good, let them, it's their right. 

Most overweight people aren't going to get fit just because they feel like shit for being fat. Usually, they'd just stuff their faces out of shame and emotional eating. Vicious cycle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720931157.0" user="Livves25" delta="False">
    <text>This is what I’m talking about man, “oh it’s their choice” you know what else is a choice? Consuming drugs, many due to depression or other mental health disorders but no one says “don’t be mean it’s their choice, if they want to be addicted it’s their choice” people tell them to stop and avoid them, it’s all about social standards and what’s acceptable to what humans feel. I don’t care if their feelings are hurt when I say “you need to be healthier” cause they are going to be happier after eating or being healthier</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34721037552.0" user="SatanicOnion" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, consumption of drugs is a choice. 

And guess what? The people who get off drugs are people who want to, people who have support networks like family and friends, and rehabilitation options 

Not the people who end up in and out of prison because people like you told them they couldn't do drugs anymore. I imagine if you just kept shitting on a drug addict, they'll keep trying to escape reality. But if you make their reality worth living in, and not be so mean about it, they might make the choice themselves to stop. 

Solution: make nutritional science and better physical education mandatory in school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723992994.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>But nobody is praising or giving suport to junkies because " they look good even of they are junkies" , or " their body seems to be healthy evennof they are junkies"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722796687.0" user="roiki11" delta="False">
    <text>If they pay for the social costs of that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
