<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108117337.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1sdbvd/i_believe_antidepressants_change_who_you_are_as_a/">
    <title>I believe anti-depressants change who you are as a person rather than fix you to the way you should be. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>ArizonaBlood</original_poster>
    <original_post>submitted 3 minutes ago* by ArizonaBlood

I've taken anti-depressants before, but I don't feel like they made my brain work the way it's 'supposed' to. I think however my brain works naturally, without the use of medications, is its REAL natural state.

When I took anti-depressants, it changed the way I looked at the people in my life, the way I see how things work, even some of my opinions! I didn't feel like the ME I've been my whole life. But when I went off again, though I was depressed, I felt like myself again.

Since this experience, I've been unable to believe that depressants make you the way you're SUPPOSED to be. I feel that your natural state is acquired without the use of any medications. I'm a little old fashioned I suppose. Change my vieeeew?
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26961886202.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>There are a lot of different kinds of medications in the world, and a good doctor will help someone with symptoms find the medication that alleviates the symptoms with the fewest number of drawbacks.  
Most things you go through change who you are, if you're paying attention. The issue with medication is that it helps people with things they *don't* like. Things that are more like abnormalities that are getting in the way of their life.  
Taking a medication that helps you hold down a steady job is a great thing if that's been a problem, and a good doctor will try combinations of medications that can help you with the side effects.  
**TL;DR Every medication is different, and they all do different things.**</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
