<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108117337.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1sdbvd/i_believe_antidepressants_change_who_you_are_as_a/">
    <title>I believe anti-depressants change who you are as a person rather than fix you to the way you should be. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>ArizonaBlood</original_poster>
    <original_post>submitted 3 minutes ago* by ArizonaBlood

I've taken anti-depressants before, but I don't feel like they made my brain work the way it's 'supposed' to. I think however my brain works naturally, without the use of medications, is its REAL natural state.

When I took anti-depressants, it changed the way I looked at the people in my life, the way I see how things work, even some of my opinions! I didn't feel like the ME I've been my whole life. But when I went off again, though I was depressed, I felt like myself again.

Since this experience, I've been unable to believe that depressants make you the way you're SUPPOSED to be. I feel that your natural state is acquired without the use of any medications. I'm a little old fashioned I suppose. Change my vieeeew?
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26961903729.0" user="NeutralParty" delta="False">
    <text>Well I have two things to say to this as someone that spent nearly a year as an inpatient for such things:

1) I have no issue using my glasses as a prosthesis to augment what my body is, and I take no issue with the use of morphine to quell my perception of pain. I'd get on a dialysis machine if I needed to and I would subject myself to amputation if it was required to save my life.

By the same token why should I mind augmenting my personality artificially? My body and perception have already been altered at various points and in different ways.

2) This sort of dissociation isn't that uncommon on SSRIs. I've had it on some I was on for a time. (Those some being ones that didn't really help me at all either.)

What I'm now, though? I'm great with it. Medication is very complicated, especially psychiatric medication. A lot of people need to have a lot of fiddling done with their regimen to get an effective and non-destructive drug plan. It's just how it is for now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26961921463.0" user="ArizonaBlood" delta="False">
    <text>∆

Oh man. I use contact lenses.. and never thought of it this way. You bring up a very valid point. I can see it now, because we *do* all changes ourselves in many ways! Especially with experiences and personalities. It makes sense now. Damn.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
