<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767401551.0" user="Big_Scallion5884" delta="False">
    <text>Trump doesn't have anywhere near the power and resources you suggest. 

I'd also appreciate if you could provide your definition of 'fascism'. You could argue that Trump has clear authoritarian tendencies but he doesn't have anything like a coherent ideology or plan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767515113.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that someone needs a coherent ideology to be a fascist. Not beyond: "I'm the boss, I should be in charge of everyone, and no one should be able to stop me."

On [Merriam-Webster](https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/fascism) there is a less generous definition of fascism followed by a more generous one.

He absolutely meets the qualifications of the more generous definition, and I think you'd be hard pressed to find anyone (other than his supporters) who disagrees.

For the less generous definition: He exalts the US over the individual. He wants as much executive power as possible (centralized autocratic government), he actively oppresses sections of the population such as immigrants and more subtly oppresses others, and he has now fully revealed himself as willing to use violence against his opposition. Boxes all checked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767582888.0" user="no_politics_here" delta="False">
    <text>Antifa and BLM are using violence and fear to try to effect political change...with the goal of tearing this country apart. They even admit it. They are terrorists by every definition of the word and local politicians that support their acts of violence and riots are traitors and should be convicted of treason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767700204.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767857594.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767979163.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768092891.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MaichenM – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+MaichenM&amp;amp;message=MaichenM+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fyzsh64/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768495708.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768775246.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/TheInfiniteNewt – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+TheInfiniteNewt&amp;amp;message=TheInfiniteNewt+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz09izg/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768994366.0" user="shannonthomas139" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you are grouping entire groups and calling them treasonous and violent when the vast majority of BLM protesters are non-violent. 

You are calling people who outwardly support black lives and protest police brutality terrorists. 

Politicians are attempting to respect their right to protest police brutality, but now Trump has decided to send troops in for the purpose of preventing them from destroying capitol buildings and statues. 

Vandalizing property does not warrant abducting citizens and ignoring their constitutional rights. 

Your views further divide this country into good and bad. Do you have no respect for the protesters that are actually trying to create meaningful changes in their communities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769902362.0" user="no_politics_here" delta="False">
    <text>You say the vast majority are non-violent when cities government buildings are burning, police are being openly attacked with weapons in the street, national monuments are being torn down, and the protests leave cities looted and whole districts woth windows broken out, all the while people are shouting defund the police as murder rates are skyrocketing. 

The protestors know this is all going on and that this is much worse than the actual occurrence of police brutality so yeah, if they are still “protesting” knowing that they draw the same type that are waging war in cities and aim only for violence, it is very much so also support of those actions. I’ll group them all together at this point. 

They are criminals and some of the crap they are pulling, line throwing firework mortars at police or blocking the exits of buildings only to try to set them on fire is attempted murder. Your protestors are accomplices to and implicit in the attempted murder of police officers. They can rot in jail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771681055.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>Are you willing to hold the police to the same level of group accountability?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773754004.0" user="shannonthomas139" delta="False">
    <text>Let me say it one more time. No crime warrants the ignorance of constitutional rights. 

They cannot rot in jail if they are not found guilty of anything in a trial by jury.

Please have some goddamn decency for innocent people and stop grouping them together as if they aren't individuals with lives and families and CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34775462175.0" user="no_politics_here" delta="False">
    <text>Tell me what constitutional rights are being violated? The right to steal, assault people, and destroy other people’s private property as well as public property?

Let me say it again. If you commit a crime, you should be arrested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34775548987.0" user="shannonthomas139" delta="False">
    <text>1st, 4th, and 5th amendment rights are being violated. 

In [this video](https://time.com/5868087/portland-blm-protest-federal-law-enforcement-trump/), masked federal agents in camouflage gear, with no badges identifying who they work for, arrested a man without telling him what he was being charged with or reading him his Miranda rights. They put him in an unmarked van and drove away. No one knew who had arrested him.

A person cannot be constitutionally arrested without charge, without being read their rights, and without the arresting officials identifying whom they work for and into whose custody the arrestee is being taken or where they are being taken.

[source](https://www.forbes.com/sites/evangerstmann/2020/07/18/federal-law-enforcement-is-making-unconstitutional-arrests-in-portland/#4a110ee012a6)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776547668.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Tell me what constitutional rights are being violated?

In *Miranda v. Arizona*, 384 US 436 (1966), the Supreme Court held that the admission of an elicited incriminating statement by a suspect not informed of these rights violates the Fifth Amendment and the Sixth Amendment right to counsel, through the incorporation of these rights into state law.

&amp;gt; If you commit a crime, you should be arrested.

President Donald J. Trump [committed a crime](https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/5/2635.702).  Should he be arrested and replaced by Vice President Pence, or are you a hypocrite?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776517843.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; cities government buildings are burning

I don't believe you.  Which cities' government buildings are burning?  Name at least two of the cities you're talking about.

&amp;gt; national monuments are being torn down

Again, name two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769894990.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769905608.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772439942.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>u/no_politics_here – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+no_politics_here&amp;amp;message=no_politics_here+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz13qvc/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770735060.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>u/abseadefgh – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+abseadefgh&amp;amp;message=abseadefgh+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz13ioe/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776510432.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They even admit it.

Oh wow, then that should make it really easy to link to in your reply to this comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767583285.0" user="UncomfortablePrawn" delta="False">
    <text>Fascism refers to a very specific, extreme form of government. I'm not even an American so I have no stake in this and I would disagree with what you're saying.

Can you describe specifically how the US government is autocratic? What do you think they have done that matches the characteristics of an autocratic government?

With regards to population, can you give specific examples of what you mean when you say "more subtly oppresses others"? 

Same with violence against opposition. What do you mean by violence? When has that been used against Trump's opposition?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767667521.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>The US government is not fascist. Trump is fascist, and would like the government to be as fascist as he is, but has not gotten there yet.

More subtly oppresses others - Sure. Trump has been known to give [dogwhistles](https://gen.medium.com/trumps-dog-whistle-presidency-c889d095b60a) to white supremacists. In addition he favors socioeconomic conditions that favor the rich and punish the poor. These things aren't unheard of in the GOP, but when they are coupled with Trump's other traits, they are a component in a recipe for fascism.

Violence against opposition - Trump is currently in the process of sending federal agents in unmarked vans to cities to abduct protesters. Because these protesters are entirely left-leaning, it can be assumed that they stand against Trump. He has been clear, and gone on record stating that he is targeting "Democratic" cities.

I do not currently live in a fascist country. I absolutely believe that if Trump wins another term there is a very strong possibility that I will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767732981.0" user="Big_Scallion5884" delta="False">
    <text>But I'd argue that your definition of fascist is so broad that it is almost meaningless. Would Trump love to be in charge forever and do whatever he wants without any oversight? Sure. Does he have the support, power or even the motivation to carry out the massive changes he would need in order to make these things happen? No.

For instance you mention dogwhistles and subtle threats of violence, but can you think of a realistic scenario where Trump could get the police and army to actually implement these threats?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767853692.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that you're getting hung up on the "subtle" aspects of oppression I outlined, and not the major ones I started with.

Right now in this country there are refugees who are being placed in detention centers during a pandemic. The high risk ones were removed, but that was all that was done. ICE has removed records of sexual assault carried out against detainees, and I have personally dealt with children who have lifelong trauma after being removed from those centers.

So no, I don't imagine those scenarios. I really don't have to imagine things that are already happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34785378087.0" user="nschubach" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't Trump who had those people and children break the law... they are being detained because they illegally crossed the border.  What happened to them is a tragedy, but Trump wasn't there forcing that to happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769891194.0" user="abseadefgh" delta="False">
    <text>The police are already jumping at the gun to kill innocent people. Just look at what’s happening in Portland. They’ll do it just for fun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767769741.0" user="UncomfortablePrawn" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to be like you don't really understand what fascism is, and you're just throwing it around because you don't like Trump.

Firstly, about the economic policies - some of the ones Trump supports (from Wikipedia's first line) are tax cuts and repealing the Obamacare stuff. This is just pretty standard conservative economic policy, as you've said yourself. Why would it make a person a fascist to support the economic policies their party goes by?

Violence against opposition - I'll give you that abducting people is bad, but it doesn't make you a fascist. Fascism requires a totalitarian system - think Hitler in Nazi Germany, where he systematically maneuvered his way into becoming a dictator.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767824838.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>You are the one who dangerously misunderstands fascism.

Fascism is not just a system of government. Neo-Nazis, who have no government, are fascist. Because they believe in fascism, and they believe that the country they live in should be fascist.

In the same way, Trump absolutely believes that he should be a fascist dictator.

Saying that fascism always requires a system of government built around it to even be considered fascism is dangerous, because it easily allows the rise of fascist leaders who will then create that system. I believe that if Trump is re-elected, he will try his hardest to do it here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770148943.0" user="HillaryKlingon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the same way, Trump absolutely believes that he should be a fascist dictator.

Has Trump come out and said he believes he is a fascist dictator?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771477004.0" user="Team_Rckt_Grunt" delta="False">
    <text>I have to ask - do you genuinely expect anyone who believes they should, effectively, be a fascist dictator to say the words "I would like to be a fascist dictator"?  Because in my experience, people who want or believe awful things generally have it conceptualized differently in their head - or at least, they make sure to phrase it in a less offputting way when speaking to others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771571914.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771723617.0" user="Team_Rckt_Grunt" delta="False">
    <text>I never said anything about racism.  Where did that come from?   
I was just pointing out that wanting to be a fascist dictator is generally regarded as a negative thing, so it's pretty unlikely someone would openly admit to it even if it was true.  You know, since your previous comment was asking whether Trump had specifically admitted to being/wanting to be a fascist dictator?  


Also, there's no need to go around insulting people just because you didn't like their comments.  That seems a little immature, imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771754784.0" user="ihatedogs2" delta="False">
    <text>u/HillaryKlingon – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+HillaryKlingon&amp;amp;message=HillaryKlingon+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz23glm/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767759967.0" user="ProjectShamrock" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Fascism refers to a very specific, extreme form of government.

Can you provide that definition?  As far as I know, it's fairly poorly defined other than being an autocratic government that is extremely nationalist.  Even the famous "14 signs of fascism" that Umberto Eco came up with aren't universally accepted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767783839.0" user="UncomfortablePrawn" delta="False">
    <text>I might have been exaggerating a little. You might be right to say that there's not really a clear definition, but we can look at the governments that have been considered fascist, such as Hitler's. There's definitely clear traits such as an autocratic government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767810417.0" user="ProjectShamrock" delta="False">
    <text>I think it would be fair to say that Trump himself has fascist tendencies and given enough time and support, he would bring the U.S. to become a fascist nation.  However, that would require steps much further than I would expect to see in the next four years if he wins another term.  I think the U.S. is a "failing" state in some measures but not all but it's difficult to make direct comparisons to historical governments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767942307.0" user="UncomfortablePrawn" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I agree with you and that’s kinda my point to OP. He might share some traits with fascist leaders but the US is pretty far from becoming a fascist state by any means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769939738.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't believe that someone needs a coherent ideology to be a fascist.

I'd gently suggest reexamining that belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770621859.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Why?

I have already explained that my point of view is that all you need to be a fascist is to believe that you, the leader, should have absolute power. The rest flows naturally from that. I don't think Kim Jhong Un, or his Father, ever walked around thinking of themselves as fascists. They are/were just purely people who believe that they, and a select group, deserve absolute power over their country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770669085.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>First, the will to power exists independent of any system of political thought. 

What's happening is that I'm using the word as it was ... designed to be used, not as broadly as you are.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
