<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767671543.0" user="Andynonomous" delta="False">
    <text>Trump has proven that he is tough with his words, and will get away with what he can, but he withers as soon as he is challenged. For example, look at everything he used to say about Obama, and then upon winning the White House he sat in the room with Obama, shook his hand, thanked him and said he was a 'good man'. I think you're right in that he will want to refuse to leave after losing, but I dont think he has the guts. He will cave when people tell him he cant do that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
