<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34769752918.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>In Portland, the officers are protecting federal property.  If these "protestors" attack federal property, they get arrested.  If they are attacking the building, the feds come out.  If they dont attack the building, nothing happens.

Dont fucking attack the courthouse and you wont get arrested.  There is nothing "fascist" about that.
We all have to follow the laws equally and the law says you dont get to vandalize federal property.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770635144.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Your timeline is a little messed up there. The courthouse got attacked after the federal forces had already shown up and started abducting protestors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770648874.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>Geee...  ok...

The just started kidnapping people...

Gotcha...

Innocent people...

Obviously antifa's trackrecord as a peaceful,  respectful organization supports your statement...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776571523.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The just started kidnapping people...

*They

But otherwise correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776578621.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>They weren't abducting them, they were arresting them.  There is a difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776651397.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that arrested citizens have to be read their Miranda rights and get arrest records, so yes they were abducting them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776855423.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>You dont get read those till you are in custody.  And if you aren't, your charges wont stick.

They are moving people quickly ;because of the whole violent mob thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776968265.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They are **moving people**

a.k.a. kidnapping</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776975100.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>Have they called the antifa whorde to demand a ransom yet?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776980082.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; they

Who?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777010112.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>Why the kidnappers, if course...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777022411.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>Who are the kidnappers?  They don't wear badge numbers or identification.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777077852.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>Not all cops do.  Detectives and plain clothes cops dont.  In this case it was the federal agents that were not wearing identifiers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777107281.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>So who are they then?

And what's the phone number for "the antifa whorde"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776979430.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think you know what kidnapping is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776987585.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>Then you gambled and lost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777014981.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>No, the antifa punk gambled when they vandalized federal property and lost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777039848.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777043554.0" user="wophi" delta="False">
    <text>Ya, pretty relevant since it got him arrested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777045597.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know who you're talking about.  What's his name?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777470545.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/hereitisyouhappynow – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+hereitisyouhappynow&amp;amp;message=hereitisyouhappynow+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz5cnoo/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
