<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767572801.0" user="no_politics_here" delta="False">
    <text>Apparently he is a fascist now because he is sending in federal agents to protect federal property because Mayors are just letting terrorists burn down court houses and try to kill cops while actually taking their side while they call for tearing down the country. It's insurrection and terrorism. I'd say he would be a failure if he did nothing. He also did not look for the first opportunity to get involved at the federal level but pleaded with state and city governments to.....govern. 

What some of these leaders are doing is actually akin to treason and insurrection...supporting groups whop are using fear and violence to push political change....which is terrorism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767751569.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Why did you make two separate posts?

The argument isn't about this. But for fun, go look up any of what you are talking about in a non-rightwing source and see if it is even remotely accurate.

But of course, the media is fake news. Primarily because it contradicts the President.

I'm just playing with you. Address the argument at hand or leave.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767851358.0" user="no_politics_here" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't you stop blindly believing everything from left-wing news and dig for some unbiased info yourself?

Like the video of "peaceful" protesters changing from street clothes to all black while someone dropped off weapons and gear to them to only come out to attack police in Grant Park. If these are peaceful protests then how do they magically have fireworks, frozen water bottles, and blue lasers to use against the police? If these riots are instigated by the police, why are they often peaceful until rioters appear and try to lock police officers in police stations then try lighting them on fire?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

But you must be right. It is just people standing there with sign with only intentions of their grievances being heard but the police always escalate. Their are no rioters. Sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768499759.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768772079.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>u/TheInfiniteNewt – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+TheInfiniteNewt&amp;amp;message=TheInfiniteNewt+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz09m3z/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34779192611.0" user="BrutalOlonus" delta="False">
    <text>i dunno dude. literally people throwing molotov cocktails, fighting, throwing deadly objects, etc. cant make that shit up. even if seen on right wing media its still true and real footage. sooooo.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770915634.0" user="xip902" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have some references for mayors 'letting terrorists burn down court houses and try to kill cops' and 'taking their side while they call for tearing down the country'? My understanding (as a non-american) is that many - i will grant not all - protests have seen police initiate violence, back away until someone inevitably commits vandalism or some other disturbance, then return with increased force. I don't really see how it would be in any mayor or police force's interest to allow terrorists to burn and kill and help them with 'tearing down the country'.

Most of the argument from the state side that I have heard has been that responding with extreme force simply begets more of the types of crimes you are describing, and thus federal involvement is only worsening the situation (of course, the benefit from the federal side is that they are seen as the strong men that they wish to be seen as).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
