<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767371303.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Democrats said the same thing about Bush (H. W. And W) and he left office just fine. Republicans said it about both Clinton and Obama.

It's absolutely hyperbolic saying any given president won't leave if voted out. But that's the point of that type of fear mongering. Scared people are idiots that are easily manipulated. Really is the oldest trick in the book.

Based on the way you claim your mind can be changed, the event has to happen and no amount of people saying otherwise will change it. Is that the case?

The problem for a lot of young people (yes I'm going to go with a boomer moment) is that the very end of Obama and Trump are their first foray into political dialogue, so they lack history and perspective. We're not seeing anything this country hasn't seen before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767438023.0" user="strumthebuilding" delta="False">
    <text>I lived through all of the presidential transitions you mention and I don’t recall anyone expressing the least bit of concern about any of them attempting to retain power beyond the end of their terms. Not saying you’re making this up entirely, since there’s somebody somewhere saying anything anytime, but I’m extremely skeptical that this was ever a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767541469.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Being alive during the events don't mean you're cognizant of the political goings-on during them.

[Obama having to declare he isn't refusing yo give up office because it was such a popular talking point](https://www.google.com/amp/s/abcnews.go.com/amp/Politics/president-obama-refusing-leave-office/story%3fid=44575517)

[Clinton was on Record for wanting a third term several times, which you know how the Republicans would respond to that](https://www.google.com/amp/s/amp.theguardian.com/world/2000/dec/08/uselections2000.usa3)

I have a hard time you don't remember people talking about Bush and Cheney not leaving office, it was an absolutely huge talking point.

People were saying the same when Bush Sr lost to Clinton. It was such a big talking point because he had just won the gulf war and had massive military support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767438602.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>You mention a lack of history and perspective....

None of those former presidents you listed did anything close to what Trump has done, such as sending in federal agents into cities and using getsapo tactics to terrorize protesters.

Never mind that those previous presidents at least had a veil of decorum and respect for rule of law and political tradition.

Trump is a textbook case of Narcissistic Personality Disorder, along with probably some other co-morbid mental illness or personality disorder.

He has spent his entire life having people kiss his ass, surrounding himself by sycophants and “yes” people who won’t dare to question him. He literally cannot stand losing or being told “no”.

Unlike those other former presidents you mention, Trump actually thinks that he was elected king, and is above accountability or the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767522114.0" user="yunyun333" delta="False">
    <text>Obama drone striked a 16 year old american citizen lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767578290.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Can y’all come up with some new material, please?

And Trump is kidnapping American citizens and violating their due process rights and rights to protest.

And that citizen he drone striked was working for terrorists.

If it had been a Republican who had drone striked him, conservatives would be singing a WILDLY different tune.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767793033.0" user="ATNinja" delta="False">
    <text>How do you expect new material?  Obama isn't president anymore. When Biden wins there will be new material because every president does fucked up shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767807353.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>No, my point is, it doesn’t matter how bad or craven gets, conservatives/libertarians love to invoke Obama drone strikes.

I swear, Trump could literally put the Constitution through a paper shredder, and drop a nuke on Chicago, and conservatives and libertarians would still be bleating “wHat aBouT tHaT tIMe ObAMa dRoNe StRiKeD tHaT wAnNaBe tErRoRiST?!”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768071196.0" user="ATNinja" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno. I hear about beghazi and the Hillary emails at least as often as the drone strike.

I think the comparison between trump's fascist bullshit in Portland and extrajuducially killing an American citizen is at least somewhat on topic though especially when the discussion is about how trump is uniquely bad. I'm sorry you're bored of hearing about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768127534.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Obama’s drone strike was an isolated incident, and it does not mean Trump gets a cart-blanche pass to steamroll this country towards a fascist dictatorship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768509769.0" user="ATNinja" delta="False">
    <text>Where could you have gotten the idea that the drone strike gives trump carte Blanche to do anything? 

Of course it doesn't. I can't believe anyone would think that Obama doing something wrong means Trump can do the same thing let alone something different but also bad.

The only reason it is relevent at all to trump is because people say things like trump doing something evil and fascisty means he won't transition power peacefully when previous presidents like Obama have done some evil and fascisty stuff and still transitioned peacefully. Obviously trump is more fascist than obama but doing fascist things is hardly unique to trump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768528887.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Again, it’s the repeated pattern of behavior that Trump has exhibited...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767828256.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And Trump is kidnapping American citizens

It's called arresting, not kidnapping. 

&amp;gt;violating their due process

Anyone not let go has been charged, in accordance to the process.

&amp;gt;rights to protest

Burning federal buildings ceases to be a protest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767838422.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>People being kidnapped and beaten up aren’t the ones burning down buildings.

Please refer to the Navy very who had his hand broken, simply for telling the federal agents to remember their paths to the Constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767883693.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>It's still arrested, not kidnapped. You can say it as much as you want but it doesn't make it kidnapping. You can argue some arrests were unwarranted, but that's the purpose of a trial. When he's going to defend people that are causing damage, he's going to be treated like he's one of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767912278.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, nothing at all to be concerned about feds from an unamed agency snatching people off the street and tossing them into an unmarked van, to be whisked away to an undisclosed location...

Yeah, nothing at all sketchy about that... 

And I’m sure when people start being “disappeared” you’ll just dismiss that as “fake news” right?

It’s just laughable that the same people who screamed tyranny every time a Dem so much as farts in the wrong direction, willfully ignore and make excuses for blatant fascism unfolding in their face.

Pretty much every authoritarian dictator in the history of forever has used “restoring order”, “law and order” and “safety” as a pretext for their tyranny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767962189.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; unamed agency

Look at the pictures. The uniforms had patches on the back and shoulders saying ecastly who they were including officer number.

&amp;gt;And I’m sure when people start being “disappeared” you’ll just dismiss that as “fake news” right?

It'll have to happen first. Can you give citation as to a single person missing due to these events?

&amp;gt;It’s just laughable that the same people who screamed tyranny every time a Dem so much as farts in the wrong direction, willfully ignore and make excuses for blatant fascism unfolding in their face.

Do you have evidence that I am one of those people, or are you simply assuming anyone that disagrees with you is identical in their beliefs, which to you consist of "all the wrong beliefs?" That would be a strawman 

&amp;gt;Pretty much every authoritarian dictator in the history of forever has used “restoring order”, “law and order” and “safety” as a pretext for their tyranny.

And pretty much *every* leader has wanted law and order and safety. That's a nonargument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768280795.0" user="Aksius14" delta="False">
    <text>Actually it's not. Here's Cornell's definition of arrest: 

"An arrest is using legal authority to deprive a person of his or her freedom of movement. An arrest is generally made with an arrest warrant. An arrest may be made without a warrant if probable cause and exigent circumstances are presented at the time of the arrest."

The DHS Secretary has already stated they are detaining people proactively. The mayor of Portland has said they shouldn't be arrested. The Federal officers having been acting outside the bounds of Federal buildings and/or Federal property. The Supreme Court has been pretty clear that exercising your right to protest is "exigent circumstances." 

The term you're looking for is extra-judicial kidnappings. 

There is a story of an actual attorney familiar with the criminal arrest process getting grabbed by Federal officers. She was not marandised, she was not told why she was picked up, she was detained without cause. 

I'm not assuming you're not a lawyer, because you might be, but I trust actual lawyers and judges (many of who have commented on this as not being arrests).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767914667.0" user="Trorbes" delta="False">
    <text>Donald Trump got his 8 year old sister killed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776492681.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34778568408.0" user="ihatedogs2" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/hereitisyouhappynow – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+hereitisyouhappynow&amp;amp;message=hereitisyouhappynow+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz50xhl/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767527201.0" user="Denikin_Tsar" delta="False">
    <text>Just an FIY, when you compare what Trump is doing to "Gestapo tactics" you are insulting the memory of my ancestors who actually suffered at hands of the Gestapo and the millions of other who have suffered also.

This kind of comparison is insensitive to the highest degree and very counterproductive to your case.

If people have no knowledge of the Gestapo and they believe you, they will think "Gestapo was bad, but it wasn't as bad as those "survivors" make it out to be".

On the other hand, those that know about the Gestapo and see your comparison will outright dismiss you as being wrong since there is no comparison</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767613016.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>“Just an FIY, when you compare what Trump is doing to "Gestapo tactics" you are insulting the memory of my ancestors who actually suffered at hands of the Gestapo and the millions of other who have suffered also.”

It’s REALLY getting tiring hearing this tacit defense for blatant fascism.

Just how close towards the Holocaust and fascism must Trump go before it will be okay to make those comparisons?

The point of “never again” is to stop the next holocaust LONG before the first gas chambers ever open up.

And yes, that means calling out Trump’s gestapo tactics when he uses them, and yes, that means calling out his concentration camps at the border.

Waiting until you have an actual Holocaust before you are allowed to make comparisons to the Holocaust, is exactly how you get another Holocaust.

I’m sure there were plenty of people in the early 1930’s Germany who said that comparing what Hitler was doing to what people had previously suffered under pogroms in Russia was insulting to those who had survived pogroms under the Tsar.

How did that work out?

You don’t wait until after the whole building is burning down before you take steps to try and prevent a fire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767657834.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767685704.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, it’s not a pissing contest.

When have I ever downplayed human suffering under the Nazis?

I haven’t. What you’re doing is a classic republican tactic to try and gaslight and downplay what Trump is doing.

Again, just how close to the Holocaust must things get before Holocaust comparisons will be appropriate?

Literally the point of making Holocaust comparison is so that a Holocaust NEVER AGAIN happens.

The whole point is to nip it in the bud, long before things ever get that bad.

The Holocaust didn’t come out of a vacuum.

It slowly happened over many years, and yes, it all started out with a populist demagogue who was democratically elected and who promised to Make Germany Great Again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767811422.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Their point is that this situation doesn't compare at all. Besides everyone knows the first person that resorts to calling someone Hitler has a weak argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767825528.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Again, just how close to the actual holocaust must things get before comparisons are acceptable?

Do people need to actually be thrown into gas chambers before it will be acceptable?

And I never called anyone Hitler.

I said trump is using gestapo tactics.

Which he *is* doing.

And everyone knows that anyone who resorts or downvoting has a weak argument, so why do you keep doing it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767857472.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And everyone knows that anyone who resorts or downvoting has a weak argument, so why do you keep doing it?

Check names, I'm not the person you've been conversing with, so I don't "keep" doing anything. That was my first response to you.

How far away does it need to be from Hitler to be compared to Hitler? If the feds arrest a citizen for vandalism is that enough?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767932645.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Except I've literally been to multiple protests where Holocaust survivors showed up to talk about how the refugee camps reminded them of 1930s Germany.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34785346196.0" user="nschubach" delta="False">
    <text>You can be reminded of something and not have it be the same thing.  I can be reminded of a time I was stung by a bee if I prick my finger, but I'm not going to smash the needle if it happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768654496.0" user="cabridges" delta="False">
    <text>Godwin, the person who created that rule, [has expressly said it doesn't apply](https://twitter.com/sfmnemonic/status/896884949634232320) when talking about actual comparable situations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776458813.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; this situation doesn't compare at all.

The Holocaust Museum says it does.

&amp;gt; Besides everyone knows the first person that resorts to calling someone Hitler has a weak argument.

Ah yes, "Godwin's Law".  But Godwin himself says this situation is comparable to Hitler's rise in Germany.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767906581.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768091275.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/MisanthropicMensch – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+MisanthropicMensch&amp;amp;message=MisanthropicMensch+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fyzwwet/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768103005.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768360366.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MisanthropicMensch – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+MisanthropicMensch&amp;amp;message=MisanthropicMensch+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz013z1/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768838233.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768019447.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/Denikin_Tsar – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+Denikin_Tsar&amp;amp;message=Denikin_Tsar+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fyzrkh6/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768461396.0" user="ericsilver" delta="False">
    <text>*"Who, after all, speaks today of the annihilation of the Armenians?"*

It's probably better to talk of genocide too frequently than to risk invoking it too seldom.  

It's probably better to be more paranoid about the end of our Democracy than to dismiss the threat out of hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768482103.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>For some reason there seems to be this attitude amongst some people, and admittedly it’s probably just conservatives trying to gaslight and deflect, that you aren’t allowed to sound the fire alarm until the building is actually completely engulfed with flames.

If you dare sound the alarm at just the sign of smoke, apparently that’s insulting to victims who have died in fires in the past.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770129779.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772439291.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>u/HillaryKlingon – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+HillaryKlingon&amp;amp;message=HillaryKlingon+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz18jub/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771330118.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Just how close towards the Holocaust and fascism must Trump go before it will be okay to make those comparisons?

How about 1/100th of the way there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767670920.0" user="Liamthedon777" delta="False">
    <text>Just an FIY, when you refuse to see the similarities between what Trump' s doing to "Gestapo tactics" you are insulting the memory of my ancestors who actually suffered at hands of the Gestapo and the millions of other who have suffered also.

This kind of comparison is insensitive to the highest degree and very counterproductive to your case.

If people have no knowledge of the Trumps actions and they believe you, they will think "Trump's actions was bad, but it wasn't as bad as those "antifa" make it out to be".

On the other hand, those that know about Trumps actions and see your refusal to acknowledge any parralels will outright dismiss you as being wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768202880.0" user="Aksius14" delta="False">
    <text>So the thing that made the gestapo... (Bad? Not sure how to phrase it correctly... Anyway, let's go with bad)... Was that they operated outside the normal legal paths present in Germany at the time. Here's a direct quote from the Holocaust Encyclopedia (I don't know if they're a good resource, but it seemed reasonable to use their quote.) 

(Small edit here: I realize this isn't clear so I'm adding it. The gestapo acting outside the law gave them the ability to do all the other horrible shit they did with impunity. )

"The Gestapo had a mandate to operate outside the law or judicial review to repress any legal activity considered unacceptable by the Party." 

Currently, in Portland, federal law enforcement officials are "proactive"ly arresting protesters. The DHS Secretary was the one who said they were being "proactive." These people are largely not being marandised. They are being arrested without probably cause. They are being arrested because they are exercising their rights to freedom of speech in a way that makes the US President look/feel bad. 

There are similarities there. It is not offensive to point it out.

Are they being killed in secret prisons? No, they are being taken to jail and imprisoned illegally for a night to 48 hours. Still illegal, but a difference for sure. 

What about this discussion or my points undermines the suffering of anyone during the Holocaust? I know the situations are different. I would like them to stay different. I would like them to become more different.

It's pretty hard to do that without acknowledging the similarities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768335339.0" user="Denikin_Tsar" delta="False">
    <text>It's certainly not offensive to point it out the way you did.  But I was not replying to you.

I was replying to a poster who was saying:  " ...sending in federal agents into cities and using getsapo tactics to terrorize protesters. "

Sorry, but there is a world of difference in people who are arguably breaking the law and causing mischief being taken in to custody for question and released 24h-48h later and the actual tactics the gestapo used to terrorize citizen.

You sounded reasonable in your arguments (though I don't fully agree with them).  the person I replied makes wild claims that "Trump thinks he was elected king" and saying that he is different mental disorders.

So you can see how I took offense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768393481.0" user="Aksius14" delta="False">
    <text>I appreciate your reply. 

As a person who is concerned about current events but trying to discuss them openly and honestly, please accept the following constructive criticism:

The way your replied will almost always illicit strong emotional replies. Instead of telling someone they are wrong and then also telling them they should feel ashamed, if you actually were offended by that statement explain why. Bonus points if you ask them to clarify why they used that language. 

You're still gonna have people call you names and treat you like shit, but that's the internet, but you might also change someone's view or get your own view changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768452451.0" user="Denikin_Tsar" delta="False">
    <text>That makes sense, thank!  
I will keep this in mind</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768457337.0" user="Aksius14" delta="False">
    <text>** shrug ** 

For the record, I fail at doing this often. 😁 But it's important to try.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768444515.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>It's not offensive to point that out at all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769916687.0" user="Armigine" delta="False">
    <text>I had relatives die at the hands of the gestapo too, and honestly the thought that parallels can't be drawn - essentially that lessons can't be learned, and future situations like that can't be nipped in the bud - seems far more offensive to their memories than someone using it too lightly. I'd rather err on the side of that not happening again, and debating whether a given comparison is a fair one seems a far better way to do that than complaining about the comparison being made at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770134707.0" user="Denikin_Tsar" delta="False">
    <text>My issue isn't exactly that someone makes the comparison.  (For example someone comparing the NKVD in Soviet Russia would be making a fair comparison).
However, comparing the brave men and women of our security forces, trying to bring order to a city to stop violent looters and arsonists from destorying buildings and hurting people to the Gestapo is extremely insulting.  Obviously to the people who serve and protect but also less obviously to the victims of the Gestapo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776448118.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; you are insulting the memory of my ancestors who actually suffered at hands of the Gestapo and the millions of other who have suffered also.

Your ancestors don't *have* any memories anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777021583.0" user="Denikin_Tsar" delta="False">
    <text>Not the dead ones, but the ones that are alive do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34777043154.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>I just called them and they said they weren't insulted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767551646.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;such as sending in federal agents into cities

This has happened several times throughout US history. Not with the previous presidents mentioned, but that is my point. It's not exactly new.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767773353.0" user="YourSilenceSaysAll" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; such as sending in federal agents into cities 

I believe the person you are replying to isn't making the point of having merely that aspect be new, I believe the difference they are referring to comes from actually quoting the entire sentence:

&amp;gt; None of those former presidents you listed did anything close to what Trump has done, such as sending in federal agents into cities ***and*** using getsapo tactics to terrorize protesters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767784468.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>You've not seen footage of the various 60's and 70's protests then. The playbook being used now is the same one being used then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767836568.0" user="YourSilenceSaysAll" delta="False">
    <text>As many tactics I have seen across the 60's and 70's protests I've personally never heard of using federal troops to kidnap protestors. I'm not knowledgeable enough to be certain they haven't, just I personally have yet to see anything that actually resembles these specific tactics to have happened before .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767860920.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;kidnap protestors

It's called arresting, and yes that did happen. There's literally pictures of Bernie being arrested for protesting during that time simply for protesting. Feds got involved a lot in that era.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767923773.0" user="YourSilenceSaysAll" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, I thought we were operating under the understanding that protestors have been getting taken by unnamed, unmarked, armed groups of people, who give no indication of being legal authority, no cautions or reasonable cause or reason for arrests given, and then forcibly taken into unmarked vehicles to be relocated?

This in any other nation is considered kidnapping.

Did this happen to Bernie?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768015160.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm sorry, I thought we were operating under the understanding that protestors have been getting taken by unnamed, unmarked,

You are under the wrong understanding then. Look at the pictures. They all have patches on shoulders and back identifying them.

&amp;gt;who give no indication of being legal authority

This hasn't been an issue just here. This is what the uproar among some communities over no knock raids has been about.

&amp;gt;no cautions or reasonable cause or reason for arrests given,

Yes, this did happen to Bernie. Also the burning builds in the vacinity is technically cause, even if it's a shitty excuse.

&amp;gt;and then forcibly taken into unmarked vehicles to be relocated?

Feds use unmarked vehicles more often than not. Most aren't from the areas they're sent to and it's impractical to maintain a fleet of cars in every major city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768323199.0" user="YourSilenceSaysAll" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are under the wrong understanding then. Look at the pictures. They all have patches on shoulders and back identifying them.

This seems to contradict the video, reliably sourced articles of the events (E.G [https://mediabiasfactcheck.com/reuters/](https://mediabiasfactcheck.com/reuters/) ): [https://www.reuters.com/article/us-global-race-protests-portland/u-s-swoops-down-on-portland-protesters-after-trump-order-to-protect-monuments-idUSKCN24I2W5](https://www.reuters.com/article/us-global-race-protests-portland/u-s-swoops-down-on-portland-protesters-after-trump-order-to-protect-monuments-idUSKCN24I2W5) "Multiple videos posted online show camouflage-clad officers without clear identification badges using force and unmarked vehicles to transport arrested protesters. ",  
 and the grounds for the criminal investigation into these kidnappings : [https://www.doj.state.or.us/media-home/news-media-releases/attorney-general-rosenblum-files-lawsuit-against-u-s-homeland-security-announces-criminal-investigation/](https://www.doj.state.or.us/media-home/news-media-releases/attorney-general-rosenblum-files-lawsuit-against-u-s-homeland-security-announces-criminal-investigation/)

There is obvious evidence of some federal troops having identifying agency tags, but they are intentionally not individually identifiable:  [https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-53473732](https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-53473732)  " They said agents had identified themselves and were wearing CBP insignia but their names were not displayed "due to recent doxing incidents against law enforcement personnel who serve and protect our country." "

&amp;gt;This hasn't been an issue just here. This is what the uproar among some communities over no knock raids has been about.

Yeah that's fair, that individual aspect of the entire kidnapping in itself does have other issues surrounding it currently in America.  I don't think anybody would reasonably dispute the obvious problems surrounding this MO.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;Yes, this did happen to Bernie. Also the burning builds in the vacinity is technically cause, even if it's a shitty excuse.

I'm sorry if that came across to you as me arguing that Bernie hadn't been arrested without reasonable cause given, I was intending to make a comparison between the entire situation of the arrests, not a single facet of it. When I said had this happened to Bernie I meant the combination of every factor listed, since the topic was the method of arrest altogether.I highly doubt that occurred.

Also see my earlier listed criminal investigation source and any cursory google search on statements from US attorneys gives pretty good indication on how the grounds for reasonable cause are very disputable.

Edit:  This comment in this thread seems to cover the reasonable cause / lawful arrest aspect directly.

[https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv\_donald\_trump\_has\_taken\_concrete\_steps\_toward/fz04x5n/](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/fz04x5n/)

&amp;gt;Feds use unmarked vehicles more often than not ...

Again, I don't doubt that this individual aspect has been used before. It is very obvious to everybody considering the situation in the entirety that the issue of unmarked cars becomes an issue due to the lack of any other means to have any reasonable way for those detained to be able to distinguish those they are being detained by from genuine kidnappers dressed up.

giving entirely separate examples of *some individual aspects* of the arrest, but none of them all combined together, does not make it the same as actions with all of them culminating together,  the culmination of all of these factors creates an obvious difference in severity and is an obvious large part of the comparison to arrests.

Also I think It would be helpful if you provided a source for any of the unsubstantiated positive claims you've made.

Edit 2: no disputes? Guess we found out who's "under the wrong understanding then."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768483977.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>Good job shutting that guy up this was very well listed, and researched</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769036098.0" user="WrinklyScroteSack" delta="False">
    <text>IMO, I don't think we're on this forum to shut people up.  We're supposed to be here to have respectful debates and try to change people's opinions.  There's a lot of bad faith debaters and people who dig their feet in the sand and fire back with fallacy rhetoric when confronted with facts they don't want to agree with...  Why are these people here if they're not interested in having their views and opinions challenged?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769043480.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>Non-meaningful comments with no contribution like mine and hers aren’t lumped into this is different there was no debate of the topic at hand just a debate over why a meaningless comment was a meaningless comment lol

Me and op had a very meaningful discussion after this comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768479474.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>\-A patch is not an indication of identity 

\-Even in no knock raids upon entering they must announce they are police for it to be lawful

\-No that's not true you must state why the arrest is happening or why they're being suspected during the arrest</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768463589.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>No it's literally called kidnapping

There are laws to what constitutes an arrest local and federal laws control those standards what they're doing is not making a lawful arrest 

\-Not presenting yourself as an officer (uniform is not enough as ruled by the supreme court) then it is not a lawful arrest

\-Not having identification on a uniform makes it a not a lawful arrest

\-Not being told why there are being detained or arrested even if it seems obvious still does not make it a lawful arrest</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768106673.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Those protests were confronted by local and state police, and the national guard, which are all under the purview of the governor and local jurisdictions, not the federal government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768115790.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>The FBI has an entire file on which federal agencies inuding their own, were involved. You are not correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768148838.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>The FBI wasn’t kidnapping people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768489276.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768778579.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>u/TheInfiniteNewt – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+TheInfiniteNewt&amp;amp;message=TheInfiniteNewt+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz09e0s/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769931856.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>The very fact that mayors and governors aren't confronting protests is what is new here. And it is unsettling. Technically, it's abdication of their duty  as sworn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768065469.0" user="the_demon_gamer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Gestapo tactics

Easy to say that when your family wasn't affected by them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768091010.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>You know nothing about my family.

Easily to flippantly dismiss the comparisons when you aren’t the one being victimized by a tyrannical GOP regime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768129292.0" user="the_demon_gamer" delta="False">
    <text>You live in one of the most free countries if not the most free country. Now tell me how are you being "victimised"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768157370.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>“You live in one of the most free countries if not the most free country.”

That is patently and objectively false.

That is just some American exceptionalism bullshit that the GOP loves to spoon feed people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768171438.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768492051.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768503339.0" user="the_demon_gamer" delta="False">
    <text>Czemu. You got a problem with the truth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768636683.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>You literally have no deplorable evidence for anything you just said therefor it is invalid until proven</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768651800.0" user="the_demon_gamer" delta="False">
    <text>What did i  say that was wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768775705.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>u/TheInfiniteNewt – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+TheInfiniteNewt&amp;amp;message=TheInfiniteNewt+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz09g5v/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768821164.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/the_demon_gamer – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+the_demon_gamer&amp;amp;message=the_demon_gamer+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz02kry/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770143200.0" user="HillaryKlingon" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt; “You live in one of the most free countries if not the most free country.”

That is patently and objectively false.

That is just some American exceptionalism bullshit that the GOP loves to spoon feed people

Do you think the Democrats have your back? Your world view is very naive and your reasons are poor.  Why don't you renounce US citizenship and move to a country that you think would meet your needs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771335574.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That is just some American exceptionalism bullshit that the GOP loves to spoon feed people.

America is the greatest and freeist country that has ever existed in the history of the world.

- Political Refugee from Communism here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772647862.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>“America is the greatest and freeist country that has ever existed in the history of the world.”

That is patently and objectively not true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773627357.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773627382.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/PolishBearYawn – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776487916.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  freeist country

The United States has the world's highest prisoner rate, with 655 prisoners per 100,000 of the national population.

Your Holocaust-era relatives would be ashamed of their ignorant descendant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776564022.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>My Holocaust-era relatives loved America to literal tears. Something someone like yourself will never understand. They were constantly amazed at how free and safe the country is. They were amazed you could just go anywhere and do anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776664295.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>Blacks couldn't even use public restrooms, so your Holocaust-era relatives were stupid imbeciles for thinking the ignorant thoughts you've attributed to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776692555.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What The Fuck LOL

My grandparents from my mom's side lived through the Holocaust as young children and communism for the next 40 years and then they got to spend the last 10 or so years of their lives in America 

Christ you're thick</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776701275.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34778540019.0" user="ihatedogs2" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/hereitisyouhappynow – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+hereitisyouhappynow&amp;amp;message=hereitisyouhappynow+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz55efv/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776478106.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>By the administration's Covid response.  Now tell me why your Holocaust-era relatives would be proud of you for siding with Nazis today</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776468369.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>It's easy to say it regardless.  "Gestapo tactics." 

"Gestapo tactics." "Gestapo tactics." "Gestapo tactics."

I could do this all day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768512344.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>Talk about hyperbole, and let me fix a huge mistake in your comment. You said protesters when in fact they are rioters and terrorists. For weeks they've been terrorizing streets in major cities and terrorizing others living in those cities.

How dare Trump actually impose the law on criminals. Like what a crazy concept that people who destroy buildings, burn buildings, rip people out of cars to beat them and kill officers actually get punished.

You talk about the rule of law yet you are up in arms when law is actually enforced on CRIMINALS. Gestapo tactics, what a joke and the fact you so adamantly believe that shows how far delusional you've gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768542271.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>“Terrorists”

And what about the “unite the right” rally in Charlottesville?

Are those “terrorists” too?

What about when Amon Bundy’s and his group of thugs violently occupied a federal wild life preserve and trashed the place.

Are they “terrorists” too?

Or do they get a pass because they are conservative?

“How dare Trump actually impose the law on criminals. Like what a crazy concept that people who destroy buildings, burn buildings, rip people out of cars to beat them and kill officers actually get punished.”

How dare we have this crazy concept known as “separation of powers”?

I know. I know. Once a Dem is back in the White House, conservatives will once again believe in states rights, small government, and protest and dissent being “patriotic”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768634655.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>If they destroy property then yes they are terrorists. In Charlottesville did they set fires to buildings, destroy hard working people's small businesses, beat people in the streets. Not that I heard of. Right now these people who are destroying and burning those are TERRORISTS not protesters.

I don't even know who Amon Bundy is but if his group was destroying things then yes I'd consider them terrorists. Unlike you, to me it doesn't matter on what side of politics you are on. Destroying, burning and rioting is not alright. But all you care about is the politics so you can't see that the current rioters are bad.

"Separation of powers" you say. It's funny how Democrats believe in separation of powers only when it suits them. Maybe if they would actually do something to stop this destruction then the federal gov wouldn't have to get involved. That's a pretty crazy concept too. While we're at it why don't the states take responsibility for their COVID response instead of blaming the federal gov. Oh wait, that would just expose the shitty governance of Democratic leaders in their states and cities so they need to blame the President.

Get real man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768675988.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Oh right, in Charlottesville, they just showed up armed with improvised body armor, shields, and melee weapons, discharged firearms at counter protesters, beat a bunch of black people to a pulp with said improvised melee weapons, and ran over one person with a car, all while chanting “Jews will not replace us!”

Sounds like terrorism to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768715004.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>Okay if that's true then yeah they were. Though I suspect you are lying, I mean it would be strange to chant "Jews will not replace us!" while beating up black people, unless the black people were Jewish but anyways if you wanna link me some sources I'm more than happy to read them.

I guess you won't be addressing the rest of my comment then. That's cool.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768785941.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>“you are lying, I mean it would be strange to chant "Jews will not replace us!" while beating up black people, unless the black people were Jewish”

You don’t understand how white nationalism works, do you?

Neo-Nazis don’t like anyone who isn’t WASP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768945348.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>I said I suspect you are lying, I didn't  just say you are lying. Why should I trust anything you say now when you're willing to cut out part of my comment. It was literally 3 words so you easily could've added in to your quotations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771646286.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>You could just watch a video of the rally[Vice News](https://youtu.be/RIrcB1sAN8I) . They said lots of things, did lots of things. But you’re moving around the issue, which is that you see the current wave of BLM protesters as “others,” whom you don’t empathize with or want to understand. You can understand the police, you can understand the administration, you can apparently even rationalize a White Supremacist rally as being not terroristic at all. Often, we find or create facts that support our emotional beliefs. If they are proven false, we drop them and look for other shields.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769946147.0" user="Armigine" delta="False">
    <text>..dude, the definition of terrorism has nothing to do with the destruction of property</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776503277.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How dare Trump actually impose the law on criminals.

He doesn't.  He commuted Roger Stone's sentence.

&amp;gt; you are up in arms when law is actually enforced on CRIMINALS

Protesting is legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34800832799.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>Destroying property isn't hence criminals. Unless you're saying that there's no difference between the people protesting and the ones destroying things/setting things on fire.

Is that what you're saying? That those people are one and the same?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770109893.0" user="HillaryKlingon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Trump is a textbook case of Narcissistic Personality Disorder, along with probably some other co-morbid mental illness or personality disorder.

Do you have evidence or has his physician mentioned that he is a NPD or mental illness? I ask because of the stigma of mental illness and the hypocrisy of people throwing out labels on people they dislike.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770653919.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, many mental health professionals have concluded that he most likely has NPD.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767443172.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>I think you have a few seriously faulty premises going into this.

The first is that you seem to think that Trump is normal.

I actually was relatively politically aware during the Bush jr. election. There were things that I disagreed with about Bush was doing, but I never imagined for a second that he would refuse a transition of power.

Trump has openly declared that he might. And he has proven that he is fully capable of going against democratic values, when it benefits him.

The second is that your entire argument of "X said it about Y and that turned out fine" is really fallacious at its core. We are not talking about Bush, Obama, or Clinton, we are talking about Trump. And "it turned out this way in the past," as an argument, needs a stronger backbone of WHY it turned out that way.

I can be proven wrong if I failed to understand the US electoral system, and there is a safeguard in place I was unaware of. Or if I can be lead to believe that Trump's behavior most actually indicates that he actually will abdicate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767509382.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And he has proven that he is fully capable of going against democratic values, when it benefits him.

Perhaps, but everything he has done thus far has been within his powers as the President and Commander in Chief.  The military has always been exceptionally wary about wading into politics - so long as the order given is lawful, they will obey it - even if they believe that order is a bad idea.

Refusing to accept the results of the election is a _huge_ step beyond anything we have seen thus far.  Trump would need the backing of the military to pull off a coup of that scale - nothing short of that will be successful.  It is _highly_ unlikely that the top military brass would openly defy the results of the election (that would be wading into politics) - they would back the person elected,  regardless of what the loser claims happened.

Now, why do I have so much faith in the military here?  It is because we have already seen them defy Trump on what they believed to be unlawful orders.  According to reports, there was open rejection of Trump's desire to use the armed forces to quell the protests in D.C back in June - they did not feel the order was lawful, so they refused to deploy.  If they are willing to defy the current CiC over what they believed to be an unlawful order, it does not bode well for his chances of getting them to back him if he tries to circumvent an election to usurp power.

Trump can bluster all he wants about refusing to accept the results of the election, but Trump is just one solitary, old man.  His power comes from people following his orders due to the power vested in his office.  Once he no longer holds that office, his power evaporates and he is just one solitary, old man yelling at people who are no longer bound to listen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767686846.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>So I agree and disagree with you.

I agree that the military will not support him, ultimately, and that he will be removed by force. I consider it one of the most likely possibilities.

I disagree that it will be as simple and orderly as that, though, and that he will ever become "one solitary old man yelling at people." Like it or not, supporting Trump has a religious devotion for a real contingent of the population. What we are going to see will be messy.

Regardless, you haven't really disproven my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767715447.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I agree that the military will not support him, ultimately, and that he will be removed by force.

Nah.  Once he knows the military won't support him, he'll back down and leave without a fight.  He'll complain on OANN, but he won't actually try to be defiant in any meaningful way.  It is his playbook - talk a big game, but when it comes time to actually fight a fight you know you will lose, run away.

&amp;gt;  Like it or not, supporting Trump has a religious devotion for a real contingent of the population. What we are going to see will be messy.

I doubt it.  They will bitch and moan, sure, but are they actually going to _do_ anything about it?  Are they going to start riots?  Are they going to try to overthrow the military?

The reality is that while 20-30% of his base may worship him, only a tiny, tiny fraction would actually do anything directly self-sacrificing to try to keep him in power.  Their support is ultimately about their own selfishness - they feel that they are being taken from, so they support him because they will be better off for it.  Once they see that the will be met with the full force of the US institutions, they will back down pretty quick.  These aren't people that _actually_ want revolution - they are people who want to play dress up in tacti-cool gear on the weekends and fantasize about revolution.  Once they have to put their lives on the line and really _risk_ something for their 'hero', they will fold like a cheap suit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768463726.0" user="Head_mc_ears" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's also that these supporters really want to have the ability to violently let out their rage that built up from years of being told they're losing (check out r/publicfreakout... Yeesh), and be allowed to walk away from their damage/work worry-/consequence-free.  
Civil conflict? Kind of hard to have a quarter-pounder and strawberry shake if there are bullets flying around the drive-through.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768477926.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Yup - throwing a tantrum is one thing because the assume there will be no _actual_ consequences from said tantrum (look at how many half-assed 'I'm sorry for my actions' apologies we get from these people), but _actual_ revolution with _real_ consequences is a whole different thing.

There is a reason that revolution has always been a young man's game - older people just have too much to lose to upset the apple cart like that, even if they are not 100% happy with the cart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768514987.0" user="Head_mc_ears" delta="False">
    <text>There really is nothing better than watching the "oh, shit" wash over a red-cap's face when the police/sheriff shows up and they sober up from their rage.
That's the fun of r/publicfreakout.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768523972.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>I also love the "These actions don't reflect who I am" apologies we see.

No, you are not sorry for what you did/said - you are sorry you _got caught_.  You are not sorry for the harm you caused, but for the fact that you are finally facing repercussions for your choices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768566567.0" user="Head_mc_ears" delta="False">
    <text>Which, with many of these older boomer folks, they have always had the world on a platter.

Now that they're looking at post retirement burnout and three generations demanding a decent life and ability to move upward, the false Zero-Sum idea kicks into high-gear and that means their world-view of "I'm supposed to be the awesome one!!" doesn't calculate anymore, so... TANTRUM TIME!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771163118.0" user="Do__Math__Not__Meth" delta="False">
    <text>This happens with young folks too, look at all the rich frat/sorority type kids that get exposed for this and they give the most half assed, “oh shit they caught me” apologies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767748516.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  everything he has done thus far has been within his powers as the President and Commander in Chief

Like illegally pressuring a foreign nation to open an investigation of his main democratic rival? Two foreign nations actually, because he tried with both Ukraine and China.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767758884.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that is where is gets messy.  He _does_ have the power to work with other nations for the betterment of US interests.  Asking for the investigation _itself_ isn't illegal or problematic - it is _why_ he asked for the investigation that is the issue.  The power he exercised was valid, but his motivations were the problem.

Trying to stay in office after the election is not a power he actually has.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767806520.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but his motivation made it abuse of power, which is not in his purview. This actually demonstrates OP's point on how he starts relatively small and innocuous, then keeps pushing until heb crosses the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769917641.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Trump would need the backing of the military to pull off a coup of that scale - nothing short of that will be successful.

This is beyond unlikely. Military officers take their oath very, very seriously, and it includes "to defend the Constitution".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769927284.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly - that’s my point. I don’t see a situation where the military brass sides with him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769909483.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The first is that you seem to think that Trump is normal.

He is largely a fairly normal person. Because of an acquired style of communication, used for specific purposes, one might accuse him of all sort of pathologies but in the end, he's not a monster nor a crazy person. 

It's all an act, basically. Is he someone who lost himself in the character he plays? I can't say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770051964.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>If you wear a mask long enough, it distorts who you are underneath. He’s been wearing this projection for decades.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770094703.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>He definitely has. He does seem more human than when he started.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771706229.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>In a good way or a bad way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773629199.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>In a "good question" way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770631469.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>I'm really confused by this line of argument.

You start by saying that Trump is an abnormal person. Then you muse that he is acting as someone that he isn't, and he might have lost himself in a character he plays. But it seems like occam's razor makes it more likely that he IS the person he presents himself as, and secondarily: normal people don't lose themselves in characters they are playing. This is an abnormal trait.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770659809.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  normal people don't lose themselves in characters they are playing. 

This happens more often than you'd think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771713384.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>But once you take on the abnormal personality traits you pretend to have, are you still normal? I’d argue, no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773633467.0" user="ArkyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue " I don't really even know any more."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771310409.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771503868.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, what are you doing here?

Like I could go and find objective proof that everything you’re saying is wrong, but you could too, and you won’t. And regardless I already said that I’m not even arguing with people whose response is to insult me.

The thing I do find interesting is that you seem to think that even acknowledging the “Trump cult” is setting the stage for bad faith arguments. So what, then? His over-the-top devotees don’t exist?

*checks comments*

Yep. Not real at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771664952.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771768157.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>Here you go, I hunted for the original [Fox news](https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-pushes-back-against-critics-on-coronavirus-addresses-whether-he-will-accept-election-results-in-exclusive-interview) version of him suggesting he might deny the election results for you. Have fun, and have a great night. Enjoy your life in your bubble, and your comfortable assumptions that everyone else lives in a bubble, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34771820446.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772417306.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>u/PolishBearYawn – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+PolishBearYawn&amp;amp;message=PolishBearYawn+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz28sda/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772416144.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/PolishBearYawn – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+PolishBearYawn&amp;amp;message=PolishBearYawn+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz25ge0/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34772417882.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/PolishBearYawn – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+PolishBearYawn&amp;amp;message=PolishBearYawn+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/-/fz1xutl/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767499399.0" user="Basiord" delta="False">
    <text>Just because they were wrong about bush doesnt mean they will be wrong about trump

Trump has been setting up contesting the election</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767564364.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>In order for him to be able to "just say no" he would need military support. The type of support that Bush Sr. had but Trump does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767582362.0" user="Basiord" delta="False">
    <text>Very true

But he could make it a very difficult transition</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767617433.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That's the thing: no he can't. He can be as uncooperative as can be and Jan 20th he's still gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34773667815.0" user="Giacamo22" delta="False">
    <text>He may not be in the Oval Office come next February, but it’s not madness to think there’ll be violence around his ousting. Fox News has deified Trump, and those who watch Fox News day in and day out, are afraid for him, they pity him, they love him and they firmly believe that he loves them and that BLM is coming to kill them. Tucker Carlson said a few weeks ago, “and when they defund the police, who are you going to call, when they come for your children?” This is the sort of talk that goes on before scared people do terrible things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767554671.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>I don't remember anyone ever saying anything about any of these previous presidents trying to illegitimately stay in office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767570406.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Then you did not pay attention, I provided context in another reply, with a couple links about Clinton and Obama.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767621683.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>There is a huge difference between saying you would *run* for a third term *if* it was allowed, and saying that you are going to stay in office even if voted out or your second term expires.  There was not even a suggestion of illegitimacy in those articles, even though the sources tried to spin the comments as hard as they could.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767656919.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>And yet regardless it became a talking point. Political parties don't allow things as trivial as "what was actually said" to prevent them from fear mongering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767778834.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between politicos speculating about a president not leaving office, and THE CURRENT PRESIDENT very publicly saying that he wont commit to a peaceful transition of power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767794321.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Can you provide a video or audio clip that includes 30 seconds before and 30 seconds after that says he refuses to give up the presidency if he loses the election?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767823784.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you've already seen the news clip. He tries to explain, sure, but I don't buy it. So he is doing is trying to cast doubt on the legitimacy of the upcoming election by saying "well have to see how it goes."

Regardless, to the original point, no other president has every even give that far. They all committed to accepting the results of the election without qualification, something Trump has not done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767841703.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Trump qualifies everything. It doesn't matter what it is. That's like saying Obama doesn't give a speech without long pauses in weird spots.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767917431.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>There are some things that shouldn't be qualified, especially as the leader of a free republic. Committing to leaving office if he loses is one of them. If he doesn't know that, he's not qualified to be president. 

Also, just because someone does something "all the time" doesn't mean it's good or appropriate. Say something with high anxiety rubs their nipples to call themselves down - totally ok at home, but maybe not so appropriate if you're standing over the casket at a funeral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767979404.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are some things that shouldn't be qualified, especially as the leader of a free republic.

&amp;gt;Also, just because someone does something "all the time" doesn't mean it's good or appropriate.

Sure. It also doesn't immediately mean malintent. Never attribute to malice that which can adequately be explained by incompetence. He's either a criminal mastermind or an incompetent boob. Which do you think is more likely?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768013368.0" user="sterboog" delta="False">
    <text>You act like he can't both a criminal and incompetent. I never said he was a good criminal - he is, thankfully he's more incompetent than smart. Its not like we need to speculate - we've seen him stir up trouble before the 2018 midterm that just... disappeared afterward? After the midterms I was explicitly watching him to see if he mentioned migrant caravans and... nothing.

We know he was at least aware that wikileaks was actively harming his democratic rivals, and did nothing. In fact, he said he would take oppo research from a hostile power again, even after he was informed why it was illegal. and SO MUCH MORE from the past few years.  I'm not assuming malintent, I'm basing it on his previous actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767844069.0" user="Impossible_Cat_9796" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Democrats said the same thing about Bush (H. W. And W) and he left office just fine. Republicans said it about both Clinton and Obama.

Which of these presidents had secrete police in unmarked vans kidnapping political dissidents off the street in broad daylight?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767871431.0" user="Dallenforth" delta="False">
    <text>Which president rounded up Asian Americans and put them in concentration camps</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768067338.0" user="Impossible_Cat_9796" delta="False">
    <text>The one that served 4 terms and only left office cause he died.

Is this where we are going with Trump?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767895668.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;kidnapping

Arresting, not kidnapping. Feds use unmarked vans all the time. Most feds don't have shitloads of assets in every city, so they rent or buy new. You being unaware of their methods until now is on you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768083884.0" user="Impossible_Cat_9796" delta="False">
    <text>If your jummping out of an unmarked van and grabbing someone off the streets, that's a kidnaping not an arrest.  It's kidnapping even if the kidnappers have guns...err I mean badges.

This wasn't done before.  Federal agents may have been using rental cars.  But they where walking into office buildings with warrents, not jumping out of the cars to attack people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768097816.0" user="ltwerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's kidnapping even if the kidnappers have guns...err I mean badges.

No, it's an arrest if they have a badge and are tasked by upper law enforcement to do exactly that.

&amp;gt;This wasn't done before. 

Happened almost identically in the LA riots, except those folks didn't have patches on their shoulds and back identifying who they were.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768038306.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>Except Obama left by spying on the incoming administration and using powers to fabricate a story of Russian collusion which lasted over 3 years and did an enormous amount of damage.

The media and Democrats have done a great job of painting Trump and Republicans as some sort of crazy fascist lunatics that will take rollback gay rights and women's rights and put people in concentration camps yet none of that has happened. They've stoked the flames of fear and then you get posts like this OP who is lacking the awareness to see the only people who have refused transition of power have been Democrats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34769933763.0" user="Letshavemorefun" delta="False">
    <text>Except they literally have been rolling back gay rights and women’s rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34770484335.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>So here's the problem.

The idea that Obama entirely fabricated the story of Russian collusion is a lunatic belief. It is so far from grounded reality that this is the only way I can describe it. You, personally, in your day to day life might not be a lunatic. However, you do not have the right to believe whatever you choose to believe and have no one judge you for it.

Gay rights have been rolled back. Women's rights have been rolled back. Refugees have been put into detention centers in which death and sexual abuse has occurred. Everything that you are declaring "true" is easily identifiable as false, and everything that you are declaring "false" is identifiable as true, and it can all be verified with a quick glance at politifact.

I do not believe that you personally believe in fascism. However, you are presenting an entire worldview here that is not based in objective reality, and it's easy for a fascist leader to take advantage of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776434074.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; fabricate a story of Russian collusion

Source?  Tweets don't count.

&amp;gt; rollback gay rights and women's rights and put people in concentration camps yet none of that has happened. 

All of that has happened.  You just don't know about it because Christians are ignorant in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34800815712.0" user="True-Natural" delta="False">
    <text>Bahaha none of that has happened. You're glued daily to opinion articles about doom and gloom, I'd advise you to get outside more and into the real world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768419638.0" user="TheInfiniteNewt" delta="False">
    <text>I think this situation is a little different considering he's actively been pushing the boundary of his limitations since the day he stepped into office 

To consider this anything like any president before him would be preposterous the internet is a major part of this that needs to be considered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34776429207.0" user="hereitisyouhappynow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Democrats said the same thing about Bush (H. W. And W) and he left office just fine. Republicans said it about both Clinton and Obama.

But now Trump is saying it about himself.  That's why this is different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
