<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767938932.0" user="Veximusprime" delta="False">
    <text>These concrete steps was taken twenty years ago, after the towers fell.


It's not that long ago that occupy wallstreet was a thing. It's not that long ago that "audit the fed" was a thing. The military industrial complex protests. People were sick and tired of politicians being in the pocket of the same companies that to this day still spend billions in lobbying and bribes. Did Obama bring hope and change? Did Trump make America great again? Or did they continue where their predecessors left off? The Patriot Act and homeland security was Bushes invention, and neither president following has removed it. They're both also totally okay with the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (fisa). Edward Snowden made people aware of the extent of the surveillance, and the police are allowed to swat people based on hunches. 



In my opinion, the hysteria around the left/right paradigme is just a show. The for profit businesses that give you the news, are feeding on this like a smorgasbord. Not being from the US, it's baffling to see the difference in news channels in Europe contra the US. They successfully made some Americans legitimately believe that they are the ones who care about the well-being of the people, and that the opposition is set out to destroy the country through a totalitarian dictatorship, be it Marxist or fascists depending on what side of the line they're on.


Edit: tl;dr - It's not just Trump. It your whole system starting with Bush and the Patriot Act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767957689.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you in some sense. But I also think that this is pretty tangential to the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34768004901.0" user="Veximusprime" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I suppose I went on a tangent. Sorry about that. May I ask, you define a fascists regime?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
