<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108804453.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ss21x/i_think_the_main_reason_to_object_to_cars_isnt/">
    <title>I think the main reason to object to cars isn't pollution or gasoline, it's the space; the fact that gridlock happens at all is ridiculous. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>spazdor</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I see most car-judging on the Internet, I see people mainly talking about tailpipe emissions and the environment, or else gasoline prices and international politics. Now I want to agree hastily that these are good, important things to worry about, but I'm not really worried about them, at least not in the long term. Cars are getting more fuel efficient, and hybrid cars are gaining market share, and eventually they'll run on some other energy source anyway. 

But cars are *not* getting significantly smaller, the brief Mini fad notwithstanding, and the population is growing.

My home city, Vancouver, is certainly not the worst North American city when it comes to traffic, and I think some people would even say we're comparatively pretty good. But still every morning, and every evening, for about 2 hours each, our downtown core and the major arteries of our city are full. Not completely jammed, but moving slowly, bumper-nearly-to-bumper, travelling at roughly the same average pace as a moderately-fit jogger.

They move this slowly because there are such-and-such many cars per kilometre of road, and because it would be unsafe to drive at/near the speed limit when the distance between cars is so short; no one has that kind of reaction time. And there are so many cars because, as a society, we have this thing where it is basically expected that every adult who has passed some tests, is entitled to occupy their own 4 or 5 meter rectangle of public road space to themselves, for as long as they need to. 

This is something which most city dwellers see as normal, and I can't seem to get anyone else to see this everyone-gets-a-car-or-at-least-most-people model of urban life as a completely absurd, ludicrous solution to a pretty simple engineering problem. The usefulness of everyone's car decreases slightly with each additional car there is on the road, and I feel like most medium-to-big cities are already at the point of diminishing returns, where additional cars slow down their neighbours by a greater margin than they provide their own driver, and so actually have *negative net utility.*

Does it make sense for people to use the same machine to traverse between cities (highway systems are *very* efficient!) as they use to cross town? If it does, CMV!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26969260574.0" user="Thalenia" delta="False">
    <text>2 issues here...

First, what do you expect to use as an option to cars to get around?  Very, very few cities have the infrastructure to shuttle all their people around without cars.  

Mass transit isn't useful in smaller cities, and costs too much in places where the cities are already developed.  In order to construct trains or other rail systems, you have to buy the rights of way out from under business and homeowners before you can even start to construct.

Oh, the same applies to building more highways.  Once a town is built, it costs tons of money to commandeer people's houses to build new highways.  People don't like that.  High paid lawyers love the idea though, and many get to pay off their vacation homes anywhere this happens.

Buses sure, assuming only 1% of the population uses them, but when it becomes 50% all you have is streets full of buses instead of cars, and people getting around town very much slower than they used to, which solves nothing.

Second, how do *get to* the highways?  You drive the cars there.  And, unless you live on the highway, you'll have to drive through town to get there.  Or if you're lucky enough to work in town, you probably still have to drive there (see above). 

Even if your town has a system where you can commute to a mass transit system, this doesn't solve the problem.  My area is like that, and again, you still need to drive through the 'local' area to get to it, so the local traffic isn't effected.  Not everyone can live within walking distance of the stations, and they can't possibly build enough stations to prevent local traffic.

Lastly, before the 'well just move / get a job closer or more convenient', most people don't have that luxury.  I won't add to the wall of text explaining that unless you don't understand for some reason.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
