<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108804453.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ss21x/i_think_the_main_reason_to_object_to_cars_isnt/">
    <title>I think the main reason to object to cars isn't pollution or gasoline, it's the space; the fact that gridlock happens at all is ridiculous. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>spazdor</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I see most car-judging on the Internet, I see people mainly talking about tailpipe emissions and the environment, or else gasoline prices and international politics. Now I want to agree hastily that these are good, important things to worry about, but I'm not really worried about them, at least not in the long term. Cars are getting more fuel efficient, and hybrid cars are gaining market share, and eventually they'll run on some other energy source anyway. 

But cars are *not* getting significantly smaller, the brief Mini fad notwithstanding, and the population is growing.

My home city, Vancouver, is certainly not the worst North American city when it comes to traffic, and I think some people would even say we're comparatively pretty good. But still every morning, and every evening, for about 2 hours each, our downtown core and the major arteries of our city are full. Not completely jammed, but moving slowly, bumper-nearly-to-bumper, travelling at roughly the same average pace as a moderately-fit jogger.

They move this slowly because there are such-and-such many cars per kilometre of road, and because it would be unsafe to drive at/near the speed limit when the distance between cars is so short; no one has that kind of reaction time. And there are so many cars because, as a society, we have this thing where it is basically expected that every adult who has passed some tests, is entitled to occupy their own 4 or 5 meter rectangle of public road space to themselves, for as long as they need to. 

This is something which most city dwellers see as normal, and I can't seem to get anyone else to see this everyone-gets-a-car-or-at-least-most-people model of urban life as a completely absurd, ludicrous solution to a pretty simple engineering problem. The usefulness of everyone's car decreases slightly with each additional car there is on the road, and I feel like most medium-to-big cities are already at the point of diminishing returns, where additional cars slow down their neighbours by a greater margin than they provide their own driver, and so actually have *negative net utility.*

Does it make sense for people to use the same machine to traverse between cities (highway systems are *very* efficient!) as they use to cross town? If it does, CMV!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26969027726.0" user="CWHz" delta="False">
    <text>Vancouver here as well!

I agree with your argument that gridlock is not very efficient in the long run, but I think the three negative aspects to car use you mentioned (gasoline, gridlock, greenhouse gasses - three Gs!) vary depending where you are and how your city is designed. For example, Phoenix is one of the [least congested](http://www.bizjournals.com/phoenix/news/2013/11/08/study-finds-phoenix-one-of.html) cities but one of the most sprawling, car-dependent cities in the US. I would argue that in Phoenix the price of gasoline and pollution, as well as the health effects of car dependency, outweigh the problems of gridlock. Your argument works in in traffic-heavy urban areas, but I don't think it can be applied generally.

Also, Vancouver is one of the most congested cities according to some sources [1](http://www.theprovince.com/Vancouver+tops+most+congested+city+North+America+Survey/9132602/story.html) [2](https://www.google.ca/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=6&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;ved=0CGEQFjAF&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.vancouversun.com%2FVancouver%2Bsecond%2Bmost%2Btraffic%2Bcongested%2Bcity%2BNorth%2BAmerica%2Breport%2F7374883%2Fstory.html&amp;amp;ei=EaeqUtHpCYb4oAShyICADA&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNER2VaJxah_R3Hh008QxOaWu2F1ng&amp;amp;sig2=RFW7EZHS6PF7mUQmNR9z9w&amp;amp;bvm=bv.57967247,d.cGU)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969473388.0" user="spazdor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Vancouver here as well!

:D! Coconuts go!

&amp;gt; Buses sure, assuming only 1% of the population uses them, but when it becomes 50% all you have is streets full of buses instead of cars, and people getting around town very much slower than they used to, which solves nothing.

Why do you think this? ten thousand people's worth of full, or let's say half-full buses, take up *insanely* less space than the same number of people do in single-occupant cars. I think people would get to work *faster* on buses than they currently do in cars, if only the buses didn't have to share the road with so much car traffic.

&amp;gt; Also, Vancouver is one of the most congested cities according to some sources 

I didn't know this at all!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969954232.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Buses are just slower moving than cars, has nothing to do with traffic at that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26970723092.0" user="Jabberminor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Buses sure, assuming only 1% of the population uses them, but when it becomes 50% all you have is streets full of buses instead of cars, and people getting around town very much slower than they used to, which solves nothing.

In the UK, there's usually a bus lane which allows the bus to drive past all the traffic and so a 10 minute traffic jam becomes a 2 minute ride on the bus.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
