<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108804453.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ss21x/i_think_the_main_reason_to_object_to_cars_isnt/">
    <title>I think the main reason to object to cars isn't pollution or gasoline, it's the space; the fact that gridlock happens at all is ridiculous. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>spazdor</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I see most car-judging on the Internet, I see people mainly talking about tailpipe emissions and the environment, or else gasoline prices and international politics. Now I want to agree hastily that these are good, important things to worry about, but I'm not really worried about them, at least not in the long term. Cars are getting more fuel efficient, and hybrid cars are gaining market share, and eventually they'll run on some other energy source anyway. 

But cars are *not* getting significantly smaller, the brief Mini fad notwithstanding, and the population is growing.

My home city, Vancouver, is certainly not the worst North American city when it comes to traffic, and I think some people would even say we're comparatively pretty good. But still every morning, and every evening, for about 2 hours each, our downtown core and the major arteries of our city are full. Not completely jammed, but moving slowly, bumper-nearly-to-bumper, travelling at roughly the same average pace as a moderately-fit jogger.

They move this slowly because there are such-and-such many cars per kilometre of road, and because it would be unsafe to drive at/near the speed limit when the distance between cars is so short; no one has that kind of reaction time. And there are so many cars because, as a society, we have this thing where it is basically expected that every adult who has passed some tests, is entitled to occupy their own 4 or 5 meter rectangle of public road space to themselves, for as long as they need to. 

This is something which most city dwellers see as normal, and I can't seem to get anyone else to see this everyone-gets-a-car-or-at-least-most-people model of urban life as a completely absurd, ludicrous solution to a pretty simple engineering problem. The usefulness of everyone's car decreases slightly with each additional car there is on the road, and I feel like most medium-to-big cities are already at the point of diminishing returns, where additional cars slow down their neighbours by a greater margin than they provide their own driver, and so actually have *negative net utility.*

Does it make sense for people to use the same machine to traverse between cities (highway systems are *very* efficient!) as they use to cross town? If it does, CMV!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26969042291.0" user="makamakamakamaka" delta="False">
    <text>What about car accidents? They are pretty bad too.

There is no point in using your argument to devalue the emissions arguement.

Your argument is just another point in the case against the car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969043704.0" user="spazdor" delta="False">
    <text>I just wanted to narrow the focus of the CMV to this one facet.

Car accidents and the hazards posed to pedestrians are pretty intimately related to the density of cars on the road too, in complex and hard-to-characterize ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969051140.0" user="makamakamakamaka" delta="False">
    <text>Im not sure that you should change your view, gridlock is an obvious and serious problem. Comparing it to the problem of greenhouse emissions just seems like an unnecessary argument. 

Its like arguing cancer is worse than clinical depression. Both are bad, but affect people differently</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969061767.0" user="spazdor" delta="False">
    <text>Only peripherally related, but it occurred to me how funny it is that people sometimes buy bigger, heavier cars and especially SUVs on the rationale that they're safer.

"Safer? That thing looks like it could smash into stuff way harder and with more destructive force than a Jetta!" was my first thought when I heard this kind of talk, at the age of 10 or 12. Then it dawned on me: they just mean safer for *them*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
