<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="108804453.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ss21x/i_think_the_main_reason_to_object_to_cars_isnt/">
    <title>I think the main reason to object to cars isn't pollution or gasoline, it's the space; the fact that gridlock happens at all is ridiculous. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>spazdor</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I see most car-judging on the Internet, I see people mainly talking about tailpipe emissions and the environment, or else gasoline prices and international politics. Now I want to agree hastily that these are good, important things to worry about, but I'm not really worried about them, at least not in the long term. Cars are getting more fuel efficient, and hybrid cars are gaining market share, and eventually they'll run on some other energy source anyway. 

But cars are *not* getting significantly smaller, the brief Mini fad notwithstanding, and the population is growing.

My home city, Vancouver, is certainly not the worst North American city when it comes to traffic, and I think some people would even say we're comparatively pretty good. But still every morning, and every evening, for about 2 hours each, our downtown core and the major arteries of our city are full. Not completely jammed, but moving slowly, bumper-nearly-to-bumper, travelling at roughly the same average pace as a moderately-fit jogger.

They move this slowly because there are such-and-such many cars per kilometre of road, and because it would be unsafe to drive at/near the speed limit when the distance between cars is so short; no one has that kind of reaction time. And there are so many cars because, as a society, we have this thing where it is basically expected that every adult who has passed some tests, is entitled to occupy their own 4 or 5 meter rectangle of public road space to themselves, for as long as they need to. 

This is something which most city dwellers see as normal, and I can't seem to get anyone else to see this everyone-gets-a-car-or-at-least-most-people model of urban life as a completely absurd, ludicrous solution to a pretty simple engineering problem. The usefulness of everyone's car decreases slightly with each additional car there is on the road, and I feel like most medium-to-big cities are already at the point of diminishing returns, where additional cars slow down their neighbours by a greater margin than they provide their own driver, and so actually have *negative net utility.*

Does it make sense for people to use the same machine to traverse between cities (highway systems are *very* efficient!) as they use to cross town? If it does, CMV!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26969312019.0" user="bentzi" delta="False">
    <text>You have identified a problem, but not a working solution.
Yeah, it's a problem that there is rush hour for two hours twice every day, and everyone hates traffic and driving, but people still do it for one obvious reason, there is no better alternative.

&amp;gt; he usefulness of everyone's car decreases slightly with each additional car there is on the road, and I feel like most medium-to-big cities are already at the point of diminishing returns

If you say that public transportation is the solution, think about how the same argument applies to a bus. Which one is more enjoyable, a bus with 25 people, or a bus with 100, where everyone is crammed and can't move? have you ever been in line for a bus, and not able to get on it because it got full? a bus that passed by you in a bus station without stopping because it's too full?

My argument, is that most public transportation systems are not designed to handle all the population of the city, and requires at least some people to drive and not use the bus for the system to function.

If you say that we should invest in public transportation so that we don't have this problem, can't you say the same things about roads? why is one inherently better than the other as a solution to this problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969457736.0" user="spazdor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a bus with 100, where everyone is crammed and can't move? have you ever been in line for a bus, and not able to get on it because it got full? a bus that passed by you in a bus station without stopping because it's too full?

Yes, as a transit user these are pretty much daily problems for me. Buses are much more pleasant when they're not crammed, but even a half-full bus manages something like 10 to 20 times as many people per meter of road space than typical single-occupant vehicle traffic does; if the number of buses on the road increased and the number of cars decreased accordingly, congestion would still ease considerably. The fact is that our transit system can't keep enough buses on the road to keep up with demand(This is mostly because our provincial government are dicks and expect transit to mostly pay for itself) *and* the roadways get packed every day. 

&amp;gt; public transportation systems are not designed to handle all the population of the city, and requires at least some people to drive and not use the bus for the system to function

I think the main reason buses are so slow is that they have to share the road with cars.

&amp;gt; why is one inherently better than the other as a solution to this problem?

Scalability. The ceiling of usefulness for vehicles in a city is dependent, more than any other factor, on the number of people per vehicle. Doubling the surface area of our major roadways would double our headroom. Replacing our private cars with mass transit would give us more like a factor of ten.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26969949002.0" user="DJWalnut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think the main reason buses are so slow is that they have to share the road with cars.

would it help if buses were given their own lane on the road all to themselves?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
