<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109219544.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t0yc8/i_believe_creationism_andor_intelligent_design/">
    <title>I believe creationism and/or Intelligent Design should be discussed alongside evolution in high school biology classes. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dyslexda</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a Microbiology graduate student; I also am agnostic. I do not believe creationism or Intelligent Design have any scientific validity. That being said...

I believe that, unlike most on Reddit, creationism and/or Intelligent Design *should* be discussed in conjugation with teachings on evolution. There are two benefits derived from this:

1.) First, creationism provides the perfect foil for discussing what actually constitutes a good scientific theory. The common (and accurate) criticism of creationism is that it has no scientific validity. I believe we should expose students to it to lead them through discovering precisely *why* it has no scientific validity. Is it because there are no reproducible results? Is it because it, as a theory, cannot be disproven? Is it because it does not make testable predictions? Is it because of lack of peer reviewed literature? A combination of those, and more? Yes. As is, people love to extol the theory of evolution, but generally do a poor job explaining what *precisely* makes it a good theory. The best education is one that allows people to draw parallels to new concepts not learned; knowing evolution is a good theory does you nothing if you aren't able to make a similar critique of other theories.

2.) Second, knowledge of public discourse. Like it or not, it's a big issue in the public sphere. Exposing students to it in a controlled environment allows them to explore it, develop an understanding of the issue, and, as I mentioned above, discover what its severe flaws are. This also can serve to educate on how science must interface with the public. As scientists, we need to realize that, to best communicate with the public, we need to change from evidence based communication (assuming that all we have to do is present the facts and rely on others to arrive at the same conclusions) to story based communication. The debate over evolution is a perfect opportunity to explore how a message can become distorted from the scientific community to the public if not packaged correctly. 

tl;dr: Discussing creationism or ID alongside evolution, as long as the scientific merits (and lack thereof) of each theory or nontheory are clearly and unambiguously presented, offers an important foil for students to become better educated on what exactly a scientific theory is, as well as learning about the public debate in a controlled and unbiased environment.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26973305717.0" user="ccbeef" delta="False">
    <text>I'm an anti-theist, and I'd love to see science classes implement this -- in theory.

I see two problems arising:

1. This will churn up a shitstorm from all sides. Non-creationists won't want bullshit non-science taught in the class, even if it *is* for the intention of knocking it down. But, more importantly, the *creationists* will be angry because the entire section of the class would be about breaking down their faith. Creationists already think that teaching evolution = teaching atheism, and this would just exacerbate that.

2. How many teachers would *actually* teach this in the way that you specified? I imagine many would teach them as equals, and many would  put even more credibility in creationism than evolution. The implementation of your plan would actually have the opposite of its intended effect in these cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973339016.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>1.) Frankly, that's not a bad thing. The ID movement is based on trying to pass creationism off as scientifically valid. Well, perfect, let's put it to an unbiased test and see how it comes out.

2.) Standardization would be difficult, admittedly. As I commented below, I don't have a background in education, and don't have advice for curriculum development. However, that doesn't mean it's not a challenge to be overcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973376976.0" user="CNoitez" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Frankly, that's not a bad thing

Seems like it to me. You are putting a belief that while considered scientifically invalid, is still held by many kids due to their parents. These kids are perfectly capable of learning evolution while still believing Creationism in their hearts, so putting it on a pedestal to be attacked is more likely to cause harm than good. Might as well start trying to pick apart the entire Bible. 

&amp;gt; As I commented below, I don't have a background in education, and don't have advice for curriculum development. However, that doesn't mean it's not a challenge to be overcome.

I feel like the current trend is not to bash ID openly in class, but rather, merely give it its due weight. As a largely unsupported theory that most of the scientific community disagrees with, I would put it on-par with the flat Earth theory: you might mention that people used to think the Earth was flat, but you wouldn't spend entire periods of class focused on proving the Earth was round - it's simply unnecessary. I only had one Biology class in college, and in that one they basically said at the start of the semester:

"We recognize that there are some people who may believe alternate theories about the origin of the world. However, the fact is the BBT/evolution/etc. are what scientists believe, and that's what we believe. So that's what we're teaching. You don't have to believe it, but if you want to pass this class you'll need to learn it anyway."

And from then on, it was just science - mostly dealing with current biological processes and not the origin of species and such. I think this approach minimizes the amount of harm inflicted to firm ID believers, while avoiding any legal or ethical issues that would come from pushing the theory in class (even as a farce).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
