<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109219544.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t0yc8/i_believe_creationism_andor_intelligent_design/">
    <title>I believe creationism and/or Intelligent Design should be discussed alongside evolution in high school biology classes. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dyslexda</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a Microbiology graduate student; I also am agnostic. I do not believe creationism or Intelligent Design have any scientific validity. That being said...

I believe that, unlike most on Reddit, creationism and/or Intelligent Design *should* be discussed in conjugation with teachings on evolution. There are two benefits derived from this:

1.) First, creationism provides the perfect foil for discussing what actually constitutes a good scientific theory. The common (and accurate) criticism of creationism is that it has no scientific validity. I believe we should expose students to it to lead them through discovering precisely *why* it has no scientific validity. Is it because there are no reproducible results? Is it because it, as a theory, cannot be disproven? Is it because it does not make testable predictions? Is it because of lack of peer reviewed literature? A combination of those, and more? Yes. As is, people love to extol the theory of evolution, but generally do a poor job explaining what *precisely* makes it a good theory. The best education is one that allows people to draw parallels to new concepts not learned; knowing evolution is a good theory does you nothing if you aren't able to make a similar critique of other theories.

2.) Second, knowledge of public discourse. Like it or not, it's a big issue in the public sphere. Exposing students to it in a controlled environment allows them to explore it, develop an understanding of the issue, and, as I mentioned above, discover what its severe flaws are. This also can serve to educate on how science must interface with the public. As scientists, we need to realize that, to best communicate with the public, we need to change from evidence based communication (assuming that all we have to do is present the facts and rely on others to arrive at the same conclusions) to story based communication. The debate over evolution is a perfect opportunity to explore how a message can become distorted from the scientific community to the public if not packaged correctly. 

tl;dr: Discussing creationism or ID alongside evolution, as long as the scientific merits (and lack thereof) of each theory or nontheory are clearly and unambiguously presented, offers an important foil for students to become better educated on what exactly a scientific theory is, as well as learning about the public debate in a controlled and unbiased environment.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26973490151.0" user="HeloRising" delta="False">
    <text>I don't support this for a number of reasons.

It lends weight to the idea that ID is a valid scientific theory. It isn't. It hasn't passed peer review rigor, it predicts nothing, it explains nothing, and cannot be disproven. This makes it inherently unscientific and thus does not merit discussion as a topic for those discussing science. ID has had every opportunity to prove itself a valid idea worthy of inclusion into the textbooks and it's failed at every step. It's proponents insist it be treated as valid science for the sake of "fairness" except science isn't about fairness, it's about how sound your idea is. 

Using it as an example of junk science is fine but I would think it would be more valuable to simply teach them the hallmarks of junk science and allow them to identify ID as such on their own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973498692.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>Everything you mentioned in your second paragraph is something I had already mentioned. I believe its value comes specifically *because* proponents pass it off as true science; it leaves itself to be dissected in an academic context.

Regarding the second paragraph, that is ultimately the goal here, but how better to teach the characteristics of junk science than having a high profile example? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973503310.0" user="HeloRising" delta="False">
    <text>Because by bringing it up, you're validating it in some way and that's not the way to handle junk science that's caught on in the public eye.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973504843.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>Ignoring it obviously hasn't worked. I'm willing to try a different strategy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973509052.0" user="HeloRising" delta="False">
    <text>Except academia *hasn't* been ignoring it. They've been taking time out to discuss it and attend debates about it or be interviewed for TV programs on it. That's not ignoring it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973539113.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>It's been largely ignored in the classroom, which is what I mean. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
