<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109219544.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t0yc8/i_believe_creationism_andor_intelligent_design/">
    <title>I believe creationism and/or Intelligent Design should be discussed alongside evolution in high school biology classes. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dyslexda</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a Microbiology graduate student; I also am agnostic. I do not believe creationism or Intelligent Design have any scientific validity. That being said...

I believe that, unlike most on Reddit, creationism and/or Intelligent Design *should* be discussed in conjugation with teachings on evolution. There are two benefits derived from this:

1.) First, creationism provides the perfect foil for discussing what actually constitutes a good scientific theory. The common (and accurate) criticism of creationism is that it has no scientific validity. I believe we should expose students to it to lead them through discovering precisely *why* it has no scientific validity. Is it because there are no reproducible results? Is it because it, as a theory, cannot be disproven? Is it because it does not make testable predictions? Is it because of lack of peer reviewed literature? A combination of those, and more? Yes. As is, people love to extol the theory of evolution, but generally do a poor job explaining what *precisely* makes it a good theory. The best education is one that allows people to draw parallels to new concepts not learned; knowing evolution is a good theory does you nothing if you aren't able to make a similar critique of other theories.

2.) Second, knowledge of public discourse. Like it or not, it's a big issue in the public sphere. Exposing students to it in a controlled environment allows them to explore it, develop an understanding of the issue, and, as I mentioned above, discover what its severe flaws are. This also can serve to educate on how science must interface with the public. As scientists, we need to realize that, to best communicate with the public, we need to change from evidence based communication (assuming that all we have to do is present the facts and rely on others to arrive at the same conclusions) to story based communication. The debate over evolution is a perfect opportunity to explore how a message can become distorted from the scientific community to the public if not packaged correctly. 

tl;dr: Discussing creationism or ID alongside evolution, as long as the scientific merits (and lack thereof) of each theory or nontheory are clearly and unambiguously presented, offers an important foil for students to become better educated on what exactly a scientific theory is, as well as learning about the public debate in a controlled and unbiased environment.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26973314496.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>In many places teaching Evolution is controversial enough and you want to formally teach why Creationism is wrong or at least why many people think it is wrong?

Yes, I think It's a good idea for people to learn what makes a good scientific theory but religion is probably too hot a topic.

Also, the term "agnostic" is criticized by many. What most people mean is non-religious or agnostic atheist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973334033.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>It is a hot button topic, certainly, but that should be no reason to shy away from it.

Also, using Google's definition ("a person who believes that nothing is known or can be known of the existence or nature of God or of anything beyond material phenomena"), I'm definitely agnostic. Almost by definition God is beyond that which may be tested through material means; thus, it is impossible to know through empirical testing either way whether or not a God exists. Now, you can get into a debate on Revelation vs Empiricism vs Rationalism, but I feel that's beyond the scope of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973382006.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I did try writing a reply but the basic premise was always that it depends on the many interpretations of definitions of words.

If you would like to know what I was thinking then there is the criticism section on the Wikipedia page.

I probably should have kept to the topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973389670.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>And there's a high chance I've used it incorrectly according to some definitions. I realize the agnostic/atheist monikers have nuances to them, but I've stopped worrying about them; the basic point, that I have seen no proof for or against a divine, and don't believe such proof is possible, remains the same whatever it's called.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973397553.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I went looking for definitions and it turns out I'm like 10 different things if you take their definition literally. 

Your belief system is exactly what I believe. Language can be annoying sometimes. I really wish there was a word accepted by all for that without further implication. The trouble is, especially from where I'm from, people use the word Agnostic when they mean Undecided. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
