<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109219544.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t0yc8/i_believe_creationism_andor_intelligent_design/">
    <title>I believe creationism and/or Intelligent Design should be discussed alongside evolution in high school biology classes. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dyslexda</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a Microbiology graduate student; I also am agnostic. I do not believe creationism or Intelligent Design have any scientific validity. That being said...

I believe that, unlike most on Reddit, creationism and/or Intelligent Design *should* be discussed in conjugation with teachings on evolution. There are two benefits derived from this:

1.) First, creationism provides the perfect foil for discussing what actually constitutes a good scientific theory. The common (and accurate) criticism of creationism is that it has no scientific validity. I believe we should expose students to it to lead them through discovering precisely *why* it has no scientific validity. Is it because there are no reproducible results? Is it because it, as a theory, cannot be disproven? Is it because it does not make testable predictions? Is it because of lack of peer reviewed literature? A combination of those, and more? Yes. As is, people love to extol the theory of evolution, but generally do a poor job explaining what *precisely* makes it a good theory. The best education is one that allows people to draw parallels to new concepts not learned; knowing evolution is a good theory does you nothing if you aren't able to make a similar critique of other theories.

2.) Second, knowledge of public discourse. Like it or not, it's a big issue in the public sphere. Exposing students to it in a controlled environment allows them to explore it, develop an understanding of the issue, and, as I mentioned above, discover what its severe flaws are. This also can serve to educate on how science must interface with the public. As scientists, we need to realize that, to best communicate with the public, we need to change from evidence based communication (assuming that all we have to do is present the facts and rely on others to arrive at the same conclusions) to story based communication. The debate over evolution is a perfect opportunity to explore how a message can become distorted from the scientific community to the public if not packaged correctly. 

tl;dr: Discussing creationism or ID alongside evolution, as long as the scientific merits (and lack thereof) of each theory or nontheory are clearly and unambiguously presented, offers an important foil for students to become better educated on what exactly a scientific theory is, as well as learning about the public debate in a controlled and unbiased environment.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26973312615.0" user="rodion_kjd" delta="False">
    <text>I think creationism and/or intelligent design should be taught in school but not in science class.  The reason for this? They aren't science.

If you asked your children what they did in math that day and they said everyone finger painted or learned how to play tuba you'd be upset because, while those are perfectly legitimate things to learn, they aren't math.

Keep creationism and intelligent designed in philosophy or comparative religion classes where they belong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973318733.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think a more apt analogy would be studying math proofs that turned out to be based on flawed logic. What's wrong with using a bad proof as a demonstration of what a good one needs to do to be considered correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973348218.0" user="rodion_kjd" delta="False">
    <text>I think the answer is because a proof based on false logic still has its roots in reality.  Creationism and intelligent design are completely made up.  They have legitimacy as an idea and as a way to understand human thought and the human experience but not to understand the order and function of the universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973356233.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Are you allowing for a distinction between "well it says so in the bible" and attempts at scientific reasoning? For example, one line of reasoning commonly cited by creationists is the unexpected preservation of soft tissue in dinosaur fossils. This created an apparent paradox between the age of fossils and the existence of these tissues. It was recently found that iron incorporation *would* allow for preservation over millions of years. So, it was wrong to posit that the existence of soft tissue in fossils was evidence for a young earth, but I would still classify it as science, just not science that was done particularly well or without bias - two important lessons for students to learn. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973400166.0" user="rodion_kjd" delta="False">
    <text>What other bad/inaccurate science do they teach anything beyond lip service?  The Earth is the center of the galaxy?  Should biology teach about black bile?  The different humors that cause disease?  Should The Flat Earth Society have a chapter dedicated to them?

If your argument is that we should teach the pitfalls of logical fallacy and mistaken causality I think you're right; I just think there are better ways to address it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973404908.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That is principally my argument, but I would couple it with the argument to stay up to date. Creationism and climate change skepticism are two ideas that are fairly prevalent in modern society, whereas I wouldn't say the issues you listed are anymore. So I think that lends credence towards them being good examples as foils to good science. 

The best of both worlds is probably a "history of science" class (which is useful for a lot of other reasons as well). Since they're already cutting classes across the board, probably not feasible though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973407256.0" user="rodion_kjd" delta="False">
    <text>I like that idea a lot actually.  It could even a be a unit that lasts a week or two (if we're talking a high school level general science course) covering all the bad science and the evolution of scientific observation.  This would be a perfect time to introduce and hammer home just what a "theory" is as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973412355.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. And I think it's inherently helpful for kids to learn *how* scientists came up with the major theories, especially if it's something they might go into. Learning how to do design evolution experiments and think critically is arguably more important than learning a bunch of facts about it (of course you need both, but most students probably just get the latter). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
