<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109219544.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t0yc8/i_believe_creationism_andor_intelligent_design/">
    <title>I believe creationism and/or Intelligent Design should be discussed alongside evolution in high school biology classes. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dyslexda</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a Microbiology graduate student; I also am agnostic. I do not believe creationism or Intelligent Design have any scientific validity. That being said...

I believe that, unlike most on Reddit, creationism and/or Intelligent Design *should* be discussed in conjugation with teachings on evolution. There are two benefits derived from this:

1.) First, creationism provides the perfect foil for discussing what actually constitutes a good scientific theory. The common (and accurate) criticism of creationism is that it has no scientific validity. I believe we should expose students to it to lead them through discovering precisely *why* it has no scientific validity. Is it because there are no reproducible results? Is it because it, as a theory, cannot be disproven? Is it because it does not make testable predictions? Is it because of lack of peer reviewed literature? A combination of those, and more? Yes. As is, people love to extol the theory of evolution, but generally do a poor job explaining what *precisely* makes it a good theory. The best education is one that allows people to draw parallels to new concepts not learned; knowing evolution is a good theory does you nothing if you aren't able to make a similar critique of other theories.

2.) Second, knowledge of public discourse. Like it or not, it's a big issue in the public sphere. Exposing students to it in a controlled environment allows them to explore it, develop an understanding of the issue, and, as I mentioned above, discover what its severe flaws are. This also can serve to educate on how science must interface with the public. As scientists, we need to realize that, to best communicate with the public, we need to change from evidence based communication (assuming that all we have to do is present the facts and rely on others to arrive at the same conclusions) to story based communication. The debate over evolution is a perfect opportunity to explore how a message can become distorted from the scientific community to the public if not packaged correctly. 

tl;dr: Discussing creationism or ID alongside evolution, as long as the scientific merits (and lack thereof) of each theory or nontheory are clearly and unambiguously presented, offers an important foil for students to become better educated on what exactly a scientific theory is, as well as learning about the public debate in a controlled and unbiased environment.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26973315114.0" user="Arkesios" delta="False">
    <text>I think most reasonable opponents of Intelligent Design would agree with you. There is no harm in a teacher discussing and dissecting the topic. 

I'd say most opponents of ID want to keep it out of the classroom in the sense that they don't want states to pass legislation mandating that it be taught as scientific truth.

Some opponents might take an absolute approach for fear of allowing teachers too much latitude. The reasoning could be that if you let teachers discuss ID at all, that might lead to teachers' personal religious beliefs influencing the way they teach in the classroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973336518.0" user="dyslexda" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why there would have to be a curriculum developed for this. I don't have a background in education (aside from educators for parents), so I don't pretend to know how to develop the curriculum. However, that doesn't mean it's not a challenge to be overcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26973503886.0" user="Arkesios" delta="False">
    <text>Curriculum development is a resource intensive process. Should we be allocating our resources into developing a science course curriculum that explicitly dedicates (some might say wastes) time addressing non-scientific criticisms of established and accepted science?

After all, we don't do this in other areas of science, as far as I am aware. When students study astronomy, I don't think their instructors take out time to review the tenets of astrology and the signs of the zodiac.

That might be a silly example, but should Intelligent Design get special treatment just because its currently a hot topic in our cultural awareness? How loud do non-scientific dissenters have to be before they  get a special place in scientific instruction? 

Intelligent Design should certainly get special consideration in a different class, maybe social studies or something that's more explicitly a study of modern culture and society. But does it really have a place in a biology class? It depends on what you expect out of your science classes and how purely scientific you want said classes to be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
