<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26977069556.0" user="Omnipotence456" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that humans tend to care about each other is the whole reason anyone gives half a fuck about the important issues. We want to make the world a better place for everyone, or for our children, because we experience love and friendship. 

Additionally, there is a distinction between things that "feel good" and things that "give meaning to life." Things that "feel good" are just dopamine rushes. Doing those things does not change you much as a person, except maybe to further ingrain the habit of doing that particular thing. You don't learn anything from "feel-good" behaviors.

Behaviors that "give meaning to life," on the other hand, you do learn from. People learn a lot from friendships. Not only do they get better at social interaction, but they learn about themselves, since friends often discuss their emotions and experiences with each other. It turns out that saying things out loud often helps you work through them. Of course you could do the same with a psychologist, but they cost money, and friends are free. Other things that "give meaning to life" are producing art, consuming some forms of art (flash games and reality TV are technically art but I don't think most people get much out of them), travelling, reading books, exercising, hiking, camping, studying or learning to do pretty much anything, spending time alone thinking, and most other hobbies.

Edit: this is not at all an argument against doing "feel-good" things. Just that there should be a high ratio of things that "give meaning" to your live vs. "feel-good" things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977719103.0" user="singerinasmokyroom" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but the point is that "feel-good" things and "give meaning to life" things are, ultimately, both distractions. The energy spent on these things could be spent trying to solve real-world problems, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26978007014.0" user="Omnipotence456" delta="False">
    <text>No. If you aren't happy, you aren't motivated to do anything, you'll just sit around feeling sorry for yourself. (Similarly, if you aren't sad enough, you don't do anything about big problems because they don't bother you. This is a balance I often wonder about.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
