<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26976915500.0" user="UncleMeat" delta="False">
    <text>You don't get to take anything with you after you die. Sharing life and experiencing joy with the people you love is the **most** important thing you can do, in my opinion. Why spend time working on improving the world if nobody is having any fun living in it? 

Remember that there is waaaaay more to love and friendship than just sex and "having fun". I can rely on my friends and loved ones in a time of crisis and they can rely on me. They can share in the joy of my successes and I can share in the joy of theirs. This amplifies the best moments of your life and diminishes the terrible ones. Some people are fulfilled by work, but most people aren't. Most people get fulfillment, the stuff that really matters, from being with people that they love. These are friends, family, and romantic partners. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
