<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26977026725.0" user="Yxoque" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, love and friendship is in our genes. Not partaking in them will, for most people, result in severe distress over time. It's just the way our brains are wired. So my first point is: Humans are social animals. Deal with it.

Secondly, love and friendship are rather low-hanging fruit for becoming happy. And people being happy is one of the most important things in the world (And if it isn't, why are you trying to solve climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties?). 

Not only that, but happy people work harder (thus having more money) and are more willing to give to charities that impact the world.

You're also making a mistake that if people stopped having friendships and romantic relationships, they'd devoid that time to solving problems. Most humans don't even think about actually solving those problems, let alone doing it themselves. If you eliminate love and friendship, they'll just spend more time gaming or watching TV.

And finally: 

&amp;gt; Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Are you pretending love and friendship don't impact people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977712451.0" user="singerinasmokyroom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First of all, love and friendship is in our genes. Not partaking in them will, for most people, result in severe distress over time. It's just the way our brains are wired. So my first point is: Humans are social animals. Deal with it.  

Yes, you're right. But my point is that if you have a supportive and loving family, you really shouldn't need any more social interaction.  

&amp;gt; Are you pretending love and friendship don't impact people?  

No. I'm saying that they impact people the same way iPads, the Kardashians, and the PS4 do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977826009.0" user="Yxoque" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, you're right. But my point is that if you have a supportive and loving family, you really shouldn't need any more social interaction.

And many people don't have that. And a loving and supportive family does not automatically fulfill all your social needs. There are many things I can share with my friends/girlfriend that would be a lot more difficult to share with my family.

&amp;gt; No. I'm saying that they impact people the same way iPads, the Kardashians, and the PS4 do.

And at this point you're just ignoring how the world actually works. People's friends bring them happiness. Shared experiences change people's life. In ways much bigger than random pieces of technology do.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
