<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26977074780.0" user="therealswil" delta="False">
    <text>Why is climate change important? Why should people have rights? Why should there be economic equality?

To me, and I imagine plenty of others, the endgame of solving those is human happiness. Relationships, sex, and friendships are absolutely crucial to human health and happiness (if this isn't obvious enough to you, google a few studies). To sacrifice those for the other issues would be nonsensical and self-defeating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977704070.0" user="singerinasmokyroom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Relationships, sex, and friendships are absolutely crucial to human health and happiness (if this isn't obvious enough to you, google a few studies).  

I've always been quite skeptical of this. Yes, those things are nice, sure, but I feel that we, as a species (and definitely in the west) give a bit too much importance to those things. You don't see, for example, starving people in Africa dying of AIDS worrying about those things.  

Of course, sex is essential for the propagation and survival of the species, but aside from that, most of the time people do it for fun. And that, I'm arguing, is why it's no different than, say, watching Duck Dynasty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977836750.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You don't see, for example, starving people in Africa dying of AIDS worrying about those things.

I don't know all that much about starving people in Africa dying of AIDS, because I'm a middle class HIV negative westerner. But I find it hard to imagine that starving people dying of AIDS don't want sex, and don't worry about their relationships and friendships.

My relationships to other people are the most important thing in my life; I care about politics, world events, etc, *because they effect people and I care about people*.

I think the notion that poor, sick, people in third world countries don't care about relationships and friendships is so bizarre that it requires proof, rather than assertion.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977876119.0" user="therealswil" delta="False">
    <text>Your assertion that relationships, sex, and friendships can be abstracted to having the same effect as consumable goods is incorrect.

You have simplified down all kinds of relationships to merely adding 'fun'. That is not the case. Relationships of all kind are critical to our wholistic psychological wellbeing, which has a huge effect on our physical wellbeing.

Have a read of [this recent article](http://www.salon.com/2013/12/08/american_mens_hidden_crisis_they_need_more_friends/), and explore some of the links from the last section.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
