<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26976820444.0" user="charlesfkane" delta="False">
    <text>Human interactions are more than just stimulants like the ones you mentioned. For a good amount of people, sex is fun AND meaningful. Although I do agree with you that the culture glorifies romance but it's all hollywood and they do the same with violence, which is something we shouldn't trivialize at all. 


The academic world will host studies exploring romance and friendship because its fundamentally human interaction. How we interact and why we interact is related to science (ex: anthropology, psychology, neuroscience). Human behavior is a fascinating subject that helps us understand our brains as well as the brains and behaviors of other animals. 

I also think you are playing down relationships. Relationships don't hold value because they provide fun. They are a form of human interaction. Once again if you look at relationships at a scientific perspective, you will see that interaction is incredibly important for a society to survive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977729441.0" user="singerinasmokyroom" delta="False">
    <text>Are they really that fundamentally human? I think that we're often led to believe that because we're constantly *told* that they're so important. Like you said, I think Hollywood plays a role in this. Likewise, Hollywood constantly seems to tell us that the Kardashians and Miley Cyrus are important, which seems to lead to large chunks of the population actually believing that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977839823.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>In my life, I've experienced being a lone wolf, alone and friendless; I've also experienced being enmeshed in a social network with many connections, both deep and shallow, to many people.

I would prefer the latter *any day*; I think that's fundamental to my psyche. Not because Hollywood told me so, but because I've experienced both and recognized the change in the way I feel in both.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
