<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="109547212.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1t7z64/i_believe_that_romantic_love_and_friendship_are/">
    <title>I believe that romantic love and friendship are little more than distractions from important issues in the world. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>singerinasmokyroom</original_poster>
    <original_post>We often criticize people in our society for not caring enough about important issues that impact everyone (like climate change, economic inequality, social injustice, or erosion of rights and liberties) and for caring more about meaningless distractions (such as the Kardashians, the new iPad, the PS4, and twerking). But I have trouble seeing how friendships, romantic relationships, or sex are any less of a distraction. At the end of the day, they're all things that make us “feel good” and raise our endorphin level, yet those are the same reasons people enjoy watching reality TV, playing video games, or buying crap they don't need. They make them “feel good”. They're “fun”.

People pour so much energy, time, and money into these things, especially sex and romance, and our society is obsessed with them. Look at any newspaper or magazine and there will often be entire sections dedicated solely to sex and dating. Researchers at universities spend taxpayer money to study them. You can't watch a single TV show or movie without seeing a romantic subplot, and it seems like pretty much all of popular music is based on romance and sex. I often hear the refrain “man, if only people cared as much about things that really matter as they do about the latest Call of Duty game or how many points LeBron James scored”. But I think that people spend even more time energy and money on friendship, romance, and sex, and aside from some feel-good rationalizations about how those things “give meaning to life”, I fail to see how they're any less of a distraction. Think of the amount of time and energy people spend on making friends, hanging out with friends, dating, and trying to get laid. Now imagine if half of that time and energy were spent actually trying to do something to deal with real issues that actually impact people.

Of course, sex is required for the perpetuation of the species, so it is, at some level, necessary. But most people in our society obviously don't have sex for that reason. For most people, and most of the time, sex is something done for fun, and that's what makes it no different, in my eyes, than iPads and the Kardashians.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26976763619.0" user="Seifuu" delta="False">
    <text>It's what emotionally appeals to people. I'll tell you what, climate change, economic inequality, and social injustice hardly affect me. Having a girlfriend? That is like a day-to-day or even hour-to-hour benefit that regularly affects the way I live my life. Why should I care about other people's happiness more than my own? Heck, why should I care about other people's happiness at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977580899.0" user="singerinasmokyroom" delta="False">
    <text>With all due respect, that sounds a bit selfish. And things like climate change, inequality, and injustice may not affect you now, but there's a good chance they will in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26977649777.0" user="Seifuu" delta="False">
    <text>It's super selfish. I don't think there's a good chance those problems will affect me if 


A) I don't plan to have children and climate change doesn't have disastrous effects in my foreseeable lifespan (~50 years)


B) I am a part of the dominant ethnic group in my country and I have a padded resume and a cushy job.





You have to draw empathetic parallels to appeal to people like this. 


i.e. "Hasn't your father/boss ever stopped you from doing something you wanted to do? Imagine they did that all the time for everything you do. Imagine only being able to eat what they said you could or having to do miserable labor instead of something fun - that's what it's like to be a minority" 


Getting down to brass tacks, it's literally impossible to argue down to an objective point that someone "should" do anything from a non-self-interested point of view - mainly because it's impossible (afaik) to prove objective morality. You'll be hard-pressed to tell people what they should prioritize in their lives, because for [most people](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socialization) that's not really a choice. A more effective option (as demonstrated above) is to frame your appeal within their moral system.   


Be wary of people who don't act out of rational (conscious) self-interest such as trolls and teenage anarchists. These are people whose projection of personal experience onto an "objective" backdrop makes for a warped view of reality. In my experience, you have to create [some sort of](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teachable_moment) paradox in their world view to get them to change.


**In Review**

* There are people who are unaffected by overarching global/social problems (fortuitous birth circumstance)

* You want them working towards the common good anyway (they're probably rich)

* Everyone's in it for themselves (by definition, because our bodies are biofeedback machines)

* What people "want" is usually more a factor of their environment than a logically-sound opinion

* Some people are just know-it-alls who have to be coaxed or smashed out of their shells


So basically, arguing predictively (these issues will/could affect you) is typically shaky ground because the future is imprecise and our generation has access to tons of competing information. Arguing out of self-interest (a strong individual works to solve problems) is usually solid because that's self-fulfilled. I'm grossly oversimplifying things (people can have both [rational and irrational opinions](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_dissonance)), but the point of all this is that no desire is inherently better than another. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
