<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34899118296.0" user="Sparky_PoptheTrunk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition. This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.

I know this isn't the focus of your CMV, but i disagree with this.  The decision to cancel is because of liability, not to protect the Student athletes.  If athletes had played i'm sure covid may have spread among them, but without sports now covid will spread far worse among athletes.  They are going to hang out and party and no be occupied by their sport.  Playing sports is actually the best thing for the athletes, it just put all the liability on the schools and they didn't want that.

Most Athletic department and academic  arms of the school are kept separate outside of athletic fees charged outside of tuition and profit paid back to the academic side by Athletics.  Athletic revenue is actually pretty small compared to Tuition, room and board, dining, etc.  revenue.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
