<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34898833436.0" user="joshgilkerson" delta="False">
    <text>TLDR: Schools need revenue. Not having in person as an option reduces revenue, which may never be recovered. Athletes and leagues have power. Fixed costs don't go away.


I suspect the schools themselves would choose to hold the sporting events if given the choice. As established elsewhere, they are desperate for revenue and struggling for their existence. For the schools that make money on sports they certainly would want to play them. Even if they don't turn a "profit", it's not like all the expenses are going away. They still need to pay coaches, maintain facilities, etc. There are probably a good deal more schools that would be better off financially playing the games than not even if they don't turn a profit on the overall sports programs most years.

However, athletes and leagues have power. The athletes and the NCAA are probably the reason for cancelling the events, not the schools.

On the tuition side, the schools are just maximizing revenue. If a student wants to come on campus, they can. If they offer online, students that don't want on campus go there. Some students will chose to defer. If they did not offer in person classes, online and deferral students stay the same. If the ones that would have come on campus, some will attend online, but some will defer or even transfer or drop out. The deferrals are deferred revenue (not good for business), but the transfers and dropouts are revenue they will not recover.

All the while, salaried employees are often still drawing a salary, facilities need to be maintained, insurance must be paid, next year's class needs to be recruited, etc. The university can't just stop paying many of it's expenses of they intend to have in person classes next year or even the year after.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34900167895.0" user="-Spoobs-" delta="False">
    <text>I get the point you’re making about profits coming to the schools, but the athletes are not in favor of canceling programs, and the majority of B10 schools are (all besides Nebraska and Iowa).  I know  a guy who is playing football in B10 and he is definitely opposed to canceling his season.  Most of the athletes are willing to take risks because as young people who are also some of the most physically fit in society, the virus poses little threat, and as they live on campus, they won’t spread it to family.  Coaches also generally share the same viewpoint.

https://apple.news/ADdxRsyYxTki1coy1fxwTXg


Nick Saban On College Football: ‘Players Are A Lot Safer With Us Than They Are Running Around At Home’
 https://www.dailywire.com/news/nick-saban-on-college-football-players-are-a-lot-safer-with-us-than-they-are-running-around-at-home</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34900234636.0" user="joshgilkerson" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have deltas to give :(

Do you know if the schools in favor of cancelling are also cancelling in-person learning?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34900340692.0" user="-Spoobs-" delta="False">
    <text>Im not sure, I’ve mostly been concerned about being able to watch football this fall. Srry</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34901396639.0" user="ball_in_uh_cup" delta="False">
    <text>That's just such a poor attitude AND you're spreading misinformation while trying to pretend you aren't. I can't believe you wasted your life making a fake account to try and get people sick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902287277.0" user="-Spoobs-" delta="False">
    <text>No misinformation my guy.  According to the CDC, as of August 6th, people under 18 represent 76 out of the approximately 164,000 deaths nationally, or about 0.00046%, despite being 24% of the population in the most recent census.  Im not sure what part of this is trying to make people sick or why I would do that, but I play football, and literally all of my teammates are intensely motivated to have our season happen.  I also don’t get where I had a poor attitude, I just said I didn’t know about some schools reopening policies.  Finally, I’m disappointed that you would say I’m trying to make people sick just because we disagree. 

This chart shows deaths across age groups if you want to check for yourself.
[CDC COVID Deaths by age group US](https://data.cdc.gov/NCHS/Provisional-COVID-19-Deaths-Among-Ages-0-18-Years/nr4s-juj3)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903411202.0" user="ball_in_uh_cup" delta="False">
    <text>Your attitude is considered poor because it's extremely selfish. It's not because we disagree.

You are cherry-picking one fact that fits your narrative and trying to base your entire argument around it instead of looking holistically. You're ignoring that young people still get sick even if they all don't 100% die, and there's starting to be evidence of longterm health problems for that do survive, so even with a vaccine, this ain't going to end anytime soon. Plus, you can still transmit the disease to other people who could die, including your own family, friends, teammates, neighbors, etc. You wouldn't be trying to do it. It would just happen. You may get covid, tackle someone and spread the virus, then that person goes home and infects an older relative who may die. Would you feel like you should go to that funeral? 

By your logic, let's look into whether or not football should be banned everywhere due to the number of deaths. But wait, you say, there's more nuances to the situation than just deaths. There's a lot of people that aren't dying too. Well yeah. Exactly. Same with COVID. Both football and covid can leave you with long lasting medical complications. But with football, you choose to go on the field and hurt yourself. Fans don't get paralyzed with you if you're hit the wrong way. You get helmets and other preventative measures to help survive. With Covid, you don't get that choice and we don't have those preventative measures yet. Other people being irresponsible can majorly mess up your life or that of a loved one. Limiting social gatherings and wearing masks are the closest thing we have to pads and helmets for surviving covid. You could play football without these things and be fine, but likely not. And remember, that only hurts you. Right now, society is running around without great protective gear and you're trying to throw more players on the field. 

So yeah, trying to make everything back to normal is, in essence, advocating for people to get sick because it will happen even though that isn't your intent. I know you just want your season, but I think some people would rather keep their family alive and I'll always advocate for the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
