<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34899090662.0" user="ExtraSmooth" delta="False">
    <text>It's hard to really make any case about what a university "wants" or "cares about"; universities are made up of thousands of people, all with very different objectives and values. As others have pointed out, college sports, tuition, and room and board are all important revenue streams. The university has to maintain its buildings, even if nobody uses them, and it has to pay its professors, administrators, and staff even if they are teaching online classes. We could argue that universities shouldn't use college sports to pay for these things, but this is the situation as it stands. For better or worse, all those revenue streams (including a university's endowment) are necessary to keep the university running at a certain capacity. If businesses and ventures are boats, universities are like cruise liners--they can't turn on a dime. Even relatively minor decisions like adding a course or changing a degree requirement can take years of meetings, negotiations and paperwork; a fundamental decision like shifting the medium by which classes are taught would normally take decades. So the rapid and extreme measures taken by universities in this scenario are rather unprecedented, and there is significant pressure beyond financial (i.e. bureaucratic) for universities to maintain the status quo in the face of uncertainty. 
  
Those points aside, I find it very unlikely to think that universities are *only* interested in profit (or, more properly, revenue). Universities are really bad at generating revenue; state universities lean heavily on state governments for funding, and private liberal arts colleges all over the country are hemorrhaging cash and going under left and right. There are some exceptions: Purdue has garnered attention by refocusing itself as an efficient, job-focused university that turns out high-earning graduates and maintains a balanced budget. Other universities may be following suit. But even still, the primary interest of universities is promoting education and research. Many secondary interests, such athletics and social groups like fraternities, have tethered themselves to universities as a source of funding and stability. But if you want to actually turn a profit, working for a university is a really poor way of doing it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
