<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34900115293.0" user="HardstyleJaw5" delta="False">
    <text>I think the biggest flaw not being acknowledged is the safety measures being taken at many schools. I'm in grad school right now so I can't speak to student housing but I do know that: building access has been revoked to undergrads except those necessary (classes), the library has switched to fully online, there is mandatory contact tracing in the event of a positive case, mandatory 2x/week testing and masks and social distancing must be observed at all times on campus. Not to mention all the 50+ seat classes are fully online to allow larger halls to be used for smaller classes. I am TAing this semester and my class is completely online including office hours. 

Will some students defer? Sure. But even if they all came back there is a lot in place to try and be proactive about everything. We've already seen several small outbreaks in a few research groups over the summer and each was caught and contained very quickly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34901865838.0" user="landodk" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention a high level of testing in a self contained area. a large group can get together safely IF all of them are negative. I don't know about large schools, but a small school with almost all on campus housing could be safer than the general community (but always at a high risk for rapid spread)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
