<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34898886617.0" user="one_mind" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect that sports present a larger risk of spreading the virus than normal class activities. So stopping sports but continuing classes is a path that removes the higher risk activity. I would argue that sports creates a higher risk because:

* Athletes are are in close contact, breathing heavy, likely can't wear masks and play.
* Athletes are in rotational contact with other athletes compounding the virus spread if there is exposure.
* Public attendance, if allowed, would be a very high risk for spreading the virus. Attending sports fans are more likely to become less vigilant about masks and social distancing in the excitement.

I would argue that normal class activities presents a significantly lower risk because:

* The structured environment allows a high degree of control over the use of masks and social distancing.
* The same group is attending every time, so contact tracing is more feasible, and distribution outside the group is not multiplied (like it would be with sports team rotations).

A second argument I would make for continuing classes is simply that the students want to attend. This is a freedom of choice argument. School programs are setup so that if you sit out a semester or two, you can snap right back into your program when you return. Let the students who want to take the risk and attend do so. Let the students who don't want to take the risk sit out. Let people decide their own risk tolerance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34900325362.0" user="-Spoobs-" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with the idea of canceling sports and believe that things like college football should happen.  First of all, college athletes are, with certainty, the least vulnerable to coronavirus in our society, as they are all young and extremely physically fit, meaning that they are at virtually no real risk individually.  Secondly, public attendance would definitely not open.  The MLB isn’t doing it now, and neither will any other organization this year.  In respect to football (which is really all anyone cares about) all activities without masks are conducted outside, where transmission is considerably less likely, and extensive sanitary measures are taken.  In respect to your argument that contact tracing is unfeasible in athletics because of “sports team rotations” and “rotational contact” (?) the same group of people always goes to practices, so I’m not sure what that means or why tracing would be any harder.  In the same argument, athletic envious are far more structured and controlled than any other in a school.  Along with this, your second argument that continuing classes is a matter of one’s freedom of choice to accept risk if they want to attend is equally if not more valid in respect to athletics.  As someone who plays football, I can tell you that literally every one of my teammates wants to continue their season in full.  Any athlete who does not wish to do so does not have to participate.  Im sure you don’t believe me about the risk levels to students, so I’ll provide statistics.  According to the CDC, as of September 6th, 76 people between 0 and 18 died of COVID-19 in the US.  That is proportionate to 164,000 total, meaning that people 0-18 represent less than 0.00046% of deaths, despite representing 24% of the population in the 2010 census.  I know you might not believe me because you may have been misinformed as to the reality of the disease so here is the CDC chart

[CDC Covid deaths by age](https://data.cdc.gov/NCHS/Provisional-COVID-19-Deaths-Among-Ages-0-18-Years/nr4s-juj3)

I hope you can take these points to make a more concise argument in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902234311.0" user="todpolitik" delta="False">
    <text>Covid does more than just kill.

Athletes are the most physically fit. That means that after ravaging their bodies, the athletes still have a good chance at survival.

But it will permanently wreck their bodies, and their hopes of ever being athletes again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902359248.0" user="-Spoobs-" delta="False">
    <text>You’re incorrect as to the severity of illness for young people, especially young athletes.  I know several people on my high school football team that had COVID and are now operating at full physical capacity, and never suffered from covid doing anything as drastic as “ravaging their bodies” or “permanent” damage.  I would say many of us have already had it and didn’t know because we were asymptomatic.  The fact is that young people are at a very mitigated risk compared to anyone else.  My best friend tested positive along with his sister, but never even suffered any symptoms.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
