<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34899241689.0" user="Grenzer17" delta="False">
    <text>Other people have already addressed hows and whys of the financial aspect, so I'm going to address another aspect of this sitution that you didn't mention. 



While schools do host athletic events and [obviously] teach students, college campuses are also a place people live. I really can't overstate that particular point. There was an NPR article from the beginning of the pandemic that mentioned how many LGBT college students found themselves returning to unwelcoming homes when they were forced off of college campuses (a situation I also unfortunately experienced). However, that said, I was pretty lucky I got somewhere to stay at all. Many people were forced back into living situations far worse than mine, and really had no place to go. This only became more true when the economy tanked and jobs became less available. 



I know friends from campus who have been bouncing from place to place, living with extended family, etc. Many couldn't find work in short term positions and have been doing anything they can to find places to stay until we can go back on campus. One of my friends has literally been homeless for the past 6 months or so and just camped around a state forest near our college. 



Colleges reopening isn't just about returning to classes, it is about reopening a MASSIVE amount of living spaces that would otherwise have remained closed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
