<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1102614149.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i8guit/cmv_i_dont_think_ted_cruz_is_eligible_to_be/">
    <title>CMV: I dont think Ted Cruz is eligible to be president of the United State</title>
    <original_poster>PuckSR</original_poster>
    <original_post>Kamala Harris was recently selected as Biden's running mate, and it re-sparked a common misunderstanding of the Constitution. The definition of "natural born citizen". Clearly, Kamala Harris is eligible.

John McCain, however, was not so clearly a "natural born citizen" as he had been born in the Panama Canal Zone to two US citizens. It was contentious enough of an issue that the Senate passed a resolution saying he was eligible. Specifically, McCain was born to two US citizens who were overseas at the direct orders of the US govt. If McCain was ineligible then every child born to US servicemembers overseas would be ineligible and most people agreed that this was not the founders intent.

However, Rafael "Ted" Cruz was born to an American and a Cuban while they worked in Canada for a private company. If Ted Cruz is eligible to be a US president, then basically anyone who has a claim to citizenship is eligible, even if they have never lived in the United States.

*Example: A young woman is born in China. Her mother is American, her father is Chinese. She lives her entire life in China, but claims dual citizenship for legal purposes. At the age of 42, she decides to move to the United States. She becomes a popular politician and runs for President, only 14 years after being elected to the US House of Representatives.*

Would she be eligible? This seems like the exact scenario the founders were trying to prevent. Someone with loyalties to another country taking the reins of power of the USA.If Ted Cruz is eligible, then this woman would be eligible. At that point, why wouldn't we extend the presidency to citizens like Arnold Schwarzenegger?

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause)

Edit: adjusted for the residency requirement

**For all mentions of the Nationality Act of 1790.**The law, as written in 1790 said the following:

* Only free white males could become citizens
* Provided, that the right of [citizenship](https://immigrationhistory.org/item/1790-nationality-act/#) shall not descend to persons whose fathers have never been resident in the United States

First, we obviously don't still have this law on the books. It was fully and totally cancelled and the phrase about "natural born citizen" was removed. You can't point to a law that is not currently applicable as your definition. They clearly felt the need to define the term, and they later rescinded that definition

Further, I think you could make a strong argument that it only applied to children of the father with that definition. This fits with what I have read of citizenship laws in Europe, which stated that citizenship status descended from the paternal line. (I know this because it was a big controversy when people started raping slaves, as it would make the children citizens and free. Most countries made a law explicitly exempting this rule in the case of slave-master relationships)

**Naturalized vs natural born**

The term naturalized wasn't created until the 1940s, when international travel became much more common. The term presently means "conferred after birth", but that term was not used during prior to that period. In fact, "natural born" was used in the US and the UK to imply a citizen granted citizenship by their birth in the USA.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34904122477.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>There is nothing completely definite in the realm of who constitutes a "natural-born citizen" as it has not been squarely addressed in any Supreme Court decisions and, as you have already been over with several commenters in this thread, is not absolutely clearly addressed in statute either, although in both cases to the extent it has been addressed in either, it has not been resolved in favor of your view.

But most legal scholars and commentators believe that "natural-born" means that someone was a citizen at birth. This is in accord with the term's usage in British law prior to the adoption of the Constitution and it has also consistently been interpreted that way whenever the question arises. It's actually hard to really contemplate what the alternative view would be. Is it your contention that only people physically born in the US are eligible? Then why doesn't the constitution say that and why have many people not in that category run campaigns without being disqualified?

I think you are getting too hung up on your Chinese thought experiment. Let's say both parents are Chinese but the child is born in the US on a vacation one day before the family returns to China. That's probably even more problematic from the perspective of avoiding foreign loyalties, but it is clearly allowed by the Constitution. In a more abstract sense, just because someone wrote Rule A to try to reduce Problem X, it does not follow that Rule A actually prohibits every instance of Problem X. You have to look at the text of Rule A and see what it actually does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904190654.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then why doesn't the constitution say that and why have many people not in that category run campaigns without being disqualified?

From my understanding, we aren't even sure who would disqualify a candidate.  
We have elected a few people to federal office who were NOT qualified, but they were elected.

[https://www.cop.senate.gov/artandhistory/history/minute/Youngest\_Senator.htm](https://www.cop.senate.gov/artandhistory/history/minute/Youngest_Senator.htm)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904223579.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>That just shows that enforcement hasn't been perfect, but it appears in those cases that the age of the candidates wasn't even clear at the time, which is not analogous to the birth situation.

Looking at some of your other responses, we may be stuck in an unresolvable loop. Maybe no one has standing to challenge eligibility in court but all challenges in the only available venue (ballot access) fall in favor of people in this category being natural born citizens. However, you don't accept these as they are not court decisions.

Thus the world operates as if your definition is wrong, but you aren't willing to change your definition without a court ruling which can never happen. So what could change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904250804.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but it appears in those cases that the age of the candidates wasn't even  clear at the time, which is not analogous to the birth situation. 

In at least one case it was clear but ignored.  
In another case, they explicitly said that they wouldn't invalidate a candidate in the election.

&amp;gt; Thus the world operates as if your definition is wrong, but you aren't  willing to change your definition without a court ruling which can never  happen. So what could change your view?   


No, you are confusing the concept of "elected" with "eligibile"  
I fully agree that some people think Ted Cruz is electable. That doesn't mean he is actually eligible for the position even if he does get elected and hold the position

&amp;gt;So what could change your view? 

A document pointing out that "natural born citizen" is interpreted differently than I see it. No one has produced any such document.

The closest is a state department policy I found.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904276660.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A document pointing out that "natural born citizen" is interpreted differently than I see it. No one has produced any such document.

They literally produced a law written by the same people who wrote the Constitution that said exactly that, but you decided that it wasn't enough. There's nothing better than that out there so I guess you can continue believing whatever you want, as long as you realize there is absolutely no connection between what you believe and the way the world operates in this instance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904315837.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>The only law that had that phrase was revoked by the same people 5 years later when it was superceded by a new law, which oddly removed that term.

So, you want me to believe that they all agreed with that interpretation. Passed a law defining that interpretation and then passed a new law to revoke it.  
  
So. your argument is that Congress can define it, they did define it, then they removed that definition. So we should definitely still use it?  
  
You know, Congress also said that only white people could be citizens. Does that mean Obama wasn't a "natural born citizen" because he wasn't white?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904454238.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>I started this off by acknowledging that it has not been completely squarely addressed by a court decision or by a statute. And yes, the Naturalization Act of 1790 is no longer in effect. My contention is not that this law is still currently effective. The point is that if you are analyzing what a term in a document means then the same term in other related documents written by the same people is relevant evidence. 

If you want something written by the same people who wrote the Constitution that says someone born abroad can be a natural born citizen, you have it ([Naturalization Act of 1790](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naturalization_Act_of_1790)). If you want a recent resolution of the US Senate that states someone born abroad can be a natural born citizen, you have it ([S. Res. 511](https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/110/sres511/text)). There's not much else of consequence out there, since there are no court cases, and due to standing, there may never be. No candidate in this bucket has been disqualified to run, but sure, we can split that hair and say that running, being elected, and serving can still happen if you are ineligible. So I guess we are just at an impasse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904482773.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, let me explain what I want.  
I would change my view if someone produced a document which was NOT a rescinded US law, but a letter which explained the view of the framers of the US constitution

I would also change my view if someone produced a law that explicitly defined "natural born citizen" and was still in effect

  
**Problem with the 1790 law**

The 1790 Act is a law. It was meant to define things. The fact that several founders agreed to that definition in the law does not mean that they assumed that this was a well-understood term.   
The term "executive power" is not defined, but most of the framers seem to have thought that it was an obvious term and they needed no laws to clarify

So, even if a few of them agreed to that definition, I see this as evidence that they did not automatically assume it meant "all people born to a US citizen parent". The fact that they removed that term later tells me that they still wanted to clarify the term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904560079.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>There is not any letter from the framers detailing what they meant by "natural born citizen." And, since 1795, naturalization and citizenship statutes don't use that term either. So all I can tell you is the definition of who gets citizenship at birth under current statutes. And I can tell you (and it even seems you may agree) that these people are in practice highly likely to be able to run and, if elected, serve as president. 

But that is all that's out there. This is not a question of someone just not presenting this to you. What you are asking for does not exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904566297.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Ok  
So you are saying you can't change my view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904592483.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>If the documents you described above are your requirements for changing your view, then unless someone discovers a hidden compartment in John Jay's antique desk containing some heretofore unknown pontification on this particular aspect of the Constitution, your view is not changeable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904621867.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Not to be disagreeable, but I always find the argument you are making to be silly.

Changing views/beliefs is not a voluntary action.   
I cannot fathom all of the possible arguments, evidence, etc that  could exist or that would change my view.  

A view/belief isn't a scientific theory. A person with a valid scientific theory must imagine a way to invalidate their theory. A person with a view does not and in fact many views/beliefs are impossible to conclusively invalidate. 

If that 1790 naturalization law was all it took to change my view, then I wouldn't have posted here. I would have just read about it on wikipedia and had my view changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904854781.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't make an argument so much as just point to the requirements you gave. But your point that there could be other things out there that you don't necessarily know about that could change your view is well taken.

So with that in mind, can you help me understand your view? You can poke holes in arguments for other definitions of natural born citizen all day, but which ones support your view? From your OP all I can discern is that you think the founders were looking to avoid foreign influence and that reading "natural born citizen" your way does that, but in my first comment you completely ignored the part that was focused on that motivation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906158654.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I remember prior to the 2008 election that the view was pretty widely held that "natural born" meant that the candidate must be born in the USA  
  
This is why there was controversy around Romney.  
This is why they tried to say Obama was born in Kenya</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906382348.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I remember prior to the 2008 election that the view was pretty widely held that "natural born" meant that the candidate must be born in the USA

Being a citizen from birth who was born outside the US, although without political aspirations, I have been casually interested in this question for decades and I must say that my recollection does not match yours. It's been debated and not entirely clear for a long time, but the weight of opinion has generally been on the citizenship at birth = natural born citizen angle.

&amp;gt;This is why there was controversy around Romney.

There's at least some level of controversy and commentary every time this question arises because, as we've agreed, the question is not entirely settled. However, I'd say that the fact that there has never been any decision at any level that a person is ineligible on these grounds, and there have been several decisions at several levels (U.S. Senate, State officials in charge of ballots) that they are not ineligible on these grounds, your side of the argument has less support than the other.

&amp;gt;This is why they tried to say Obama was born in Kenya

If Obama were born in Kenya he would not have been a natural born citizen. The citizenship statute in effect at the time would not have conferred citizenship on him at birth as his mother did not meet the applicable residency requirement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906394046.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>What residency requirement for his mom?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906447339.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>If Obama was not born in the US (which, to be clear, he was) then he would not have been a US citizen at birth. [It's actually pretty complicated and there are various requirements that the parent needs to meet before their child is a citizen at birth.](https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/travel-legal-considerations/us-citizenship/Acquisition-US-Citizenship-Child-Born-Abroad.html)

Specifically, the pertinent part provides:

&amp;gt;For birth between December 24, 1952 and November 13, 1986, the U.S. citizen parent must have been physically present in the United States or one of its outlying possessions for 10 years prior to the person’s birth, at least five of which were after the age of 14 for the person to acquire U.S. citizenship at birth. The U.S. citizen parent must be the genetic or the gestational parent and the legal parent of the child under local law at the time and place of the child’s birth to transmit U.S. citizenship.

Since Obama's mother was 18 at the time she gave birth to him, she would not have met the residency requirement that she be physically present in the US for five years after the age of 14. So if Obama was born outside the US he would not have been a US citizen at birth.

I should note that the above analysis pertains to the statutes as they were in effect at the time of the controversy. The immigration statutes have subsequently been amended to read differently and different rules now apply to people born outside the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34908693839.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>So, all children of US citizens are obviously "natural born citizens", but under current US law they might not even be legal US citizens?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34909125255.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure where you got that impression. People who were citizens at birth are natural born citizens. That group does not include everyone with a citizen parent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34910225100.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>so, do we have any evidence that Ted Cruz had a right to be a citizen at birth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34910892347.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>From what I can tell, this question rests on exactly the same provision I quoted above since Cruz was born to married parents in 1970, one of whom was a citizen and one of whom was an alien. I'm not an expert on his family history but from some articles I've read, his mother was born in the US in 1934 and moved to Canada in 1967. So she would have met the residency requirement at the time of his birth, having lived in the US for about 33 years, approximately 19 of which were after the age of 14. 

Thus he was a citizen at the time of his birth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34910905773.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>well, I think we are going to have to agree to disagree about Ted Cruz.I don't believe that the term "natural born" citizen was well-defined and I interpreted it to mean a citizen born in the USA.

I believe there was an attempt by congress to change that definition, but cancelled that definition and never touched it again.  

  I find that a lot of the US constitution was based on UK law. The 2nd amendment, for example, was borrowed directly from it

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause#Antecedents\_in\_Britain](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#Antecedents_in_Britain)

And the antecedents in Britain justify my position</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34911035112.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>Have you read those? The British antecedents are almost entirely on the side against your position. There's a bit of quibbling about being "deemed" a natural born citizen vs. being one, which I don't think really means anything in the end. If you are deemed, for all intents and purposes, to be a natural born citizen then it follows that you are a natural born citizen for the purposes of presidential eligibility, even if you can still claim there's some other sense if which you aren't a natural born citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34911044357.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text> 

Jurist [William Blackstone](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Blackstone) wrote in 1765 that "Natural-born subjects are such as are born within the dominions of the crown of England".[\[15\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-McManamon-16)[\[20\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-Bill-21)  Blackstone added that offspring who are not inhabitants may also be natural born subjects:[\[20\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-Bill-21)[\[21\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-22) 

&amp;gt;But by several more modern statutes  ... all children, born out of the king's ligeance, whose fathers were  natural-born subjects, are now natural-born subjects themselves, to all  intents and purposes, without any exception; unless their said fathers  were attainted, or banished beyond sea, for high treason; or were then  in the service of a prince at enmity with Great Britain.

In 1775, however, Blackstone reversed his opinion and explained that  the children "are now deemed to be natural-born subjects" rather than  "are now natural-born subjects."[\[22\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-23)  Similarly, [Francis Plowden](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Francis_Plowden_(barrister))  initially explained that an early English statute made foreign-born  children of English parents "in fact and law . . . true native subjects"  and that the eighteenth-century British statutes made persons  natural-born subjects by statute law just as others were natural-born  subjects by the common law.[\[23\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-24)   However, after further consideration he also reversed his opinion and  concluded in 1785 that the statutes did not make the children natural  born subjects—rather, there remained a "relict of alienage in them."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34911519033.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's exactly what I'm referring to. The quibbling about being "deemed." And I've just dived deep into Francis Plowden and I must say that Wikipedia has really missed the ball on this one. First, this entire work is on the question of whether a child born abroad of a father *who has been convicted of treason* is a "natural born subject." And Plowden appears to be arguing that the child is! The particular section quoted is when he is addressing potential counterpoints and he is discussing the reasoning of a case that initially appears to contradict him. The "relict of alienage" line is essentially a dig at people who disagree. He says:

&amp;gt;The next judicial determination upon the point of Alienage, which I can find, is the case of LESLY and LESLY, which came before the House of Lords in five different shapes. The point there determined was, that the immediate grandson of a British subject born abroad, was not a natural born subject of this realm by virtue of the 7th of Queen ANNE. This case does not apply to the immediate subject of our present consideration, which is the case of the child of an attainted father born abroad; but establishes the grounds, upon which the 13th of his present Majesty, which I have noticed in the Investigation, was passed. Upon reflecting on the reasoning, which induced me to think, that the son of an Englishman born abroad is not a natural born subject himself to all intents and purposes, if his child born abroad is not as inheritable to him, as he was to his father; I must profess my opinion to be most conclusively determined. I know some members of the Legislature, and many worthy loyal subjects of this kingdom, who were born abroad; but there must exist a strange relict of alienage in them, if, their wives having equal license with others to quit the kingdom, and they themselves perhaps attending the business of the Nation in Parliament, at the time their children may be born abroad, they are to be deemed aliens as the Law now is. **It is the grossest repugnancy, to pretend to establish any such difference between two persons, the one born in England, the other of English parents in a foreign country.**

He's essentially saying, "this can't be the case because then a bunch of your children wouldn't be natural born subjects."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34911609542.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I read it as "this is the case, but I think it is bad"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34912063225.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>As I mentioned, this is about the children of fathers convicted of treason. In context, this entire work is how it would be unjust to take rights away from children due to the crimes of their fathers. If children of normal parents born abroad were not natural born subjects, then there would be no reason for this entire work to exist.

But I want to thank you for taking me down this rabbit hole. After reading tons of this and the relevant portions of Blackstone, a few things are pretty clear to me:

1. This was actually a much more important question to the British than to us, because it appears the entire question of whether you could inherit your parents' property and titles could turn on it. This was important to a large group of their aristoracy.
1. At least in the 1600s and 1700s, gradually (ambassadors, then merchants, then everyone) the general answer became that if your parents were in good standing nothing prevented you from being a "real" Englishman and inheriting land and titles and serving in Parliament just because you were born abroad. If you think about it, this makes sense as they were starting to travel more and more and do business in other places more often. It would be really inconvenient for them if happening to be in France managing business affairs meant that your entire line of succession could be messed up.
1. The discourse around this, including articles from respected scholars, betrays an amazing ability to misjudge or mischaracterize the source material. 

I've gained a much deeper appreciation for the history here and I want to leave you with a few words from the work of Francis Plowden we were discussing:

&amp;gt;The mind of man is naturally open to prejudice: for every one is readier to decide, than to examine; and it rarely happens, that the feelings of individuals do not direct their judgments. Thus prejudices often generated in pasion, are handed down to the latest posterity; and no tradition is so blindly received, as that, which is founded on prejudice. When a person has thus received a prejudice, his reasoning is usually directed at strengthening and justifying, rather than investigating the grounds of his belief.

I encourage you to also read the relevant source material and investigate, rather than strengthen or justify.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34916247708.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I will read it when I get a chance.

But would you agree with the general statement: There is more question about a person born on foreign soil being "natural born citizen" than a person being born to alien parents on US soil?  
In other words, the debate over Kamala Harris's eligibility is on much shakier ground than Ted Cruz's eligibility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34917825075.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, under current US law I would say it is very clear that anyone born in the US is a natural born citizen, while I agreed at the outset that it is not entirely clear in the case of a child born abroad. But I didn't understand your CMV as being a direct comparison of the two and I would not have really tried to change your mind on that point. I'm just trying to convince you that it is more likely than not that Cruz is eligible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34917888043.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn't my view. It was just a statement I made.  
After such a lengthy discussion I wanted to make sure we could agree on something</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
