<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986641173.0" user="maxpenny42" delta="False">
    <text>So it is common where you're from for society and family to put down women, demand they stay home, limit their access to school and work. It is common to treat them as less than and put chains around their lives holding them back and consistently calling them inferior. And you are surprised to find that most women you know aren't excelling or are dependent? That's all they know! Don't cripple a man's leg and then challenge him to a race. 

Here in the states we've done the opposite for a while. We stopped putting women down and started encouraging them. We didn't switch to put down men but we didn't overemphasize man power the way girl power was. Now women dominate in college and university. Obviously things aren't perfect and women still have disadvantages and men still advantages but 100 years ago women had almost no access to higher ed and now they dominate it. I'd say we are a product of our environment and regardless of what potential we may have based on biology, it is what we are allowed to do with it an what we choose to do with it that makes up our worth. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987679605.0" user="HumorMe11" delta="False">
    <text>You should elaborate on "dominate in college and university". I am sure your version differs from many. Some statistics show there are more women in college/university, but that does not really mean they're dominating. They're still a heavy minority in engineering, mathematics, and the sciences. My opinion is that by dominating, you're a apart of one of these (but not limited to) challenging, and progressive fields. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987800302.0" user="maxpenny42" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. While there has been a lot of talk about how useless degrees can be and how they can still wind up with a job at Starbucks the truth is that people with *any* degree are still more likely to make more money and be more successful than those without. You don't need a stem degree to accomplish this and frankly I'm tired of the elite at attitude that stem degrees are somehow better than or more important than other ones. Yes stem is a reasonably guaranteed healthy income and is almost certainly a challenging field.  But other degrees are far more valuable and some are far more challenging. It just depends really. Even the same degree can vary in effectiveness and worth based on school or other experience an individual has. 

So I don't question your statement that women don't dominate stem. I just think it is bullshit to ignore a stunning majority of college students are female because a couple fields are still male dominated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26988039657.0" user="HumorMe11" delta="False">
    <text>Valid points. If we are looking more directly at the gender differences and observing that women are getting more degrees in general than men, I can agree with you. That's only why I asked that we have the meaning of "dominating" in this context elaborated on. 

And while I respect your opinion, I still think STEM degrees are somehow superior to other degrees, but for unique reasons. Not because they might be more challenging or more profitable. I do not value a person on their income or their ability to learn. Instead, I think their superior purely based on the utility of the degree and how it serves human society at this point in time. There are too many flooded degree fields, and too many students getting a degree to merely have one and doing little with it. Note that this opinion is gender unbiased. There are many fields which I can consider more of a hobby than a career that are being flooded. Journalism, arts, english, psychology, IT. There are exceptions in these fields for people of exceptional ability, skill, or experiences, but there's little to no need pursuing this. Anyone can make a blog and be a hobby journalist or writer. 

There are even significant numbers of non-STEM degrees that are in demand and more useful, career-wise. I won't value a person based on a career field or monetary income. I value more on their work ethic and lack of self-serving behavior. With that said, there is an obvious differential between the type of person who would pursue a career in a STEM field and otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
