<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986769963.0" user="LegendaryOdin" delta="False">
    <text>The thing here is that gender is largely defined from an anthropological standpoint and can be excessively fluid as to how it is perceived. The varying cultures across the world all have ineffable and a plethora or ways to perceive either gender, each of them different from the other in some way. Some cultures would have you believe there is one weaker than the other, others would empower one above the other; the point is, reality and culture are largely perception based. 

I will state now that I am a woman. I live in America. I work a full time job earning a fairly nice living because I know the workings of computers and machines better than my coworkers. I help support my elderly father and younger sister, as he is on a pension and she is too young to work. I've also recently graduated with three degrees from community college and plan on eventually moving up to a Masters. All of this, I have done on my own, with no financial support or backing. Despite it all, my father believes he is still the more capable person despite being limited not only financially, but physically due to some old injuries. He will believe until he dies that he is better at computers than I am. This, I believe, is because of the society that conditioned him. 

My father was raised in the classic South; good "ole" boys, women in the kitchen or raising kids, etc. His perception is still what he was conditioned with and without ever wanting to change it or believing he may be incorrect, he will refuse to believe otherwise. 

Long story short, you are a product of your society as is any other human being. If society deems a gender is unfit, I would suspect people of that gender may very well begin to believe it. I am of the belief that every person is simply human and gender is much too fluid for me to make any sort of judgments on, so I observe each person as I meet them and make my own decisions based on what I see. Could I be wrong? Perhaps. But I think that any *human* is capable of being something immensely spectacular, despite society, despite gender, despite anything that we might think could hinder them. I do not feel weak; I've worked in a warehouse moving heavy boxes along with men twice my age. I know what I'm capable of, female or not. 

I doubt that will change your view. We all start out unsure of who or what we are and we look to society to give us some idea as to where we are meant to start or who we might one day become. Rarely does it give us anything positive to work with. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
