<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986495748.0" user="BlackHumor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. 

Wait, so, doesn't this mean your view has already been changed? If you already know you're wrong (or at least, that there's no reason to believe you're right), then what view do you want us to change?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986497669.0" user="Lanayru" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to try to explain it with a rather uncommon example that has to do with social phobia. 

A social phobic often, if not always, realizes that their fears are irrational and most of the time implausible, yet they can't stop thinking about them and letting them take control of their behavior (social withdrawal). 

In my case I do realize that these sexist ideas are immature and unfounded, but I can't deter from thinking about them and fully believing them and letting them drive my behavior towards women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986500743.0" user="TsukiBear" delta="False">
    <text>How, exactly, do you expect anyone to change a view using logic and reason when you *already* know it's totally irrational to begin with?  

All we can do is show how you're logically wrong, we can't make you a better person, and we can't change the culture your countrymen have shoved down your throat already.  

What you're asking is neither possible nor reasonable.  Although good for you for taking what are obviously your first steps in reversing the brainwashing.  Have patience and keep at it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986504916.0" user="Lanayru" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All we can do is show how you're logically wrong

That's actually the main reason behind this submission, because I doubt that simply stating "You're wrong" has ever been successful in changing someone's view. Of course I'd like to see /how/ my ideas are wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986507196.0" user="TsukiBear" delta="False">
    <text>There seems to be some miscommunication here.  I was under the impression that when someone says their views make them "feel really immature,...aren't objectively true...and are the product of generalization and blunt sexism," they kind of already know their views are wrong for the reasons that you just conveniently provided.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986512244.0" user="Lanayru" delta="False">
    <text>I must've not explained myself properly, I apologize. Please look at IntroTheWest's post, they've explained my situation much better than I did in a wall of text.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986506439.0" user="IntoTheWest" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. I think OP "knows" his views are wrong from a societal perspective, but keeps coming back to them because to him, they logically make sense.

He might feel that there is a way to logically prove him wrong, but he just doesn't know it. Until we disprove it, he can only rely on the best logic he has, which is one that has kept him is this loop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986510957.0" user="Lanayru" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, this is exactly it! Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986514751.0" user="BlackHumor" delta="False">
    <text>In that case:

[Across a wide variety of measurements, women score extremely near equal to men](http://www.careerpioneernetwork.org/wwwroot/userfiles/files/the_gender_similarities_hypothesis.pdf). This is true whether or not there's a "right answer" for the measurement (e.g. it's true on measures of ability and it's also true on measures of personality.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986533210.0" user="IntoTheWest" delta="False">
    <text>Of course!

Also, if this thread doesn't change your mind about women (and it might not) I would recommend finding some smart women you really admire. Try to be their friend.

A lot of our views are based more on personal experience than logic, and I think that being around some really smart/driven/independent women might help.

Best of luck</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
