<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986533526.0" user="cyanoacrylate" delta="False">
    <text>One thing that no one else has commented on: in your country, the sexist ideas you hold may well be "true" in the sense that your country is a self-fulfilling prophecy. When young girls are raised with the expectation that they're not as good, they're held to lower academic standards. They're held back from positions of authority. Every time they try to become "as good as a man," they're pushed back against because they "obviously" can't be, despite never having been giving a chance.

You admit that women in your country are forced to become stay at home moms. You, as a sexist, are part of what keeps those barriers in place.

So, it is not necessarily that women are inherently less intelligent... but that your country is literally stifling their intelligence and preventing them from fully growing into it. Of course they'll do less well academically. Of course they'll fulfill your stereotypes. You make them. They have no other choice.

Biologically, women ARE much weaker. You might say women should rise up, but in a country filled with men who are much stronger physically and with better access to weaponry and military training, and armed revolt would be incredibly difficult. In your country, women are brought up to be sexist too - so a revolt of women standing their ground is opposed not only by men, but by women. It is a difficult thing to combat.

I think it's important to look at every woman you find inferior and think hard on the contexts that force her into that position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986973984.0" user="petrus4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You admit that women in your country are forced to become stay at home moms. You, as a sexist, are part of what keeps those barriers in place.

Sexist, sexist, sexist.  Try to come up with something other than name-calling.  We've apparently reached a point where political correctness is sufficiently pervasive, that the PC police's favourite neologism only needs to be mentioned, and the entire argument is considered over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986991845.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>OP admits freely that he is a sexist and is asking to have his view changed.  /u/cyanoacrylate acknowledges that it's an appropriate label, but there is a point to be made beyond name calling.  

Invoking the pc police, however seems to be totally irrelevent in this case.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987252933.0" user="JasonMacker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Biologically, women ARE much weaker.

The question, however, is how *much* of the weakness is due to biology. Women today are much, much stronger physically than they were just 100 years ago. A lot of this has to do with the fact that it's a lot more socially acceptable for women to exercise and wear clothes that doesn't restrict mobility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987258203.0" user="cyanoacrylate" delta="False">
    <text>I'd take a look at the Olympics. Those people of both sexes work out and train for a living. The effort on the part of men and women are about as equal as is possible. Women are still slower, lift less, et cetera.

Even given equal effort and exercise, women are much, much weaker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987275050.0" user="JasonMacker" delta="False">
    <text>First, my point is that the innate strength of people is changing over time, with a trend of increase as we move forward in time. This is largely due to factors such as better health, better food, and better opportunity for exercise. So women today, although weaker than men, are much stronger than women in the 19th century.

Second, the problem really boils down to what you define as "woman". A lot of people define "women" to mean weak, so if you take someone with XX chromosomes and give them enough steroids and muscle, a lot of people will say "that person is not a woman anymore". Your gender identify of *woman* is questioned or challenged if you have six-pack abs or big biceps/triceps. So basically, if you bulk up, you lose your womanhood, and this fact is part of the reason why women are weaker than men... because humans are specifically categorizing people as women based on their strength. If humans really wanted to, we could give every person regular doses of strength-building hormones and they'll be much stronger. But at that point, a lot of people will say that there are no longer "women".

If you look at the Olympics, a lot of women have their gender questioned and they're accused of being "men" if they perform too well. Check out [this article on gender verification in sports](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_verification_in_sports).

So basically, yes, "women" are weaker than men, but only because we *define* weak people as women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987510240.0" user="atheist_at_arms" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First, ...

This phenomena isn't exclusive to women. Men as a group are also becoming stronger (specially in places where there's a trend towards taller people, for obvious reasons) and faster. The explanation, IIRC, is due to the fact we have better medical care and better nourishment. The 1900's adult record for the 100m run can today be beat by a 12 years old.

&amp;gt; Second, ...

If you have to give non-endogenous androgens to someone so that "she" could compete, you just PROVED that "she" is weaker...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987659596.0" user="JasonMacker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This phenomena isn't exclusive to women. Men as a group are also becoming stronger (specially in places where there's a trend towards taller people, for obvious reasons) and faster. The explanation, IIRC, is due to the fact we have better medical care and better nourishment. The 1900's adult record for the 100m run can today be beat by a 12 years old.

Yes uh, that's basically exactly what I said. Did you read my comment?

The point is that the strength gap between men and women is closing, and nowadays it's largely arbitrary because of the advancement of medical science that, if people chose to, allows people to bulk up as much as they want, essentially. But looking the life prospects of a bulked up woman, it's not really what straight men are interested in so that reduces her viability in terms of dating and relationships.

&amp;gt;If you have to give non-endogenous androgens to someone so that "she" could compete, you just PROVED that "she" is weaker...

...it's supplements. It's not like the hormones are completely foreign to the female body... women have testosterone too just in lower amounts.

The point I'm making is arguing that women are weak is a bit circular, because people *define* women to be weak, aka "the weaker sex". If you get too strong as a woman then your womanhood gets questioned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26988154441.0" user="Ragark" delta="False">
    <text>He was agreeing with you on the first thing. The second however, on average woman are smaller and have less muscle mass. This is due to their being more testosterone in men, not because women are weak by definition. For the average, I'll agree that culture does a lot to sculpt people, but in places like the Olympics, men routinely outlier women, among other strength based competitions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26993808597.0" user="Love_Em" delta="False">
    <text>Given a man and woman of equal mass, the man will remain stronger. It's not only the fact that men are larger, they also have, pound-for-pound more powerful muscles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987321650.0" user="F4rsight" delta="False">
    <text>Hey- Strength isn't everything. Try and mess with a woman blackbelt in X martial arts. There are women stronger than men out there. There are woman who are SMARTER than men out there. Stereotypes are just an ignorant way to label a group/people/race, and is NEVER accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987541338.0" user="oddaffinities" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So, it is not necessarily that women are inherently less intelligent... but that your country is literally stifling their intelligence and preventing them from fully growing into it. Of course they'll do less well academically. Of course they'll fulfill your stereotypes. You make them. They have no other choice.

It's important to emphasize that it is not just the sort of forcible stifling and limitation, though that exists. It is also that boys and girls are rewarded, not just punished, for different behaviors. I have tested into the 99th percentile on just about every standardized test I've taken my whole life; I was summa cum laude and Phi Beta Kappa in college; I'm now in a PhD program at a top university. But as a teenager, I figured out that I was much more accepted and considered more attractive and cool when I acted ditzy and clueless and naive. So I did. It wasn't a lie, exactly, but it was emphasizing and exaggerating certain aspects of my personality while de-emphasizing others. I have no doubt that many of the people I knew then thought I was "smart, but not on the level" of guys I was objectively smarter than. Or that I just "studied hard" but wasn't really naturally *that* smart. Because a guy could be smart and cool, and not de-emphasize that intelligence. Among some sets, a guy being smart made him cooler. It just really was not the same as a girl. As I grew up I learned not to suppress that side of myself, but to some degree it is probably still part of me to do so.

There is also just general bias. What is OP basing his perception that the "very smart" girls he knows are not as smart as the very smart guys? Aside from the sort of socialization I discussed above, we are taught to code things that are feminine as unserious or superficial, and things that are masculine as serious and with depth. This includes people and their intelligence. One of the things that galled me as a teacher was the way that several of my male colleagues commanded an automatic respect from students that female colleagues who were equally brilliant simply did not. I adored some of my male colleagues and they often deserved that respect, but so did some of my female colleagues. [Research has backed this up](http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/business/2012/09/women-studying-science-face-gender-bias-study-finds/): when scientists were given identical resumes, only one with a female name and another with a male, the group with the male applicant rated him an average of 4 (on a scale of 7), and the female applicant a 3.33, and offered her 85% of the salary. And that's in the U.S.

All of these things are mutually reinforcing. Given the *massively different* pressures on and biases about girls and boys, it is remarkable to me that they are *so incredibly* similar that true differences have been difficult to definitively establish scientifically.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
