<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986503204.0" user="Bodoblock" delta="False">
    <text>What country are you from, may I ask? I think it would be pertinent to know when trying to change your view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986507108.0" user="Lanayru" delta="False">
    <text>Mexico.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986511275.0" user="Bodoblock" delta="False">
    <text>Look at it in this context. Mexico as a nation, arguably, is less "successful" in certain things like the economy, safety, stability, fighting corruption, etc. Particularly so when compared to the mostly Anglo and Germanic peoples in America. 

Does that make the Mestizo Mexicans an inferior race? Or are they simply a group of people who have succeeded and failed based on their circumstances?

Likewise, women are the same. They are people like everyone else constrained by circumstances around them. Getting into or being born into those circumstances in the first place isn't something that makes them inherently inferior in some way.

I am ethnically Korean. Am I racially superior to a Mestizo Mexican because my race built a safer and more prosperous than Mexico?

In fact, Korea provides a great contrast. One is a wealthy, advanced, and peaceful nation. The other Korea is a backwards, totalitarian, repressed, and poor nation. It really goes to show it's less about the purported inferiority or superiority of the people and more about circumstance.

Inherent inferiority isn't built in (excluding mental or physical diseases). Circumstance is much more important the way I see it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986535516.0" user="IntoTheWest" delta="False">
    <text>From what I understand, Mexican culture emphasizes and values strength.

Strength has really been a "male" characteristic- men are stronger and more aggressive. It is easy to think it makes us better.

Perhaps if we value something where women excel- communication or emotional sensitivity to others, you could consider women "better"

Try to determine what you value-- what makes men "better" and see if those values are relative. For example: why should we value strength over communication? We don't fight for our lives anymore, but we need to communicate with each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986691921.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Given that your country is engaged in a brutal war against drug traders and the crime rate (mostly due to males fighting) is sky high, I'd have thought you'd be supportive of women's adaptions- avoiding combat, superior social skills, lower aggression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986717865.0" user="thecowsaysmoo123" delta="False">
    <text>You mention your belief that men are smarter than women.  This isn't true.  http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sex_differences_in_human_psychology says that there is no difference in mean scores for most tests of intelligence.  Yet until recently most women were not found at all among doctors, CEOs, scientists, etc...

How many mexicans have won nobel prizes compared to non mexcians?  Why do mexicans perform pathetically academically when in the US,  even after multiple generations?  Why is mexico so poor and violent?  Maybe the same reason for women's bad performance until recently is the same reason for the poor performance of mexicans.

Edit:  The entire point of this post is to show that non-innate factors can have profound effects on people's behavior and cultural values,  just in case anyone misses it.  I do not believe that biological factors are responsible in any significant amount for the disparity between mexicans and non-mexican americans. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
