<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986544683.0" user="Necron_Overlord" delta="False">
    <text>Inferior by what standards exactly?  How can women be inferior to men unless one is comparing them against men by the standards held to men?

Men are physically stronger than woman.  Maybe this is true, maybe it is not. For sake of argument, let's assume it is true.  Does this make men *superior* to women, or simply *stronger* than women?

Why is stronger better than weaker?  Who decides that?  Men?  That's clearly biased; rigging the game so that one can win.  What would an objective judge with no attachment to any particular outcome view as the superior option between strong and weak?

I would argue that men and women are fundamentally different, intended by nature for different purposes, and with different attributes that serve those different purposes.  How can one be said to be superior to the other?  It's like saying a car is superior to a boat.  Sure it is, if you happen to need to go down a road.  If you have to get to an island however...
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986703449.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Just to play devil's advocate:

-Men are stronger than women (we can only speak in generalizations here).  To insist this is up for debate is asinine and only an attempt at regurgitating equo-bullshit.

-Stronger means survival in the wild (surviving is a by-product of environmental superiority).  Take away the luxuries of modern life and there will be no hierarchical change - men will continue to rule.

-Stronger is better than weak, evolution tells us that.  There is no rigging, unless you think mother nature is in on the scam.

At the end of the day, neither exists without the other.  Both are equally important to society and should be treated as we would treat any human being.  However, the argument and conversation about which is stronger is tired and it's ridiculously absurd to qualify responses to such a question ("by what standards, exactly?")  Gimmie a break - we all know what standards we're talking about.  Life.  Earth.  Those standards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986753294.0" user="The_Mahatma_Fonzie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Stronger is better than weak, evolution tells us that.  

What are you talking about?  A) evolution doesn't tell us anything is better than anything else, it continues based on what survives.  B) Being weaker does not always lead surviving less.  C) The difference in strength between men and women is not so atronomical that women are incapable of fending for themselves in the "wild of nature," and in fact they are better adapted than man at gathering food from plants (their brains have evolved to be better at that, while men's brans were evolving spacial reasoning skills to hunt).

So please stop talking out of your ass about evolution.  Of course men are physically stronger, and, of course, women have skills (such as multi-tasking) that they are simply better than men at.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986761757.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Of course men are physically stronger, and, *of course, women have skills (such as multi-tasking) that they are simply better than men at*

Why are you qualifying this?  This is my point entirely, the need for qualification exists because of the desire to be 'equal' when we aren't.  We're both humans, but we are different humans with specialized traits which are very strictly reinforced by gender.

And personally, I think we should celebrate our differences not get hung up on them.  

P.S.  Multitasking is an illusion.  I'm not trying to be pedantic - but it is humorous that in your attempt at qualifying equality in the sexes that you are referencing a trait that is not only scientifically impossible, but that you do it by closing with, "please stop talking out of your ass..."

EDIT:  Probably a better example would be men being great at reading maps/understanding direction, while women excel at recalling conversations much more accurately than men.  My theory is that because men have been conditioned to understand that in the basic fight for life, the minute details are of little importance to survival and therefore we have a tendency to dismiss, or 'throw caution to the wind.'  This type of thinking doesn't guarantee social progression but it does indeed solve basic survival.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986818429.0" user="The_Mahatma_Fonzie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is my point entirely, the need for qualification exists because of the desire to be 'equal' when we aren't... And personally, I think we should celebrate our differences not get hung up on them. 

Hm... so that's why you said "Stronger is better than weak, evolution tells us that."  See, my qualification wasn't to say that they're "equal," my qualification was to show that comparing only one trait (strength) makes no sense, when there are tons of traits that affect survival.

&amp;gt;P.S. Multitasking is an illusion. I'm not trying to be pedantic - but it is humorous that in your attempt at qualifying equality in the sexes that you are referencing a trait that is not only scientifically impossible, but that you do it by closing with, "please stop talking out of your ass..."

Please spend two seconds looking something up before you try to act intelligent.  Had you spent two seconds doing a google search you could have seen that scientific studies have shown that women are in fact better at multi-tasking.  So don't worry about being pedantic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986793217.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>Your entire post reads like it comes from someone whose entire exposure to these topics came from reading the first couple sentences on wikipedia, because it is *very* confused.

&amp;gt; Stronger means survival in the wild

Nope. It does not.  If your thesis were at all true, why are humans, one of the proportionally weakest animals in existence, the dominant species on the planet?  I'll give you a hint:  it's because strength isn't really important at all when you have other features that outweigh it.  

Humans are on top *only* because of our intelligence, language, opposable thumbs, etc.  All features that both sexes of our species have in common.  Elephants and lions and bears are what words like "strong" refer to in the wild, and look at how far its gotten them.

Also, I'm not sure why I have to point this out, but even if you had been correct about the importance of strength in the wild, we're not *in* the wild, so that was a bit of a non-sequitur.  Surviving is definitely a product of environmental fitness, but our environment is sidewalks and starbucks.  You are not a mountain man, so referring to random environments that have nothing to do with your own is a pointless waste of time.

&amp;gt; it's ridiculously absurd to qualify responses to such a question ("by what standards, exactly?") Gimmie a break - we all know what standards we're talking about. Life. Earth. Those standards.

Yes, it is absurd.  So I find it interesting that you wrote an entire post doing nothing but that.  You first qualified the standards to an environment our ancestors left thousands of years ago, and even then couldn't apply the standards correctly.

But yes, the *rest* of us do know what standards we're talking about:  the standards of modern life in the 21st century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986894047.0" user="Ralkir" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Humans are on top only because of our intelligence, language, opposable thumbs, etc. All features that both sexes of our species have in common. Elephants and lions and bears are what words like "strong" refer to in the wild, and look at how far its gotten them.

Just because I want to keep things factually correct humans are not on top *only* because of the traits you pointed out. 

The reason humans were able to foster the trait of increased intelligence (and the ability to design tools) was because we had a biologically innate ability of physicality that made us better than everything else in the wild. No, I am not referring to strength, I am referring to Endurance. Humans are one of the, if not the number one endurance runners on the planet. 

It was this ability that allowed us to survive the harsh ground life as we evolved from our tree swinging ancestors. So quite the contrary it does appear as if mother nature favours physical attributes first, and other attributes second. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986903108.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>Well fair enough, but count that under the "etc" in the list of traits that both sexes share then.  The real gist of my point was that strength in particular is not important and that the features that make us fit are not unique to either sex, however many there are.  (Which is almost tautologically true, since if one of the sexes lacked the features that make us fit they would have had difficulty surviving, and consequently our species would have likely failed as well)

Although it's still worth mentioning that that is not relevant to today's environment either.  It was thousands of years ago, but in a measurement of our fitness as a species today, essentially nothing with respect to athleticism makes the list.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986809176.0" user="Necron_Overlord" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Stronger means survival in the wild (surviving is a by-product of environmental superiority). Take away the luxuries of modern life and there will be no hierarchical change - men will continue to rule.

Great.  Now produce another generation of humans.  Oops!

&amp;gt;Stronger is better than weak, evolution tells us that. There is no rigging, unless you think mother nature is in on the scam.

Evolution tells us nothing, because evolution is a process and has neither opinions nor an ability to express them.  Mother Nature is an anthropomorphic fiction, and is not "in on" anything.  She doesn't exist.

&amp;gt; However, the argument and conversation about which is stronger is tired and it's ridiculously absurd to qualify responses to such a question ("by what standards, exactly?") Gimmie a break - we all know what standards we're talking about. Life. Earth. Those standards.

Earth and Life are not sentient beings, they have no opinions nor any standards.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986850605.0" user="pulkit24" delta="False">
    <text>Strength isn't the only physical prowess necessary for survival. In fact, a strong, heavy-muscled man may be overtaken by an agile, high-stamina woman when fleeing from a predator, which can be all the difference between life and death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986942944.0" user="thro_way" delta="False">
    <text>Men are, on average, faster than women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26986894882.0" user="AnnaLemma" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Stronger is better than weak, evolution tells us that.

I had to laugh at that. Black rhinos are pretty conclusively stronger than humans, so by all rights they should be running the show. Yet they're on the verge of extinction, and here we humans are....

So look, if sheer strength were the sole criterion for evolutionary advantage, *human females would have evolved to be as strong as the males*. The very fact that human sexual dimorphism includes a stronger male and weaker female means that *there are advantages go both* (or at least that the trade-off is worth it).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26987505066.0" user="Sadsharks" delta="False">
    <text>I have a feeling you don't actually know what evolution is and/or how it works.  Read On the Origin of Species or the Greatest Show on Earth before you try to say "stronger is better than weaker".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
