<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="110515761.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1tsqi9/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender : CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Lanayru</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this CMV has been done before (I searched before making this particular submission), but I believe the circumstances in which my sexism has grown are different enough from the other OPs of other similar threads (like user TyKillsTyGoT) to make a new topic that suits my reality better.

I share many of the views held by this user, such as:

    "The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly."

    "I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges. "

    "The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. "

They all pretty much sum up the most prevailing sexist ideas I have.

Now, I should clarify and explain why my reality is different from that of TyKillsTyGoT. I've lived all of my life in a very sexist country, (I'm not from the US, and although I'm sure they have their own issues with sexism, it is, by far, a lot less severe than that which my country has held with such determination) and my parents, siblings and other people close to me have been raised with a sexist ideology. This ideology can vary from the pettiest, smallest things like the situations I listed above, to more serious and aggressive behaviors such as a generalized violence against women in households, or forcing women to stay at home raising kids with no opportunity from their partners to seek financial independence.

I do not share or condone in any way, shape or form the latter. However, I do share a vast majority of the former, and they make me feel really immature, since I know those views aren't objectively true, and are nothing but product of generalization and blunt sexism. In all due honesty, most of the women in this country are not really doing much to change my ideas (I'm not saying that they have to, but rather that their behaviors reinforce all those sexist stereotypes, inevitably so, as we've all been raised inside a sexist nation), by either fitting the stereotypes almost perfectly or using their gender as a mean to get benefits or escape certain situations (such as the "chivarly" most, if not all, of them demand. Personally I think chivarly is based on the idea that women are weaker, and therefore a man must do the hard job for them).

I really want to open my mind and change the view this country has force-fed me with since childhood, so please reddit, CMV.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26986504383.0" user="ablarga" delta="False">
    <text>So this is the best response I've read on this topic, [from this response](http://www.reddit.com/r/relationships/comments/1t6uyr/i_just_realize_im_sexist_towards_women_im_going/ce53zhc): 

&amp;gt; The concept to break down is that 'men do/are certain things' and 'women do/are other things.' Splitting things up into two camps creates comparison where comparison isn't actually necessary. It isn't about men being better, or women being better. It isn't about 'men's work' being more difficult or valuable, or 'women's work' being more difficult or valuable.
We are people first. We have gender, but that gender affects us each in different ways, and I dare say, means something different to each of us.
You are a man. But not everything you are IS a man. All the things you are good at aren't man things. They are YOU things. I am a woman. But not everything I am IS a woman. All the things I am good at aren't woman things. They are ME things.
You and I are MORE THAN just our genders.

It's up to you to change the way you look at all people. If you want to stop seeing women as inferior, you need to stop seeing women and start seeing people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
