<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1108187397.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ibsav9/cmv_voting_for_the_president_is_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: voting for the president is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>TheRealPifftastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The reason I feel this way is because of the electoral college.  The popular vote hasn't been used to elect a president since sometime in the 1800's. Donald Trump lost the popular vote by 2.8 million in 2016.All of the "get out and vote" sentiments are such a waste of time,money, and effort.  I do vote in local/state issues and politicians, because that really is the power of the people in action. All of my friends think I'm missing the point, and I may be. I really feel that out political system is deeply flawed. From all the special interests groups and lobbyists to tax breaks for multi million dollar companies that don't pay American taxes or pay a livable wage to the workers. I feel that nothing can change until the power of the people rule the country and not 538 voters that are easily swayed by greed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34945858717.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>The popular vote decides how the electors of the state are chosen. Faithless electors are a thing, but there have never been anywhere close to enough of them to make difference. And the Supreme Court just ruled it's legal to punish and replace them to align with the voters (which some states were already doing).

There are definitely issues with it, but they aren't some totally arbitrary group selecting who they want. They're voting based on the winners of the state they're in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34945881809.0" user="TheRealPifftastic" delta="False">
    <text>My main point is the electoral college should be abolished and the popular vote is the only one that should decide the outcome of the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34945890271.0" user="dudemanwhoa" delta="False">
    <text>That's different than "voting is pointless". Most people here I'm sure agree that we change the EC, but that doesn't mean voting is pointless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34945895917.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree. I'm a fan of removing the electoral. But you are making it sound like the electoral college is just voting however they want and aren't beholden to anything. Since they're following the will of the state they're in voting *does* matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34945908223.0" user="Adodie" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree that the electoral college should be abolished, but how does that ruin the value of voting? By voting, you can still be a part of making sure your state selects the correct electors.

In any event, every time there's a popular vote/electorally college split (such as 2016), there's more pressure to get rid of the electoral college. So even if your end goal is to remove the electoral college, voting still may have a (albeit extremely small) impact</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34946152423.0" user="Nervusnus" delta="False">
    <text>Doing this would ensure that your vote doesn’t matter unless you live in CA, TX, FL, or NY.

It would be the opposite of what you’re trying to achieve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34946215809.0" user="wrathandplaster" delta="False">
    <text>The presidential votes of Republicans in CA and NY are worthless in the current system.  How is that fair?  Same for Democrats in Texas.

Floridians votes are worth much more since it’s a swing state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34946887470.0" user="dkh_189" delta="False">
    <text>Which is a problem of the winner takes all system, not EC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34947513387.0" user="wrathandplaster" delta="False">
    <text>I agree from a technical standpoint.

However, the states are given the power to decide whether they do winner take all or proportional or whatever in the EC system.

States with a dominant party are incentivized to do winner take all since the majority is in charge and they can leverage all of their electors for their party.  Swing states are incentivized also because they get more attention from the candidates.  48/50 states are winner take all.

If all of the states were forced to do proportional elector allocation none of this would be an issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34947882688.0" user="dkh_189" delta="False">
    <text>Why shouldn't the decision be up to the people of that state? Why should they be forced to do something they don't want to? 

If you want your vote to "worth" as much as those from swing states, then maybe don't support a certain party no matter what. If you give them unconditional support, it's no surprise that they wouldn't care about you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34947087752.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>This is completely false.

Under a popular vote, every vote has equal weight, regardless of where you live. A vote in Wyoming matters just as much as one in California.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34948094044.0" user="Nervusnus" delta="False">
    <text>I did the math once. 1/2 the votes in CA was equivalent to the total vote of about 14 other states. If you live in one of those 14 states your vote is meaningless. The population distribution between states is incredibly disproportionate. CA, NY, FL, and TX would decide every election regardless of what happens in the 46 other states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34948110301.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Your vote still means exactly as much in those 14 states as it does in CA, there's just more people in the latter state. But each individual person in CA has exactly as much influence on the election as every inhabitant of any other state.

Remember, we're discussing a popular vote scenario. Under this scenario, the states do not matter at all.  The candidate that recieves the most votes will win, regardless of where his voters live.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34949102346.0" user="dkh_189" delta="False">
    <text>But the states should matter. Someone living in Wyoming has wildly different needs and wants compared to someone living in CA. How would they even get a voice when their entire population is only a fraction of that of CA?

Imagine you are assembling a world government, would you let the top 5 or so most populous countries making all the decisions? The U.S. is just a smaller version of that with 50 countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34949194230.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the states should matter. Someone living in Wyoming has wildly different needs and wants compared to someone living in CA. 

I can make the exact same argument with any given demographic.      
More votes for LGBTQ   
More votes for religious minorities
More votes for POC   
More votes for the poor, or for the 1%   
And so on...

Lots of people have different needs, after all...

&amp;gt;Imagine you are assembling a world government, would you let the top 5 or so most populous countries making all the decisions? The U.S. is just a smaller version of that with 50 countries.

This logic only works if you assume that every given country is a monolith. Neither countries nor states are monoliths, every single vote counts equally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34949606765.0" user="dkh_189" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I can make the exact same argument with any given demographic.

No one is stopping you from proposing such system. Doubt that it would get any traction.

&amp;gt;This logic only works if you assume that every given country is a monolith. Neither countries nor states are monoliths, every single vote counts equally.

You still haven't answered the question. Would you implement popular vote in that case? Countries don't need to be a monolith. They just need to be less different within the country than without.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
