<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1108187397.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ibsav9/cmv_voting_for_the_president_is_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: voting for the president is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>TheRealPifftastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The reason I feel this way is because of the electoral college.  The popular vote hasn't been used to elect a president since sometime in the 1800's. Donald Trump lost the popular vote by 2.8 million in 2016.All of the "get out and vote" sentiments are such a waste of time,money, and effort.  I do vote in local/state issues and politicians, because that really is the power of the people in action. All of my friends think I'm missing the point, and I may be. I really feel that out political system is deeply flawed. From all the special interests groups and lobbyists to tax breaks for multi million dollar companies that don't pay American taxes or pay a livable wage to the workers. I feel that nothing can change until the power of the people rule the country and not 538 voters that are easily swayed by greed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34945975702.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Bernie Sanders just said: *This is not normal.* The biggest reason you feel voting for president is pointless is because Donald Trump has done everything possible to make you feel that way. This includes limiting mail in votes, suggesting that the election is fraudulent, convincing you that everyone is equally horrible, etc. He drags everyone down to his level and beats them with experience. That way, you won't vote and his base will.

Meanwhile, if people think voting works, it does. It's like an elephant that is tied down by a rope when they are young. They can't break the rope, and over time they get used to it. Then when they are big and strong enough to easily rip open the rope, they don't. They think they can't break free even though they have the strength to easily tear it down. If you want to keep an elephant captive, your job is to make sure they never realize they can easily leave.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
