<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1108187397.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ibsav9/cmv_voting_for_the_president_is_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: voting for the president is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>TheRealPifftastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The reason I feel this way is because of the electoral college.  The popular vote hasn't been used to elect a president since sometime in the 1800's. Donald Trump lost the popular vote by 2.8 million in 2016.All of the "get out and vote" sentiments are such a waste of time,money, and effort.  I do vote in local/state issues and politicians, because that really is the power of the people in action. All of my friends think I'm missing the point, and I may be. I really feel that out political system is deeply flawed. From all the special interests groups and lobbyists to tax breaks for multi million dollar companies that don't pay American taxes or pay a livable wage to the workers. I feel that nothing can change until the power of the people rule the country and not 538 voters that are easily swayed by greed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34945909535.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text> [https://www.census.gov/data/tables/time-series/demo/voting-and-registration/p20-580.html](https://www.census.gov/data/tables/time-series/demo/voting-and-registration/p20-580.html) 

If you look at Table 1 you'll see that of the eligible voters, just over half of them are actually registered and voting.

The greatest single voting demographic are non-voters. If all of the eligible voters that don't vote decided to vote third party they could, if appropriately spread out among the states, easily elect a 3rd party candidate. 

Voters influence the electoral college in what is formally enshrined in some states as winner-take-all. Faithless electors are not common. 

It is easy to think that voting doesn't matter, but it is harder to tamper with elections when you need to subvert multiple millions of votes than it is when you only need to tamper with a few dozen thousand. 

It may seem like your vote doesn't matter, or that it matters less than it should, but voting is still important. Especially at the local level. 

Remember, Mickey Mouse isn't gonna get elected if we don't vote. #Mickey2020 #I'mkiddingpleasedon'telectamouse</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
