<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1108187397.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ibsav9/cmv_voting_for_the_president_is_pointless/">
    <title>CMV: voting for the president is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>TheRealPifftastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The reason I feel this way is because of the electoral college.  The popular vote hasn't been used to elect a president since sometime in the 1800's. Donald Trump lost the popular vote by 2.8 million in 2016.All of the "get out and vote" sentiments are such a waste of time,money, and effort.  I do vote in local/state issues and politicians, because that really is the power of the people in action. All of my friends think I'm missing the point, and I may be. I really feel that out political system is deeply flawed. From all the special interests groups and lobbyists to tax breaks for multi million dollar companies that don't pay American taxes or pay a livable wage to the workers. I feel that nothing can change until the power of the people rule the country and not 538 voters that are easily swayed by greed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34945914948.0" user="the_platypus_king" delta="False">
    <text>The popular vote actually coincides with the electoral vote the majority of the time. We've had 58 presidential elections and only five popular/electoral vote mismatches.

How people vote isn't tracked individually, but it is semi-reliably tracked at a group level. And if your groups (age, sex, race, location) get out to vote at a disproportionately high rate, politicians will pander more to your interests. There's a reason politicians cater to the interests of the old and the higher income disproportionately; those are the groups that vote.

And again, the system is flawed, and not directly representative, but ultimately, it is democratic, and there's not a strong reason not to if you have the slightest preference between candidates.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
