<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="111698351.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ui2zz/cmv_i_think_mike_tyson_is_insanely_over_rated_and/">
    <title>CMV: I think Mike Tyson is insanely over rated, and over hyped. And is not even a top 10 fighter of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>YesIamaWizard</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ring magazine has Tyson ranked 72 of the last 80 years. There are much more amazing fighters that have come and gone, and I think specifically the most damning part to Tyson's mystique is that he fought a bunch of tomato cans and didn't fight anyone of real quality during his prime.

When Tyson did fight quality opponents he lost or had his ass handed to him by Lewis and Holyfield.
A huge portion of the mystique is Mike Tyson's punch out. Many people who know fighting know Tyson was over rated. But a vast majority don't know, and only know how "great" he was because of his video game.

I think currently there are a couple active fighters that are better pound for pound guys. And I think Lennox Lewis was even a better champ than Tyson with a far better skill set.

So convince me that Tyson is the greatest ever, and not Ali,Frazier,Foreman,Louis, or Robinson. I could continue on with the list. I really think Tyson is over hyped, and was more of a sideshow with mental and personal problems than great fighter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26998734721.0" user="anonymous123421" delta="False">
    <text>He may not have been the best, but coming from someone not really into all of those fighting sports I can tell you with certainty that he, Muhammad Ali, and the fictional Rocky Balboa have done more for boxing than any other people in history, at least in the United States.

Tyson was a beast in his time, but what he did for the sport was greater than any accomplishment in the ring. Of course he had a great deal of skills to back it up, but man he was popular. He deserves major recognition for bringing that sport to where it is today.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
