<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="111698351.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ui2zz/cmv_i_think_mike_tyson_is_insanely_over_rated_and/">
    <title>CMV: I think Mike Tyson is insanely over rated, and over hyped. And is not even a top 10 fighter of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>YesIamaWizard</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ring magazine has Tyson ranked 72 of the last 80 years. There are much more amazing fighters that have come and gone, and I think specifically the most damning part to Tyson's mystique is that he fought a bunch of tomato cans and didn't fight anyone of real quality during his prime.

When Tyson did fight quality opponents he lost or had his ass handed to him by Lewis and Holyfield.
A huge portion of the mystique is Mike Tyson's punch out. Many people who know fighting know Tyson was over rated. But a vast majority don't know, and only know how "great" he was because of his video game.

I think currently there are a couple active fighters that are better pound for pound guys. And I think Lennox Lewis was even a better champ than Tyson with a far better skill set.

So convince me that Tyson is the greatest ever, and not Ali,Frazier,Foreman,Louis, or Robinson. I could continue on with the list. I really think Tyson is over hyped, and was more of a sideshow with mental and personal problems than great fighter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26998703204.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So convince me that Tyson is the greatest ever

There is a huge difference between being the greatest ever and being known as a great fighter. I think many people agree that Tyson was a great fighter, but I don't know/haven't heard many people try to claim that Tyson is the greatest ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26998706924.0" user="YesIamaWizard" delta="False">
    <text>I am giving an open mind to consider him as a great fighter. Some consider him GOAT. 

I will accept either argument, although I think they are both wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26998710395.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I don't know enough about boxing to change your view, I just wanted to clear up the fact that most people don't consider Tyson to be the GOAT.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26998728321.0" user="YesIamaWizard" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.reddit.com/search?q=mike+tyson&amp;amp;restrict_sr=off&amp;amp;sort=relevance&amp;amp;t=all 

Its basically thread after thread ball washing Tyson.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26998816647.0" user="Forbiddian" delta="False">
    <text>Uhm, none of those threads do that. They're talking about his biting his opponent or workouts, or gifs of him fighting, but they're not ranking him in any way.

The only thread that ranks him is buried and says he's "one of the best".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26998811363.0" user="IndependentBoof" delta="False">
    <text>I don't even actively follow boxing and I know he's not GOAT. I don't think anyone can make a reasonable argument that he is.

However, were you claiming that ranking him #72 in the last 80 years was too high?

I don't think that sounds out of line. The dude was uniquely feared for the power of his punch. While he wasn't a great all-around boxer, give him credit where credit is due. He had one of -- if not THE -- hardest punch that modern boxing has seen. 

He's been inducted into both the World Boxing Hall of Fame and the International Boxing Hall of Fame. I'm not a boxing expert, but apparently those who have a voice in that community have deemed him "great" if they honored him in that way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
