<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112092849.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1uqje9/m23_i_refuse_to_flirt_before_the_first_date_of_a/">
    <title>M23 I refuse to flirt before the first date of a serious relationship CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwawaytrex</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL;DR: Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator.  Furthermore, any incompatibilities can often times be worked out with open and honest communication.  

I don't do casual dating, hookups, etc.  When I date, it's to find an entire life partner: that is what I'm looking for.  Because that's what I want, I accumulated a lot of advice on what makes a successful long term relationship, and it is a combination of compatibility, communication, and compromise, among others.  

Getting to the point: flirting is about turning each other on sexually.  In a open and honest relationship, both partners will communicate to one another their desires, and depending on that sexual compatibility, and other things, the relationship will or will not work out.  It doesn't make sense for "blind" flirting to occur, before both parties know what each other honestly wants, and then based on how lucky you are at guessing the other person's flirting strategies, succeed and win the first date.  

Problems with this approach: My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.  The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.  

Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants.  To me, seduction is like acting out a role.  And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27002672351.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>But what if she doesn't want you to act out a role, but wants to be intimate with your true self? You make it sound like you are mentally removing yourself from your own sexuality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27002680535.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>yeah the 'background' section in particular sounds like he's expecting them to take turns enjoying sex while the other acts, because they couldn't possibly enjoy it at the same time or without pretense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27002704320.0" user="throwawaytrex" delta="False">
    <text>I'm happy that I'm making her happy, and vice versa.  I love doing a good job, so I enjoy seeing her happiness if I'm succeeding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27002716324.0" user="throwawaytrex" delta="False">
    <text>This is an interesting point...can I take it someplace wild?

First I'll answer you: I guess then we will need to find out if we are compatible with our true selves.  I feel like mind and body are separate, that's why I can separate my identity, which is my true self, from my sexuality, which is biological.  

Now I take it someplace wild:

Let's say I don't mentally remove myself, and I honestly express my sexuality.  Then I will get rejected by everyone who doesn't match, and attract those who do match: the first filter is by sexual compatibility. 
Then we date and we filter by emotional, intellectual connection, etc.  

The chances of me finding someone that fits all the criteria, decreases the more criteria I impose: I'm looking for something more and more rare.  Because of my perceived advantage in the physical compatibility, which I believe I have due to acting, I am saying I can be the most flexible in that department, and afford to be more strict in the other ones I focus on.  Therefore, I want to remove physical compatibility...I guess I need to explain to the other party that I'm doing this and see what that person thinks, since she needs to buy into that idea too.  Hmm, open and honest communication of my dating strategy.  
Then we arrive at the age old: well I can't submit to her a relationship contract for her to read over, and vice versa, and yet actual compatibility is based on the overall contract, but whether each party learns enough to get there depends on the order in which the terms are revealed...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
