<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112092849.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1uqje9/m23_i_refuse_to_flirt_before_the_first_date_of_a/">
    <title>M23 I refuse to flirt before the first date of a serious relationship CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwawaytrex</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL;DR: Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator.  Furthermore, any incompatibilities can often times be worked out with open and honest communication.  

I don't do casual dating, hookups, etc.  When I date, it's to find an entire life partner: that is what I'm looking for.  Because that's what I want, I accumulated a lot of advice on what makes a successful long term relationship, and it is a combination of compatibility, communication, and compromise, among others.  

Getting to the point: flirting is about turning each other on sexually.  In a open and honest relationship, both partners will communicate to one another their desires, and depending on that sexual compatibility, and other things, the relationship will or will not work out.  It doesn't make sense for "blind" flirting to occur, before both parties know what each other honestly wants, and then based on how lucky you are at guessing the other person's flirting strategies, succeed and win the first date.  

Problems with this approach: My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.  The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.  

Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants.  To me, seduction is like acting out a role.  And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27002674636.0" user="carasci" delta="False">
    <text>Successful relationships aren't based solely on overt communication.  Yes, that's a very important aspect, but in the day-to-day a huge part of what makes relationships work is the ability to read and act on a variety of less overt cues.  Flirting is a way of assessing precisely that: the ability to read the other person and intuit things like mental and emotional state *regardless* of what they specifically want.

Relationships are never perfectly open.  There are always things that go unspoken, even when communication is overall extremely good.  The type of intuition that is seen in flirting plays a large part in resolving that, because by and large flirting is about intuiting someone else's desires and states then responding in a positive way.

TL;DR: Flirting assesses a lot more than just sexual compatibility, it also assesses mutual understanding of non-verbal and non-overt communication, which is very important for maintaining a long-term relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
