<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112092849.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1uqje9/m23_i_refuse_to_flirt_before_the_first_date_of_a/">
    <title>M23 I refuse to flirt before the first date of a serious relationship CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwawaytrex</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL;DR: Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator.  Furthermore, any incompatibilities can often times be worked out with open and honest communication.  

I don't do casual dating, hookups, etc.  When I date, it's to find an entire life partner: that is what I'm looking for.  Because that's what I want, I accumulated a lot of advice on what makes a successful long term relationship, and it is a combination of compatibility, communication, and compromise, among others.  

Getting to the point: flirting is about turning each other on sexually.  In a open and honest relationship, both partners will communicate to one another their desires, and depending on that sexual compatibility, and other things, the relationship will or will not work out.  It doesn't make sense for "blind" flirting to occur, before both parties know what each other honestly wants, and then based on how lucky you are at guessing the other person's flirting strategies, succeed and win the first date.  

Problems with this approach: My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.  The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.  

Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants.  To me, seduction is like acting out a role.  And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27002664405.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>How will you know when the time comes if you're not using this pretty standard form of romantic interaction? Are you planning on it being a love at first sight thing? If you get to know her without any sign of romantic/sexual intent, even actively shunning hers, won't she dismiss you as a potential partner? How do you know if a date is casual or the start of a serious relationship? 

I'm also interested as how you'd define flirting, since in my experience other than cheesy pick-up stuff it's essentially just interaction based on trying to get romantic rather than friendly, and if you're planning on asking the girl out on a date wouldn't you require using the former? 

People need to become comfortable discussing sexuality to figure out each others sexual compatibility. Surely the first step of that is flirting?

I'm also completely failing to understand what the relevance is of your 'background' section.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27002701548.0" user="throwawaytrex" delta="False">
    <text>I use non-sexual indicators like whether she has a passion, what interests she has, activities she involves herself in, personality, treatment of friends, quality of pre-existing relationships, social level, values, taste in arts, intelligence.  After I build all that up, do I make the decision to ask for a date, because I feel like if I am NOT a potential partner, I am more likely to see the real her, than if there are emotions and bias clouding judgment, which may happen when dating occurs; or if seduction is distracting; or if I or she acts like someone else on dates than who they naturally are.  

The way I was told to define dates is: if it's not explicitly a date, it's not a date, just a hang out between two friends.  This is confusing for the girl, yes, but I want to see her in her natural state is the goal.  Long term relationships, most of the time you're interacting with a natural state, only every once in a while (hopefully often) you find time to date--chores, responsibilities, work will take up most of the time, so I want to see what she's like.  

I define flirting as anything that would suggest intimacy.  I use "date" to suggest that such behavior is now acceptable.  

The purpose of the background section, and this CMV in general, is my declaration that sexual behavioral compatibility shouldn't be the first indicator of the possibility of a relationship.  

1. Visual assessment of attractiveness
2. Evaluate personality compatibility
3. Values and Ethical compatibility
4. Intellectual and Emotional compatibility
finally
5. physical compatibility.  

The purpose of background is to say that I am confident in my seduction ability--once I get to know you well enough to know what kind of person you like, I could use my acting skills to become that person and seduce you, therefore guaranteeing physical compatibility with nearly anyone, assuming I can act out the character.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27003525937.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>Well I think u/revolutionary at the top has summed it up pretty well. You're confusing flirting with sexuality and sexual compatibility and they are not the same thing. 

You also seem to be arbitrarily defining and removing societal norms. When it comes to relationships and dating and basic human interaction you're definitions and rules stand in the way more than they help because the person isn't immediately aware they're supposed to be following your rules as opposed to just normal social interaction. Like you said, your definitions and rules about dating are confusing for the girls; how is that going to help you see them behave naturally - if anything you're seeing them ill at ease.

You also have to remember that there are several aspects to the 'real/ natural' person. How she acts in non-romantic situations will show that version of the 'real' her but she may behave differently, be a different 'real' version in a romantic context - which you are excluding until later in the relationship. The natural state is a bit of a fallacy. I act in a natural state around my friends, around my coworkers and around my partner, but these are all different natural states. 

You also have to bear in mind how important sexual compatibility is in long term relationships. While you may be able to act out the character the girl wants, are you going to be fully satisfied by that for years and years and years - is she going to be happy that you're not actually sexually compatible but merely acting it? Many would argue that true sexual compatibility is, if anything, the truest 'natural state' in which people are completely open, honest and in to each other. 

You seem to be separating seduction and the rest of the relationship, but they are inherently intertwined. Romantic long term relationships are not simply compatible friendships + seduction. It is far more complex than what you are reducing it to. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
