<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112092849.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1uqje9/m23_i_refuse_to_flirt_before_the_first_date_of_a/">
    <title>M23 I refuse to flirt before the first date of a serious relationship CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwawaytrex</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL;DR: Flirting assesses sexual compatibility, which alone is not sufficient to guarantee long term success, making it not a useful indicator.  Furthermore, any incompatibilities can often times be worked out with open and honest communication.  

I don't do casual dating, hookups, etc.  When I date, it's to find an entire life partner: that is what I'm looking for.  Because that's what I want, I accumulated a lot of advice on what makes a successful long term relationship, and it is a combination of compatibility, communication, and compromise, among others.  

Getting to the point: flirting is about turning each other on sexually.  In a open and honest relationship, both partners will communicate to one another their desires, and depending on that sexual compatibility, and other things, the relationship will or will not work out.  It doesn't make sense for "blind" flirting to occur, before both parties know what each other honestly wants, and then based on how lucky you are at guessing the other person's flirting strategies, succeed and win the first date.  

Problems with this approach: My guess is, women look for a spark, and I actively avoid generating it--if there is a flirt opportunity, I consciously turn it down.  The rationale being that when the time comes, I'll turn up the seduction and work it out, but that time only comes during dating, not before.  

Background: I was a child actor, so once I find out my partner's turn ons, I can play out the fantasies and characters she wants.  To me, seduction is like acting out a role.  And the compromise is if I give her a night of acting, I'll get one in return.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27002694954.0" user="plank831" delta="False">
    <text>Your desire for a longterm monogamous relationship for reproduction is the standard biological drive found in all of us. Flirting is behavior that allows you to implicitly determine the probabilities of a successful romantic relationship. 

Humans havent always had verbal language, so for a long time before we relied on specific behaviors. These are biological cues found in other animals too. And even though we can communicate verbally now, those behaviors are still widespread and universally accepted.

We usually laugh, smile and hug our friends instead of saying "You are my friend." We may stare, frown, lipbite, raise shoulders, throw insults, or clench fists instead of saying "I want to fight you." We may cry or yell curse words instead of sayinf "Im angry/sad."

And in terms of finding a mate, we tend to use sly body signals or language to express interest. People dont say "I find your personality intriguing, and your looks sexually appealling, wanna go on a date?" And these behaviors are deeply ingrained in human culture. To have a real chance in dating, it would be advantageous to follow the universal social norms. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
