<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077756472.0" user="rmeestudios" delta="False">
    <text>Let me guess: you live in/were influenced by a religious/Christian culture?

I've been thinking a lot about this lately. I don't think Porn™️ itself is what "ruins people's lives". What causes problems is people not understanding how to respond to their own sexuality. If people knew how to interact with porn and whether or not their urges/desires were normal or unhealthy, it would solve a lot of problems.

I think that's the issue. Not seeing nudity on a screen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079699408.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>No actually, I am a Satanist. My parents were agnostic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
