<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077170423.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

The question should be: do you have any justification *for* your view? If yes, what is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079693629.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Read the rest of my post? Honestly, did you just stop reading it after the quoted portion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080008354.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>You're only listing claims. I was asking for justification to back those up, i.e. evidence...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080029285.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>How are these for evidence? 


[5-8% of adults suffer from porn addiction ](https://www.therecoveryvillage.com/process-addiction/porn-addiction/related/pornography-statistics/#Porn_Addiction_Trends)

[Money Laundering, Coercion, And Exploitation: Uncovering The Porn Industry’s Shady Business Practices](https://fightthenewdrug.org/uncovering-porn-industry-shady-business-practices/)

[How Teens Get Tricked, Coerced, And Trafficked Into Doing Amateur Porn
](https://fightthenewdrug.org/how-teen-girls-get-tricked-into-doing-porn/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080085702.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. The medial profession actually rejects the existence of porn addiction and sex addiction:

It's mainly the self-help industry (and religious organizations) who are pushing this idea:

* Science Stopped Believing in Porn Addiction. You Should, Too ([Psychology Today](https://www.psychologytoday.com/ie/blog/women-who-stray/201808/science-stopped-believing-in-porn-addiction-you-should-too))
* [AASECT](https://www.aasect.org/position-sex-addiction)...does not find sufficient empirical evidence to support the classification of sex addiction or porn addiction as a mental health disorder</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080144803.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, porn addiction is realized by medical professionals, but not as an addiction all on its own. It is under the umbrella term of Hypersexual disorder, in which people can be addicted to excessive masturbation, cybersex, pornography use, telephone sex, sexual behavior with consenting adults, strip club visitations, etc. This is taken from [this](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6352245/) article. This article addresses how the APA views hypersexual disorder &amp;amp; excessive pornography use. 

I was wrong by implying that porn addiction is a freestanding addiction. You are right about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080186271.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, excessive use may be bad, but that goes for anything.

Was your point just that it's *possible* that it can ruin someone's life?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080195848.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Yes actually, and I definitely need to reword my post that way. No way do I believe porn WILL ruin everyone who watches its life or anything like that. I just meant that it can ruin lives and does more frequently than people care to admit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
