<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077655639.0" user="aardaar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. 

I should point out that not everyone who watches porn, watches porn involving the opposite gender.

Another point I feel I should make is that you have a limited view of pornography. Not all porn consists of videos of real people. Pornography can exist in any medium, prose, poetry, art, music, ect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079714945.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I did consider your first point there. I just assumed that gay porn was covered under "ruins your perception of yourself" since gay men/women might compare their bodies to the bodies they see on screen. 

That second point is an extremely good point i didn't even consider!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
