<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077228939.0" user="Nybear21" delta="False">
    <text>I think your initial statement is overstated. Porn can have a negative impact on someone's life, but that doesn't mean that it inherently leads to a negative impact. How do you accurately parse out people who have addictive personalities or other mental health issues they were trying to escape from and would have filled that gap they were using porn for with something else that would have lead to issues in their life vs people for whom it was specifically porn? 

When you're talking about the people in the porn, there's also some logistics to consider. If that person has other career options, why did they choose porn? Seems like it's probably not that big of a negative if they turned down other avenues for it. If they don't have any other option, would being out of work and making no money be a larger negative impact on them? (Only taking into consideration legal businesses here obviously. People who are forced into it is a different conversation than the initial assertion made.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35077474281.0" user="edispU6197" delta="False">
    <text>to support OP here, it is true that some of these companies are legal but it is very hard to tell which ones are ethical and which ones aren't, they do everything they can to seem ethical and good but a lot of them really aren't. not to mention that the bigger problem is the sites themselves, pornhub is technically legal but they definitely don't do enough to stop people from posting videos that show real abuse etc.. (for example I've seen a tweet of a women saying she has been trying to take down a video on pornhub of her being raped when she 14) I do agree with you tho that it isn't inherently bad</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35077517350.0" user="Aclopolipse" delta="False">
    <text>I did feminist activism with a woman who used this argument to make the case against consuming any kind of porn.  Whether they're actually underage, it's straight up rape (as in your example) or it was otherwise made under duress (pimping, etc.), you can't be absolutely certain it was free of exploitation.  Tbh kinda spooks me to this day.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
