<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077500839.0" user="RooDooDootDaDoo" delta="False">
    <text>You’re making a generalized overstatement on the effect of people’s lives who watch porn. Yes, it can ruin lives but this is extremely rare and doesn’t usually happen. Unless you have some sort of source to prove that this is the case, it’s a baseless claim. So yeah, sure, SOME people’s lives are ruined by porn but that doesn’t mean that por. Ruines consumer’s lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079732834.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>I actually did my research into this belief. In the most respectful way possible, you should have as well before assuming i did not. 

[5-8% of adults suffer from porn addiction](https://www.therecoveryvillage.com/process-addiction/porn-addiction/related/pornography-statistics/#Porn_Addiction_Trends)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079812840.0" user="RooDooDootDaDoo" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for proving my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079820204.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Your point was in no way proven? You said it was extremely rare. If you think 5-8% of adults is extremely rare, then you need to learn a few things about statistics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079831530.0" user="RooDooDootDaDoo" delta="False">
    <text>That means 92-95 percent of people are not addicted. So yeah, extremely rare. Again, thanks for proving my point. If you don’t like the statement, make it just very rare. Either way, your point is disproven because you claimed it ruins people’s lives which you’ve now shown is a nonsense claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079906191.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>In America, less than 2% of people have contracted COVID. Yet it is not considered rare. But by your logic, COVID is extremely rare. Does this mean COVID deserves no attention, since it is so rare? Please think before you respond.


Once again, please educate yourself on fractions. And actually read the article. It explains how porn addiction ruins lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079912553.0" user="RooDooDootDaDoo" delta="False">
    <text>Irrelevant. Your claim was disproven, porn only ruins SOME people’s lives. End of story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079919381.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>I never said porn ruins everyone's lives. Your claim that porn ruining lives is rare was disproven. End of story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079939402.0" user="RooDooDootDaDoo" delta="False">
    <text>A) Yes you did. B) Yes it’s rare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079960169.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>A) no I didn't. If I did, please respond to that comment right now so I can see it. Or was it in my main post? Because I sure don't see anywhere that I said that. 

B) so then you're claiming COVID is rare? Bc porn addiction is almost 3 times as likely as contracting COVID in the US. Porn addiction is in no way rare. Also, schizophrenia affects a bit over 1% of the population WORLDWIDE. Yet no one considers Schizophrenia to be rare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079918139.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079924802.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>This is so sad. I can only assume you're struggling with porn addiction yourself since this post hits so close to home :'(

Next time I'll include a trigger warning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080978781.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/RooDooDootDaDoo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+RooDooDootDaDoo&amp;amp;message=RooDooDootDaDoo+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/-/g45oe2j/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
