<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1126922915.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/imxvab/cmv_porn_ruins_peoples_lives/">
    <title>CMV: Porn ruins people's lives.</title>
    <original_poster>OutlinedSnail</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am posting this here after making this argument elsewhere on reddit. I saw lots of people there arguing that porn in fact does not ruin people's lives, so I accept that possibly my view is flawed.

 I believe that porn ruins lives because :

Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender. It ruins marriages and relationships. It van cost people tons of money and even their jobs. It can also lead down disgusting or illegal roads. 

Not to mention the people who are IN the porn. Porn can ruin them as well. More women than you realize are forced or drugged into porn. And no this isn't just dark web porn, this includes porn on pornhub. I guarantee you've seen many videos with blackmailed, drugged, kidnapped, or trafficked women in them. Porn ruins those women's lives as well.

EDIT: I do not mean that watching porn will inevitably ruin your life, i mean it CAN ruin lives, and does more often than people realize/admit.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35077397885.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Porn ruins people's perceptions of themselves and the opposite gender.

Could you expand on it in bit more detail. The way you phrase it, seems a bit vague to the point of being non-descript. In what way exactly porn does ruin people?

Is there for example a trend of people going broke because of porn subscriptions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35079745338.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>On the quoted sentence, airbrushed and surgery altered pornstars give unrealistic expectations for what the human body is supposed to look like. This can make people feel bad about their otherwise attractive bodies, or become less/unattracted to their spouses or partners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080016561.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;On the quoted sentence, airbrushed and surgery altered pornstars give unrealistic expectations for what the human body is supposed to look like.

You are talking more about conventional media. There is all sort of porn, one of the most popular category couple years running being "amateur" which by definition give realistic view of how people have sex. Not to mention tags like "chubby" or "mature" are also popular, especially with the recent popularity of the all step-mom craze.

&amp;gt;or become less/unattracted to their spouses or partners.

Could you cite some source? I hear that a lot on basically everything in media. Games are turning kids into murderers and all sort of nonsense. But nobody ever actually has any solid evidence beyond one outrageous article. Do we have some studies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35080073872.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>To address your first point, that is a very good point. There are other issues with non mainstream porn such as amateur porn. 

[How Teens Get Tricked, Coerced, And Trafficked Into Doing Amateur Porn](https://fightthenewdrug.org/how-teen-girls-get-tricked-into-doing-porn/)


This article contains 3 separate studies:
[What Porn Can Do to Intimacy](https://www-psychologytoday-com.cdn.ampproject.org/v/s/www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/tech-support/201407/what-porn-can-do-intimacy?amp_js_v=a3&amp;amp;amp_gsa=1&amp;amp;amp&amp;amp;usqp=mq331AQIKAGwASDIAQE%3D#aoh=15993360971910&amp;amp;csi=1&amp;amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com&amp;amp;amp_tf=From%20%251%24s&amp;amp;ampshare=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.psychologytoday.com%2Fus%2Fblog%2Ftech-support%2F201407%2Fwhat-porn-can-do-intimacy)

[How Pornography Distorts Intimate Relationships
](https://www.mentalhelp.net/blogs/how-pornography-distorts-intimate-relationships/)


Also, I grabbed my assumption that porn makes people less attracted to their spouses based off of personal testimonials on various subreddits that say this. I should have looked into it for myself, but now that I have, I linked the correlating studies above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35137291910.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To address your first point, that is a very good point. There are other issues with non mainstream porn such as amateur porn.

Couple of things. Firstly what percentage do you think are people coerced into porn vs how much porn there is?

Second, how are people influenced by porn has nothing to do with how the porn was made. If the actors have unrealistic body types and you care about people being influenced by unrealistic body types, it doesn't really matter that the actors were coerced into doing it.

&amp;gt;This article contains 3 separate studies:

I agree. Porn can do a lot of bad things to people. But that is true about almost everything. TV, Games, sports, going clubbing, etc... They all have problems that get people hurt or addicted or whateves.

The thing is that studies consistently show that worlds happiness index is increasing, the number of sexual and domestic crimes is decreasing, personal satisfaction goes up, etc... This are not disconnected from porn also, number of studies showed link between the legalization of porn and the above mentioned factors.

&amp;gt;Also, I grabbed my assumption that porn makes people less attracted to their spouses based off of personal testimonials on various subreddits that say this.

Yeah, personal anecdotes are less than worthless as they are actively skew your perception of reality based on selected few.

The thing is that you are not wrong when you talk about the problems with porn. Buuuut, your claim was about porn ruining lives. And I'm sure you can find one or two examples of rare disfunctions where people are addicted, or cannot operate without porn. The norm is that porn is pretty normal thing that influences us in pretty normal and non-extraordinary ways. Just like most other media or hobbies. When compared to for example gambling. You cannot even compare those two when it comes to addiction rates, or personal, financial and psychological damage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35147890523.0" user="OutlinedSnail" delta="False">
    <text>Porn addiction is actually quite common, it affects up to 8% of adults</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35156339245.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Actually it's problems with stress that manifest as obsessive behavior. And porn is a common outlet. 

Not a problem with porn, but with stress tho.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
