<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1127710637.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iner3h/cmv_the_root_of_the_us_healthcare_crisis_could/">
    <title>CMV: The "root" of the US healthcare crisis could simply be the food we eat.</title>
    <original_poster>godlike_hikikomori</original_poster>
    <original_post>Yes, we do have a crisis with healthcare costs/medical bills. Insurance and pharmaceutical companies are major players. However, I believe the root of the "health crisis" in America is in our food/diet. Many peer reviewed studies have shown that the US population's obesity, diabetes,and cancer rates are at multi decade highs, compared to other countries. Policy experts must focus on making the whole medical system more cost efficient and more focused on functional/holistic health. Enforcing food and environmental regulations are a must. Also, many low income communities do not have the money to afford healthier foods, and some of them live in food deserts. Society should encourage people to avoid and overcome chronic illness so that they can avoid the hospital beds in the first place. This system may allow Americans to actually rely less on healthcare, and this could decrease the amount that taxpayers have to pay for Medicare. Heck, the life expectancies in Korea, Japan,and Singapore are much higher than in the states. Their cultures all promote good diet and exercise. The conversation of reforming healthcare should boil down to this question: Would you want to live a life where you constantly have to rely on pills and hospital visits, instead of improving your overall, long term health?

You can disagree with me on this view,and I may be wrong. However, no one can deny that there are many studies that support the claim that US leads the world in chronic illnesses, and something has to be done about this eventually. In my own spare time, I have studied deeply about how the advent of fast food/junk food actually came about. The history of fast food in the states actually spans from gaining mid- Western farmlands during Manifest Destiny, to the gov't allowing more food to be produced from more acres of land during the post WW2 period, to Big Agra and Food constantly lobbying the gov't, and to the rise of fast food joints in all 50 states. If you study the effects that junk food and food additives have on the body, you would come to understand that it's really not a pretty picture. I just believe that we should be more focused in actually making people healthier in the long-term. To be frank, I strongly disagree with many of the policies put forth by virtually every politician with regard to healthcare. They all seem to ignore how the food we eat can impact our long term health, even though they all have their own merits when discussing the other aspects of the healthcare crisis.

What are your thoughts on how we solve our health crisis?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35082510958.0" user="Loki-Don" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, fast food plays its part, but it isn’t everything. 

While the US consume the most fast food in the world per capita, France is number 2 by a slim margin. 

Yet the French’s life expectancy is also 4 years higher than ours. They suffer significantly less rates of cancer and significantly lower deaths per capita from America’s biggest killer, heart disease. 

Why?

Nationalized healthcare. When people have access to easily accessible, cheap healthcare they get regular check ups. They don’t avoid the doctor for a year with random chest pain and only show up in the ER when they pass out. Their health is continually monitored, adjusted, treated and despite them eating like shit, like we do, they live longer, healthier lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35082558962.0" user="godlike_hikikomori" delta="False">
    <text>Good point. I didn't realize the extent to which check ups from your physician can do wonders for how you can plan to manage your own health. They definitely can help a great deal. However, I still disagree on what you said right at the end of your last paragraph. What do you actually mean by "they live longer, healthier lives?" "Being healthy" is a very abstract concept, in my opinion. It seems as though the way that Western medicine views "health" is that some receptor is inhibited/blocked by some drug, in order for your homeostatic processes to continue normally. I know a decent amount about how these pills work, since I have studied biology and the health sciences during my college years, and so I appreciate the rigors of research that go into these kinds of things. However, the researchers never ask how the chronically ill person devolved into that condition in the first place. What kinds of vitamins and nutrients can make his/her long term health better? What kind of exercise  should he/she undertake on a regular basis, provided that he/she has the time? Once the pills' effects are over, there is really nothing stopping the excess production or scarcity of some organic substance in your body. These pills, in reality, are only short term solutions to very fundamental issues that involve a person's health.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083389412.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Remember, if your view is partially changed, do drop a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083826468.0" user="pmirallesr" delta="False">
    <text>There is a movement in pharmacy that advocates exactly for what you're saying. We are overmedicated, for a variety of reasons, and imo reducing this would be a positive thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35082989784.0" user="27482" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue not just nationalised health care. It isn’t the answer to everything. 

If we are sticking to food look at the french diet and realise when talking about fast food they are talking about different things. French are high in fruit, Veg and FAT (specially animal fats like cheese). It is FAST food not overly processed shit they eat. FFS McDonald’s really struggles to keep its doors open there. 

Ansel Keyes has a lot to answer for with is push to flip the pyramid upside down. He had a hypothesis he liked and edited the data he like liked to support it. France was one of the countries that diet was vastly different to what he deemed healthy so he eliminated it and 13 other countries from his 7 country study. If the West’s public health have one figure to blame iit is he.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083147373.0" user="isoldasballs" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying you’re wrong, but is there any evidence suggesting that nationalized health care is actually what accounts for the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083429027.0" user="PCIEx2" delta="False">
    <text>Their increased life expectancy is not due to nationalized healthcare but is rather a function of their increased consumption of wine which is thought to increase cardiovascular health and resistance to cardiovascular disease

[https://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2001/feb/20/features11.g21#:\~:text=It%20was%20a%20Bordeaux%20cardiologist,put%20it%20down%20to%20wine](https://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2001/feb/20/features11.g21#:~:text=It%20was%20a%20Bordeaux%20cardiologist,put%20it%20down%20to%20wine).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083830017.0" user="a_theist_typing" delta="False">
    <text>High fructose corn syrup. Not just fast food. That shit is in everything because of corn subsidies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35083914357.0" user="GetCapeFly" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder whether part of this is also portion sizes. Fast food is popular in Europe too but our sizes seem to be much much smaller than those in America. For instance at McDonalds a small drink in the UK is 250ml, a medium is 400ml and large is 500ml whereas in the US a small is 475ml, a medium is 620ml and a large 945ml. Doritos in the UK as a large sharing bag is 180g and the US they’re 276g. 

Healthcare is definitely going to be a huge factor and probably the access to free school meals for children. I know it’s a generalisation but American school meals are seen as unhealthy by the rest of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35084041355.0" user="lefranck56" delta="False">
    <text>As a French, I think your point misses a major difference in the rest of the food we eat compared to the US, and even more in what we drink.  We cook more, we eat less processed food, our food doesn't have high fructose corn syrup, adults rarely drink soda (tap water is by far the most popular drink). Many families never have soda at home.

In my experience, fast food consumption figures are driven up by young people (&amp;lt; 25). They don't become I'll because of their age, and older people eat better food and drink less soda. It's also possible that moderate amounts of red wine have a protective effect on the heart, but I don't know if it's a myth or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35084338771.0" user="steakisgreat" delta="False">
    <text>Fast food isn't the only bad food plaguing America. Go to any grocery store and read the ingredients of basically anything and you'll find 10+ grams of sugar per serving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35084706224.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>Context question...is 4 years difference significant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35084867132.0" user="Loki-Don" delta="False">
    <text>82 versus 78, or 5% longer. 

and it just isn’t the years it’s the quality of life, I.e...the French spend fewer years incapacitated, in old folks homes, needing care etc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
