<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010562255.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>ok so lets just say you value time by outcome, you like to watch a movie, but it was a lousy movie you didn't enjoy.

you have then wasted the time you had, unintentionally but you will never have that time again.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010569316.0" user="Absurd_Simian" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but the follow through to your example is that wasted time is always a matter of personal opinion and can only be judged as such. Person A can never say that person B wasted their own time. Person A can say that if person B is anything like A then they should not watch the movie because it was a waste of A's time.

TL;DR: The only person that can confirm it was time wasted is the owner of said time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010571721.0" user="MorganaLeFaye" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that you didn't waste your time, you just didn't enjoy the time you spent. 

There is no caveat that only time spent actively enjoying yourself 100% of the time, is time not wasted. 

But I guess I should clarify that I am specifically talking about when people say things like "video games are a waste of time" and other value judgments like that. Not necessarily that an individual will never regret spending time doing something. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010583266.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>so more something like one cannot judge the activities of another as valid or invalid </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010585360.0" user="MorganaLeFaye" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. I have edited my OP for clarification. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
