<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010805601.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>I have to say that "A waste of time" is a colloquial explanation of an economic theory of "Opportunity Cost". Playing Video Games, watching TV, or being on Reddit all consume time. Time that could be used doing something else. Playing Video Games, watching TV, and being on Reddit all provide a benefit that is largely subjective. People have a goal to get the most out of life, but that is constrained by such things as physical access, money, and of course time.

When a person says "that is a waste of time" they are saying "I could be doing something better". Better, being subjective, isn't the same for everyone. So to someone who gets more out of watching TV than being on Reddit, spending time on Reddit that could be used watching TV is a waste of time.

There are some activities that are an objective waste of time, in that everyone has a better alternative, but no healthy, sane, and sober person does those things because it would be "spectacularly dumb" to do them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
