<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27011140549.0" user="doodledraft" delta="False">
    <text>First, in the specific category:  
  
It is possible for person A to hold values which result in them considering activity X a waste of their time compared to activity Y.  
  
It is possible for a person B to realize, either through direct observation of person A's deeper values or through recognition that they share values on synonymous subjects, that activity X wastes more time than activity Y according to person A's values.  
  
Finally, it is possible for person A to not have considered or realized that activity X is a waste of time compared to activity Y according to their deeper values, or for person A to otherwise not be acting on those values.  
  
Considering this, it is possible for person B to tell person A that something is a waste of time (also to include it being valid that they should raise the issue for consideration assuming that person A holds said values, even if, after consideration, person B rejects it).
  
Second, in the general:  
  
It is possible for a group of people to share similar values as a matter of memetic geneology and culture.  
  
It is possible to construct valid, specific judgements based on general principles and values, for specific comparisons (in this case, between activities).  
  
Thus it is possible for a person B to form judgements about an activities worth based on the aims of a particular cultural family of values. Note: I'm suggesting that "X is a waste of time" comes with the implicit connotation that "According to your underlying values, I believe with more scrutiny that ultimately you yourself will consider a waste of time."  
  
Anyway, best shot on this one. Not sure I feel it's that great of an argument, but I don't think personally rejecting "X is a waste of time" simply because there may be exceptions is valid either. Unless one's engagement in an activity is exceptional, it would seem the tendency is for such statements to have more truth than error.  
  
Ninja Edit: I would also note that values change over time as well, and the value of an activity can shift as culture shifts, so the fact that those statements are many times made across generations resulting in inapplicable judgements is not a valid reason to say the statements cannot be made.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
