<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010834047.0" user="Ultrateon" delta="False">
    <text>I am just going to approach this from an economics perspective - I feel it's appropriate, so please bear with me.

The concept of "opportunity cost" should be fairly well-known, but the standard definition is: "The next best alternative foregone." In economics, we assume people and firms make the best possible choices from their own individual perspective, but I will drop that idea for this explanation.

I like /u/FaerieStories ' example very much, so I will use it here as well. If you spent 2 hours working on a bibliography, you would not be making the best use of your time, *given your goal in mind*.

We must acknowledge here, that the idea of opportunity cost - and therefore the answer to your question - can be, and is often subjective. For me, the best way to spend a Friday evening in terms of utility gained (or "amount of fun had" for the economically illiterate) might be to see a movie. If I have gone and played video games all night, I have not made the best use of my time - *given that my goal is to maximise utility* (which is what we assume consumers do in economics.).

However, the reason your question cannot be answered is because by changing the goal, you make it possible for millions of answers to exist. For example, what if having fun, in the short term, was indeed the right thing to do for that evening, but in the long term, if I had worked on an essay, I would get a higher mark, and be more successful in the future, and that would have been more "useful" to me, so on, so forth.

Another example yet again linking to FaerieStories' comment: The opportunity cost of writing a bibliography is obviously very high if we consider that it wasn't necessary. However, with a change of perspective (i.e. "what if I need to [learn/consolidate my ability] to compile a bibliography?") - you can make it totally worth your while, and maybe even argue that the opportunity cost is zero.

The main idea that I'm trying to convey here with all this talk of the subjective nature of the opportunity cost, is that your question cannot be answered without setting down a specific goal. And even then there may be differing perspectives on how that goal is best achieved.

So you are right, in fact, that nothing is a waste of time, *given the right perspective*. However, one often needs to be able to find a suitable perspective to look at things from - i.e. "will this be useful to me now? next week? in 2 years? in the next 10 years? will it be of use to my children long after I am dead?"

For most things in life, we cannot afford to have such a "flexible" perspective. I believe you will find that we can often pick out a decent perspective that makes sense with the context.

In economics, we are mainly concerned with the fact that there is a *scarcity* of resources. This is a good parallel for time in our case. You have a scarcity of time. Our aim, as economists, is to allocate our scarce resources as efficiently as possible. In our case, it is to make the best use of our time.

So returning to the aforementioned example, with the given goal of "finishing your essay", which I think is obviously the primary perspective to take in this situation, writing an unnecessary bibliography is indeed a total waste of time. However, with a change of perspective, you could say it isn't. But ask yourself honestly - do you *really* think that perspective is fitting for the situation?

We all need more clarity in our lives. We can't just blur the picture we have in front of us. We need to be able to make clear judgements, with a clear stance in terms of our perspectives, because only then can we come to any conclusions about what the best use of our time is - because don't forget, *time is scarce*. I think now you will find that sometimes, some things can indeed be a total waste of time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
