<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010727100.0" user="A_Merman_Pop" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that the goal of all of humankind is to maximize their enjoyment/happiness. There are only 2 valid ways to spend time in pursuit of this goal.

1. Actively enjoying the present.

2. Investing your time into an activity you don't enjoy in order to acheive a goal that will bring you greater happiness in the future.

Therefore, I feel a person would be fairly justified in calling an activity that does neither of these things a waste of time. For example:

Bob wants to be an astronaut. He constantly tells you how happy he'd be if he were an astronaut and how he'll never be satisfied until he gets there. Bob spends all his time sitting on the floor of his room and staring at the wall. He complains to you every day that staring at his wall is boring and how much he hates it and wishes he were an astronaut. Bob is: (1) spending his time doing an activity he does not enjoy, (2) not making or attempting to make any progress towards the goal that will bring him happiness. If you are not justified in telling Bob he is wasting his time, then the word "waste" has no meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
