<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010728582.0" user="convoces" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One man's trash is another man's treasure.

Your post reminds me of this quote; since you say no one can tell someone else what a waste of time is to them. Here, the key is that "waste" is *relative* to the "waster" or alternatively, "treasure" is relative to the treasurer.

I think it is arguable to say that since an action is relative to the person  performing that action as you are doing. 

However, by similar token, I would say that the *measure* of an action is relative to the goal or outcome the action is intended to produce. In this goal-oriented relationship, we *can* make judgements on what is objectively able to produce the goal/outcome intended. Yes, watching paint dry may be a treasure to *someone* but it will not help me learn how to become a doctor if that is my goal. 

Relative to that goal, I or someone else can *reasonably* tell me that "the action of watching paint dry is a waste of time relative to the goal of becoming a doctor, and relative to the set of things you could be doing to become a doctor."

Even if the goal is "personal entertainment," yes, there may be someone who finds that watching paint dry is endlessly amusing and we cannot deny their feelings, but we can *reasonably* and *meaningfully* say that this activity is unlikely to be enjoyable and thus, "a waste of time." 

If my friend asked me, "convoces, I'm bored and I'm looking for something fun to do, what do you recommend?" I could not justifiably suggest that they watch paint dry, because it is *likely* to be a waste of time in pursuit of the goal of personal leisure/entertainment.

Therein lies the meaning and utility of the phrase of "waste of time."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
