<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010564940.0" user="starving_grad" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not?

When it comes to personal leisure time, nothing. Everyone is entitled to their opinion, but at the end of the day it is solely up to the individual to decide whether or not her free time was spent wisely.

In other words, there is such a thing as a waste of time, but it exists by mere virtue of the time-waster's judgment.

My sole caveat is that it may be wise to, at times, defer to more experienced or collective judgment before deciding how to allocate your time and effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010580352.0" user="MorganaLeFaye" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I just don't feel like your post actually addresses my primary argument (which may be because I didn't phrase it properly... if so, I apologize). 

I am specifically talking about when other people make value judgments on a type of activity, like video games or watching TV (I've heard it said that reading is a waste of time, for crying out loud). 

Let me know if I should edit my OP to be more clear. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
