<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010874308.0" user="thehumbleguy" delta="False">
    <text>You brought a really interesting point. Sometimes it is easier to show what is wrong with the approach if we see the conclusion of applying that approach. If nothing is waste of time, so everyone can do anything and people will loose motivation to better their lives and society. for example if I, who wants to be in a healthcare, starts watching porn all day and thinks it isn't waste of time any more (Lets say you were able to prove that watching porn is not a waste of time) compared to working for community or studying, then watching porn is justified. If we will be brainwashed that nothing is waste of time, we will do reckless things and will have no way to decide between two tasks based on their outcomes as nothing is bad to do. 

In addition I think if we want to give our lives a purpose, we have to choose somethings as worth doing and other ones worthless. If we can't make any distinction, then we will not be able to do it. I think this would be really hard life for someone like me to live with. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
