<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017669859.0" user="vethlock" delta="False">
    <text>You are making a bunch of generalizations. The title of your post is flawed, we couldn't "destroy the universe" even if we wanted to. Im assuming you mean we are going to make earth uninhabitable. You are right that we are having an impact on the environment. You are wrong about there being no change. There are thousands of companies, governments, products, and individuals that are investing a good deal of time and money into fixing various climate and social issues. Relatively speaking we are currently living in on of the most peaceful times in human history. Just because a few extremists blow people up doesnt make every muslim a war mongerer. Just because stalin was an atheist doesnt make every atheist a communist. The reality is that most people on this earth are"good", there just happen to be some baddies with a lot of money and power that create conflict. I'd recommend you take a break from mainstream news whose sole goal is to sensationalize their stories to get more viewers. Do some of your own research on these topics that you are so concerned about.

You also make an assertion that is blatantly false: every religion is intolerant of everyone else (including atheists) and all they bring is hatred and violence. First of all, go look up the religion of jainism. Look up the charity works done by christians, muslims, jews, and atheists. You are essentially claiming that literally every person ever has only been interested in violence and hatred and that the relgious and non relgious alike haven't done anything good in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017716260.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>You are right I made some generalizations, it's a big topic so it's hard not to. But you seem to be generalizing even farther and countering points I didn't make such as "destroying the universe." I do appreciate your effort though.

The expression "a few bad apples doesn't ruin the whole bunch" goes in the opposing direction as well. A few good apples doesn't make the whole rotten bunch much better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
