<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017666633.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>Humanity does indeed change. 

There has been a [consistent decline in violence](http://www.ted.com/talks/steven_pinker_on_the_myth_of_violence.html) throughout history. 

For the first time in history do many people consider discrimination based on ethnicity, religion and sex to be a bad thing. 

We're exposed to a lot of bad news (there's certainly no shortage of it), and as our population and technology has grown, our impact on the rest of the world has grown as well... but overall, people are less likely to die violently today compared to other times in the past, are more likely to care about the environment (beyond a purely self-interested view) and are more likely to care about people from different groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017711122.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>Not that I'm necessarily disagreeing with you, but who are the many people who consider discrimination bad? People give lip service to it but my understanding is it still very prevalent to some degree even in "first world nations." People seem like they need something to cling to say "its us and we are better than them." In America it seems like it's the right vs the left, in the Muslim world it's Shia vs Sunni vs Jewish vs whatever. I can't help but think that sort of ape thinking is built into humans on a fundamental level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27018005087.0" user="gooberoo" delta="False">
    <text>It's true that humanity isn't perfect or even remotely "good," however the argument is that it's not only better than it was say 500 years ago, it's constantly getting better than it was before. You can say that discrimination still exists, because it certainly does. But if you say 'who are the many people who consider discrimination bad?' you could be easily pointed to tons of people. What about you? What about me? There's two people who actively dissuade themselves from discriminating. Now compare this to even five hundred years ago. Was there anybody who didn't discriminate? Was there even a single group who was even slightly more proactive than not caring about skin colour, not to mention not killing or shaming them immediately?

If humanity hasn't destroyed itself yet, I can't see it doing it any time soon. If not a single mind provides some sort of resistance maybe, but I honestly can't see that happening with the way things are currently going.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27018538789.0" user="void_er" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but my understanding is it still very prevalent to some degree even in "first world nations."

Yes and in poorer nations it tends to be worse. 

But on average, every year that passes, we get more educated, the standard of living grows, and we as a result, tend to be better people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
