<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27018061404.0" user="BuckminsterJones" delta="False">
    <text>There are micro-organisms that live miles down in solid rock, multi-cellular complex life-forms. Humanity could go out of its way in a fit of collective destructive rage and attempt to wipe out life on Earth, and those little guys wouldn't even notice. What's more, they have genetic material in their DNA from the surface, laying dormant and unexpressed, just biding its time.


In a few billion years, the sun will become a red giant, and then all life on Earth will be exterminated. But until that time, not even a large meteor strike, or the worst humans might muster, pose a serious existential threat to all life on Earth. But when the sun goes? We all go. Right down to the last extremophile.


So if life hopes to go on after that time, it's going to have to find a way to spread. Intelligent technological life is the answer. One species that will bring all the others with it to other stars. That might be us. Or maybe the next one. We did the hard work of evolving the gene sequences that allow for extremely high intelligence, so it could happen again much more easily in the future. The genetic cat is out of the bag, so to speak. If there were to be a mass extinction event tomorrow? I would expect several if not more creatures to evolve as much intelligence as we have, given a relatively brief amount of time, evolutionarily speaking.


Humans are the key to the survival of life on Earth either way, either directly with spaceships, or through our advancement of the capabilities of the Earth-based genome. 


So, yes. You should worry about us, we might fuck it up, for us. Or we could be the ones that make the Galax stinky with Earth life, not that nasty Alpha Centauri life, But life isn't necessarily smart, what it is is insidious. And it will find a way... we will find a way. (please excuse any cheesiness)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27019867662.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>I can't say you've really changed my mind about humanity, but you've certainly put things in perspective quite well. Humanity's evil is only important to a human from a human point of view. The cellular life living in volcanic vents in the ocean will never care less about us. Neither will Alpha Centauri life (probably, hopefully.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
