<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017681166.0" user="relyiw" delta="False">
    <text>The point you seem to be overlooking is that you are a member of humanity. Furthermore, your view is so common nowadays that it's practically a cliche. Loads of people feel exactly the same way, and wholeheartedly share your desire for a better world. What makes you so sure that you and all of the people who agree with you are incapable of changing things for the better? Why do you believe that you are the only one who cares about the problems we presently face as a species? What makes you so special?

I don't accept the premise that humanity doesn't change. On average, we are happier, healthier, wiser, and more prosperous than we have ever been. Change at the level you're talking about must obviously happen slowly, and mistakes are inevitable, but you can't deny that we are better off now than we were in the dark ages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017693017.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is I know I am a member of that humanity. And it is a cliche, but one that earnestly bothers me.

Most people on the whole want the world to be better, me included. I think almost no one does anything with the though "I am going to do evil and make the world a worse place." It seems to me humans create destruction and intolerance inadvertently.  We have ape brains but the consequences of our technology and influence far outstretch the capabilities of our brains.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017759248.0" user="relyiw" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me that you are essentially troubled by two recurring problems:

1. Not enough people recognize that [insert problem].
2. Among the people who do recognize it, too few are willing to act.

But both of those problems are demonstrably temporary. You insist that humanity never changes, but take a good look at the history of the United States. It was founded on the backs of slaves, and for a long time that state of affairs was considered acceptable by the majority of Americans. Now, just a few centuries later, the country is run by a democratically elected member of the formerly enslaved race. I call that a result.

We change slowly, but we do change. It takes us a while to work up the courage to act, but eventually we always do act. The fact that you recognize the problems you are complaining about proves that human beings in general are capable of recognizing them. Instead of bemoaning the fact that too few of them do, you should look to yourself for evidence of the fact that they *can*, and work to convince them that they should.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
