<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017839696.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>How can you possibly argue that humanity hasn't changed? Violence is at the lowest level ever, our understanding of the consequences of our actions is at the highest. We are clearly learning, but we are not learning the lessons that you want us to learn, mostly because the lessons you want aren't the lessons taught by experience.

Your commentary about religion means that everyone has to be about hate and intolerance, because you defined it in such a way that every human being on the planet falls under one of those labels. Wouldn't it be way more accurate to say that someone people hate and are intolerant and that the justification they use is irrelevant?

And yet US CO2 emissions are lower now than they were in 1964, there has never been more proven (accessible) oil reserves, we're developing the ability to capture asteroids for more resources, desalination techniques are available but are currently too expensive as water becomes scarcer relative to demand you'll see all these new systems suddenly spring up out of nowhere as they become profitable.

Answers for all the problems are available or are being developed. We just don't do expensive and hard things on a whim, we do them when we are sure we need them. Humanity doesn't reorder itself to your preference or mine, but it does, has, and will accomplish the tasks that need doing assuming that we see it coming.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
