<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1146362973.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iyijbx/cmv_aaron_burr_gets_a_bad_rap/">
    <title>CMV: Aaron Burr gets a bad rap</title>
    <original_poster>HotSauce2910</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like a lot of people have a really negative view of Burr, in large part because of Hamilton (which I do love btw : /). I think I mean this specifically that his reputation/legacy is negative relative to Hamilton's, at least from a progressive point of view.   


* He tried to abolish slavery in the 1780s as a NY Assemblyman and worked with the Manumission Society. He was admittedly hypocritical here, being a slaveowner himself (so fuck that). But Hamilton's relationship with slavery was also [pretty complicated](https://www.womenshealthmag.com/life/a33023827/was-hamilton-a-slave-owner/). Despite that, I think there is a perception out there that was clearly anti-slavery while Burr was clearly pro-slavery. 
* Burr was a feminist. He was a big fan of Mary Wollstonecraft, believe that women were intellectually equal to men (which was rather radical at the time), and wanted equal education opportunities. Apparently Hamilton attacked Burr over this opinion. 
   * Wikipedia also says he submitted a proposal to give women the right to vote, but w/ no citation and I couldn't find a source that confirms it. 
* He started the first bank that extended credit to small businessmen instead of just the aristocracy. His methods/motives were dubious, but the result were meaningful. Hamilton, as I understand it, was rather elitist and wanted a strong aristocracy.
* Burr supported the rights of naturalized citizens and opposed a constitutional amendment (that the Fedarlist party was pushing) to bar naturalized foreigners from holding office. 
* He was accused of ["'revolutionizing the state,' because in the state legislature he backed progressive policies for funding internal improvements such as roads and bridges, debtor relief, and establishing a more democratic method of electing state senators."](https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/03/30/liberals-love-alexander-hamilton-but-aaron-burr-was-a-real-progressive-hero/)     


I am curious about if I'm just missing something, if I just drank some counterculture kool aid, or if there's something actually here.   


Also, I noticed after typing out the title that it almost counts a pun... was not intended...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35213059255.0" user="Gushinggr4nni3s" delta="False">
    <text>Burr isn’t just known for killing Hamilton. Killing Hamilton killed his career. The Burr conspiracy killed his reputation. Basically, after killing Hamilton and splitting from the Democratic republicans due to disagree with Jefferson, Burr moved to the frontier. He tried to establish an independent country in the then southwest part of the country (Louisiana, Arkansas, parts of Mississippi) and Texas(then part of Spanish Mexico). In the act, he would be declaring war on the US. Burr claims that he was trying to “farm” land in Mexico. He was arrested and tried. Although he was found not guilty due to the odd wording of the treason clause. He should’ve been convicted, but the constitution didn’t have conspiracy to commit treason as a crime (ex parts Bollman case). After this though, his image was shattered. He was forced into exile in Europe after multiple states threatened on press charges through their state courts. Effigies of his likeness were burned by mobs. Burr tried to gain support for a revolution from England and France during his exile, but he was forced out of both countries. He later returned to the US, got married, and died the day his divorce was granted because his wife left him due to poor finances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213064988.0" user="HotSauce2910" delta="False">
    <text>Historically, this is all true. I'm talking about his recent reputation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213093308.0" user="Gushinggr4nni3s" delta="False">
    <text>His recent reputation is a carry over of his historical one. Most people base opinions on burr based on the musical Hamilton, which is based on historical accounts of Burr’s personality and actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213117892.0" user="HotSauce2910" delta="False">
    <text>But the historical examples you listed weren't mentioned (if at all, it was like one throwaway line in a piece) in the musical.  


The musical mainly criticizes him for not having any values that he stood by as opposed to Hamilton, which seems wrong to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213530472.0" user="Thwackey" delta="False">
    <text>If all that the majority of people know is Burr's representation in Hamilton, then can you say he got a bad rap? The dude committed treason and tried to become emperor of Mexico, and he owned slaves, but none of that is shown in Hamilton. The show paints him as desiring power for power's sake, yes, but it also paints him as very sympathetic after killing Hamilton which the papers at the time absolutely did not. Hamilton is much better for Burr's reputation than the history books are, even if it isn't entirely accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35267549231.0" user="november13" delta="False">
    <text>There is no actual proof of this.  Burr gathered men for what was then called a filibuster.  Basically, it was a common practice for men to head to western territories and try to use military might to take over certain territories owned by foreign governments or Native Americans.  It was all part of the belief in manifest destiny.  Burr had no intention of trying to over throw the U.S. government.  He intended to try to take Texas from the Spanish.  All charges of treason came from a general named Wilkinson, who actually was a spy for the Spanish government (although this would not be known until after Wilkinson’s death).  The main evidence against Burr was a cipher letter which supposedly mapped out Burr’s plans to take over the U.S. government.  Wilkinson admitted at trial that he changed the wording in parts of the letter.  Also, the letter wasn’t even written by Burr though Wilkinson claimed it was.  Lastly, Burr was tried for treason in three different jurisdictions and found not guilty in all three trials.  All three juries found no evidence of “overt acts of treason.”  Burr did not get off on a technicality.  There was simply no evidence of treasonous behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
