<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1146362973.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iyijbx/cmv_aaron_burr_gets_a_bad_rap/">
    <title>CMV: Aaron Burr gets a bad rap</title>
    <original_poster>HotSauce2910</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like a lot of people have a really negative view of Burr, in large part because of Hamilton (which I do love btw : /). I think I mean this specifically that his reputation/legacy is negative relative to Hamilton's, at least from a progressive point of view.   


* He tried to abolish slavery in the 1780s as a NY Assemblyman and worked with the Manumission Society. He was admittedly hypocritical here, being a slaveowner himself (so fuck that). But Hamilton's relationship with slavery was also [pretty complicated](https://www.womenshealthmag.com/life/a33023827/was-hamilton-a-slave-owner/). Despite that, I think there is a perception out there that was clearly anti-slavery while Burr was clearly pro-slavery. 
* Burr was a feminist. He was a big fan of Mary Wollstonecraft, believe that women were intellectually equal to men (which was rather radical at the time), and wanted equal education opportunities. Apparently Hamilton attacked Burr over this opinion. 
   * Wikipedia also says he submitted a proposal to give women the right to vote, but w/ no citation and I couldn't find a source that confirms it. 
* He started the first bank that extended credit to small businessmen instead of just the aristocracy. His methods/motives were dubious, but the result were meaningful. Hamilton, as I understand it, was rather elitist and wanted a strong aristocracy.
* Burr supported the rights of naturalized citizens and opposed a constitutional amendment (that the Fedarlist party was pushing) to bar naturalized foreigners from holding office. 
* He was accused of ["'revolutionizing the state,' because in the state legislature he backed progressive policies for funding internal improvements such as roads and bridges, debtor relief, and establishing a more democratic method of electing state senators."](https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/03/30/liberals-love-alexander-hamilton-but-aaron-burr-was-a-real-progressive-hero/)     


I am curious about if I'm just missing something, if I just drank some counterculture kool aid, or if there's something actually here.   


Also, I noticed after typing out the title that it almost counts a pun... was not intended...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35213092854.0" user="Anazeteo" delta="False">
    <text>You may be right that Hamilton (the musical) has shone a negative light on Aaron Burr in the eyes of the general public, but the historical image of Aaron Burr has been primarily negative in the eyes of many historians and most history buffs. 

I’m not going to try to refute or support the arguments of what he did or didn’t do with his career; the crux of this discussion hinges on the fact that far too many only know of Aaron Burr from a footnote in their 5th grade U.S. History class and then years later watching Hamilton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213129430.0" user="HotSauce2910" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the historical image of Aaron Burr has been primarily negative in the eyes of many historians and most history buffs.

His image historically was pretty negative, but was it negative to historians? From what I understand, historians are pretty split on Burr.   


&amp;gt; far too many only know of Aaron Burr from a footnote in their 5th grade U.S. History class 

I don't even know if he got that in my U.S. history...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35214414329.0" user="Anazeteo" delta="False">
    <text>“His image historically was pretty negative, but was it negative to historians? From what I understand, historians are pretty split on Burr.”

Correct. That is why I made the distinction between “many historians” and “most history buffs.”
Experts are familiar with the more nuanced and complex life and impact of Burr, but history buffs are more likely to have a cursory knowledge as his life is always overshadowed by Hamilton’s. 
As a history buff, myself, I know all too well the limits of knowledge, and even the history I love, the events and the people I’ve studied are much more complex than the surface level knowledge I have. 
I expect I have many pieces of historical trivia that is distorted by time, rumor, and myth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35214157723.0" user="ritr135" delta="False">
    <text>While we're on the subject, some people mostly know Aaron Burr as being the punchline of the legendary first Got Milk ad, directed by Michael Bay!

But yeah, his character in Hamilton-the-musical is very much based on the reputation he had among historians already: a mixed bag and very human person with strengths and flaws who gradually alienated his powerful friends through life and became a historical trivia question.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
