<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1146362973.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iyijbx/cmv_aaron_burr_gets_a_bad_rap/">
    <title>CMV: Aaron Burr gets a bad rap</title>
    <original_poster>HotSauce2910</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like a lot of people have a really negative view of Burr, in large part because of Hamilton (which I do love btw : /). I think I mean this specifically that his reputation/legacy is negative relative to Hamilton's, at least from a progressive point of view.   


* He tried to abolish slavery in the 1780s as a NY Assemblyman and worked with the Manumission Society. He was admittedly hypocritical here, being a slaveowner himself (so fuck that). But Hamilton's relationship with slavery was also [pretty complicated](https://www.womenshealthmag.com/life/a33023827/was-hamilton-a-slave-owner/). Despite that, I think there is a perception out there that was clearly anti-slavery while Burr was clearly pro-slavery. 
* Burr was a feminist. He was a big fan of Mary Wollstonecraft, believe that women were intellectually equal to men (which was rather radical at the time), and wanted equal education opportunities. Apparently Hamilton attacked Burr over this opinion. 
   * Wikipedia also says he submitted a proposal to give women the right to vote, but w/ no citation and I couldn't find a source that confirms it. 
* He started the first bank that extended credit to small businessmen instead of just the aristocracy. His methods/motives were dubious, but the result were meaningful. Hamilton, as I understand it, was rather elitist and wanted a strong aristocracy.
* Burr supported the rights of naturalized citizens and opposed a constitutional amendment (that the Fedarlist party was pushing) to bar naturalized foreigners from holding office. 
* He was accused of ["'revolutionizing the state,' because in the state legislature he backed progressive policies for funding internal improvements such as roads and bridges, debtor relief, and establishing a more democratic method of electing state senators."](https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/03/30/liberals-love-alexander-hamilton-but-aaron-burr-was-a-real-progressive-hero/)     


I am curious about if I'm just missing something, if I just drank some counterculture kool aid, or if there's something actually here.   


Also, I noticed after typing out the title that it almost counts a pun... was not intended...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35213102940.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/HotSauce2910 (OP) has awarded 1 delta(s) in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [here](/r/DeltaLog/comments/iyjr08/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_aaron_burr_gets_a_bad_rap/), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view doesn't necessarily mean a reversal, or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
