<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="115882088.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1wzr6w/i_dont_think_factory_farming_is_anywhere_near_as/">
    <title>I dont think factory farming is anywhere near as sadistic as it is claimed to be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jo9008</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ok let me first say that, yes, the conditions of chickens in battery cages is horrendous and I try to only by free range of cage free.

Moving on, I grew up in a rural area and have seen many chicken houses, dairy farms and cattle ranches. It hurts me to hear people demonize farmer based on information that is clearly biased, extremely exaggerated or down right falsified. 

At all these places the animals seem perfectly content. They all had plenty of room to move around, were kept in optimized climate conditions, had unlimited supply of water and food that is formulated to have all the vitamins and minerals they need and they get regular attention from veterinarians who look for any aberration from perfect health. Stress is very bad for the quality of meat produced so farmers/ranchers have a big incentive to keep these animals as happy and comfortable as possible.

With these ideal conditions they have shown to have lower rates of disease, mortality and pathogens that end up in your meat than free range. A lot of that is because they’re not walking around in their own waste. Disease is also more easily transmitted back and forth with outside critters in free range. 

Antibiotic are a big issue but it's not as straight forward as it's made out to be. The FDA highly regulates the levels that go into animals and animals are regularly tested by vets to make sure they are where they need to be. These animals are not like humans. They can’t tell you they are sick. It may be days before they start showing signs and by then they could have passed it on to the entire flock/herd. It is primarily a preventative measure. Antibiotics used for growth are being phased out. No steroids or hormones are ever given to chickens or pigs. The ones given to cattle have shown not to affect the human physiology or to be in such low levels that it is negligible. (estrogen {ng/500g} in tofu 113,500,000 while in beef 7)

Lastly, for pigs, gestation cages are for their own good. Like many animals, pigs establish a hierarchical social order when mixed together. When sows are in groups, dominant sows tend to act aggressively and can even harm their own babies. They are only kept in these cages for a fraction of their lives until they can be re-integrated.

I realized I made a lot of claims there. I'd be happy to provide citations for any of those as requested.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27040192494.0" user="TacoBellvue" delta="False">
    <text>So basically you want people to argue with your anecdotal observations?  

What your sources for statements like this: 

With these ideal conditions they have shown to have lower rates of disease, mortality and pathogens that end up in your meat than free range. 

I mean, if you have sources for all of this info, share them.  Why are you making people ask if you have them readily available?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040231428.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Laziness mostly. It would have taken me a while to compile everything. http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2010/05/is-free-range-meat-making-us-sick/56333/
http://www.asi.k-state.edu/species/poultry/research-and-extension/heritage-poultry-small-farm/disease-control.html
http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/01/090114200003.htm</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
