<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="115882088.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1wzr6w/i_dont_think_factory_farming_is_anywhere_near_as/">
    <title>I dont think factory farming is anywhere near as sadistic as it is claimed to be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jo9008</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ok let me first say that, yes, the conditions of chickens in battery cages is horrendous and I try to only by free range of cage free.

Moving on, I grew up in a rural area and have seen many chicken houses, dairy farms and cattle ranches. It hurts me to hear people demonize farmer based on information that is clearly biased, extremely exaggerated or down right falsified. 

At all these places the animals seem perfectly content. They all had plenty of room to move around, were kept in optimized climate conditions, had unlimited supply of water and food that is formulated to have all the vitamins and minerals they need and they get regular attention from veterinarians who look for any aberration from perfect health. Stress is very bad for the quality of meat produced so farmers/ranchers have a big incentive to keep these animals as happy and comfortable as possible.

With these ideal conditions they have shown to have lower rates of disease, mortality and pathogens that end up in your meat than free range. A lot of that is because they’re not walking around in their own waste. Disease is also more easily transmitted back and forth with outside critters in free range. 

Antibiotic are a big issue but it's not as straight forward as it's made out to be. The FDA highly regulates the levels that go into animals and animals are regularly tested by vets to make sure they are where they need to be. These animals are not like humans. They can’t tell you they are sick. It may be days before they start showing signs and by then they could have passed it on to the entire flock/herd. It is primarily a preventative measure. Antibiotics used for growth are being phased out. No steroids or hormones are ever given to chickens or pigs. The ones given to cattle have shown not to affect the human physiology or to be in such low levels that it is negligible. (estrogen {ng/500g} in tofu 113,500,000 while in beef 7)

Lastly, for pigs, gestation cages are for their own good. Like many animals, pigs establish a hierarchical social order when mixed together. When sows are in groups, dominant sows tend to act aggressively and can even harm their own babies. They are only kept in these cages for a fraction of their lives until they can be re-integrated.

I realized I made a lot of claims there. I'd be happy to provide citations for any of those as requested.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27039907041.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Moving on, I grew up in a rural area and have seen many chicken houses, dairy farms and cattle ranches. It hurts me to hear people demonize farmer based on information that is clearly biased, extremely exaggerated or down right falsified. 

So your experience has been with small to mid scale farm operations, and not corporatized farms?  Am I interpreting what you said correctly?  Because if that is the case we've highlighted your problem.

The majority of the outrage is for the mass corporate farming, not your typical farm.  The problem occurs though that we don't have enough small farmers to supply our nation with the food we enjoy consuming, and thus turn a blind eye to most of the problems that come with large scale agri-farming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27039936197.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain to me the differences in practices between a mid size and large scale operation. It seems to me the logistics would be very similar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27039955218.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a farmer myself, but I would imagine something like [This](http://advocacy.britannica.com/blog/advocacy/wp-content/uploads/chickens-11.jpg) and [This](http://www.upc-online.org/freerange/black_eagle_farm2.jpg)
as opposed to [This](http://thumbs.dreamstime.com/z/rural-poultry-farm-young-white-chicks-bred-chicken-meat-small-scale-industry-situated-south-indian-34710803.jpg)

I'm actually pretty neutral toward the entire process myself, but in essence, the corporate farms have been charged with animal cruelty and bad business practices that can cause health risks (IE [Antibiotics used in Animal feed and its impact on human health](http://journals.cambridge.org/download.php?file=%2FNRR%2FNRR13_02%2FS0954422400000767a.pdf&amp;amp;code=a0c0bff3c4f3f932e332fec41a70bb64)).  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040006790.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>The first two are the battery cages used for egg laying that I said in the first line I was not ok with. There is a lot of debate going on right now as to whether antibiotics are best for everyone or not. I described some of the reasons in the post. It's also important to know that most of the antibotics used are not compatible with humans so the potential "super bugs" arent adapting to the antibiotics we normally us. Furthermore, it is very rare for viruses to be able to jump from bird/pig/cow to human. Also your link last link didnt work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040121166.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>Raw last link:
http://journals.cambridge.org/download.php?file=%2FNRR%2FNRR13_02%2FS0954422400000767a.pdf&amp;amp;code=ab708fb95748bbe23f42f347c677729f
It's a direct link to the PDF.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040143497.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Conclusion:

Antibiotic-resistant human pathogens are a major challenge in human medicine (Collignon,
1997; Turnidge, 1998; Williams &amp;amp; Heymann, 1998; Guillemot, 1999). There is some risk that
excessive attention to transfer of antibiotic-resistant bacteria or genes from animals to man will
divert attention from the need to address problems inherent in the medical use of antibiotics.
Antibiotic-resistance problems in human medicine include those of MRSA, VRE, multiresistant
Mycobacterium tuberculosis, penicillin-resistant pneumococci, multiresistant Gram-negative
organisms and extended-spectrum b-lactamase-producing Gram-negative bacteria (Gold &amp;amp;
Moellering, 1996; Collignon, 1997). For most of these organisms there is no connection with
antibiotic use in animals, but there are exceptions


In other words it's not really putting humans at risk outside of a few minor exceptions. If you read on, these exceptions are typically treated with growth promoter antibodies that are being phased out and the other one typically is not treated with antibodies when found in humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040270697.0" user="eblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In other words it's not really putting humans at risk outside of a few minor exceptions. 

No, they're saying that the incidents of antibiotic resistance which result from factory farming are "exceptions" because most antibiotic resistance problems stem from human use.

All uses of antibiotics carry risks -- this is the rule, not the exception.  Most antibiotics are used on humans, so most risks arise in a human medical setting.  But factory farms are also pumping antibiotics into animals, creating another vector for resistant organisms to develop.  We've already seen some of these resistant organisms cross over and infect humans. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
