<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393882861.0" user="Det_" delta="False">
    <text>Slippery slope:

If you don't put a high value on individual human lives, what argument do you have for not removing, say, 100,000 human lives that are in your way, if you have some noble goal?

What's the difference in value between **1**/7,000,000,000 and **100,000**/7,000,000,000? Is it significant enough to convince a powerful leader not to lead a population to commit genocide, for example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393963687.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>Those 100,000 (and also the 1!), if they are a human being, are irreplacable.


If those 100,000 are embryos in a stem-cell facility, are only worth something to the people doing the testing; I have no problem convincing someone not to run back in to save them if the facility is on fire, as they have essentially no worth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393975863.0" user="Det_" delta="False">
    <text>Where's the cutoff between when they have no worth (embryos) and when they have worth?

At birth? After they can walk on their own? After they can feed themselves? When they can vote?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394092101.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>Always the hardest argument to decide, definitely. I'm not really prepared (or possibly educated enough on all of the details!) to make such a judgement, and I can see where the issue comes up from that viewpoint, but there's still a significant difference between a developed human with a consciousness, and an embryo that someone has decided they don't want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394111577.0" user="Det_" delta="False">
    <text>Much like someone else's artwork, or someone else's car, perhaps your definition of the value of human life does not reflect the things others believe?

For example, if someone is creating and caring for 100,000 embryos, as you said, they likely believe the value of the embryos is much higher than you do.

You're using basic supply and demand to determine value; they're using "high expectations of future existence" to determine value.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
