<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393854554.0" user="notsuspendedlxqt" delta="False">
    <text>I am not an economist, but I always though that the Laws of Supply and Demand were economic principles, not moral or ethical principles? I don't think you are supposed to use supply and demand curves to make moral judgments. Supply and demands aren't even "laws", they are simply models used to determine the monetary price of a good. Even in economics, there's no definition for objective value. 

It's an entirely different topic altogether. Like saying "You should be allowed to tackle people in golf, because you are allowed to tackle people in American football".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393874136.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm using an economic model to show that something has little-to-no innate value. If you choose to rid yourself of something with little-to-no innate value, how can you be committing a morally reprehensible act?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393912823.0" user="MyGubbins" delta="False">
    <text>You are conflating two different usages of the word value. Theres economic value, and then theres a type of moral value. They are two completely different things that share the same word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35397673697.0" user="Responsible_Virus" delta="False">
    <text>while I largely agree with you I feel some utilitarians would disagree with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393927161.0" user="notsuspendedlxqt" delta="False">
    <text>I do not believe abortion to be a morally reprehensible act, but for a different reason: outlawing abortion is a violation of bodily autonomy. The problem with your view is that supply and demand does not determine innate value, it determines market price, which is another thing. The definition of "value" has a different meaning in a capitalist marketplace than in an ethical framework.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394507246.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394690197.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35395157383.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>u/MyGubbins – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+MyGubbins&amp;amp;message=MyGubbins+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/-/g9d31qt/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35395159780.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>u/4chanman99 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+4chanman99&amp;amp;message=4chanman99+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/-/g9cz4ku/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
