<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393880532.0" user="Zirathustra" delta="False">
    <text>This is incoherent:

&amp;gt;**the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**

The demand side of supply and demand is also a matter of mere subjective worth. All demand originates from human needs and desires, it is not an intrinsic property of a good or service in a vacuum, they only have value within the context of a human society. Supply and demand has nothing whatsoever to do with "innate worth." The rest of your post hinges on this starting assumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393950792.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, I'll approach it from the other direction: The Laws of Supply and Demand show that Human Life has a worth approaching zero, due to far too much supply, and not enough demand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394092579.0" user="Zirathustra" delta="False">
    <text>How is that another direction? You're still assuming that supply and demand tells you something about "worth", it doesn't, it only tell you what something will buy or sell for in a market. These aren't the same thing. An innate worth would remain constant and not be influenced by external factors, that's what "innate" *means,* originating from within a thing and being essential to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394126210.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>That's why I didn't include "innate" in the statement. And existence is a market all its own; transactions between people in terms of emotional attachment, favors, gifts, etc. A very subjective market, but it still exists. In this market of existence, I propose that human life (before the development of a consciousness) approaches a value of zero currently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394744228.0" user="Zirathustra" delta="False">
    <text>Well in that case, just look at the market then: [https://www.iadb.org/en/news/human-traffickings-dirty-profits-and-huge-costs](https://www.iadb.org/en/news/human-traffickings-dirty-profits-and-huge-costs)

Answer: A human life is worth between $4,000 and $50,000, depending on the make, model, and year.

As for the "before the development of consciousness", that's where the rub lies i think and your argument just reduces to how you define a human being in the first place, so you're begging the question by assuming a pre-conscious homo sapiens embryo  is a "human being" to begin with. Even then, people pay money for surrogate parents, surrogate embryos, sperm and eggs even, and there's a market for that as well, but again it all varies by make, model and year. It seems that to say "human beings have no value" because the average zygote isn't being bought and sold is like saying "cars have no value" because people rarely buy unassembled cars.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
