<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393915240.0" user="AleristheSeeker" delta="False">
    <text>I have several problems with this:

* 1) The "Law" of Supply and Demand is not a law at all.

It is a construct that (even only roughly, really) fits the economy we have created around it. There is nothing enacting it, calling it a "model" would be much more suitable.

* 2) "Money" also only holds subjective worth, as do most luxury goods.

If you insist on using economic theory for humans, you should consider that many luxury goods are vanity items that hold no value beyond what people are willing to pay for it. Luxury items are not necessary for survival, do not make life easier, etc.

* 3) While "production" of human life is easy, production of *one specific kind* of human life is very difficult.

Your argument is akin to saying "I can just scoop up silicon sands in the desert, why are microchips so damn expensive?!?" - you don't just want silicon, you want it in a specific configuration, with certain addons, etc.

* 4) There *is* a demand for that is often far higher than the production - because people want *their* children.

Again, your argument is akin to saying "There is no demand for watches! You can just stick a stick in the ground and read the time!" - yes, but that is not the type people want. They want one specific thing, which they can only get through very specific means.

* 5) Producing a child creates costs and even "any" child can have value.

This is perhaps the most morbid of thoughts, but embryos - even if we did treat them as a ware - actually have a monetary value attached to them precisely because production is limited. Stem Cell research, for example, does sometimes require embryonic stem cells - or at least, research could be accelerated with them.

* 6) The jump from "Human Life has no value for economic reasons" to "There is no morality involved" is a ridiculous one.

Morality and Economics have a difficult relationship, but Economy does not generally dictate Morality. That is the assumption you'd have to make to take that jump, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394046866.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>I have several problems with this:

&amp;gt; * 1) The "Law" of Supply and Demand is not a law at all.

Yes, and the Law of Gravity is only a theory, but as long as it continues to make mathematical sense, we adhere to it.


&amp;gt; * 2) "Money" also only holds subjective worth, as do most luxury goods.

Children hold no value to some people who want an abortion, so me theory seems to stand here.


&amp;gt; * 3) While "production" of human life is easy, production of *one specific kind* of human life is very difficult.

This is exactly why I defined a difference between "life" and "a person." The person is a microchip, with years of work and details built into it, and therefore has worth (people as a developed being are basically irreplaceable). An embryo is a grain of sand. Obviously the comparison isn't exact, but someone could have a very personal expectation for that grain of sand, and want to turn it into a detailed, incredible microchip. Others could just see a grain of sand, which they dislike, as it's irritating and gets everywhere.



Overall, if you remove the morality attachment, I guess I'd like to focus on how people decide that any given embryo innately has value and should be saved. That does not seem to be the case, which is where my premise is drawn from.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
