<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393865368.0" user="littlebubulle" delta="False">
    <text>In your scenario, the humans are both the product and the customer. Humans have value for other humans. 

This means that if the number of humans increase, both offer and demand increases. Inversely, if the number of humans decrease, both offer and demand decrease.

Value is also never innate. All values are subjective. And values differ from person to person. Some people find human life worth committing atrocities against all other species. Some wish for the human race to die.

Also, I feel this is a abortion debate with the law of supply and demand shoehorned in. Laws of supply and demand have little to do with how much humans value other humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393927096.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>I don't feel like you're separating "life" from "being" enough. Very few people seem to be as up in arms about embryo farms, stem cell research, or the fact that many forms of birth control **kill** an embryo by preventing it from attaching to the uterine wall. So if the life itself isn't worth enough for people to fight for it, why is an abortion any different?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
