<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35397669067.0" user="Responsible_Virus" delta="False">
    <text>The laws of supply and demand effect price that is they are about quantities exchanged typically cash for some other resource. It's probably not Good to measure the worth of human life on a exchange. you can do it but it's probably not good. here are some reasons 

1. it's probably not your life we're talking about here you want to sell your own life? well maybe that's fine but the prolife debate is mostly about weather it's alive or not when they do the procedure
2. Markets don't always get it right sorry I don't believe in efficient markets I've seen the theory yes logically it's sound. the assumptions are wrong which is obvious but I'd say they aren't even particularly useful except in very limited circumstances just my opinion.
3. Markets only ever have relative values and are subject to change I'll claim it can't ever measure a inherent value if such a thing exists.
4. Markets don't even value what people "value" they measure both what people value *and* their resources ie how much they can pay. I might love pizza more than anyone ever but if I'm broke how much I value pizza means nothing to the market. using the laws of supply and demand for ethics implicitly hands moral authority over to the wealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
