<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35393866820.0" user="Rainbwned" delta="False">
    <text>Humans have a shelf life, and an even smaller time window in order to create more humans. So far, the only way that we know how to make more humans, is by humans procreating. If no new humans are made, than the human race goes extinct.

So humans would be considered incredibly valuable, as they are the only possibly method of creating more humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393935377.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>Test Tube babies already exist; 100 years ago, I might have agreed, but with climate shift, pollution, and technology as it currently exists, I'd say we could stand to pull back on the procreation for a bit, yeah?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35393957393.0" user="Rainbwned" delta="False">
    <text>Population is not our issue though.

Test Tube Babies still only work when humans are involved. 

Any negative impact to the planet has zero bearing on value when you are talking about supply and demand.  Humans are a finite supply, and there is at least some demand to continue the human race, so there is at the very least a small amount of value in each person.

Your point of view only applies if you are arguing from the perspective of Gaia.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
