<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536506100.0" user="Morasain" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you are thinking of the same kind of hate as people who say these things. Being critical of yourself and working on your flaws isn't hate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536623377.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>I am talking about such a deep despise towards yourself that will make you think of suicide everyday, and you will struggle just to stay sane. What I am trying to say is that hate you want to fix/push down/remove, is not what the problem is. It's all those struggles to fix/push down/remove that is causing the suffering, and once you face and accept the hate for yourself you will see that it is not so bad, and there is nothing to be afraid of it. You don't even have to remove it, only listen to it with curiosity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536722073.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, no.  

It is not healthy to deeply despise yourself or think of suicide every day. Most people do not feel that.  

You shouldn't just go into denial about it, but addressing why you feel that way will help you feel better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
