<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119375664.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z2muo/i_want_to_take_forgetting_pills_to_erase_every/">
    <title>I want to take "forgetting pills" to erase every bad memory I still can't get used to. (Some of which gave me ideations of suicide / self-harm.) CMV</title>
    <original_poster>EgaoNoGenki-XX</original_poster>
    <original_post>[I don't know HOW SOON these forgetting pills will arrive, but when they do, they won't be a moment too soon!](http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/02/ff_forgettingpill/all/)

I'd bet heavily that these memory-erasing pills will cause suicide rates to NOSEDIVE. Happiness indices in countries with ready access to these forgetting pills may soar.

Still, I'll observe results seen in other people before I start on them myself.

I have reason to believe that when I forget all the unsolvable bad events in my life, and any bad memory that still hurts me to this day, I'll feel a heavenly bliss not felt since the happiest day of my childhood.

(If there's ANY OTHER way to feel total bliss again, then **PLEASE SHARE IT!!!**)

Some memories I've gotten used to and won't feel hurt by them anymore, but others are so hard to get over, that I look upon these forgetting pills as a kind of "last hope."

I've been told that "memories form who we are." There are many reasons why I don't like the way I (currently) am so that lends me reason to believe that I'll be a better person once certain memories are erased.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27072019879.0" user="captainlavender" delta="False">
    <text>I swear I'm going to actually respond to this soon, but I just had to say, you and the person in the next post who doesn't want to cure their depression need to have a chat.

edit: okay, actual response

You say you'd be happy to change yourself by giving up memories, but I imagine you're assuming you'll maintain your current beliefs and values. This may not be true -- one experience can change a person's whole position on some issue. It's possible you'd erase some memories and come out the other side somebody who doesn't believe memories should be erased. Or someone who never made friends with that poor kid in school and consequently has none of your developed empathy for poor people. Or even just someone who never had that one perfect apple and so hates apples instead of loving them, like you do now. How much of your identity are you willing to give up? 

If I could erase my memories of working under my abusive boss, it wouldn't be very tempting for me, because I doubt it would cure my PTSD. But if it could... well that's a more interesting question. But as shitty as that experience was, and as bitter and mistrustful as I am now, I'm also stronger. I also did things I never thought I could, and learned an independence I had never before found in myself. There were also many positive aspects of the experience itself (in that I was working with a disadvantaged population and interacting with them was both rewarding and illuminating). I would lose all of that knowledge, all of that hard-earned self-reliance, all of that fierce conviction that I was never quite able to muster up before. Would I erase all of that? Honestly I don't know. But I suspect I would not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072049105.0" user="EgaoNoGenki-XX" delta="False">
    <text>Those are **very** interesting theories about what could happen after I erase select memories!

That is why I'll observe the test results from the first trial group (or first few trial groups) of test subjects undergoing selective amnesia therapies, then decide more informedly, whether selective amnesia is worth it for my circumstances.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
