<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536337633.0" user="Frenetic_Platypus" delta="False">
    <text>I mostly agree with you and I always thought it's weird when people say "be satisfied with how you are! You're perfect! Don't change!" And all that bullshit because it's true that people should strive to improve and correct their flaws rather than just accept that it is what it is.

However, I feel like hating oneself is not quite the sweet spot either. There should be a middle ground between being blissfully happy with who I am and hitting my head against the wall to punish myself.

Also, it's not really productive to direct that hatred towards oneself as a whole rather than specific flaws. "I hate myself" is far less likely to make you a better person tomorrow than "I hate how I always procrastinate."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536483475.0" user="OnionToothpaste" delta="False">
    <text>Completely agree. Hating yourself and thinking you're perfect are two sides of the same coin. Whether you think of yourself positively or negatively, in both cases you'll refuse to attempt to improve. Either you'll think it's pointless, because you're perfect already, or you'll think it's hopeless, because there's no way someone as pathetic as you could ever change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536561834.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly my thought. You can have one AND the other. Self love is not the absence of self hate. They both have their purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35537584006.0" user="OnionToothpaste" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I completely misunderstood your post then. To me self love and self hate are mutually exclusive. What you're talking about, I'd probably call something like self confidence and self criticism. I'd say that you need something in between self love and hate, rather than both at the same time, but I guess that's just semantics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536559524.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, it is not the sweet spot in any way. Hating yourself and loving yourself are just reflections of how you see yourself. They are the 2 sides of the same coin if I can put it like that. Most of what a lot of people me included are doing, is trying to do things to stop hating ourselves. If you hate yourself for a past failure, going to the gym will not help you to not feel hate for that failure. But if you accept that you hate yourself for why you failed, you can move on, learn from that failure, and stop wasting energy to stop hating yourself, you will not die and nothing bad will happen when you admit you hate yourself. And all that energy that you are not wasting now, will be free to spend on something that is good for you, like going to the gym.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
