<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35538519520.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you can hate yourself a little bit.  If you hate yourself a little bit, then you are really just being self critical.

I don't like that i spend so much time on my phone, especially when my kids want me attention.  But i don't hate myself.  YOu might say i hate one behavior.  I want to change it, I want to improve, grow, and become a better dad.  This is self love.  I'm critical of myself because i want to improve.  I want to improve because i love myself.  When I put my daughter on timeout because she hit her sister, that is not out of hate.  Its out of love.  When i'm upset with my own behavior that too is love.

Self love doesn't mean never criticising yourself.  And self hate doesn't mean criticising yourself so that you can grow an improve.

Some people definitely lose the healthy self criticism in an effort to love themselves, and that's a big problem.  I agree with you there.  But self hate isn't constructive criticism.  Self hate is like, i'm a fat cow and nobody will ever love me so i'll eat an tube of ice cream to make myself even fatter.  Self love is being a little ashamed that you ate the ice cream because you love your body and the ice cream isn't good for it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
