<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536392948.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>*hating* yourself is useless. All that does is lock you in negative feedback loops. What's important is self-*criticism*, but you need to be able to criticise yourself without letting that turn into hatred cos you need your attention to be on how you go about improving that, not wallowing in self-pity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536575636.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>You can't control emotions, you can do nothing to prevent self-criticism to turn in to self-hate. What locks you is not the hate itself, it's all the energy you waste trying to stop hating yourself. If you fucked up ALOT, self hate is a natural response. It wants to show you your mistakes, it is there for a reason. You have zero reason to prevent self hate, or deny it, and you don't have to. It is a part of you, and maybe the most important part. Only when you accept even the deepest darkest parts of you do you stand a chance to experience self love.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536597115.0" user="I_read_this_and" delta="False">
    <text>Emotions are emotions, it's how you deal with it that matters.

And rather and preventing or accepting self-hatred, what matters much more is how you can frame it. You have to be able to detach yourself and see things in a more neutral space.

*Enabling* self-hatred when you have a great life, have everything going for you, and are objectively a good person makes little sense. So rather than enabling that hatred, you should explore what's really behind those feelings.

On the other hand, self-hatred when you are an absolute loser who is toxic to everyone around you makes a lot of sense. Yeah, you should probably get your damn life in order.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536668243.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>" *Enabling* self-hatred when you have a great life, have everything going for you, and are objectively a good person makes little sense.  "

Emotions don't care if you are a good person or not, sometimes emotions don't make sense if you want to put it like that. If there is self hate, it is there whether you enable it, preventing it or accepting it, it's there and it's not going anywhere.

" So rather than enabling that hatred, you should explore what's really behind those feelings. "

This is where accepting the self-hate comes in help. You don't need to explore or wonder. If you listen to the self-hate it will straight out tell you what the problem is, and if you can fix it, do you need to fix it, or do you need to just let it go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536705669.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>You can't control emotions, but you can train your brain to respond to emotions in constructive ways, instead of its normal habit of spiralling. What you want to do is make it so that when you *do* hate yourself, your brain's response to that is to acknowledge the mistake, figure out how to deal with it and then not make the mistake in future - which will result in you no longer hating yourself. Self-hating is useless if you're not going to improve on it, but if you do improve on it then it's ultimately temporary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35537838454.0" user="Seratio" delta="False">
    <text>Self hate is *not* the natural response.

 Some say "I made a mistake", others quickly jump to "I'm a mistake". Many people say "That person made me do a mistake" or "I'm doing better than this one over there". The list goes on.

There's wildly different attribution styles and none of them are the natural, normal one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
