<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119312081.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z19sh/i_wouldnt_mind_artificial_intelligence_replacing/">
    <title>I wouldn't mind artificial intelligence replacing the human race. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Sleakne</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is not an incredibly well though out position so plenty of scope to change my view.

I am not debating whether or not it is possible for artificial intelligence to take over just that i'm okay with it if it does happen.

I am imagining a world where we create AI and it becomes smarter and smarter and soon becomes better than us at everything we do. We would be utterly dependent on them because only they would be intelligent enough to manage the incredible complexity of the society they have created.  

It is possible that they might keep the human race going but if they decided to wipe us out (humanely) I'd be okay with that.  They are the next step of our evolution, they are smarter than us in every way and keeping around our limited and flawed physical bodies seem unnecessary.

We can't go on forever, we will eventually die out.  Why fight it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27071418450.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are the next step of our evolution

Next step towards what? Evolution has no goal. All that matters is what survives best. If they beat us, I guess it's good game for humanity, but I see no reason to roll over and take it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071427403.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>Well we have established the AI in this scenario would survive better than us and would be so far ahead of us that fighting back wouldn't be an option.

Let me put it another way.  If all humans were basically just pets, still alive and enjoying happy lives but contributing nothing and the AI said "look guys, keeping billions of you alive and in a life of luxury is kind of a drain on our resources, would you mind if we painlessly killed you all so we can get on with our lives"  I'd vote to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071432812.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>I couldn't care less if my existence is a "burden" on them. I see absolutely no benefits to letting them kill me. What purpose does it serve besides making the AI happier?

Also why did we become unable to provide for ourselves? We're perfectly capable of doing it right now without any AI assistance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071438597.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think we are perfectly capable of providing for ourselves.  We still pollute and waste resources, think short term, are subject to biases and prejudice, start wars, kill other species and wildlife and let people starve.

I don't know why they would want to wipe us out completely either but I could easily imagine them wanting to massively reduce our population and if there was a reason to get rid of us I'd accept that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071448581.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>What would you say the ultimate goal of humanity is/should be? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071452563.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>i don't think there is one.  Life just happened and has gradually got more and more complex.  All we can do is keep surviving and trying to make life easier for the next generation.  Does that next generation have to be human though or can it be something that human's have created that surpasses us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071456970.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>In my mind it has to be human, I can't view AI as "our children" in any sense. 

But for the sake of argument, let's say they are. I still wouldn't kill myself to avoid being a burden on my son, unless circumstances were so dire that it became him or me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071474969.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>We created them...children is a stretch but they are certainly our creation.  

I'm not saying you should kill yourself.  I'm saying you should allow or consent to being euthanized or sterilized so that your child/successor/what ever  didn't have to spoon feed you every thing for the rest of your life and all your children's lives.

You might think that we can feed ourselves now why can't we keep doing that.  Because everything we do would be hopelessly inefficient.  All the land we need to farm, all the materials and chemicals we need to do it all the energy we spend just to get some steak. It would be much easier for them to just make the steak for us.  Or build the house for us or create the art for us.  Any other task, the most efficient option would be for us to let them do it and so we produce nothing we are good for nothing.  We would just be a burden.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071481342.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>How do you feel about euthanizing the mentally handicapped, and others who are currently just a burden on society? It seems to me that if a society has the resources to support its members, then it is immoral to destroy some of them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071484175.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>If they have the resources, then definitely keep us alive and the same goes for disabled people.  If its is them or us, then for me, I choose them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
