<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536439417.0" user="BlueZoglin" delta="False">
    <text>Something being a part of you doesn't make it inherently good.

One can't exist without the other is something you don't know to be true and cannot know to be true but for the sake of argument let us assume it to be true. 

There are benefits from loving yourself more than hating yourself.

First of all is self preservation, if you hate yourself more then you love yourself then why would you attempt to preserve your life? Assuming that every person perceives their life to be something of value then clearly it's not about whether or not you want to preserve your life but about whether or not you should.

Second is that they are more resilient. If you hate yourself more than you love yourself, often you can do more damage to yourself more than any other person ever could. If every punch hits you even like 1% more than someone who loves themselves then it will take less punches to take you down then it would for someone who loves themselves (not saying it as a jab just a point). 

Third is that you're a risk taker. In order to take a risk, you have to believe in yourself. By risk, I mean like to be an entrepreneur or to be an astronaut or to be a doctor. To be more than what you are, you have to be able to inspire yourself and to be able to aspire to see yourself in those shoes. Somebody who hates themself more than they love themself, how would they believe they could be anything else than what they are now?

Loving yourself is never something done in a day, it's a journey we experience every day. Even I'm not done.

But I to go a step further beyond just saying it's better to have self love and actually saying that self hate is bad. Let's go back to one cannot exist without the other. It's clear that one is better than the other so then doesn't that just make self hate bad?

I think there is a difference between hating yourself and being critical of yourself. You need to make sure that you recognise your faults not beat them into you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536706314.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>In a perfect world, where people can choose how to feel, all this sounds good and I agree.

But in this world, emotions don't work like this. There are not yours to control. If Love yourself there is a reason to love yourself, if you hate yourself there is a reason for that too. The problem comes that hating yourself doesn't feel good, so we try to remove it (ironically this could be from self love, not to feel bad). But since we can't we struggle more everyday and we start to feel powerless. But in accepting that you hate yourself, you will free all that wasted energy, you will see there is nothing to fear about that hate, as it is trying to teach you something. 

Love feels better, hate is a better teacher.

If you picturing hate in the end product which is rage, that only comes from resisting your emotions, where you feel powerless. Once you realize there is nothing to resist, there is no reason to be angry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35539256818.0" user="BlueZoglin" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting. Well, you can't always choose how you feel but you can always change your perspective.

Also the argument is about whether or not self hate is bad. So whether or not you can control it is irrelevant. 

But if you could control it, then the benefits of having less of it and more self love make it clear that it is something that would be desirable to be controlled if it could. And if you could control it you would choose to have less of it because the benefits of having more of it than self love is bad. 

You're supposed to rebutt with reasons why self hate is good or that having some self hate is good but I'll respond to what you've said. 

Sorry, but are you not just admitting that self hate is bad? You've only added that self acceptance is the cure. That as a response in our world is more realistic for which I agree. But that doesn't add to your point. 

I think hate as an emotion makes it a powerful tool for memorisation but I wouldn't conflait that with learning. Hate is not a good teacher because it impairs your most valuable learning tools which is the ability to view things objectively and think critically. The things we learn are incremental, without that lens or to have it impaired can cause us to accept things we believe to be true with no real basis that they are. The people who push their fields beyond their scope the hardest and fastest are not the people who hate their fields it's the ones who are passionate about it. 

Self hate is bad. There may be a use for it somewhere but it's still bad.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
