<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119375664.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z2muo/i_want_to_take_forgetting_pills_to_erase_every/">
    <title>I want to take "forgetting pills" to erase every bad memory I still can't get used to. (Some of which gave me ideations of suicide / self-harm.) CMV</title>
    <original_poster>EgaoNoGenki-XX</original_poster>
    <original_post>[I don't know HOW SOON these forgetting pills will arrive, but when they do, they won't be a moment too soon!](http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/02/ff_forgettingpill/all/)

I'd bet heavily that these memory-erasing pills will cause suicide rates to NOSEDIVE. Happiness indices in countries with ready access to these forgetting pills may soar.

Still, I'll observe results seen in other people before I start on them myself.

I have reason to believe that when I forget all the unsolvable bad events in my life, and any bad memory that still hurts me to this day, I'll feel a heavenly bliss not felt since the happiest day of my childhood.

(If there's ANY OTHER way to feel total bliss again, then **PLEASE SHARE IT!!!**)

Some memories I've gotten used to and won't feel hurt by them anymore, but others are so hard to get over, that I look upon these forgetting pills as a kind of "last hope."

I've been told that "memories form who we are." There are many reasons why I don't like the way I (currently) am so that lends me reason to believe that I'll be a better person once certain memories are erased.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27072003741.0" user="Omnipotence456" delta="False">
    <text>People aren't depressed because something bad happened to them. People are depressed because their brains are broken. Many people have all sorts of horrible shit happen to them and are still happy. Thus, taking "forgetting pills" would not fix you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072011436.0" user="EgaoNoGenki-XX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Many people have all sorts of horrible shit happen to them and are still happy.

What does it take to get to this point then?

How do I "rewire" my mind in a different, currently-doable way to get that to happen more easily?

&amp;gt; Thus, taking "forgetting pills" would not fix you.

We wouldn't know until test results are in from the first group of test subjects.

Could the memory-erasing treatments also get me to forget even *how to feel depressed?* And how about any other negative emotion that I wouldn't mind removing either? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072015594.0" user="Omnipotence456" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know what will fix you. I'm a neuroscientist, and fixing depression is one of the problems I'm interested in working on. But at this point, if you don't respond to currently available antidepressants and therapy, no one knows what else to do. That really sucks, and I'm sorry, but that doesn't mean you should pin your hopes on something that will actually not help you.

Even assuming that "how to feel depressed" is something you learned rather than something that was wired into you from the beginning due to genetics, memory-erasing still wouldn't help you. Memory and learning are separate in the brain. Memory is for events - it's the ability to say that you had a specific experience in the past, and to "relive" that experience in a limited sense. Learning is for abilities - it's the reinforcement of things that you do often so that you do them better. These two functions belong to separate areas of the brain. People with brain lesions which prevent them from forming new memories can still learn things. If you give them a task, every time they do it they'll think it's the first time they've done it, but they'll get better every time.

I don't deny that these pills could be helpful for people with PTSD. There, the issue really is with memory - they can't stop reliving a specific event. But depression has little to do with memory and thus these pills won't help you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072012376.0" user="PixelOrange" delta="False">
    <text>In this case, it very well may, since it permanently alters the neural pathways in the brain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072017108.0" user="Omnipotence456" delta="False">
    <text>Everything you experience "permanently alters the neural pathways in the brain." Altering pathways that have nothing to do with your depression won't change your depression. Also I'm really tired of that phrase, it's extremely alarmist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072029139.0" user="PixelOrange" delta="False">
    <text>The forgetting pills are a little more extreme. Not many things break memories down. If you were able to forget all your negative memories, it would go a long way towards being a happier person.

I'm against any sort of memory alteration, but to just dismiss it as "this won't fix anything, because you're depressed" is glossing over the cause of many people's depression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075895322.0" user="ICE_IS_A_MYTH" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that extremely traumatizing events can't cause depression or depression-like symptoms?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
