<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119375664.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z2muo/i_want_to_take_forgetting_pills_to_erase_every/">
    <title>I want to take "forgetting pills" to erase every bad memory I still can't get used to. (Some of which gave me ideations of suicide / self-harm.) CMV</title>
    <original_poster>EgaoNoGenki-XX</original_poster>
    <original_post>[I don't know HOW SOON these forgetting pills will arrive, but when they do, they won't be a moment too soon!](http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/02/ff_forgettingpill/all/)

I'd bet heavily that these memory-erasing pills will cause suicide rates to NOSEDIVE. Happiness indices in countries with ready access to these forgetting pills may soar.

Still, I'll observe results seen in other people before I start on them myself.

I have reason to believe that when I forget all the unsolvable bad events in my life, and any bad memory that still hurts me to this day, I'll feel a heavenly bliss not felt since the happiest day of my childhood.

(If there's ANY OTHER way to feel total bliss again, then **PLEASE SHARE IT!!!**)

Some memories I've gotten used to and won't feel hurt by them anymore, but others are so hard to get over, that I look upon these forgetting pills as a kind of "last hope."

I've been told that "memories form who we are." There are many reasons why I don't like the way I (currently) am so that lends me reason to believe that I'll be a better person once certain memories are erased.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27071996933.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>What would be your criteria for taking one. You probably don't want to erase all bad memories? And do you think they should require a doctor's/psychiatrist's approval?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072010693.0" user="EgaoNoGenki-XX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You probably don't want to erase all bad memories? 

I don't feel like erasing those whose situations have been positively resolved. Nor those that hurt so little now that I may even look back to laugh at them.

If they genuinely still hurt, and I face poor to no prospect of solving them positively anytime in the near future, then I must erase them.

&amp;gt; And do you think they should require a doctor's/psychiatrist's approval?

When I express prior suicidal tendencies because of those (unresolved) events, it would be a mutual understanding that these memory-erasing drugs will help strengthen my will to live.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
