<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536358372.0" user="Roller95" delta="False">
    <text>Please expand on some points. You bring them up and immediately abandon them.

&amp;gt; trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire.

How? Why? 

&amp;gt; Self hate is just as important as self love

Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536644227.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>You can never control your emotions, only suppress them at a great price. Drinking, smoking, porn, etc... If you try to do something out of love for yourself, let's say working out, or eating healthy, that will not stop you from hating yourself for something you did or the way you are. How many people try to do those things, only to quit shortly after.

Self hate shows you exactly what self love does. One shows you what you don't want in life and from yourself, the other what you do and do want. Now somethings are out of our control. If you hate yourself for being short, there is not much you can do about it, but accept that you hate it. The problem is trying to shove that hate down, to remove it, which is impossible. But once you stop struggling to do that, you will have your energy free to see the other side of the coin which is love. "Ok I hate myself for being short, that doesn't have to stop me from doing something good about myself, like going to the gym and get bigger and stronger. "</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
