<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119312081.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z19sh/i_wouldnt_mind_artificial_intelligence_replacing/">
    <title>I wouldn't mind artificial intelligence replacing the human race. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Sleakne</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is not an incredibly well though out position so plenty of scope to change my view.

I am not debating whether or not it is possible for artificial intelligence to take over just that i'm okay with it if it does happen.

I am imagining a world where we create AI and it becomes smarter and smarter and soon becomes better than us at everything we do. We would be utterly dependent on them because only they would be intelligent enough to manage the incredible complexity of the society they have created.  

It is possible that they might keep the human race going but if they decided to wipe us out (humanely) I'd be okay with that.  They are the next step of our evolution, they are smarter than us in every way and keeping around our limited and flawed physical bodies seem unnecessary.

We can't go on forever, we will eventually die out.  Why fight it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27071376152.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>How about if the "replacement" occurs during your *own* lifetime, while you are young and healthy?

Would you just sit there and be happy with you (or a loved one's) "humane" extermination?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071392005.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>If AI arrived and then took over in the next 20 years say then I would be happy to be sterilized along with the rest of the world.  Or if everyone was simultaneously and painlessly killed.  I would be okay with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071422455.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>I almost convinced myself to take your side on this using this argument: I would happily die to preserve something I loved and couldn't live with myself if I saw it die - a loved one, humanity, the existence of the world or the universe for example - because I acknowledge that their continued existence is of greater value to me than my own life. So if we had AI children who were godlike, I might die for them.

However! AI children *wanting us to die* contradicts their goodness/benevolence, as is proof of their evil/malevolence - and I couldn't love such a thing, just as I couldn't love/worship an "unjust God". A god or AI that sees no value in our specie's existence, or only sees value in our specie's extermination, proves their irrationality and their unworthyness of us dying for them.

A rational god/AI acknowledges that each human individual has the potential to choose and create their values and that this ability gives them the moral right to own their life, and moreover, that any particular individual can not be judged by their race, skin colour, specie or the actions of other individuals.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071433797.0" user="Sleakne" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying they would kill us maliciously.  I'm saying that if they asked us if we wouldn't mind them killing us or sterilizing us because 7 billion of us are quite a drain on resources and some of us are violent or disruptive, i wouldn't mind.

I see it like a much larger scale version of the old people of a tribe committing  suicide because they have become a burden.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27071545550.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand the ritual suicide to relieve burden of the tribe. The economics in a tribal system are such that resources are limited.

In a modern capitalistic economic system however, the quantity of  resources are not a limiting factor to progress or survival - all resource/access problems can be solved by technology and politics. Just as a person can exist without being a parasite on others, so to can an AI.  An AI would create new wealth and new resources that never existed before - there is no possible way that a rational (therefore benevolent) godlike creature could consider us a drain. (Certain individuals as disruptive to their existence, yes, maybe!)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
