<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1193963621.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jqus85/cmv_self_hate_is_not_something_bad/">
    <title>CMV: Self hate is not something bad.</title>
    <original_poster>NasZ1</original_poster>
    <original_post>All the popular self help information points, that we must not hate ourself, and try to love ourself. However hating yourself is a part of you. And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire. Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other. The problem with self hate is not the self hate itself, but the huge amount of energy we spend, trying not to hate ourselves. You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35536337177.0" user="AleristheSeeker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And trying to stop hating yourself will only backfire.

That is a baseless claim. How exactly would it backfire?

&amp;gt;Self hate is just as important as self love, and you can't have one without the other.

Love and Hate are generally considered polar opposites. What you mean is that you cannot have *the concept* of love without *the concept* of hate, but both of those concepts exist and are experienced. They need not be experienced towards oneself.

&amp;gt;You don't need to stop hating yourself, but to accept that it is a part of you, and like all emotions it is there for a reason, and it has valuable knowledge.

You're confusing "hating yourself" with "questioning yourself" - hate is a negative emotion that does not solve anything, it only makes you suffer. Questioning your choices, analyzing them and learning from them is not hate, it's self-reflection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536601964.0" user="NasZ1" delta="False">
    <text>" That is a baseless claim. How exactly would it backfire? "

Drinking, smoking, porn, procrastination. You will do nothing with your life, because deep down you know that nothing that you will do will stop the self hate. But you don't need to stop it. Self love is not the absence of self hate. How many people try to eat healthy or go to the gym, only to stop, because they still hate themselves.

" Love and Hate are generally considered polar opposites. What you mean is that you cannot have *the concept* of love without *the concept* of hate, but both of those concepts exist and are experienced. They need not be experienced towards oneself. "

You have zero control of what you experience and what not to. No one who ended up hating themselves did so on purpose. Hating your self tells you something very important, what you hate about yourself, only when you listen to the hate, can you know what you need to do with yourself.

" You're confusing "hating yourself" with "questioning yourself" - hate is  a negative emotion that does not solve anything, it only makes you  suffer. Questioning your choices, analyzing them and learning from them  is not hate, it's self-reflection. "

I am not confusing anything. Hate is not a negative emotion, there is no such thing as a negative emotion. And hate solves a lot of problems. What makes you suffer is resisting your emotions, as that is impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35536675234.0" user="AleristheSeeker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You will do nothing with your life, because deep down you know that nothing that you will do will stop the self hate. But you don't need to stop it.

I think those are symptoms of self hate, not of trying to fight self hate...

&amp;gt;Hating your self tells you something very important, what you hate about yourself, only when you listen to the hate, can you know what you need to do with yourself.

This is what I mean in the remainder of my post - that is not hate, that's self-critique. Hating something, for the most part, excludes aiding or trying to improve it. When's the last time you helped a person you hate?

&amp;gt;Hate is not a negative emotion, there is no such thing as a negative emotion.

That depends on your definition of "negative" - I would say that emotions that make you feel bad should be considered "negative" - people generally don't crave those emotions outside of a controled environment (like media). Noone wants to feel sad. Noone wants to be scared. At most, they want a tiny bit of that emotion while having the full power to disable the source (like a movie).

&amp;gt;What makes you suffer is resisting your emotions, as that is impossible.

So... being scared isn't suffering, it's trying to act brave? Being sad isn't suffering, it's trying to be happy?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
