<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119375664.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z2muo/i_want_to_take_forgetting_pills_to_erase_every/">
    <title>I want to take "forgetting pills" to erase every bad memory I still can't get used to. (Some of which gave me ideations of suicide / self-harm.) CMV</title>
    <original_poster>EgaoNoGenki-XX</original_poster>
    <original_post>[I don't know HOW SOON these forgetting pills will arrive, but when they do, they won't be a moment too soon!](http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/02/ff_forgettingpill/all/)

I'd bet heavily that these memory-erasing pills will cause suicide rates to NOSEDIVE. Happiness indices in countries with ready access to these forgetting pills may soar.

Still, I'll observe results seen in other people before I start on them myself.

I have reason to believe that when I forget all the unsolvable bad events in my life, and any bad memory that still hurts me to this day, I'll feel a heavenly bliss not felt since the happiest day of my childhood.

(If there's ANY OTHER way to feel total bliss again, then **PLEASE SHARE IT!!!**)

Some memories I've gotten used to and won't feel hurt by them anymore, but others are so hard to get over, that I look upon these forgetting pills as a kind of "last hope."

I've been told that "memories form who we are." There are many reasons why I don't like the way I (currently) am so that lends me reason to believe that I'll be a better person once certain memories are erased.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27072382257.0" user="cabr1to" delta="False">
    <text>The way I see it there are three parts to this problem:  The memories themselves, the distress they cause you in remembering/experiencing them, and the possibly harmful reactions they motivate.

You can't do anything about the first part.  It doesn't work simply because of the way your brain functions, thoughts and memories are connected to each other the more you pay any sort of attention to them -- even voluntarily "forgetting" involves a "remembering"!  Besides, the goal of chemically erasing your troubles has been tried by countless addicts, compulsives and runners-away since as long as humans have been around to have bad shit happen.  The obsession with forgetting is itself just another kind of reinforcement of the bad thing.  What thoughtless stuff might you do when you are busily "forgetting"?  Maybe you were supposed to learn from that.  So instead the cycle continues.  It's just a no-go.

So the second hand, you can't avoid remembering unpleasant or difficult things, and as a result you have this feeling of distress.  This is the part I think you are trying to get over, which is what's making the memories "bad" and what you are trying to avoid feeling.  Think of something really embarrassing or unfortunate you did and wait for the cringe.  It's not a nice experience, is it?  But even though that repulsion to unpleasantness is going to happen, you can still shape the way you regard it and how you respond to it.

So instead of trying to do something about the feels, instead imagine the "bad" situation again, but this time you think about the decisions leading up to it, the surrounding people, places, context and allow yourself to just observe it non-judgmentally.  Instead of that memory happening to you, **you** are now happening to **it** by understanding it in a more compassionate way, in a way that lets you feel what you're going to feel but understanding the cause of the actions without judging them as "good" or "bad".  It's a sort of agreement with yourself that you can feel things without jumping on the impulse of judging these feelings as "BAD FEELS, go away, DO NOT WANT!" or even "good feels, want MORE!" -- just feel the things and notice that it happens.  It might be really intense in the moment but it passes.  What you get instead is what /r/Buddhism might call "equanimity" -- radical permission to feel things without letting the feelings overwhelm you, just letting them be felt and then letting them move on.  

So instead of wishing something didn't happen or you didn't remember it, you just give up control over the past and tell yourself "yeah, that happened."  This works for recalling bad things others have done to you too, but in that case you have to look at their own motivations, their situation, maybe some bad shit of their own that they were just passing on.  There's an equal part remembering, contextualizing, yes, *feeling* -- but then understanding, forgiving, accepting that bad shit has happened before and is going to happen again, but you don't need to let it control your reaction.

TL;DR:  Basically, you can reshape the way a "bad" memory works by just meditating on it a bit so you get some perspective.  It's not an immediate thing but it does help.  Just sit there, breathe, think about the thing and how it came to be, and before you know it the "badness" is lessened and the memory loses its power.  If you can't forget, this is probably the next best thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27072384408.0" user="totes_meta_bot" delta="False">
    <text>This thread has been linked to from elsewhere on reddit.


 - [/r/Buddhism] [Trying to help out a fellow redditor who is feeling distressed by &amp;amp;quot;bad&amp;amp;quot; memories of the past. How&amp;amp;#x27;d I do?](http://np.reddit.com/r/Buddhism/comments/1z3ojh/trying_to_help_out_a_fellow_redditor_who_is/)


*^I ^am ^a ^bot. ^Comments? ^Complaints? [^Send ^them ^to ^my ^inbox!](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=totes_meta_bot)*

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
