<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119700622.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z9lla/a_warmer_earth_will_be_better_for_humanity_cmv/">
    <title>A warmer earth will be better for humanity CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terrdc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here are my basic thoughts laid out.

I'd rather live on the equator as compared to antartica.

A warmer earth will be caused by the trapping of heat which means that antartica should heat up faster than the equator as heat flows from the center of the earth and less goes into space.

So even if some land is overtaken by rising sea levels more land should be livable.


Now to be clear this is not an argument against attempting to slow down and eventually stop global warming.  My main argument is that today's temperature is not the best temperature and that the "best" temperature would be higher than it is today.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27074944945.0" user="__Pers" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe that biodiversity is a good thing for humanity? We are going through a mass extinction as a consequence of human impact on ecosystems (including, but not limited to climate change). Species can neither evolve nor migrate quickly enough to stave off these systemic shocks. 

Much of the land being "freed up" in the Arctic and Antarctic is permafrost and would be far from ready for human cultivation or settling (much will never be habitable in any real sense). Moreover, trapped methane, a far more potent greenhouse gas than CO2, risks a positive feedback loop accelerating the climate change in an uncontrolled manner. 

Much research has shown that a consequence of anthropogenic climate change is a higher frequency of extreme weather events. Hurricanes and cyclones are stronger with more energy pumping them. Jet streams are weaker, meaning that long droughts, cold snaps, deluges of rain are more severe and last longer. The past few years have shown that humanity has a hard time dealing with such shocks. Large swaths of the population (including much of China) are water-insecure, meaning diminished access to safe, clean drinking water. If one adds the possibility of systemic drought to the mix, this could lead to untold and unprecedented suffering. (Much of the conflict in Syria today stems from resource competition; now imagine this on a far vaster scale.) 

Finally, deglaciation of Greenland and Antarctica could ultimately lead to several meters of change in sea levels, with devastating impact for coastal communities. 

You're going to balance all this against a gut feeling that somehow it'll all work out and that we'll smoothly ease through the transition and find ourselves in a promised land of milk and honey? You have far more faith than I, my friend. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27074994019.0" user="terrdc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Much research has shown that a consequence of anthropogenic climate change is a higher frequency of extreme weather events.

I've heard that, but personally I've always thought that evidence was cherry picked.  Its like the articles say "Some models show more wildfires occur".  So what?  Is it 10% of models showing that and 90% showing that less will occur?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075004329.0" user="__Pers" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it would seem that [the international community of climate scientists](http://ipcc-wg2.gov/SREX/) disagrees fundamentally with your gut feeling that the data are "cherry picked" (and please, by all means, produce your data refuting the IPCC findings). 

The takeaways from the report, which were compiled from the most comprehensive climate data available: 

* Extreme weather is occurring more frequently around the globe. 

* Extreme weather disasters are becoming deadlier and more expensive.

* Warming causes extreme weather events. 

* This warming with very high likelihood is being caused by greenhouse gas emission. 

* Humanity needs to be actively planning how we will adapt to such eventualities in order to minimize human suffering around the globe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075019674.0" user="terrdc" delta="False">
    <text>I took a look at some of that and it doesn't really fit with what you said.

For example there is one line in http://ipcc-wg2.gov/SREX/images/uploads/SREX-SPMbrochure_FINAL.pdf

&amp;gt;There is medium confidence that there will be a reduction in the number of extratropical cyclones averaged
over each hemisphere

&amp;gt;Average tropical cyclone maximum wind speed is likely to increase, although increases may not occur in
all ocean basins. It is likely that the global frequency of tropical cyclones will either decrease or remain
essentially unchanged.

Or in other words cyclones are likely to get faster in some local places, but occur less often globally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075032440.0" user="__Pers" delta="False">
    <text>The quoted text does not refute what I'm saying. Storms with higher wind speeds are generally more damaging and thus more expensive. Perhaps there are fewer storms, but the ones that occur are likely to be more damaging.

Storms are not the only extreme weather events one must consider. Systemic, extreme drought is affecting much of the Southwest, e.g., and has transformed the landscape (bark beetles have destroyed much of the pinon and pine forests in the high deserts). How many "decadal" storms hammered the Midwest and East this winter alone? 

Whatever final migration to the Arctic and Antarctic circles you envision to somehow save humanity is going to be tempered by dealing with these extreme weather events. (And [the Arctic is hardly immune](http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/02/090205083526.htm) to such.) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075041504.0" user="terrdc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The quoted text does not refute what I'm saying. Storms with higher wind speeds are generally more damaging and thus more expensive. Perhaps there are fewer storms, but the ones that occur are likely to be more damaging.

They are likely to be more damaging in certain local areas.  So it could be that the overall damage is less.  It could be that it is more.  I am not saying that weather events will get better, just that the evidence that it will get worse is inconclusive.

On droughts (according to the pdf)
&amp;gt;There is medium confidence that some regions of the world have experienced more intense and longer droughts, in
particular in southern Europe and West Africa, but in some regions droughts have become less frequent, less intense,
or shorter, for example, in central North America and northwestern Australia.

And I think your talk about Antarctic migration doesn't have anything to do with my argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075054405.0" user="__Pers" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I'm glad you're so certain of your position that you're willing to risk everything for your purported land of milk and honey. I'm willing to bet that if you have a car, you also have insurance to protect from the possibility of an accident; you probably have medical insurance to pick up the tab in case you become injured or infirm; you may even shell out for homeowner insurance in case your home or flat is damaged. Most people guard against severe risks, even unlikely ones. Serious disruption in the ability of the planet to support human life and livelihoods seems severe. 

Yet you're willing to gamble with the planet itself, taking conservative qualifying statements in the IPCC reports (hint: if something is 90%+ certain, they'll say "highly likely"; if it's 75% certain, they'll say, "likely"; if something has a 50% chance, they'll say "possible") as justification for the most extreme possible interpretations of potential outcomes. It's adorably inconsistent.

Edit: typo</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
