<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119700622.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z9lla/a_warmer_earth_will_be_better_for_humanity_cmv/">
    <title>A warmer earth will be better for humanity CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terrdc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here are my basic thoughts laid out.

I'd rather live on the equator as compared to antartica.

A warmer earth will be caused by the trapping of heat which means that antartica should heat up faster than the equator as heat flows from the center of the earth and less goes into space.

So even if some land is overtaken by rising sea levels more land should be livable.


Now to be clear this is not an argument against attempting to slow down and eventually stop global warming.  My main argument is that today's temperature is not the best temperature and that the "best" temperature would be higher than it is today.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27074949977.0" user="RobertK1" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, lets accept your basic premise for a second without argument - that there is a temperature, X, that is the "ideal temperature" for humanity, and that it is higher than the current temperature.

It would STILL not be ideal for humans to let the earth warm.  Human civilization is adapted to the current temperature and weather patterns of the earth.  Arizona is adapted to being a desert, with massive irrigation systems and buildings and places designed for the desert.  Brazil is adapted for tons of rain.  

What does climate change look like?  Have you seen the so-called snowpocalypse?  Southern cities used to getting a few inches every year getting actual snowfalls?  Millions upon millions of dollars being lost, lives being lost in accidents, disasters everywhere, emergency services paralyzed?  

How much will it cost them to buy snow removal equipment?  Tens of millions.  Possibly hundreds, for all of the southern states.  It is an expensive, dismal undertaking to imagine. 

Climate Change is this to the entire world. It will be TRILLIONS of dollars to adapt to the changing climate.  Lives will be lost.  Agricultural regions will collapse.  Do you think the new regions that are now "suited to agriculture" are empty?  What are we going to do, kick people out of their homes because they're now in an agricultural belt and turn their suburbs and cities into farms?

Yeah, we might.  Humanity, at the end of the day, really likes food.  It beats "no food" solid.  Do you think this is a good thing?

Finally, if you still think it's a good thing, let me point to the eye.  The eye is perfectly adapted to seeing in the spectrum of visible light.  Now it JUST SO HAPPENS that the spectrum of visible light is the highest concentration of light to hit the earth.  More "visible light" hits the earth than any other spectrum (infrared, ultraviolet, etc.).  

Do you think that's a coincidence?  No.  The human eye evolved to match the exact range of conditions experienced.  There is no "more ideal" spectrum of light for us because we adapted to the exact spectrum we have.  Similarly, we have adapted to the climate we have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27074997634.0" user="terrdc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is no "more ideal" spectrum of light for us because we adapted to the exact spectrum we have. Similarly, we have adapted to the climate we have.

We don't live in the exact climate that we evolved from.  Humanity spreading across the globe is a relatively recent thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075004930.0" user="RobertK1" delta="False">
    <text>I have to say that in CMV the most frustrating thing is when the OP chooses to ignore your entire post to nitpick one point.

It makes you feel like they really aren't interested in talking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
