<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="119700622.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1z9lla/a_warmer_earth_will_be_better_for_humanity_cmv/">
    <title>A warmer earth will be better for humanity CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terrdc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here are my basic thoughts laid out.

I'd rather live on the equator as compared to antartica.

A warmer earth will be caused by the trapping of heat which means that antartica should heat up faster than the equator as heat flows from the center of the earth and less goes into space.

So even if some land is overtaken by rising sea levels more land should be livable.


Now to be clear this is not an argument against attempting to slow down and eventually stop global warming.  My main argument is that today's temperature is not the best temperature and that the "best" temperature would be higher than it is today.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27075030990.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a climate scientist, I explain this to people for a living.  The problem is not necessarily that it's "warmer", so no, a rapid cooling wouldn't be any better.  The problem is simply how quickly it's changing.  Yes, it may be that there would be several benefits to a warmer climate.  A longer growing season is the most obvious. 

However, the problem is not that it's getting warmer.  The problem is how QUICKLY it's getting warmer.  The planet simply can't adapt this quickly.  When this kind of thing happens over tens of thousands of years, it's less of a problem.  Species adapt, they migrate, everything works out.  But now you're talking about entire landscapes changing in the course of decades.  Evolution can't happen that quickly.

So yes, certain aspects of humanity would benefit from a warmer climate, but the problem is the rate of change, not necessarily the magnitude. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27075148891.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Evolution can't happen that quickly.

Life uh..finds a way..</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
