<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35569720993.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>In US if you give legitimate criticism of coal industry you can be sued for all you are worth and get your life ruined because poor had ideas that wealthy are not allowed to poison your water. This can't happen in Europe where wealthy are forced to pay in same circumstances.

In US you don't have free speech if you are poor and try to fight the rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570202508.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>Free speech doesn't protect you from lawsuits.  It protects you from jail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570294405.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>That's statement is oxymoron.

If something protects you from jail it must protect you from lawsuits. Lawsuits (once lost) send you to jail. It's not the murder that sends a person to jail, it's the lost law suit that follows it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570297933.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>Of you sue me and I lose I can't go to jail..I don't get your point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570412694.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>If you lose a law suit, you are going to jail (or pay fines). That's how legal system works.

I think you are confused what free speech actually protects. In US it only protects you from government. Meaning government law suits. Rich people can sue you and ruin you. 

In more just systems (like those in Europe), those rich oil people would have no case and would lose all cases because people have freedom to criticize their practices. Also in those systems government will represent it's own citizen when someone attacks them (ie. Protects women when individual says that all women should be raped and killed). In US this latter doesn't happen because there is no clear plaintiff (single victim) that can start the law suit.

US system benefits the rich and the bigoted while punish the poor and oppressed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570420067.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>Not in the US.  If you lose a lawsuit you owe money...Now that can ruin you, but you don't go to jail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570574818.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>That's how civil law suits work every where in the world. Freedom of speech has nothing to do with it.

But freedom of speech is much more than protection from government suits (something that US actually does wrong because it benefits bigots). US also lacks in journalist freedom in additional to frivolous defamation suits. Both that benefits the rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35591208714.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>[Here's](https://www.popehat.com/2016/06/11/hello-youve-been-referred-here-because-youre-wrong-about-the-first-amendment/) an article written by a first amendment lawyer. Relevant portion below:

&amp;gt;The First Amendment limits your ability to sue people.

&amp;gt;Civil lawsuits employ government power in two ways. First, they are premised on laws passed by legislatures. A defamation lawsuit is a lawsuit based upon a defamation law enacted by a state, which is an action by the state. On occasion, they're based on a nebulous collection of non-statutory precedents called common law, which are nonetheless recognized and enforced by the government through the courts. Second, civil lawsuits employ government power to force you to come to court and force you to pay any resulting judgment against you.

&amp;gt;So in 1964, faced with an Alabama defamation judgment against the New York Times for running an advertisement about abuse of civil rights protesters by local officials, the Supreme Court noted that the First Amendment obviously applies to private civil actions that employ state power. "The test is not the form in which state power has been applied but, whatever the form, whether such power has, in fact, been exercised." Because civil lawsuits aimed at speech invoke state power to attack speech, they are limited by the First Amendment. That doesn't mean that all civil lawsuits attacking speech are absolutely barred. It means that First Amendment analysis applies to them, and may or may not provide a defense to them.

&amp;gt;If you think about it even a little, this is the only sensible interpretation. Under a contrary interpretation, a state could pass a law saying that private parties could sue you for offending them, or annoying them, or for expressing certain political views the state disfavors. People could then use the coercive power of the courts to sue you based on those laws. Although I admit there is a certain appeal to a regime under which I may ask a judge to compel you to pay my bar tab if you say stupid and ignorant things about the First Amendment, I recognize that it is not consistent with ordered liberty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35574521131.0" user="iceandstorm" delta="False">
    <text>What happens if you ow money and you do not pay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35574528457.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>They can garnish your wages, put a lien on property or you claim bankruptcy.  Not much else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577229493.0" user="iceandstorm" delta="False">
    <text>ah that is good, for some reason, maybe inspired by television i thought that if you refuse to pay it can escalate and you end up in jail</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578125367.0" user="MotherofPutin" delta="False">
    <text>Free speech protects you from criminal suits, not civil suits</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35591189732.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>At least in the US, this is wrong. If something I'm saying falls under the legal definition of free speech, you cannot sue me for it.

If I lie and say that you are a dog rapist, that is defamation, which is not covered by free speech. You could sue me for that. 

If I say that you're a worthless piece of shit, that's an opinion. If I say that I think you're a racist because you said something bad about a person of another race one time, that's an opinion based on disclosed facts. I can also say anything bad about you if it's true. You couldn't win a lawsuit over those kinds of things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
