<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35568842553.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>Before i start investing my time: have u even read ur own sources?

No single of those cases is unreasonable. Especially considering the context those happened in. U cant forget most of europe and especially germany had to deal with the blow back of Nazis After ww2.

Meaning some of these laws or behaviors are in place to keep something like that from happening again. Like someone said in here. At the point where ur freedom of speech inhibts another persons its not free anymore.


And especially regarding the study from germany it sounds to me like all of them are just to scared to admit their right wing interests in public. Since u do get Kinda crucified for it in germany depending on the Region u live in. In either case that study is Showscases a much larger Problem that is happening, namely the increase of right wing votes for the AfD. 

As i said. Context. Studies give u numbers. Putting it into historical context is what gives them meaning and relevance.

I mean depending on were u are in the us ur either a hero or villain for hating on black,gays etc.

Its the same anywhere in the world just for different subjects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35568961511.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No single of those cases is unreasonable. 

All free speech violations are unreasonable. It's a human right. 

&amp;gt;Meaning some of these laws or behaviors are in place to keep something like that from happening again. 

Anti Semitic speech was illegal in Germany before hitler rose to power. That did literally nothing to stop him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35568995137.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>Could u please answer my question? Did u read ur own sources? Yes or no?

&amp;gt;All free speech violations are unreasonable. It's a human right. 

Smh. Selective reading is a thing with u i see.

They are not. If u exhibit ur free speech and violate someone else right to it by doing that or if u violate any basic human right because of ur "freedom" of speech u just lost that right to do so. Thats how human rights work. As long as u doing u doesnt hurt someone else its fine. But in at least 50% of u examples this is not whats happening. At least Half of these sources have a clear Pattern of someone violating someone else human rights via ABUSING their right to free speech...

And that isnt something i pulled out my ass. Its written down in almost all european consitutions this way.

&amp;gt;Anti Semitic speech was illegal in Germany before hitler rose to power. That did literally nothing to stop him.

So now we should just allow it and make it easier for anyone with the same Ideals to get to power? Also something like Hitler Hadnt happened before. There are such things as learning expiriences. Even if it was an extrmely costly and fucked up one. Now everyone knows better then to repeat the same stuff. 

The logical conclusion isnt that the before Used Methods were bad. Its that they were not enough. In any case anti semitic speech isnt forbidden in germany anymore. Otherwise the whole AfD would be imprisoned. 

Also looking at how Hitler gained his power there is much More to it. As i said before CONTEXT. First ww was just over. The Country was unhappy and in disarray. Hitler simply knew what to say and when. Just like trump who gained power by simply riding the Wave of we dont want immigrants in 2016.

There is much More to it then saying a single law wasnt enough to prevent Hitler...

Seriously dude. Context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569015920.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are not. If u exhibit ur free speech and violate someone else right to it by doing that or if u violate any basic human right because of ur "freedom" of speech u just lost that right to do so. Thats how human rights work. As long as u doing u doesnt hurt someone else its fine. But in at least 50% of u examples this is not whats happening. At least Half of these sources have a clear Pattern of someone violating someone else human rights via ABUSING their right to free speech...

Speech does not hurt others. Unless your referring to bruised egos.

Controlling speech is a tool for tyrants. Any excuse they make up along the why as to why they are doing it is incidental and interchangeable.

&amp;gt;So now we should just allow it and make it easier for anyone with the same Ideals to get to power?

It would not. That law did literally nothing, so why have it?

&amp;gt;The logical conclusion isnt that the before Used Methods were bad. Its that they were not enough. In any case anti semitic speech isnt forbidden in germany anymore. Otherwise the whole AfD would be imprisoned.

So let me get this straight.

Most of Europe had light censorship in the early 1900s and half a dozen states collapsed into fascism (Spain, Italy, Germany, Portugal, Hungary and Austria).

The US had almost no censorship and has had no fascist coups at all. The closest we have ever had is this nonsense with trump trying to not concede, and people are just laughing at him.

So your conclusion from that is that you need more cencoship to avoid fascism? If a little does nothing, a lot must do suddenly help?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569035213.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>Not doing this if u keep up the selective reading and if u cant answer my first and single question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569516569.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>To take your argument to an extreme, would it be a human right violation if I were in any way prosecuted by the government if I told everyone in a crowded theatre there was a fire?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570544864.0" user="RadioactiveSpiderBun" delta="False">
    <text>The act of yelling fire in a crowded theater is not against any law. You cannot be prosecuted for that act itself. For example; if you did tell everyone in a crowded theater there was a fire and everyone walked out peacefully, with no harm done to anyone, the government has no power to fine you or sentence you for a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569054236.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>So you are telling me that you agree, freedom of speech is indeed freer in the US. Because your opinion is *actually* that you don’t want people to express their ideas via burning a book or stating a historical figure in the past is a pedophile. You are telling me you are in favor of punishing those who express these ideas</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569070084.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>FOR EVERYONE UNABLE TO READ PROPERLY: I DO NOT AGREE WITH OP. OP KEEPS DODGING MY QUESTION WHICH IS WHY I HAVENT MADE MY CASE YET.

What i am Telling u is to answer my question.

And no. Stop Putting words in my mouth.

What i am saying and u arent getting: there is a limit to freedom of speech. 

„Diese Rechte finden ihre Schranken in den Vorschriften der allgemeinen Gesetze, den gesetzlichen Bestimmungen zum Schutze der Jugend und in dem Recht der persönlichen Ehre. “

This is what Paragraph 5 part 2 off the German Grundgesetz says. Bascislly. Ur freedom of speech is limited as soon as u disobey basic laws and to protect the children and ones personal honour(whatever that means).

So all i am saying is: u have no idea what freedom of speech is and seemingly no idea what it means to live together with others on this Planet. Since u seemingly only Think about YOUR freedom. And as i have said multiple times CONTEXT.

So? Have u even read ur own sources? Because applying Paragraph 5 part 2 to all those articles would make it pretty easy to discern why all of this happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569910309.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>you’re not getting it.  you agree with the OP that the US is freer, but you want US to be less free like Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569969887.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>Are u not able to read properly?

I clearly stated i dont. I just havent even started making my case Cause op doesnt want to answer me.

Thats all.

Also lol. Good that u know better what i am thinking then i do. Didnt know u were living in my head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570030170.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>nope your meaning is clear and i read it correctly, you’re just trying to deny the implication of what you wrote</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570096315.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously. Stop acting like u know me.

Okay to make this clear. Op has painted a very specific picture of a supposed idea how europe and germany etc work. The only thing i mentioned regarding that subject was me mentioning that there are reasons for it, by quoting the actual law.

I havent even started about how op misrepresented how the US works or what actually happened in the cases quoted by op. I also havent started debunking that stupid ass study survey he quotes regarding how open one feels in germany regarding talking about specific subjects.( i mean what is even considered talking in public? It isnt specified in the source thats for sure, very sus)

To make this clear: i Think op has an extremely faulty perspective on why and how these things happen. He keeps blaming not enough freedom of speech, but his sources Show, when read, that the freedom of speech in each of those cases wasnt the Problem. 50% of them happened because of blatant disregard for other laws. Which isnt clear when reading such a biased source but when actually crosschecking the mentioned cases with other Reports. 

Also he keeps acting as if the US is different in any way when in reality racism clearly reduces freedom of speech for a big percentage of the Population. And this isnt an issue that is fixed nowadays.
Also regarding specifically freedom of speech the law is almost the same in the US as in europe. So that in itself almost says it all. 

But as long as op hasnt even read his own sources or is able to admit that he hasnt, i wont bother debunking him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570129224.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>i don’t know you but none of what you said is coherent.  maybe english isn’t your first language and maybe you have no idea how first amendment law works in the US, but in either case this isn’t productive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570189857.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>The Supreme Court of the United States has recognized several categories of speech that are given lesser or no protection by the First Amendment and has recognized that governments may enact reasonable time, place, or manner restrictions on speech.


Public authorities may restrict this right if they can show that their action is lawful, necessary and proportionate in order to:

protect national security, territorial integrity (the borders of the state) or public safety

prevent disorder or crime

protect health or morals

protect the rights and reputations of other people

prevent the disclosure of information received in confidence

maintain the authority and impartiality of judges



U were saying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570247539.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>wrong.  wrong.  wrong.  in no scotus case law is the standard “lawful, necessary and proportionate”.  

as a substantive matter, the US courts have ruled many many times protecting speech that are explicitly outlaws in European countries, such as holocaust denial and also hate speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570285394.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; in no scotus case law is the standard “lawful, necessary and proportionate”. 

And u know that how? Besides spouting out "wrong" i cant see any proof.

&amp;gt;the US courts have ruled many many times protecting speech that are explicitly outlaws in European countries, such as holocaust denial and also hate speech.

Now lets Think about this. How would u feel if Holocaust denial would be allowed in europe? Comparing this specific subject is very stupid since europe has a huuuuge history with Nazis while the usa thinks they dont.

Thats why i keep coming back to the word context.
Context is what gives this meaning and reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570311811.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>i know that bc i’m actually a lawyer who studied actual first amendment law.  the important standards have to do with content restrictions vs manner restrictions.  the word salad you posted is no where close to what first amendment jurisprudence looks like.

context may explain WHY europe restricts speech more than the US, but it doesn’t refute the fact that it DOES restrict speech more than the US, which is the OP’s point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570340664.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;i know that bc i’m actually a lawyer who studied actual first amendment law. 

Of course u are.

&amp;gt; the word salad you posted is no where close to what first amendment jurisprudence looks like.

Thats surpising. So u dont recognize ur own freedom of speech laws when quoted? I didnt Quote the first amendment. Sure it states freedom of speech may not be infriged by the State etc. What i quoted are the named exceptions ur own Country has for freedom of speech. 

Why would i argue about the first amendment that Shits literally set in stone.


but it doesn’t refute the fact that it DOES restrict speech more than the US, which is the OP’s point.

As mentionend before i will not be going to make that point till op reacts. And again: the picture op is painting with his "facts" isnt all of it and very biased. 

Thinking about it its actually laughable how little evidence op brought forth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570483251.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>exceptions to freedom of speech aren’t “named”.  instead, the supreme court has developed a mutifactorial test for whether certain government acts improperly infringed on the first amendment.  the crap you posted comes nowhere near the supreme court tests articulated in numerous cases, most notably the brandenburg cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578122572.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Public authorities may restrict this right if they can show that their action is lawful, necessary and proportionate...

This is **not** US law. It's from the UK's human rights act of 1998. Requirements for restricting speech in the US are different and much stricter than what you list here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578089068.0" user="MotherofPutin" delta="False">
    <text>Just because there are reasons for Europe to be less free doesn't mean that Europe isn't still less free</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570189513.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>What questions is he dodging?  You asked one question, did he read the sources? 

The German paragraph 5 prices they have less free speech.  In the US as long as the speech doesn't directly incite harm or directly cause harm Even like things like libel and slander aren't illegal in the sense you can't go to jail, you could sued.  

Hate speech is free speech in the US.  Most countries it isn't.  Therefore OP is right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570206623.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You asked one question, did he read the sources? 

And exactly that is the one he is dodging. I even made it easy by only asking one question.


&amp;gt;Hate speech is free speech in the US. Most countries it isn't.

It actually isnt if it incites violence. Which is Used alot as Argument for reducing hate speech in the us. 

&amp;gt;In the US as long as the speech doesn't directly incite harm or directly cause harm Even like things like libel and slander aren't illegal in the sense you can't go to jail, you could sued. 

Same for europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570239275.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>It has to directly incite violence...

If I said "Blue people are subhuman trash.  They are lower than dogs. They are animals. They and their God's are evil and should never have existed." That is allowed. If you interpret that as violence and act violent the speaker isn't responsible.

If I said "Blue people are subhuman trash and should be hunted down and killed!". That is inviting violence since I specifically called for violence.

You are wrong. Defamation is illegal and a criminal offense in most of Europe and can lead to jail time.

http://legaldb.freemedia.at/defamation-laws-in-europe/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570312701.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are wrong. Defamation is illegal and a criminal offense in most of Europe and can lead to jail time.

&amp;gt;http://legaldb.freemedia.at/defamation-laws-in-europe/

U are funny. As far as i can see from ur source a third of european countries imprison u. Another third fines u and in the Rest its just the same as the us(UK and scandivia and a few)

So ye. I mean sweaping all of europe under the same cloth is Kinda stupid as well since every Country has their own rules within the EU and the EU does little beside regulating unecessary stuff(the length of bananas for example. Not joke)

&amp;gt;It has to directly incite violence...


The point was that u said there i nothing that infringes on freedom of speech because first amendment. Now we are at the point were we are discussing what counts as infringement...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570356500.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>First math isn't your strong suit.  Of the 31 countries that are one of the 3 colors (might be off by a couple since I came make out smaller counties on my phone that well) 19 have jail time, over 60%. 4 it is a crime, so just shy of 3/4 defemation is a crime. Not bit all, but the majority of Europe it is a crime.  In the US is isn't a crime.

I never said there was nothing that infringes on free speech.  I said hate speech is free speech.  Inciting violence is an exception. There are exceptions to everything. In the US there are less exceptions than most Western countries</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570378601.0" user="Arus420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First math isn't your strong suit. 

Usernamen Checks out i guess.



&amp;gt; In the US there are less exceptions than most Western countries

Define Western. Define most. And are u sure? Have u checked how many other exceptions there are?

Have u checked how many of the assumed exceptions op presented are actually true? have u given a thought to how reality and the law written might differ in their enforcement? (Obviously referring to racism here)

My point being u just assume because op said so and because i havent brought any real Arguments against.(still waiting on op to react tbh)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35667419456.0" user="ZirillaFionaRianon" delta="False">
    <text>Unlike American Freedom of Speech, European Freedom of speech does not mean you're free of the consequences of what you're saying.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
