<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35568827217.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>I’m from the UK and I feel that I have plenty of freedom of speech, if I use that freedom to express intolerant racist or homophobic opinions there’s going to be backlash and that’s to be expected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35568958110.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>That's the problem. You don't care because what you intend on saying is favored by the government. If the government changes it's mind, you may suddenly feel less free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569562538.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Well that’s like saying I should be opposed to law and order, since it isn’t currently a crime to watch television or eat crisps, but if the government changes their mind I would become a criminal.

That’s just how a society works. A democracy is built on letting others dictate how we behave in the extremes (no stealing, no inciting violence, etc)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569309558.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>I used those issues based on the examples you gave, there is plenty I disagree with our government on and I’m perfectly free to voice it. Not to mention that there are prominent political parties in the UK who many deem to be inherently racist and backwards. There was a neo-nazi march not far from me that had a police escort, so we may have harsher penalties on defamation, but people are 100% allowed to voice their opinions, but there’s a line that can be crossed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569922215.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>your govt arrested someone for making a youtube video of a dog doing the hitler salute.  your govt also arrested someone for misgendering someone on twitter.  you don’t have freedom of speech friend.  you have a woke authoritarian govt that you don’t mind bc you happen to agree with persecution of people that the govt targets right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570287253.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re referring to the people I think, the nazi salute guy wasn’t arrested he got a fine and the woman was sharing personal and medical information about a trans woman in a direct attack. I think you need to do some research on the UK Conservative government (who aren’t left btw), their opinion has no bearing on my social standpoint and they definitely aren’t “woke”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570319230.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>what happens if you don’t pay the fine?  you get arrested.

and your excuse about “sharing personal and medical info” is BS.  The person is a stranger on twitter.  The “personal and medical info” shared is that the person is a biological man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570369276.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>Didn’t get arrested though did he, and you can call it what you want, feeling the need to throw up personal info online seems like harassment to me. Your examples are so few and far between, plenty of people in the UK post racist and homophobic content and the vast majority go without consequence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570392589.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>well you won’t get a fine in the US, so it’s freer, and you don’t get arrested for getting into a twitter argument and have it characterized as “harassment”.  the “personal info” is not their residential address or anything remotely threatening physically.  Even if you think those fines and arrests are justified, it doesn’t change the fact that those things can be done in the US, which means the US has greater freedom of speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570577394.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t actually state the UK had more freedom at any point, the difference is that in the US you have the ability to hate more intensely than we do without any repercussions. Do you think this is a good example of ‘greater’ freedom for all involved? I’ll stick to trying to get along with people, thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570611598.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>yes, it is literally more freedom.  freedom doesn’t mean just doing things you or the govt think are acceptable.  you talk about trying to get along with people but you’re the one in support of the police getting involved with fining people making dog videos on the internet and arresting people for twitter argument. 

in my book, getting along means leaving people alone and not using govt agents with guns to coerce people into not doing things you disapprove of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570662198.0" user="PanDiggit" delta="False">
    <text>You’re using racist videos and transgender slurs as examples of people trying to get along, listen to yourself! Again, assuming the government is responsible for my social values which is just nonsense. You want to spread hate go for it my man, nobody will stop you evidently. Live a happy life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570850533.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>nope.  a dog doing hitler salute is a funny joke, not racist.  that is why the UK hate speech laws is so dangerous.  it allows people like you to justify gestapo tactics to shut down speech that you don’t like by labeling it racist or hateful.  

i personally think your speech is hateful, by advocating for threat of state violence against people doing joke videos.  but i’m not calling for you to be fined or arrested.  it’s a good thing that we don’t have enough people like you to change the US constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35580160573.0" user="crambunker" delta="False">
    <text>good thing we don't have a constitution that tolerates nazism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35580195308.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>wrong.  we do.  the ACLU defended actual NAZIs’ right to march through a town filled with holocaust survivors.  that’s what makes America better, we defend everyone’s right to speech, not just people we agree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35580648652.0" user="crambunker" delta="False">
    <text>wasn't talking about the American constitution, I'm not American  


Claiming allowing Nazis to parade around Holocaust survivors makes America better isn't a proud hill to die on. Free speech should end where it incites violence, and being a Nazi is inherently violent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35580694994.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>nope, it’s not.  what came of allowing nazis to march in skokie IL?   nothing, no violence, just counter protest and arguments, which is what free speech was designed for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570098322.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Unless you insult a rich person...

https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.citynews1130.com/2020/05/29/rowling-spurling-twitter/amp/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
