<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35571444415.0" user="natkolbi" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of speech is not a get out of jail card to treat other people or groups of people as sub-human.

Your freedom stops when you start on infringing someone elses freedom. 

This is the case with racism for example. You're not allowed to send murder threats to people. Well, racism is basically a murder threat to an entire group of people.

The other is religious freedom, would you rate freedom of speech more important than freedom of religion? Then you misunderstood the concept of freedom. 

We have laws in place to secure civilzed living condition for ALL people. Those examples you mentioned were of people who were trying to take other peoples freedoms, which is not and should covered by freedom of speech, not in Europe and not in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35572132634.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>Getting your feelings hurt by someone else’s speech is not the same as getting your freedom infringed upon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35572291372.0" user="natkolbi" delta="False">
    <text>Are you actually suggesting victims of racism have just had their feelings hurt?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35572304929.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>Someone saying “i hate black people” or “i hate white people” hurts the black or white persons feelings, sure. But that does not in anyway infringe or restrict the black or white “victims” freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35576421448.0" user="natkolbi" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so now you're ignoring centuries of opression, slavery, murder and rape that goes on even today. You are also ignoring the fact that hate speech is also a crime in the US. You obviously don't want to understand.

Edit: a word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577755179.0" user="Manaliv3" delta="False">
    <text>Would you brew happy for me to stand outside your house all day and night shouting that you are a child molester and people should stab you? Or would that be something you'd consider unacceptable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578114352.0" user="MotherofPutin" delta="False">
    <text>Saying that he should be stabbed is a call to violence, so that's already illegal.

I certainly wouldn't be happy about someone standing outside my house and screaming at me, but as long as your not on my property, its not a crime. This aspect of free speech should be protected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578141509.0" user="Manaliv3" delta="False">
    <text>Well then you agree with the hate speech laws of the UK.

Except that over here we would consider the nutter spout i ng lies about us in the street to be a breach of the basic slander/harassment laws so they would have to go. That's how I like it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578661800.0" user="MotherofPutin" delta="False">
    <text>IF you sue them. The state shouldn't be enforcing speech laws using the police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578859612.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>No one would be happy, yet I don’t think the government should arrest you if you made a statement accusing me of being a child molester. That’s free speech.

They can and should arrest if you are threatening and calling for violence which is not protected free speech in America</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
