<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35568809309.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>And many of the things that are happening in the US wouldn't be happening in those countries such as:

- [Government organs fining and prohibiting swearwords and nudity on TV](https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/obscene-indecent-and-profane-broadcasts)
- [Editing a video to make it seem like one is singing a dirty song to minors](https://www.mediaite.com/online/youtube-comedian-gets-two-months-in-prison-after-appearing-to-sing-dirty-sex-song-to-kids/)—one would never even get any time in any of those countries for signing an  actual dirty song to minors
- [Free Speech Zones](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_speech_zone)—because one can not criticize one's leaders everywhere.

It's cherry picking, but there seems to be an overal pattern that in Europe it's harder to say things that could constitute an incitation to violence, and in the US it's harder to criticize one's leaders or use swearwords, sexuality or nudity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35568944627.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Variations on all of that exist in Europe, with the addition of blasphemy laws in many places.

As for your examples, the FCC one is the only one of real concern. Large gatherings, such as protests, need permits to keep things safe. Those "zones" while ugly, make security easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569075478.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Variations on all of that exist in Europe, with the addition of blasphemy laws in many places.

Examples?

And many US states also enact blasphemy laws in practice—sure you'd beat them when you get it to the supreme court, but that's a good example of "rights are the privilege of those with enough capital and time to file suit to defend them".

&amp;gt; Those "zones" while ugly, make security easy.

Yet they were somehow not needed before G.W. Bush and they are somehow not needed in other places.

Be real man: not allowing opposing views for the "safety" of the president? If I wanted to assassinate the president I'd just have a sign that supports to not draw attention and then shoot anyway.

This isn't for safety—this is to arouse the impression that they have more popular support than that they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35571470295.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;many US states also enact blasphemy laws in practice

Not, they don't.

&amp;gt;Yet they were somehow not needed before G.W. Bush and they are somehow not needed in other places.

They where unpopular so got dropped. I don't see the big deal.

&amp;gt;Be real man: not allowing opposing views for the "safety" of the president? If I wanted to assassinate the president I'd just have a sign that supports to not draw attention and then shoot anyway.

What? No. The secret service will not let you bring a gun to the President just because your a registered Republican.

And everyone had safety. What do you think was happening?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577226533.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blasphemy\_law\_in\_the\_United\_States](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blasphemy_law_in_the_United_States)

Similarly many European states have such old-timey laws that are almost never actually applied or become challenged when they get into effect. Like that paragraph that got attention when the German Comedian insulted Erdogan by exemplifying the difference between an insult and a valid parody.

And as far as I know the "blasphemy laws" aren't against blasphemy itself but against inciting riots because you deliberately offended religious groups to the point of violence with that. If they begrudgingly accept that then you're not charged. So it's not about the act of blasphemy, it's more of a special form of harassment and it's kind of criticized for that vagueness and the potential bullshit that can arise from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577423457.0" user="Manaliv3" delta="False">
    <text>There was some kid facing jail in the usa recently for pretending to fuck a statue of jesus. That's a blasphemy law right there</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35575115838.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Time place and manner restrictions, which is what protest zones are, have been in existence long before Bush.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577207822.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>And this isn't a TPM restriction; this is a _content_ restriction passed off as one.

The supporting side does get to show their support—that's the fundamental difference.

If you want to do a TPM you should treat all speech the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569537868.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>“Extreme views, such as paedophilia or anti semetism, need permits to keep things safe. These hate speech laws, while ugly, make the safety of Jews and children stronger”</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
