<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35568793076.0" user="h0m3r" delta="False">
    <text>Is your view just “USA has greater freedom of speech than Europe”, or is it “USA has greater freedom of speech than Europe, and this is a good thing”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569089792.0" user="WiseBlacksmith03" delta="False">
    <text>That was  my first question too.  I would argue that we are starting to prove to the world that the US has too much leeway on free speech. It is becoming more of an entitlement and excuse to commit slander, and spread disinformation.

Hell the whole "wearing a mask infringes on my freedoms' stance just goes to show how entitled and misinformed we are on freedoms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570082346.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Slander is one area where I'd say that the law in the US doesn't go far enough to protect free speech, despite going farther than most other countries.

It is far too easy in many states for a person to suppress critical speech just by suing anyone who criticizes them. Some states have laws that force people who bring frivolous defamation lawsuits to pay the legal costs of the defendant, but it isn't strong enough in most places, so it's easy to get around that.

If suing for slander is too easy, it's a serious threat to freedom of the press. If you're a newspaper and you learn that a rich and powerful person has *probably* done something bad, but reporting on it could put you through a costly legal battle even if it's true, why go through the trouble?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570180765.0" user="WiseBlacksmith03" delta="False">
    <text>I believe we have seen the opposite effect during the Trump administration.  He was able to spread disinformation, insults, name calling, and general discrediting towards anyone he viewed as an "opponent".  And it is all protected based on our slander/free speech guidelines for public figures...  


I don't see how we would want to expand on that?  Allowing free speech to the point where all truths and factual evidence is drowned out by 'who has the loudest voice'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35570496336.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>[Trump](https://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/02/donald-trump-libel-laws-219866) has often suggested that it needs to be easier to sue people for libel.

Of course, that would mean that some people could sue *him* more easily as well. But people like Trump would ultimately benefit; they can easily hire lawyers to both harass people who say bad things about them, and defend themselves in court for anyone who is willing to sue them. The end result is that good speech is suppressed just as easily as harmful propaganda.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
