<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1199233688.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jtzqmw/cmv_america_has_far_greater_freedom_of_speech/">
    <title>CMV: America has far greater freedom of speech than Europe.</title>
    <original_poster>achicomp</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that free speech is factually more free in America than the European Union + UK overall. None of the following ever happens in America and never could under the US constitution:

In Austria, a woman was **convicted for blasphemy** when she called the Prophet Muhammad a pedophile. In Austria, Germany and Poland the offence carries a potential prison sentence as well as a fine.

[https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp](https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/calling-muhammad-paedophile-not-protected-by-free-speech-1.3678825?mode=amp)

In France, 12 protesters were **fined** for supporting the boycott of Israel.

[https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467](https://www.ibtimes.com/israel-controversy-france-2015-pro-palestine-protesters-punishment-upheld-organizing-2155467)

In Denmark, a politician was **convicted for burning Korans.**

[https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election](https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-03/a-convicted-racist-joins-list-of-candidates-in-danish-election)

A German politician was **criminally charged** for calling migrants “scum.”

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/19/head-of-german-anti-islam-group-pegida-trial-hate-lutz-bachmann)

In England, a Baptist minister was **jailed overnight** for preaching against homosexuality and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela **joke**.

[https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/02/05/preacher-locked-hate-crime-quoting-bible-gay-teenager/)

[https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184](https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/news/local-news/shop-owner-quizzed-over-bernard-6383184)

Also in a poll of German citizens. Only 18% of Germans feel free to express their opinions in public. 59% of Germans did not even feel free expressing themselves in private among friends. And just 17% felt free to express themselves on the Internet. [https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html](https://www.welt.de/politik/article193977845/Deutsche-sehen-Meinungsfreiheit-in-der-Oeffentlichkeit-eingeschraenkt.html)

CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35568898314.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>So there seems to be couple of problems here. Most of your examples of the breach of free speech would be equally punished in US.

&amp;gt;In France, 12 protesters were fined for supporting the boycott of Israel.

In the recent events people were beaten, gassed, killed and of course charged by police officers because of peaceful demonstrations. Countries often use either security or hate-speech as a reason to deter people from protesting.

&amp;gt;In Denmark, a politician was convicted for burning Korans.

Typical hate-speech. There isn't even an excuse, a famous racist going to Muslim parts of cities being caught on tape literally inciting violence and "covering the Korans in the semen of Christian men". Yeah ...

&amp;gt;A German politician was criminally charged for calling migrants “scum.”

Incorrect, he was charged because of series of facebook post where he in lengthy posts called them cattle, trash, sub-human, etc... aaaand basically ticked every single box in order for this to be classified as hate speech. It's also important to mention that there was an actual terrorist organization arrested that planned to bomb refugee centers with illegal fireworks for some reason and they cited him as the reason for the bombing.

&amp;gt;In England, a Baptist minister was jailed overnight for preaching against homosexuality

This is an interesting one there is finally some nuance and not just racist commiting hate speech. So apparently the preacher as religious people tend to do in rural religious communities spent couple of hours explaining the wrongness of homosexuality to vulnerable young gay teen. The teen called police and acused the preacher for threatening and abusive behavior toward sexual orientation. The preacher spent night in jail and then he was cleared of all charges.

Personally I find it disgusting that religious authorities still are able to preach about how homosexuality is wrong in one on one session with kids. But the preacher was cleared of all charges so the system obviously worked on that instance. Altho I find it more comforting than threatening that preaching wrongness of homosexuality slowly becomes identical to hate speech.

&amp;gt; and a man was investigated for telling a Nelson Mandela joke.

Yeah this one is genuenly disturbing. It's the reason of US style patriot act in action where law enforcement agencies pick off certain keywords and put them on "terrorism watch" list and in this case it got them 8 hour interview with police. And this Mandela joke is more ridiculous result of this style of policing. But the man was not actually charged, but the fact that it went that far is concerning.

Now the only flat out wrong example in your comment is the first one.

&amp;gt;In Austria, a woman was convicted for blasphemy 

A blasphemy laws are fucking disgrace and there is reason that effectively only Austria has them (Ireland has them too, but never actually gets convicted because of the ridiculous standard for something being offensive). But other than that every single example is something that regularly happens in US too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35568953538.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>None of that happens in the US. Your attempts at drawing a moral parallel between officially sanctioned laws and some illegal edge cases in the US is absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569046359.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>Everything that you stated supports the idea that freedom of speech is indeed freer in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569530980.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I’d argue the protest stuff makes the US seem pretty bad for free speech. I live in the UK and there didn’t seem to be people destroying other people’s livelihoods, or on the flip side police committing brutality on peaceful protestors. 

I mean free speech is only useful insofar as it can be used practically. If North Korea doesn’t actually have any laws banning criticism of the state, but sends in riot police when people criticise the state, it’s still pretty blatantly a violation of free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35571329475.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Depends. Everybody who ever managed a forum knows that the single best kind of forum is well regulated one. Meaning that if you are free to ban trolls and brigaders for example, you are much more likely to achieve high quality content.

On the flip side the infamously anonymous 4chan is seen as the scum of the internet, exactly because there is no repercussion whatsoever.

In real life we have the concept of paradox of tolerance. Meaning that society that is tolerant without limit will get their ability seized by the intolerant. Therefore in order for tolerant society to exist you mut not tolerate intolerance.

Same idea goes for speech. If everything is permited it will eventually push some type of speech away and make your speech less free. The key part is balance. You can for example say whatever you want in theatre, as long as it's not the word fire, very loudly and repeatedly.

So far the main contention for the freedom of speech in Europe lies almost entirely within the realm of savage racism, sexism transphobia, etc... If those are your main scions of free speech, then I say that free speech is doing just fine.

The example of valid free speech violation in Europe is the blasphemy law in Austria for example which is an actual free speech disgrace. Or protesters being charged for peacefully protesting. But then again, taht shit is going in US right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35572170383.0" user="achicomp" delta="False">
    <text>Getting your feelings hurt by someone’s talk does not in any way take away your free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35654709974.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about feelings. We are humans, we have heard mentality. If you get people riled up, you can get regular people to get truly awful things because of that fact alone.

That's why there is difference between critieque and call to action, a true threat, etc... If a social group can't get their voice heard because of violence against them, then their speech isn't heard, forget it being free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35578078057.0" user="MotherofPutin" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP, but I have a quick question. I've heard of Popper's paradox of intolerance before, and the thing that stops me from swallowing the argument is this: how do we decide what counts as intolerant? Who gets to decide?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35654660260.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>In the same way who got to decide what the constitution is? No system is perfect, you just have to make sure to limit the inconsistencies.

Ideally you want a system that defines it's initial assumption like high court. And has some checks and ballances to hopefully prevent a faul play.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35574388490.0" user="MarkAndrewSkates" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed 👍</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35667396719.0" user="ZirillaFionaRianon" delta="False">
    <text>How exactly do they support that idea? You can be investigated and persecuted for most of the stuff that they cited in the US just as well as in the US. Not because you said Statement X, but because Statement X had certain consequences. Free speech doesn't mean being free of consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35569903492.0" user="thisdamnhoneybadger" delta="False">
    <text>you obviously don’t realize that hate speech cannot be legally punished under the first amendment in the US.  only speech that incites imminent harm can be punished, or true threats.  And no, harm and threat do not consist of hurt feelings</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35571117421.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; only speech that incites imminent harm can be punished, or true threats. And no, harm and threat do not consist of hurt feelings

Yep, otherwise called a free speech exception. Just need to check few paticular boxes in order to make it criminal case. Same in Europe but you have a bit more boxes about human dignity and threats can be aimed at groups etc... 

But the examples OP made tho qualify as criminal cases in US :D</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35573479174.0" user="Terpomo11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Altho I find it more comforting than threatening that preaching wrongness of homosexuality slowly becomes identical to hate speech.

So is the Bible hate speech now? It says 'thou shalt not lie with a man as thou liest with a woman' and such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35577736863.0" user="Manaliv3" delta="False">
    <text>No. Saying you are against homosexuality is not a crime. People might think you're a fool but that's it. Publicly calling for attacks on gay people would be the crime</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35579916827.0" user="Terpomo11" delta="False">
    <text>But the Bible explicitly calls for the execution of men who have sex with men, see Leviticus 20:13.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35654684247.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>So I'm not from US right. I'm form the middle of Europe and if I have seen the US style bible bashing preachers publicly disparaging gay people. I woul intiuitively think it's hate speech. Don't really know about the legal system tho. But it would get regular people upset, that would probably provoke some sort of response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35574937124.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>No such thing as hate speech in US jurisprudence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
