<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120501850.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zqrtm/for_the_sciences_a_masters_degree_is_considered_a/">
    <title>For the sciences, a master's degree is considered a failed phd. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>AI52487963</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, graduate science programs typically roll the master's degree into the phd program (ie, first 2 years is masters work, final 4 is phd). It is rare in the physics world, for example, to have a master's degree, as the jump typically goes from bachelor's to phd.

It's my view that in the professional world, people see master's degrees as failed phds and are worth as much. With the over-saturation of the job market by undergraduates, more and more employers are looking to those with graduate degrees for entry-level and internship-level positions. Yet, while a master's is technically considered a graduate degree, it is worthless for applying to graduate-level required education positions. This is because if an employer sets minimum requirements as a master's degree, that means a wide majority of those applying for the position will have phds.

Overseas in Europe, master's degrees in the sciences are more common, as they tend to be separate from the phd programs. In some cases, the master's degrees are rolled the opposite way into the undergraduate program, such that a 4 year undergrad program would include the master's courses and degree at the end. 

If a student from this background were applying for places that required minimum level master's degrees, they would be devalued by the flood of phds applying. On the other hand, if the master's degree holders were applying below their level, they would be cast aside from the fact that graduate-level degrees tend to demand higher wages than positions lower than that would support. Thus, for the sciences, a master's degree is too expensive for entry-level positions, yet too unqualified for positions at the graduate level, and thereby about as valuable as a failed phd.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27082279731.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;they would be cast aside from the fact that graduate-level degrees tend to demand higher wages than positions lower than that would support.

Can't this apply to phds?  Wouldn't a masters give someone an edge in an area that requires some higher level of education without having the wage-demand baggage that a phd requires so long as they apply within that scope?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
