<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084430631.0" user="electricmink" delta="False">
    <text>I am an atheist and so is my wife.  We donate a fair chunk of our household income to charities, including Red Cross for disaster relief, Goodwill, Doctors Without Borders, ASPCA, the local food bank, and the local no-kill animal shelter.

Make of that what you will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084495274.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>and I do not mean to belittle that. I just want to know why you do this? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084501776.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>Why does a theist give to charity? Would they stop giving to charity if they stopped believing in their god? If so, it means that they are only doing it to please their god, and not from a deep sense of compassion which is within them regardless of any theistic beliefs.

Atheists can, and very often do, have this deep sense of compassion and this desire to live in a world where everyone cares for everyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084597662.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>Human compassion and empathy?

You don't have to believe much to believe that some people need help and that you can provide it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084703076.0" user="electricmink" delta="False">
    <text>Because life is short and we have nobody else to turn to to fix the world's problems.  The responsibility rests squarely on our shoulders to help each other out - I can't just pray and pretend I've done something to help like the religious can, nor do I have some kind of twisted assurance that suffering in this life is somehow ennobling or will result in reward in the next.  There is no next life, this is all we get, and that makes it infinitely more important to do what we can to relieve the suffering of others here and now.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
