<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084416887.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Well, atheism isn't a philosophy..  It's absence of theism.  You don't need to label yourself to show others compassion - just show it.  If some people that so happen to be atheists are semantic and argue trivial inconsistencies, who cares?  There are plenty of jobs where that way of thought is mandatory.  If you don't like them, don't associate, but you can't really be in the right when you're calling someone out for being correct, no matter how pedantic.  

I guess I'm this 'legalistic' type person as well, but it's only because I live in a society that I don't feel properly understands my position before they start having their vocal opinions of it.  You know, the 'I sat around an *evil*utionary camp fire last night.  Guess what?  The fire didn't come from nothing' crowd.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
