<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084369745.0" user="ThatsSoRighteous" delta="False">
    <text>This is not a view. This is your dislike towards atheists that you meet. You have nothing to say other than your opinion of random people that you are presumably representing accurately. Also, are you intoxicated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084377200.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>If you had read the entire description, you would also find that I am curious to know what 'dogma' or argument atheists have to help other people.

Also, yes, this is a view. If I was a racist, then my view would be that people that are not in my race is inferior. That is a view, bad as it is, but it still is a something that people base their decision. That's a view. It's a view that I have met a lot of bad people and that I want to get to meet other atheists and their views. I am curious and want to understand the mindset of secular 'humanity'

Also, I never claimed that I have a representative sample. I wanted to meet people on reddit that could have an answer to this and, perhaps I had framed the question in an incorrect frame, but I had innocent intentions.

If you are so insecure in your beliefs (atheism is a belief based on logic and reason) that you view this as an attack on atheists, then you didn't read the whole thing. I am AGNOSTIC, not religious, not even close. And if you say "you are not a true agnostic", apparently, I could claim the same thing against you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084392204.0" user="ThatsSoRighteous" delta="False">
    <text>Being racist would be considered a belief because true racism is unjustified and without empirical reason. A view is something that has real reasons justifying the standpoint. What you offer is your experiences.

&amp;gt;"They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' "

Your conclusion doesn't follow the premise and your premise is your opinion. Your opinion based off an unfairly represented, narrow-scoped demographic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084554383.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>As an atheist, I don't believe anyone up there is looking out for us, so we have to look out for each other. 

We're all on this rock together, so we should probably try to help out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084708062.0" user="Facetious_Otter" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; to know what 'dogma' or argument atheists have to help other people.

None. Atheism is the lack of belief in a claim. Do you think people who are short have a dogma to help other people? Do bald people? Because that's what it's sounding like *you* believe.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
