<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628531628.0" user="alskdj29" delta="False">
    <text>I think women want men that are successful or have the potential to be. There are a lot of people who are not by any stretch of the imagination and do not show the potential to be either. Being physically attractive is only one of many metrics to determine this success/potential success. There is very good reason for this as it is a predictor of ability to secure resources. Since women when pregnant are restricted in their ability to do that to an extent.

I actually think, in this society it is easier for less attractive men to succeed. Imagine if the only metric was physical appearance then most of the pool would be eliminated. Since there are other means IE wealth it gives a person with an undesirable quality like being shy and or ugly has a chance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628572200.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Yes , but as long as looks are not changeable and it plays a sginficiant role it must be discussed. Perhaps in the future genetic engineering will create humans who do not look so different from each other and do not have determined advantages, yes I have familiarised myself with how look are not everything but they play a role in every social interaction even between same sexes</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
