<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084407286.0" user="skulder7" delta="False">
    <text>You raise a number of points that I find questionable.

You say that atheists are judgmental. Judgmental how? I can say with certainty that there are many Christians who are judgmental. Hell, judgment is built right into the ideology (barring some of the more liberal branches) with the idea of heaven and hell. Individual atheists may be judgmental, but it's a flaw of those people, not of atheism itself (which doesn't have judgment directly ingrained in it). Atheism doesn't require judgment. I think the key concept here is that people who believe they know something about the universe that others don't are judgmental to their "less enlightened" peers. This applies to certain people of all belief systems, Christian and Muslim and Atheist alike.

I'm not exactly sure what you're talking about when you mention "emotional cliques", but it seems like an interesting point that could use some more clarification. Obviously, atheists are going to care more about their loved ones than about other people. That's true about people with any beliefs. I'm not sure what you mean by attacking people who "step out of line" though. I haven't heard of any groups of atheists that go around beating up Christians.

On the topic of pettiness, welcome to debate. As an atheist, I get the exact same response from Christians. People in general tend to shut down when faced with evidence contradicting their belief systems. I'd like to believe that atheists are more resistant to it because they already had to break out of a belief system in the first place to become an atheist, but I can see how they might be prone to over-reaction. Mind you, the specifics can be important in some cases (especially with some of the semantical arguments for the existence of God).

As far as the philosophy goes, how about plain old Humanism? Humanism is all about valuing human beings. Valuing people tends to correlate with treating them kindly and compassionately. In general, it does feel good to do good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
