<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084403278.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving.

Are you sure that's not nostalgia? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084499299.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>Nostalgia? Perhaps. I want to believe that there is a God. I'm pretty sure we all do. I mean we all desire to be loved and to have a 'family' no matter how ridiculous this may be.

I have been a Christian for a very long time. About 18 years. I've heard of people (former Christians turned atheist) that these feelings (fear of hell) sticks like a 'virus'. I disagree in a way. I have always been somewhat spiritual and I find that Christianity was a way for me express this. 

I also consider myself a rational mind. I have always had a knack for science and math. maybe I may always hold on to those values that I had grown up with. Maybe that makes me a pseudo-Christian and pseudo-atheist. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084508154.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have been a Christian for a very long time. About 18 years. I've heard of people (former Christians turned atheist) that these feelings (fear of hell) sticks like a 'virus'.

I was 19 when I stopped going to church; and 20 before I was conformable with the title atheist; I never feared hell, instead what I miss is the dopamine hit from prayer.

Nothing I can say can really help you through that; but what ever, just remember the truth doesn't need to train children with emotional triggers for people to believe it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
