<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084706893.0" user="Facetious_Otter" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good.

I take it you mean atheist? Every atheist is different. This like saying "Anyone who likes the color blue is an asshole!" 

It makes absolutely no sense and makes *you* seem like an asshole.

&amp;gt;I have been an agnostic for some time now. 

An agnostic what? Atheist or theist? Since you were a Christian, it sounds like you're an atheist. You just called yourself an asshole.

*Everyone* does this. It doesn't matter if you're, black, white, Christian, atheist, or believe in the all-power Cthulhu, you're going to form some kind of clique. 

&amp;gt;So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?

Please don't tell me what my moral compass it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
