<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084515881.0" user="ohmephisto" delta="False">
    <text>[Secular Humanism](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secular_humanism). It's the ethical movement for caring about people without religion and superstition. I'm a secular humanist, atheist and skeptic not only because I like to follow science and reason, but also because I care about people. I do think that many religious beliefs and practices are not beneficial to an individual's life. A Baptist friend of mine once said that us humans were inferior, bad creatures. Is that a healthy way to think of yourself? If you didn't have the notion of divine punishments and sin, would you still be just as likely to feel ashamed of your body and carnal desires? My mom believes in ghosts, and gets easily scared when there's something unexplained happening (like she thought she turned off a lamp, but it was still shining). When I try to instill into her some critical thinking, I do that to ease her fears and make life easier. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
