<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084383774.0" user="pinkfatticorn" delta="False">
    <text>I am an atheist, and I think that youre hanging out with the wrong type of PEOPLE. Sure, some atheists are selfish assholes, but some religious people are like that as well. 

You say that atheists are devoid of compassion, and I find this odd. In my limited experience, the atheists that I have met in real life are kind people. They, as well as myself, believe that the current state of things is all we have. So, in order to enjoy it to it fullest, we have to try and improve the world in some way. I know many people who volunteer, and are very compassionate people. I personally have volunteered many times; not out of obligation, but by the fact that I legitimately want to help as many people as I can live a happy life. To me, a sad and abused life is the worst thing that could possibly happen to a person, because this is all there is. 


I think that most atheists do not openly talk about it, and so, youre probably meeting the vocal assholes. Much like, how people see and hear the vocal asshole religious people first. That is a two way street. It is all about what youre exposed to! More than likely youre surrounded by nice, decent people, who are atheists! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084386533.0" user="atomheartother" delta="False">
    <text>This. This is hardly a case of believing in god or not, it's just a matter of being a dick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084387291.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>yes. I totally agree with you! I have been with the wrong people. And I am still young so all of them were probably suffering from some teenage angst. 

and yes, the squeakiest wheel gets the most attention. 

I also find in my short experience in college that the agnostics and atheists are often nicer than the religious people. 

Is there any books or literature I could read about this? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084395675.0" user="pinkfatticorn" delta="False">
    <text>Which subject specifically would you like to learn about? Being a good person with out religion? Meeting atheists? Joining good atheist organizations? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084499448.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>yeah all of that please!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084611443.0" user="WideEyedLeaver" delta="False">
    <text>Well, an introductory Moral Philosophy textbook can start you off on the 'good person without religion' direction.  The anthologies edited by Louis Pojman are good, I've got a couple.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084399520.0" user="pinkfatticorn" delta="False">
    <text>Here is an article that may not be exactly what youre looking for but kinda illustrate my point. It is a livescience article about atheists being motivated by compassion
[articllleee!!](http://www.livescience.com/20005-atheists-motivated-compassion.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084423953.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, not all atheists are nihilistic anti-theists. The most controversial and extreme elements tend to get the most attention.

The image on this page [Warning: TvTropes Link](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/VocalMinority) gives an excellent illustration of the distortion. 



Looking at your last sentence maybe this simple sentence could work humanist or not, "To reduce and prevent suffering." 

EDIT for clarification: Nihilistic types aren't inherently bad. The vocal elements of any group can give it a bad name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27086116599.0" user="electricmink" delta="False">
    <text>I'd take issue with your implication that "nihilistic anti-theistd" are the group of non-empathetic assholes OP is referring to.  I am a nihilist in that I do not believe life serves any particular purpose or meaning, and I am a vocal anti-theist, firmly convinced that religion is a huge contributor to humanities problems and does significantly more harm than good - we'd be altogether better off without it.

You might find me an asshole because I will oftentimes challenge people on their religious convictions when they drag them out in public inappropriately or use them to justify hatred, bigotry, or other destructive behaviors, and I will often be quite harsh about it, offering little quarter and making my disdain for their position perfectly clear...

...but I also argue strongly for showing human compassion, accepting each other's flaws, working together to improve the world around us, I staunchly defend the rights of religious people to follow their conscience (up to the point where their beliefs step on the rights of others, anyways) despite the fact I think they are dead wrong, and I am firmly aware that we are all just a bunch of ignorant apes stumbling about in the dark and that none of us have all the answers - we're all wrong on something, and its okay, because we're all human beings and that humanity comes first.

I volunteer.  I give to charity.  I rescue animals.  I'm working toward becoming a good enough musician to volunteer at the local children's hospital during my off hours and maybe bring some smiles to sick kids' faces.  My compassion for humanity is a big part of my passionate arguments *against* religion, my confrontational approach to faith-driven injustices and the destruction they drive.

But to hear you tell it, I am a compassionless asshole evangelist out to force my beliefs on everyone else and out to belittle people of faith because, you know, "asshole".  I'll be the first to admit I am far from perfect, but please don't be so quick to write people's like me off, eh?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27086161856.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Point taken. Not all in that camp are out to cause strife.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084532337.0" user="shittastes" delta="False">
    <text>I think that some of the atheists that get angry at any ideas of God lived/met with some intolerant religious people, so they associate every mention of God with that intolerance. It's not a fair judgment from their part, but they at least have some reasons. It's not just blind hate, it's human psychology. Some will grow out of it in time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084761629.0" user="pinkfatticorn" delta="False">
    <text>That anger can also be said for religious people.;it not specific to atheists. You are right in that it isnt blind hate, and some people do grow into tolerance. Most people, learn to not spew their opinions where they arent wanted. I direct that at both groups. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
