<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084403866.0" user="fnredditacct" delta="False">
    <text>One of the main criticisms I've heard from religious people about non-religion and atheism is subjective morality.

But I think that very 'problem,' and the problem you describe as I understand it, is also the answer.

Without a "boss" each person *is* left to try to decide for themselves what is good or bad or even more basically practical or impractical, or whatever standards they have.

If there isn't a founding philosophy of compassion, neither is there a founding philosophy of mercilessness.

Which means perhaps there is nothing reining a serious asshole, but likewise there is nothing persuading a compassionate person to ostracize another.

People who get preachy about their beliefs, IMO, generally fall into the asshole camp. Which means, quite unfortunately, that we tend to hear or "learn" about different beliefs from assholes.

I am not an atheist, so there might actually be core philosophies of which I am quite unaware. But something that caught my eye in the wiki article that looks like it needs further investigation: 

"Atheism is accepted within some religious and spiritual belief systems, including Hinduism, Jainism, Buddhism, Raelism, Neopagan movements[19] such as Wicca,[20] and nontheistic religions. Jainism and some forms of Buddhism do not advocate belief in gods,[21] whereas Hinduism holds atheism to be valid, but some schools view the path of an atheist to be difficult to follow in matters of spirituality"

So it seems like practicing different kinds of religious traditions (which would include compassion) is possible (and even accepted?) without the belief in a god. Which was news to me, and I'm interested to read more on this.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
