<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="120718528.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1zvf0g/i_find_that_atheists_are_devoid_of_compassion_for/">
    <title>I find that atheists are devoid of compassion for humanity. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>lifecmcs</original_poster>
    <original_post>When I was a Christian, I found there were assholes mostly but there also seemed to be a profound desire to do good. And when it did happen, it was so fucking relieving. 

I have been an agnostic for some time now. But I feel that people are not very compassionate. They are judgment and form emotional cliques. So their entire moral compass is based on protecting these loved ones and attacking those who 'step out of line?' On top of that, many atheists that I have met are often pretty petty about their ideas and, if something sounds slightly off or 'wrong', they try and shut you down immediately instead of listening. They seem to be completely legalistic.

Is there an humanist or atheist 'philosophy' out there that promote compassion for other people?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27084383297.0" user="phridoo" delta="False">
    <text>This is similar to saying "I think Christians are quick to judge others" or "I find that Muslims are violent". It's a generalization and I'm trying not to be offended. I am a compassionate person but maybe for different reasons than some religious people are. I am compassionate because it feels right and because society works better if we work together and we work together better if we care about each other. I'm not compassionate to impress others or to get into heaven. I don't 'love my neighbor' because a book told me to, but because my neighbor deserves it. I might also argue that some religious people love humanity less because they think humanity is inherently evil (original sin) and assume that they'll hurt each other without the threat of punishment from a higher being. I don't think this is true of most humans. I don't think there is any specifically atheist philosophy, period. Why give up religion to adopt another dogma? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084388995.0" user="lifecmcs" delta="False">
    <text>I was being too general. I didn't mean to be general but I am just frustrated that there doesn't seem to be anything done for anyone anymore. Food stamps, welfare, etc. are being cut by 'religious pro-life' Republicans. 

I think a secular world view is the way to change the world and make it a better place. I just want to know how. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27084403980.0" user="phridoo" delta="False">
    <text>I see. Well I think holding politicians accountable for ignoring the separation of church &amp;amp; state &amp;amp; making decisions based on their view of religious law instead of societal law like they should be doing is a step in the right direction. I also think the current pope is, perhaps ironically, extremely helpful in this. I think you'll find though that people, on their own &amp;amp; without it being mandated by government do a lot to help their fellow humans. Churches do a lot of this too so I'm not leaving religious people out of this by any means. Though I don't think Churches should be tax exempt for this or any other reason. What you can do personally is contact your representatives in the government and vote. You can start attending your city or town's council meetings and ask questions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
