<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="121696279.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/20gdg7/i_think_reddit_has_misinterpreted_the_purpose_of/">
    <title>I think reddit has misinterpreted the purpose of the White House petition website. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>The purpose of the "We the People" website is so the federal government can keep tabs on what people are concerned about. Modeled after similar sites like those that governments in the EU have set up, it's a new way for citizens to interact with the government and vice versa. It's an easy way for the executive branch to keep track of the zeitgeist without using too much in the way of PR resources.

The purpose of the website is so you can voice your concerns. If there's enough attention given by users to one concern, then someone will listen and respond. That's it. The White House has *never* indicated that any of these petitions would affect real policy. Never.

In fact, it's not that far from petitions have traditionally worked. Civil petitions are just a formal request and show of solidarity; on their own, they are rarely effective at directly influencing policy.

So in that sense, the "We the People" website is far from the farce that /r/worldnews or /r/politics proclaims it to be.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27093836168.0" user="Thoguth" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I missed something, but what does reddit proclaim it to be? Is there an official statement on the matter somewhere?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27093865061.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/20dd49/sopa_is_returning/cg29nah

http://www.reddit.com/r/nottheonion/comments/1yjdwc/deport_bieber_petition_is_secondhighest_ever_on/cflchjp</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27093892303.0" user="Thoguth" delta="False">
    <text>Even in those comment threads, there are varying positions on what it is supposed to be.

One says it's to create an NSA watch list (which I think is unlikely, but given all the other unlikely things the NSA has done that doesn't rule it out.)

Another say it's to get a list of email addresses sorted by issue, which  I am absolutely 100% certain is part of its goal. As someone who has worked in email marketing, and has signed a petition, and has received email relevant to that petition, it is beyond a doubt to me that yes, at least part of the goal here is to target email propaganda from the executive branch.

Another says "they don't take it seriously" and along the same lines "they don't follow their own rules about what gets a response." Well... do they follow those rules?

If you're saying Reddit treats We the People as if every request that passes the bar is supposed to become law, and it's a farce if it doesn't, I don't see anything in any of those threads that supports that.  If you're saying Reddit treats We the People as if every request that passes the bar is supposed to get an official response and it's a farce if it doesn't... I think that's pretty much in line with how I see Reddit treating it, and with what you are saying too. If it's a PR site that promises official attention given for #n signatures and then doesn't give official attention to those things that have #n signatures, then yes I think it's fair to say it's not doing what it should.

There are a lot of "ifs" there ... I still think it would be easier if you just spelled out precisely in your own words what you see is the difference between Reddit's opinion of it and what it actually is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27093920843.0" user="trefitch" delta="False">
    <text>And now the White House knows just how opposed we are to a fictional bill created in redditors' minds due to their lack of reading comprehension.

In seriousness though, I do like the website but I think it's fair criticism to complain about the canned responses. They dangle this carrot of "X number of votes gets a response" but the response is always just the same talking points you see on Capital Hill and at White House press releases. I haven't read all of them but the only response I can think of that actually satisfied the petition signers was the [Ale to the Chief](https://petitions.whitehouse.gov/response/ale-chief-white-house-beer-recipe) White House beer recipe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27094258477.0" user="Hk37" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, a fair portion of the stuff posted is either something that the president has no control over (e.g., the current "stop SOPA 2014" one), things that are obvious jokes (e.g., the Death Star), or even illegal (e.g., the "deport Justin Bieber!" petition). People use the site to petition for things that aren't possible, then complain abut how no one ever listens to the petitions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
