<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="122203992.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/20r97c/i_believe_that_it_is_in_the_strategic_best/">
    <title>I believe that it is in the strategic best interests of the US to militarily intervene in Ukraine. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TEmpTom</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) The Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances. Negotiated by Ukraine, the US, the UK, and Russia in accordance to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, Ukraine should give up its nuclear arms in exchange for "protection." These "protections" specify to

&amp;gt;Seek United Nations Security Council action if nuclear weapons are used against Ukraine.

&amp;gt; and 

&amp;gt;Consult with one another if questions arise regarding these commitments.

Though, the treaty does not specify any defensive pact between these powers and Ukraine if the country is invaded or threatened militarily, I still believe that it would be in the best interests of the US to treat the Budapest Memorandum as one. Due to the nature of the agreement, with vague assurances of protection in exchange for complete nuclear proliferation of the country, it would set a terrible precedent for future nuclear proliferation negotiations with countries who have just developed their nuclear arms if Ukraine is so easily attacked with close to no assistance from other powers whatsoever. Though, the Budapest Memorandum does not guarantee protection from nuclear powers, it will be interpreted as such by politicians in countries seeking nuclear weapons. Negotiations would be increasingly  difficult if they cannot guarantee protection from larger powers if they were to be attacked like Ukraine. 

2) It sets another terrible precedent of justifying foreign invasion based on a protection of ethnic [insert people of invading country here], and also a precedent of invasions and annexations without consequence. Without western response, more countries may consider it justified to invade or annex parts of weaker destabilized countries using this very excuse. A US/NATO military response may ensure that other countries seeking to invade and annex their neighboring countries could not do so without a consequence of US/NATO retaliation. Though, they may seek some other equally trumped up justification, the mere show of force in Ukraine in response to an invading force may as well deter many similar situations in the future.

3) It will weaken Russia internationally, and possibly gain the US new allies and new NATO members. A military defeat of the Russian military by US/NATO forces will definitely weaken Russia's influence regionally, and globally. Syria would possibly lose most of their support from their biggest ally, and the Russian international prestige and economy would undoubtedly be extremely weakened by their reputation in the war. Ex-Soviet states both in Eastern Europe, and Central Asia may see the threat of the Russian invasion of Ukraine to be possibly threatening to their sovereignty in the future, as well as the US' integrity in defending their allies, and other invaded nations as an assurance to their security if they joined NATO. Ukraine is definitely going to join NATO, and nobody wants to be the second Ukraine in this situation, so many of them may immediately apply for membership.

4) Diplomacy has failed, and I do not believe that the Russians will back away from the Crimea and respect Ukraine's sovereignty within its current borders with anything short of military force. I believe that sanctions would be completely ineffective to solve the current issue at hand. Even if they did hurt Russia's economy in the long run, Crimea would be long a part of Russia, and no amount of economic downturn would ever make the Russians give up that territory. 

**Why I believe US military intervention would be relatively non-disastrous.**

1) People keep saying "Russia's a nuclear power. Its going to be WW3. Nuclear holocaust" etc. I do not believe that anyone is stupid enough to escalate a regional conflict into a full scale nuclear war even if the US decides to intervene. No one is going to throw nukes at each other, not tactically or otherwise, the concept of MAD still exists. The only possibility of Russia using a nuke is 1) NATO forces have capture Moscow, and Russia is on the brink of total defeat, or 2) In retaliation to an enemy nuclear strike. Neither of these situations are going to happen in a regional conventional war between the US and Russia.

2) People say "This is going to be another Iraq/Afghan war. We don't want to spend another 3 trillion dollars on another war." Although, an intervention would cost some money, it won't be nearly as expensive as the Iraq and Afghan wars. With clear objectives to defend a country against a foreign invader, and not to invade a country to topple their government, a US military intervention would look similar to the Gulf War on a larger scale. 

3) "Europe depends on Russian oil, so the Russians have the EU by the balls." Currently, Russian oil makes up about 32.6% of total oil imports in the EU, and undoubtedly the EU will suffer from slight oil shortages in the short term. However, the US, Canada, and Saudi Arabia could use this opportunity to establish themselves as primary providers of oil to Europe. In the long term, the massive European oil market would benefit theses countries greatly, and the EU has just made itself energy independent from a major geo-political enemy. Slight price controlled exports of oil to Europe may be needed to alleviate shortages in the short run, but ultimately all of these countries would benefit from having Europe energy independent from Russia. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27099756848.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I do not believe that anyone is stupid enough to escalate a regional conflict into a full scale nuclear war even if the US decides to intervene.

It's not a regional conflict in that sense.

From the Russian perspective, it would be an invasion of Russia.

If someone invaded us and we could not repel the invasion with conventional arms, there would *certainly* be substantial support for threatening the use of nuclear weapons, and once we'd made the threat, there would be substantial support for carrying out the threat (because doing otherwise would reveal our threats to be hollow).

I don't want to run that risk. As much as I think Russia is clearly in the wrong here, it's not worth risking the world over.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
