<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="122203992.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/20r97c/i_believe_that_it_is_in_the_strategic_best/">
    <title>I believe that it is in the strategic best interests of the US to militarily intervene in Ukraine. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TEmpTom</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) The Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances. Negotiated by Ukraine, the US, the UK, and Russia in accordance to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, Ukraine should give up its nuclear arms in exchange for "protection." These "protections" specify to

&amp;gt;Seek United Nations Security Council action if nuclear weapons are used against Ukraine.

&amp;gt; and 

&amp;gt;Consult with one another if questions arise regarding these commitments.

Though, the treaty does not specify any defensive pact between these powers and Ukraine if the country is invaded or threatened militarily, I still believe that it would be in the best interests of the US to treat the Budapest Memorandum as one. Due to the nature of the agreement, with vague assurances of protection in exchange for complete nuclear proliferation of the country, it would set a terrible precedent for future nuclear proliferation negotiations with countries who have just developed their nuclear arms if Ukraine is so easily attacked with close to no assistance from other powers whatsoever. Though, the Budapest Memorandum does not guarantee protection from nuclear powers, it will be interpreted as such by politicians in countries seeking nuclear weapons. Negotiations would be increasingly  difficult if they cannot guarantee protection from larger powers if they were to be attacked like Ukraine. 

2) It sets another terrible precedent of justifying foreign invasion based on a protection of ethnic [insert people of invading country here], and also a precedent of invasions and annexations without consequence. Without western response, more countries may consider it justified to invade or annex parts of weaker destabilized countries using this very excuse. A US/NATO military response may ensure that other countries seeking to invade and annex their neighboring countries could not do so without a consequence of US/NATO retaliation. Though, they may seek some other equally trumped up justification, the mere show of force in Ukraine in response to an invading force may as well deter many similar situations in the future.

3) It will weaken Russia internationally, and possibly gain the US new allies and new NATO members. A military defeat of the Russian military by US/NATO forces will definitely weaken Russia's influence regionally, and globally. Syria would possibly lose most of their support from their biggest ally, and the Russian international prestige and economy would undoubtedly be extremely weakened by their reputation in the war. Ex-Soviet states both in Eastern Europe, and Central Asia may see the threat of the Russian invasion of Ukraine to be possibly threatening to their sovereignty in the future, as well as the US' integrity in defending their allies, and other invaded nations as an assurance to their security if they joined NATO. Ukraine is definitely going to join NATO, and nobody wants to be the second Ukraine in this situation, so many of them may immediately apply for membership.

4) Diplomacy has failed, and I do not believe that the Russians will back away from the Crimea and respect Ukraine's sovereignty within its current borders with anything short of military force. I believe that sanctions would be completely ineffective to solve the current issue at hand. Even if they did hurt Russia's economy in the long run, Crimea would be long a part of Russia, and no amount of economic downturn would ever make the Russians give up that territory. 

**Why I believe US military intervention would be relatively non-disastrous.**

1) People keep saying "Russia's a nuclear power. Its going to be WW3. Nuclear holocaust" etc. I do not believe that anyone is stupid enough to escalate a regional conflict into a full scale nuclear war even if the US decides to intervene. No one is going to throw nukes at each other, not tactically or otherwise, the concept of MAD still exists. The only possibility of Russia using a nuke is 1) NATO forces have capture Moscow, and Russia is on the brink of total defeat, or 2) In retaliation to an enemy nuclear strike. Neither of these situations are going to happen in a regional conventional war between the US and Russia.

2) People say "This is going to be another Iraq/Afghan war. We don't want to spend another 3 trillion dollars on another war." Although, an intervention would cost some money, it won't be nearly as expensive as the Iraq and Afghan wars. With clear objectives to defend a country against a foreign invader, and not to invade a country to topple their government, a US military intervention would look similar to the Gulf War on a larger scale. 

3) "Europe depends on Russian oil, so the Russians have the EU by the balls." Currently, Russian oil makes up about 32.6% of total oil imports in the EU, and undoubtedly the EU will suffer from slight oil shortages in the short term. However, the US, Canada, and Saudi Arabia could use this opportunity to establish themselves as primary providers of oil to Europe. In the long term, the massive European oil market would benefit theses countries greatly, and the EU has just made itself energy independent from a major geo-political enemy. Slight price controlled exports of oil to Europe may be needed to alleviate shortages in the short run, but ultimately all of these countries would benefit from having Europe energy independent from Russia. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27099282762.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 2) People say "This is going to be another Iraq/Afghan war. We don't want to spend another 3 trillion dollars on another war." Although, an intervention would cost some money, it won't be nearly as expensive as the Iraq and Afghan wars. With clear objectives to defend a country against a foreign invader, and not to invade a country to topple their government, a US military intervention would look similar to the Gulf War on a larger scale.

This argument only holds if you believe that the Iraq Army in 1991 is roughly equivalent to the Russian Army today, which is simply not true.  The Russian Army is significantly larger, better trained, and better equipped than the Iraqi Army in Kuwait was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099290356.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>My point was, that this would be a war of liberation and defense. Unlike Afghanistan and Iraq, the US would not have to occupy a hostile area, and spend trillions on rebuilding their government. That's why I said it was like the Gulf War, but on a much larger scale. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099301336.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>You are making a lot of assumptions here, which I don't think you have the evidence to support.

1) You assume the local population of Crimea will see this as a liberation, rather than an invasion.  If Crimeans have to pick a side between the US and Russia, at least some of them will side with Russia.  We made the assumption in Iraq that we would be greeted as liberators.  We were wrong.

2) A much larger scale implies a much larger cost.  And after you liberate it, you need to protect it.  If the enough of the local population isn't supportive of this, you absolutely would be occupying a hostile area, one with a well armed neighbor willing to supply arms to an insurgency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099309371.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1) The local population of Crimea will see this as a liberation, rather than an invasion. If Crimeans have to pick a side between the US and Russia, at least some of them will side with Russia.

The referendum with a 97% majority asking for annexation is obviously a sham. Though I don't doubt that a majority does want to be independent from Ukraine, its not nearly as many as you would think. Also, considering that Crimea was part of Ukraine less than a month ago with no problems whatsoever. 

&amp;gt;2) A much larger scale implies a much larger cost. And after you liberate it, you need to protect it. If the enough of the local population isn't supportive of this, you absolutely would be occupying a hostile area, one with a well armed neighbor willing to supply arms to an insurgency.

Forming a coalition would be a larger cost, and victory against Russia, although inevitable, would be much more difficult than a victory against Iraq. The objectives would be clear, and occupation of the a small area such as the Crimea could easily be done by Ukrainian forces. Of course, liberating the Crimea would involve cutting off all supply lines from the Crimea to Russia, so supplying Crimea would be extremely difficult considering the geography, and the small size of the area. I also doubt that there would be much insurgency because the are was completely peaceful just about a month ago, and there were close to no signs of rebellion without Russian interference. This intervention will cost tremendously less than our wars in Iraq and Afghanistan because most of the cost of war doesn't come from deployment or combat, but from rebuilding and restructuring a government once the actual fighting is over.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099328672.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The referendum with a 97% majority asking for annexation is obviously a sham. Though I don't doubt that a majority does want to be independent from Ukraine, its not nearly as many as you would think. Also, considering that Crimea was part of Ukraine less than a month ago with no problems whatsoever.

I agree that 97% is an overstatement, but even if half that number supports Russia, that is a significant issue that cannot simply be discounted.  

&amp;gt; occupation of the a small area such as the Crimea could easily be done

Do you have any sources to back you up on this?  This same argument was made in 2003 for Iraq, that it would be an easy fight, that we would be greeted as liberators, and that it would be cheap.  None of those happened.

&amp;gt; there were close to no signs of rebellion without Russian interference

Irrelevant now.  Russia is clearly interfering now, and will be for quite some time.

&amp;gt; because most of the cost of war doesn't come from deployment or combat, but from rebuilding and restructuring a government once the actual fighting is over

I can't imagine the US military vs the Russian military fighting in Crimea will leave much, if any, infrastructure standing when the shooting is done.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099339484.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I agree that 97% is an overstatement, but even if half that number supports Russia, that is a significant issue that cannot simply be discounted.

If only a small majority opposes Ukrainian governance, then insurgency would be negligible. Unlike with places like Iraq where the entire damn population hates your presence. 

&amp;gt;Do you have any sources to back you up on this? This same argument was made in 2003 for Iraq, that it would be an easy fight, that we would be greeted as liberators, and that it would be cheap. None of those happened.

We tried to overthrow the Iraqi government in 2003, and establish a puppet government while trying to rebuild their destroyed infrastructure in a hostile area. In the Crimea, the Ukrainians would be doing most of the work. 

&amp;gt;Irrelevant now. Russia is clearly interfering now, and will be for quite some time.

It shows that they weren't really up in arms to begin with. Once the Russians are forcibly expelled, I think the population would settle down too with minor insurgencies.

&amp;gt;I can't imagine the US military vs the Russian military fighting in Crimea will leave much, if any, infrastructure standing when the shooting is done.

I would just like to see them cut off any supply lines from Russia to the Crimea, and forcing the remaining isolated Russian soldiers to surrender and leave. Kind of like a siege. Even if the fighting destroys a lot of stuff, the Crimea is much smaller than Iraq, and it will be occupied by Ukrainian forces, not the US, the government will be Ukrainian, not a US established government, and investment to rebuild infrastructure would come from the US, EU, and Ukraine. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27099752207.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the US would not have to occupy a hostile area

That's really tremendously unclear.

I do not accept the referendum results as legitimate. That said, it is clear that there is a substantial population in Crimea which *is* in favor of union with Russia, and that population would be hostile.

We know that Ukraine is not capable of maintaining control of Crimea in the presence of Russian special forces, so we'd end up having to be there for a long time, in the face of hostile opposition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27100191605.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>I think I've mentioned this in another thread. The population in Crimea, though probably mostly pro-Russian, is not overwhelmingly so. Just about a month ago, when Kiev was in in protests/riots, the Crimea was rather complacent, showing almost no signs of revolt or rebellion. Only after the Russian invasion, did Crimeans begin to be more vocal in their pro-Russian stance, and I think it is very likely that those are only a very vocal minority. 

If the US expels Russian military presence in the region, it is very likely that Crimea would return to its pre-demonstration state about a month ago. Though, some minor insurgency may still exist, its nothing the Ukrainian military can't handle on their own. Remember, Crimea is much smaller and much more geographically isolated than Iraq or Afghanistan. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
