<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="122999970.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/218bdu/i_think_that_some_industries_that_arent_currently/">
    <title>I think that some industries that aren't currently nationally standardized should be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are two industries in particular that I feel should be at the very least standardized throughout the USA. The first is the clothing industry. From pants to shoes to shirts, sizing is incredibly varied. I bought a pair of Dockers corduroys in size 32x30 and they fit me very nicely, meanwhile a pair of Levi 505 I am now in size 34x32. The same goes with shoes, I have three pairs ranging from size 9.5 to 11. I feel that all jeans should be measured in inches starting with the button placement and ending with the furthest edge of the button hole. I feel that shoes should be sized by inches. This isn't limited to pants and shoes, but I tend to find that they are the worst offenders when it comes to sizing discrepancies.

The second is the hair industry. My girlfriend is licensed to cut hair in New Jersey, but unfortunately each state handles their regulations differently. She can not go over the state line and cut hair, for instance. I feel that the hair industry should get together and create a nationwide standardization of the test and allow for the license to be nationwide.

TL:DR I feel that some industries could benefit from nationwide standardization/

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27106601686.0" user="Caressmysoul" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you should be able to cut hair without a license. We don't live in a communist country, I think you shouldn't have to have licenses and certificates to do certain jobs. It's the consumer's choice on where to get a product or service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106634103.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>My girlfriend explained it, it's not necessarily cutting the hair, it's treating it. You need to understand how to use the chemicals. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106660309.0" user="Caressmysoul" delta="False">
    <text>Like so you won't harm the customer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106680945.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. The problem is that each state allows certain chemicals and such and in every state you need to re-pass the exams and learn new things. I think that it should be standard throughout the US. I'm shocked that people who have big hair conventions nationwide haven't figured this out yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106835561.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>Different states have different environmental loads and tolerances, though - New York, for example, has more overall pollution than, say, South Dakota, so South Dakota might be able to use cheaper chemicals than NY because the overall impact is less.  Setting nationwide tolerances to SD levels would be terrible for high-population areas, and setting tolerances to NY levels might unduly burden regions like SD.

Side note: "big hair conventions" brings up amusing images.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27107090595.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>Very good points. Also definitely a laugh about big hair conventions!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
