<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="122999970.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/218bdu/i_think_that_some_industries_that_arent_currently/">
    <title>I think that some industries that aren't currently nationally standardized should be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are two industries in particular that I feel should be at the very least standardized throughout the USA. The first is the clothing industry. From pants to shoes to shirts, sizing is incredibly varied. I bought a pair of Dockers corduroys in size 32x30 and they fit me very nicely, meanwhile a pair of Levi 505 I am now in size 34x32. The same goes with shoes, I have three pairs ranging from size 9.5 to 11. I feel that all jeans should be measured in inches starting with the button placement and ending with the furthest edge of the button hole. I feel that shoes should be sized by inches. This isn't limited to pants and shoes, but I tend to find that they are the worst offenders when it comes to sizing discrepancies.

The second is the hair industry. My girlfriend is licensed to cut hair in New Jersey, but unfortunately each state handles their regulations differently. She can not go over the state line and cut hair, for instance. I feel that the hair industry should get together and create a nationwide standardization of the test and allow for the license to be nationwide.

TL:DR I feel that some industries could benefit from nationwide standardization/

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27106704877.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>"My girlfriend is licensed to cut hair in New Jersey, but unfortunately each state handles their regulations differently."
"I feel that the hair industry should get together and create a nationwide standardization of the test and allow for the license to be nationwide."

So, is the issue here that you feel that there should be regulated *federally*, rather than by the state, and not so much an industry standardization function?

By this I mean, even if all the hairdressers in America decided "Here's a test to certify that you know how to properly treat hair", it doesn't remove the function of state government health agencies being the ones to issue the licenses, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106707625.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>My issue with it is that the industry should come together and realize how ridiculous it is that many states require a new license. I can't think of any other industry off of the top of my head that requires new certifications when leaving a state to work in another. 

I'm not sure if it's actually state regulations that causes this, if so then I think that the federal government should make a standardized certifications. If it's an industry imposed thing than I think that they should get their stuff together and make it easier for them to move to another state. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106726644.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>"I can't think of any other industry off of the top of my head that requires new certifications when leaving a state to work in another."

First three that came to mind: taxi drivers, doctors and food handlers.

Added:  cops, lawyers, teachers.

And more: plumbers, carpenters, electricians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106735955.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for showing me examples. Are you sure teachers have to though? I live near the border of PA and NJ and I could have sworn that I know teachers that do both. I also know a teacher who teaches for a California University online and teaches in-house in NJ. Is that different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27106747397.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>Some teachers certify in multiple states (as do some doctors), and some states may grant exceptions.  [Here's](http://www.state.nj.us/education/educators/license/) New Jersey's certification stuff, for instance.

None of that is particularly an argument for or against whether or not certification should be handled federally or regionally, though, just pointing out that it's neither unique to hairdressers nor is it really a matter of the industry itself deciding whether or not they *want* to certify per-state or per-nation or whatever.

As for whether or not it *should* be handled on a state-by-state level, I suspect it depends on what we're talking about.  Generally speaking, states possess the right to have stricter health regulations than exist at a federal level.  When an industry delves into health matters, then, it may or may not be important to ensure that workers are educated in the state-level variances, so it would make sense that states be empowered to certify for their state only.  Now, you might decide that maybe there could be a broad federal-level certification for states that have no particularly greater level of health regulation than exists locally, with a secondary state-level certification for states that have greater regulation, but asking industry workers to certify on both the federal level AND the state level seems more burdensome than necessary - you'd be paying TWO agencies for the right to work in one state.

There's also the matter of revenue - income generated from state-based certification fees go into state coffers, federal certification goes into federal coffers.

I think it's reasonably safe to say that when a job requires knowledge of local regulations, certification on a state-by-state level is probably called for.  Where regulations are near-identical, I suspect many states and industries have cross-coverage, though as a function of generating revenue for the state, they may not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27107092263.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for sharing your opinion, I appreciate it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
