<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109329503.0" user="oxymoron1629" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine a situation where everyone is needlessly in a perpetual state of suffering for as long as they live. If you agree that being someone in that state is bad, then we have found a state of being that we want to avoid. Why? Because there is no good that can come from it and, more importantly, people are suffering (including yourself and people you love). So if you grant that everyone is trying to avoid this state of being so that they can live without suffering and so that they have others to benefit them, then there is a morally objective wrong. Sure, some people can hurt others or make others suffer, but sane people only do this because they believe that it will, in some way, benefit them. But no one would wish that everyone should suffer. Thus, if we have found an objective moral position that is wrong, then there must be a position where it is right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109515050.0" user="Medtner" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But no one would wish that everyone should suffer.

I think you're underestimating the amount of different people out there. Some people are what most of us would call monsters. The person can be entirely sane, rational. If one enjoys torture then it can be rational to torture. It has nothing to do with sanity (unless one mistakenly presumes to like torture). 

If one wants the happiness of others, then yes, one ought to do the action that brings that about. But if one doesn't...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109539145.0" user="oxymoron1629" delta="False">
    <text>There are monsters who wish the suffering of everyone. And there are masochists who enjoy suffering themselves. But I hold that no person could enjoy both. They seem almost contrary. I guess this is the assumption that needs to be made to accept the preposition that there is objective moral wrongs. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
