<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109696114.0" user="foxfact" delta="False">
    <text>The argument about objective/absolute and subjective/relative morality among the nonreligious often boils down to semantics. They're are things that are objectively harmful to the individual and the society with which the individual resides. Depending on how you define morality, the argument of whether it is absolute or relative will differ. 

If morality is defined as a motive or guide for our actions and with no intended end result that is objectively beneficial or otherwise to the society and individual, than sure, it can be relative. But if morality itself is defined as contingent on whether actions produce beneficial or harmful actions, motives, and consequences for the individual and society in question (ie the altruistic tendencies we evolutionary developed as a species), then morality is objective.

TL;DR - The criteria for which we determine how to define morality may be relative/differ, but if we accept that morality deals with whether actions are altruistic, then how we classify whether those actions are good or bad when compared to alternative choices is an objective process.

EDIT: clarified a few things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109708217.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>This is the tldr to what I've learned here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110046278.0" user="foxfact" delta="False">
    <text>So, just wondering, in your own words, how has this thread evolved your understanding of morality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110098477.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>I used to think that any morality could only come from an above human mind. I've come to see that the term morality can apply to a set of rules I devise to apply to my life as I see fit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110294384.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>But doesn't this really lead back to your original position, that morality is not absolute?  As we live and learn, our own morality changes.

Morality has changed a great deal over history, and there's no reason to believe that it won't in the future.  It's also different in different cultures, and evolving over time for them.

Isn't that the very definition of not absolute?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110564860.0" user="foxfact" delta="False">
    <text>So, by that logic, just for further clarification, you would say that as long as you follow what you deem to be acceptable, then you are acting moral regardless of the effects your choices have on others?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
