<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109134366.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Can you objectively define terms?(numbers)

Can you get objective rules form definitions? (the rule of addition) 

Can you objectively apply rules to abstract terms?(2+2=4)

Is it theoretically possible someone could objectively define morality, and from that definition, objectively figure out some rules for moral statements, and then test moral statements using those rules? ("2+2=5" is false)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109156523.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>But what are you testing the moral actions for? Are you seeing what benefits society? Are you seeing what benefits me? Those are subjective. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109203517.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Are you asking those question to my deontology or *any* theoretical one? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109212238.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Deontology required a Wikipedia search for me. I think you're claiming that morality is a set of rules, and I am asking why those rules are there, and who are they there to benefit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109258848.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Your bad at answering questions;

I'm actively avoiding taking about my morality, because my ideas are not exactly popular or something people become convinced of in one comment thread.

Should I just show how mine follows those three step(define morality in a useful way, but still follow common usage; get some rules about what a true moral statement should look like, from that defination, then use that rule to prove that an absurd statement like "murder is good" as false), risking that you falsely equate my deontology with all possible deontologys?

&amp;gt;I think you're claiming that morality is a set of rules

I'm literally using the term "deontology" to mean any theory/study of morality that isn't "virtue ethics"-ist or Consequentialist. 

To quote wikipedia "Broadly speaking, there are three competing views on how moral questions should be answered, along with hybrid positions that combine some elements of each"

-----

So are you asking those questions to my personal theory of ethics, or all theoretical ethical positions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109306508.0" user="spyke252" delta="False">
    <text>As much as I'm in line with objective morality, this is a horrible way to go about it.  You cannot objectively define any of these things- they all are dependent on which axioms you take to be true (e.g. ZFC).

Now, there may be a "One True Axiomatic Set Theory".  But this is debatable in exactly the same way (if not moreso) than the question in OP's post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109730409.0" user="apajx" delta="False">
    <text>Incredibly wrong.

Abstractions such as "numbers" have no precise application to reality. You can attempt to apply them in one domain but that does not make that domain the *realization* of the abstraction, just an application of it. Thus, the abstraction can not be used to objectively reason about physical things since you must enforce an interpretation to link the abstraction and the reality.

As for objective rules, there are several potential formalizations of the abstraction to which you are discussing. Which formalization is correct? Which one is "objective"?

Finally, the application of the formalization on abstract entities does in no way imply an objective reasoning on concrete entities without an appropriate interpretation and proof of objectivity of said formalization.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
