<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109158304.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Not to be rude, but I don't think you've defined your terms very well, so it's hard for me to change your view. Please define "objective morality" and "absolute morality."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109176125.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Objective  or absolute morality, in this discussion, is a motive or guide for all action that is not subject to change between circumstance and actor doing the action. 


Subjective or relative morality is a motive or guide for action that can be different between individuals and beliefs. 

My idea is that all "morality" is subjective. And actions that are considered self-less or morally based are done for a relief of suffering or gain of positive emotions.

Edit: to clarify: these actions are self-centered and in my opinion amoral irrelevant of consequence. 

Edit 2: I guess I was oversimplifying when I claimed that subject morality was not morality, as I saw one type of absolute morality. I didn't really see the point in morality that is relative, but have changed my view to see that morality can mean a code of action that is totally personal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109186419.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>The key problem here is that you are arguing two totally separate points, but you have combined them into a single claim. Let me try to pull them apart.

 Firstly, you are advocating moral anti-realism against moral realism. Moral realism is the claim that moral facts can be true or false based on objective features of the world. Moral anti-realism claims that moral facts are mind dependent. Thus, the truth of moral facts depends on the individual. 

The second claim you are making is one of consequentialism against some form of moral absolutism. You claim that the rightness or wrongness of an act is totally dependent on its consequences. However, this contradicts your previous point. If moral facts are true or false based on objective features of the world (measurable suffering), then morality doesn't differ from individual to individual. Right? 

Because of this confusion, you are oversimplifying a complex issue. Because you see the contrast as Christian moral absolutism vs. consequentialist morality (with no room for, say, a secular ethic based on duty rather than consequences), you are making the mistake of asserting an overly consequences-obsessed moral system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109223143.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not exactly sure where I brought up consequence based morality. Yes I do advocate moral anti-realism. But, no I do not ignore secular, duty morality. I believe (have articulated else where in the thread) that duty morality is a strategy of how to gain the most material and emotional benefits from society and my biology. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109228225.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  that duty morality is a strategy of how to gain the most material and emotional benefits from society and my biology.

One problem here is the idea that morality always garners you the most benefits. Sometimes, if you take consequentialism seriously, it means that you lose, but other people win. Actually, you aren't going to find any moral system that always benefits you materially and emotionally in a maximal way. Second of all, I'm going to turn your own argument back on you. Your moral system seems pretty absolute to me. There is always an action that increases benefits the most, and thus that action is always right, regardless of context. I might deeply value freedom beyond it giving any emotional or moral benefits, but still choose it over some form of totalitarianism that somehow maximizes happiness. Your system has not room for any values except for material gains, which hardly makes sense in, say, a society without private property. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109243252.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>To clarify: by emotional gain, I am thinking that fighting for freedom will satisfy my suffering and make me happier than under a totalitarian society, because I value freedom over what ever pleasure they give me. I also don't believe that people should act selfishly, instead that they do act selfishly. So I believe that the consequences determine what I should do, instead that I don't have an absolute purpose and I will act regardless due to the laws of physics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109252505.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To clarify: by emotional gain, I am thinking that fighting for freedom will satisfy my suffering and make me happier than under a totalitarian society, because I value freedom over what ever pleasure they give me.

So then I think you need to reframe your ethical system. You aren't really trying reduce suffering in some utilitarian way. You accept that what you are really trying to do is embody your values. I think, however, hat the key is that not all of those values are quantifiable in the way that suffering might be. So I don't think it's a tradeoff in terms of emotional gain vs. emotional gain, but instead of competing values. I think this might be what you are saying, I just find the utilitarian language to be weird. 

So thus, there are certain values that you hold so dearly, that it would take some pretty bad consequences to give up on them. How is this different from what you are terming religious moral absolutism? It never really ignores consequences entirely, it just puts far more weight on certain moral rules. Both involve competing systems of values. What is the real difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109262745.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. I would like to think that those values affect me emotionally. I guess the decision to fight would still have a negative net effect on my feelings but be weighted beneficial on a moral scale. The difference to absolutism that I weigh my individual values, while absolutism weighs universal values.  Thanks for your input. You have been very clear and intelligent. I will be calling it a night, as it is 1:00 a.m. for me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109339017.0" user="phweeb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Objective or absolute morality, in this discussion, is a motive or guide for all action that is not subject to change between circumstance and actor doing the action. 

I don't think anyone ever thinks like this, lol. You can't define reality, no one can, and no one with hard morals *thinks* you can or claims you can either. 

What we think is that you *have to* at some point make a decision to live your life by hard morals, or else you can't be consistent, and therefore you aren't doing anything for any reason other than a momentary one. If there is no hard morality, murder is right whenever you want, slavery is right whenever you want, so on and so forth. 

There is no "godly" morality, obviously, there is no "objective set of rules in the universe that never change", that would be absurd, but what objectivists mean when they say they are objectively exercising morality is that they have made a decision to act in the most objective way that they possibly can, by living their life according to a consistent (to them) set of beliefs, and things that violate those beliefs, are "wrong" in their universe/lives/brain/whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109771340.0" user="qezi2" delta="False">
    <text>You know what's better than defining terms? [The rationalist's taboo](http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rationalist_taboo).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109791998.0" user="demosthenes83" delta="False">
    <text>I hadn't seen that before. Something to think about.

Thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
