<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109301299.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>It is absolutely true for all humans...


...that *thinking* something without action does not cause things to have a physical existence in reality. Therefore, it's an absolute ethical principle, on the standard/value/goal of what is required to physically create or do something, action is a virtue - and demanding that a wish or fancy come true without action is a vice.

... that self-deception does not lead to the self knowing the truth. Therefore, it's an absolute ethical principle, on the standard/value/goal of knowing what is true, that honesty with yourself is a virtue, and self-deception is a vice.

... that stealing the effects does not make you the cause of those effects. Therefore, it's an absolute ethical principle, on the standard of what actions are required to be the causal (rightful) owner of things, theft is immoral.

... that our time is limited by our mortality, and that different actions lead to different values being achieved or not achieved. Therefore, it's an absolute ethical principle, on the standard of maximizing value, that choosing the higher value over a lesser is a virtue.

&amp;gt;How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation.

You are still entrenched in the mindset of your Christian values that makes a blanket case damning all selfishness as evil without differentiating between good and bad selfish acts! 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109510746.0" user="Medtner" delta="False">
    <text>Hey. A small critique.

It seems that you're using a very broad definition of morality. I wish to show that some of your claims either presume an arbitrarily chosen premise, are simply false or yield uninteresting "moral facts". 

1) I wish to rephrase this as "If you wish to achieve your goals, you have to work for them. Merely thought doesn't achieve them". Isn't this more physics and biology than philosophy? Or even if philosophy (agent rationality and motivation), then it gives unhelpful moral facts - "if you wish to kill your nephew you ought to stab him" is as true as "if you wish to bring about happiness, do good to others". This merely states something that (presumably) all rational agents should know and follow. So even it is a moral fact by definition, it's an uninteresting one and not the sort OP (I think) is looking for.

2) Doesn't this presume that truth is a virtue itself as well? That the agent already *wants* to know the truth? Or *should* want to know the truth (which is a moral claim).

3) Doesn't this presume the person wanting to be the real creator and not merely appear as one? Thus, if we have a person who, say, benefits from theft and doesn't care if he/she is the real author/owner, I can't see why he/she should reject theft. 
 
4) Again, I think it's analogous to the first case. It gives a guideline to rational agents: (1) if you have goals, do things that actually help to achieve them; (4) if you have to choose, pick the one that yields more benefit. This also leads to the judgement that "if you enjoy necrophilia more than rape, kill your victim before having sex with him/her". That's not the sort of fact that moral realists usually want to allow. 

I think all of the above can be summed thus: you're thinking in terms of conditionals - *if X then Y* (or *hypothetical imperatives*). But, as I've understood (but aren't that eager to accept actually), is that (universal) moral facts (as they've usually talked about) are (at least ideally) non-conditionals. It's not that *if you happen to want X, then do Y*, but *everybody should do Y*. That's at least what I've understood from my professors.

I personally like to contrast mind-independent truth value with normativity, both of which seem to be in the definition of *objective* morality. So some conditionals can be mind-independently true (given how the world is and how humans can influence it), but not universally normative - if one doesn't accept the antecedent, one doesn't have to accept the consequent. I think that mind-independent truth, and hence universal moral facts (but not necessarily universally normative!), is only possible with thinking moral judgments as conditionals. But... this isn't what moral realists are looking for. They are (as far as it seems) much more ambitious - some things are wrong for everybody, everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
