<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109515409.0" user="robesta" delta="False">
    <text>Life and death are absolutes.  To most any life form life is an end and a goal in itself.  Anything that perpetuates life is good and moral anything that perpetuates death is bad and immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109598756.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>This is assuming that in *all* cases, life is preferable to death which may or may not be the case.

&amp;gt; To most any life form life is an end and a goal in itself.

It's possible that for more simpler life forms, the purpose of life is to spread it's genes and continue their existence in the world. Since most living things in nature do not die of old age but from other factors, life would be preferable since it still has an opportunity to spread its genes. For organisms that have the opportunity to die of old age, or make willing sacrifices for the better of others, this would not be the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109615546.0" user="robesta" delta="False">
    <text>If life wasn't preferable, then humans wouldn't exist.  Life can also be expanded to perpetuating life, which would extend to the mother sacrificing their life for their child or the Soldier dying for his country. 

Everyone chooses life proactively by eating and sleeping and passively by not killing themselves and in doing so agrees tacitly that life is good.  If it wasn't they'd just die. 

OP said there weren't moral absolutes.  Life and death are absolutes and we govern behavior either for or against life on a daily basis which is morality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109664486.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If life wasn't preferable, then humans wouldn't exist.

Life is preferable *as long as it would help the continuation of the species*. In fact, the only reason we *do* exist is because there *IS* death.

&amp;gt;  Life can also be expanded to perpetuating life, which would extend to the mother sacrificing their life for their child or the Soldier dying for his country. 

This is the part that is essential, not *living* itself. Hypothetically, a disfigured spider that cannot reproduce outcompeting it's fertile siblings would be detrimental to the species.

&amp;gt; Everyone chooses life proactively by eating and sleeping and passively by not killing themselves and in doing so agrees tacitly that life is good. If it wasn't they'd just die. 

OP said there weren't moral absolutes. Life and death are absolutes and we govern behavior either for or against life on a daily basis which is morality. 

Alternatively, people chose to sacrifice themselves and end life early. Therefore, these things are not absolutes. There are circumstances when living and dying are not always "Good vs. Bad". Passing on your genes and making the world a better place is (arguably) more important than an individual life, which is why we see sacrifice at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109840880.0" user="robesta" delta="False">
    <text>Let's get out of the nitty gritty for a second. So the first requirement for any absolute morality is an an absolute to base that morality on. 

God is the most common example of an absolute. People typically think if you don't believe in God then you cease to believe in absolutes. 

Life and death is an absolute.  It's binary.  Unlike God, you can objectively prove life and death.  How you want to line up the goalposts on what constitutes right and wrong based on this absolute is arbitrary.  The fact is, you have an absolute, and you CAN build an absolute moral structure off of that. 

Do you disagree with that? 

I'd like OP to weigh in on this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109894495.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you disagree with that? 

Well it would depend on whether you use the word "Life" to describe an individual "Life" or Life in general. I personally have no problem saying that the preservation of life in the universe is preferable to the destruction of life in the universe, and actions taken in either direction would be affected by that.

This does not mean that I think that preservation of EACH life is absolutely moral. That is just what I wanted to clarify. I think there are circumstances where giving up one's individual life could be considered moral. Do you base your morality on INDIVIDUAL life or GROUP life?

Sorry if that doesn't make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109913381.0" user="robesta" delta="False">
    <text>Personally, I do it as an individual.  That being said, my individual extends to those I care about, such as my progeny and the ones I love.  
I love life and want to see those I care about around me experience the same joy.  I would even be willing to sacrifice my own life so that my children could continue to experience the joys that I already have experienced.

You can extend this to groups society and argue that certain political and legal systems perpetuate life and while some do not. 

Like I said tho, OP was disillusioned with religion and had probably been contemplating relativism, and the main point I'm offering is that religion does not have a monopoly on absolute morality.  If you have a binary such as life and death, which you can demonstrate that one is good and the other is not, you have the basis for absolute morality without the existence of God. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
