<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109103246.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I'll venture playing the Devil's Advocate here with the one situation I could think of to potentially challenge this:


Hurting a baby is considered to be wrong irrespective of where you got your morals (or lack of) from. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109108193.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to hazard a guess and say that humans (like any other species)  evolved to care for their young. Our aversion to baby-hurting is thus a biological instinct so we call it a "wrong" action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109116112.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that. So then, could right or wrongs based on biological instinct common to the human species be considered absolute morality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109125380.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>I might grant you the word "objective" since we can point to biology (facts) to explain the merits of anti-baby-hurting. I don't really see the point or value in calling it absolute, because I believe there's no one watching over us telling us absolutely what is right or wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109146450.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>Ha, but that's a whole different discussion. I gave a shot at trying to find an example of what could constitute absolute morality to answer OP. But arguing that there's a point in calling absolute or not, that I can't do. Because I agree that people act according to the way they were raised and the experience/knowledge they gather throughout life. And more things than not can be considered either right or wrong changing only the perspective let alone if you start putting things like different cultures in the equation. Even the same person's morals change over time, how can a concept get more relative than that?


Having said that, OP claims not to believe in absolute morality and I maintain that biological instinct could be a potential candidate (credit to you for extending the situation to a broader bracket, if you don't mind).
I think that even myself, believing that morality is highly subjective, could open one exception for something that comes from evolution and is present in every human being.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109156618.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>I think we agree there.

If you haven't read it, I'd highly recommend *Beyond Religion* by the Dalai Lama, in which he discusses deriving ethics from a modern secular perspective instead of a religious one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109163043.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>No I haven't, but it does sound like an interesting read. I'll check it out, thank you! :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109288514.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>No. They can be considered a set of emotional responses that we can reasonably expect all humans to have, but that doesn't make them an objective guide to what is right and wrong. One can always argue that what we've evolved to feel bears no relation to what is actually right/wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109295785.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>If we can reasonably expect all humans to feel the same way about the same thing than why wouldn't it be actually an objective guide to what is right or wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109297647.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>Why would humans be the source for an objective definition of right/wrong?

You could I guess make an argument that something is right/wrong for all humans, although I've never seen it tried (I suspect it just becomes a problem of defining what it is to be human).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109302302.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>What else could be the source? Humans came up with the concept of morality and it is only relevant among ourselves.

We may apply it to others, we can say that the dog was wrong in biting *its owner so it gets punished. But it is us that consider it "wrong", not the dog, if that makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109314683.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What else could be the source? Humans came up with the concept of morality and it is only relevant among ourselves.

Alternative sources (that don't claim to be completely objective) could be utilitarian average welfare maximization, rules based on the idea that all rational agents would agree to them, or beings other than humans (read: gods).

That suggests that, for instance, if we were to encounter aliens we couldn't tell them that it was wrong to murder conscious beings for entertainment, or that if we were to design a true AI we would have no justification for telling it how to behave.

Perhaps more importantly, however, what if someone claims not to feel the same way that the rest of humans do? We cannot prove them to be lying (as far as I know, at least), and if we assume they're telling the truth we are compelling them to act in accordance with a set of rules generated from a source they do not share.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109323955.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>So you are increasing the range of the morality concept to aliens or AI that would be able to understand the definition of right and wrong and simply not agree with the human's guide? That's a fair extrapolation, I can agree with that.


In the case of true AI produced by humans, not having a justification for telling it how to behave scares me a lot. But that's personal paranoia, possibly based on Terminator, Matrix, I Robot, ... so yeah, I won't be using films/fiction to build arguments on this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109395234.0" user="Aaberg123" delta="False">
    <text>Humans can fly. Does that mean that we *shouldn't* use plane's?

I hope you can see the fallacy of using nature as grounds for morality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109650602.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>That could be used the other way around though. Humans can't fly. So instinct will tell them that they shouldn't jump off a precipice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109690794.0" user="Stormflux" delta="False">
    <text>Not really, since at this point you're just playing at words.  There is no meeting of the minds between yourself and the person you're arguing with.  You're trying to trip him up using the imprecision in his language, not actually change his idea.

No one ever argued humans shouldn't fly, we're talking about how humans are social animals and our behavior comes from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109683163.0" user="Stormflux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I agree with that. So then, could right or wrongs based on biological instinct common to the human species

Well yeah.  It's not even a question.  This is basic.  Human morality is based on our evolution and the ways we have to interact with each other.  There's a lot of game theory in there too.  Even robots have been shown to evolve altruistic behavior given the right circumstances and enough iterations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109146893.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Society gives this to moral in us, because society is build on the trust that the strong do not take advantage of the weak. As a benefactor of society I am asked to repay those who I trusted not to hurt me as a baby by abstaining from hurting other's babies. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109153380.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>Regardless, if this behavior is common to every human society, ranging from a developed country to an African tribe, then what makes it not absolute?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109165943.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text> That African tribe is a mammal society. That is what this rule works for. Raptors ate the eggs if other beast, because they needed the food to survive. They did not have our sense of trust in their reptile brain to respect the young of others. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109173083.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>OK, the point is, can you find one human society that does not care about babies to rule out it being absolute? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109201753.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Spartans. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109215067.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not familiar with that culture. But I hope you are not talking about sacrifices. The word "sacrifice" can mean a lot of things, but not not caring, quite on the opposite it shows the value associated to babies and children. I don't think you are even opened to the idea of your view being changed in the slightest so I'll leave it at this.


I want to thank you for the CMV though. I played against myself here and ended up actually believing in the points I was making, which I find quite amazing. An unexpected plot twist. :) Cheers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109231175.0" user="matthedev" delta="False">
    <text>The Spartans left "weak" infants to die by exposure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109237565.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>From Wikipedia, because I know very little about Spartans customs: 

"These babies would not be directly killed, but put in a clay pot or jar and deserted outside the front door or on the roadway. In ancient Greek religion, *this practice took the responsibility away from the parents* because the child would die of natural causes, for example hunger, asphyxiation or exposure to the elements."


Why do you think there was a need to deny responsibility?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109249495.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks as well. I guess I've realized from elsewhere in the thread that I have confused what should be done and what is done. While humans act in a certain way, I have a hard grasping why that "should" be true. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109252299.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I'm glad the thread worked out. It certainly gave me/is giving me food for thought.

And I fundamentally agree with your OP, morality is hugely subjective on my book as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109277208.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>It came at the cost of a good sleep for me. :( But I think I've learned quite a bit about morality and changed how I will discuss it in the future. Props to Izzyisme for being cool. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109408753.0" user="oreography" delta="False">
    <text>A culture which no longer exists</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109256974.0" user="colebanning" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of cultures have practiced infanticide throughout history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109264897.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, it has happened (still does) but again, people don't limit their actions to what they consider to be morally right. Probably everyone has done something they deem wrong by their own standards at one point in their lives, at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109173925.0" user="craftservices" delta="False">
    <text>But raptors don't eat their own eggs. Humans don't hurt their own young but do hurt other animal species' young.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109198012.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Being reptiles, raptors would eat the young of other raptors, but would not intentionally eat it's own young. It does this, because it is evolutionarily beneficial to reproduce. So yes, living things do not harm their own children. But a raptor's morality, concerning his young, is subject to the raptor. The raptor has his motives and I mine. Our moralities are subjective because they serve two purposes. For me, my extension of my genes, and for the raptor his own legacy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109250680.0" user="craftservices" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that to prove absolute morality, it must apply to all living organisms regardless of cognitive function or evolutionary distance?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109269057.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Raptors were probably an extreme example. But if cognitive differences changed morality, Stephen Hawkins morality would differ from that of a college student. If hawkin's morality is absolute should it apply to the student?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109290882.0" user="craftservices" delta="False">
    <text>By "cognitively functioning," I was more referring to higher order processing that distinguishes humans from all other living organisms, not between individual humans. I don't think it's particularly fair to even begin discussing morality from the context of animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109170960.0" user="ja1896" delta="False">
    <text>A non-human without human-predispositions might have an entirely different view. It may be near-unanimous among humans, but we are only a tiny subset of the universe. Therefore it's not absolute. '

Also, it can be argued that our views on right and wrong are all unique and simply intersect in many instances, thereby leaving no universal set of right and wrong, even among humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109183490.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>But humans are all that matter for this discussion. Morality and absolute are human concepts. Animals/plants/extra-terrestrial civilizations could not care less about any of our concepts. Morality only applies to humans, if it could be/is absolute in any way, I'd say a requirement for that would be that it would have to be valid among humans and humans only.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109185833.0" user="ja1896" delta="False">
    <text>Absolute to me implies involving the entire universe/all of reality. But universal for humans? I just don't think there's anything that's quite universal. In common, yes, but not entirely shared.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109193172.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I can see that, but that *is if you consider absolute by itself. If morality is only applied to humans than absolute morality is only applied to humans. Otherwise having this discussion wouldn't even make sense. 

An analogy would be: "I don't believe that honey can ever get spoiled". The discussion is only about honey, it doesn't matter that "spoiled" can be applied to a much broader range of things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109196871.0" user="ja1896" delta="False">
    <text>i don't think "morality" only applies to humans. Then again, I don't believe morality exists. But i do think more living things than just humans deal with right vs. wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109208303.0" user="WickWackLilJack" delta="False">
    <text>Religion derived morals, religion driven sacrifices. 

http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Child_sacrifice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109208480.0" user="mobile_link_fix_bot" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Child_sacrifice


&amp;gt;
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109212636.0" user="AmorDeCosmos97" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hurting a baby is considered to be wrong irrespective of where you got your morals (or lack of) from. 

This is totally not true. Many people and cultures feel it is morally justified to harm babies.  I can think of many examples, from killing unwanted baby girls immediately after birth, to war atrocities, and genocide.

Check out [infanticide](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infanticide) on Wikipedia.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109221251.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>To say that it's carried out is different than saying it's morally justified though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109318388.0" user="conkeifador" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infanticide</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109318516.0" user="mobile_link_fix_bot" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infanticide


&amp;gt;
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109334646.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I know, people have mentioned this a lot. It's a fairly big article and I didn't go through every single line of it, so I'll say that my impression is that behind those killings there was always an ulterior motive, something that would somehow justify it.

I guess my point is, if it would be simply acceptable, such ulterior motives wouldn't be necessary because hurting/killing a child would be a good thing and hence would not need any further explanation or justification. People wouldn't get rid of babies because of A, B or C, they could do it because it's be perfectly fine to do it, they felt like it and there was nothing wrong with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109337714.0" user="conkeifador" delta="False">
    <text>People don't do "moral" things without an ulterior motive. People do things such as donating to charity or volunteering because it makes them feel good about themselves in some way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109394084.0" user="Aaberg123" delta="False">
    <text>Hurting? Circumcision is hurting an infant, yet is accepted in some cultures (Jewish, Muslim and American). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109600649.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; (Jewish, Muslim and American)

I just want to point out that while true, it is funny that these things all paired together.

'Murica!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109681186.0" user="Stormflux" delta="False">
    <text>It's not seen that way though.  Where it's performed, it's seen as a medical / cosmetic procedure having benefits which outweigh the drawbacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109717644.0" user="Aaberg123" delta="False">
    <text>Only in America, based on very poor studies. But that's another discussion. In Jewish and Muslim cultures the rights of the child is surpassed by silly religious traditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110009561.0" user="AmorDeCosmos97" delta="False">
    <text>It IS morally justified by the people who harm babies.  You and I can agree within our moral framework that murder of babies is morally repugnant, but it is not a universal morality.  People who murder babies have their own moral justification.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109234444.0" user="VarenKale" delta="False">
    <text>I think for this to be true in the way that the OP is intending, infanticide would not exist and [news like this](http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/22/us-usa-crime-washington-infant-idUSBREA2L01L20140322) would not be shown because it would not exist. Objective morality would mean that the moral statement would be true in every circumstance, to every person. That the *object* (in your example) harm to children is true in every case, outside the realm of the observer similar to the *objective knowledge* that every person on this planet will die at some point. Whereas your example is a subjective statement of morality that most people would probably accept, I do not ever condone the killing or harming of children and I do not think that you do either but somewhere (or sometime) other people do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109245163.0" user="grumpynutella" delta="False">
    <text>I get that, but I don't see it as a valid point in the sense that people don't act solely according to what they consider to be morally right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109300103.0" user="spyke252" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think for this to be true in the way that the OP is intending, infanticide would not exist and news like this[1] would not be shown because it would not exist. Objective morality would mean that the moral statement would be true in every circumstance, to every person. 

No.  Objective morality would mean that the moral statement has the same *value* for every circumstance, irrespective of what the person believes.  e.g. if lying is an absolute moral wrong, then there is never a time when lying is morally right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
