<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109299499.0" user="Jiminy_" delta="False">
    <text>Well your logical, Chocolate vs Vanilla is analogous to Hitler vs Gahndi

I have trouble getting past your argument with out reaching out to something that's un-measurable. Cause that is what morality falls under, the un-measurable. Its psychological/spiritual/emotional. I for one however have a sense that there is an objective value to life, that the universe is objectively better with life. Your girlfriend has an obvious value to you (subjective). I don't know your girlfriend she will arguably have no affect on my existence or experience in life, but I believe she has an objective value. 

I can't prove that of course, but proving stuff in philosophy and metaphysics is kinda difficult when there are different logical proofs. Nihilism can be logical if that fits with how you think you are perceiving the universe, but I for one have a feeling that things like life, beauty, justice, and awe have objective value. Yes you could believe they are subjective but they seem consistent across our species and likely others (hard to measure)

I think Emotivism is true in some "moral" statements. There are plenty of things that societies hold as "morals" that are not objective; stuff like eating habits and sexual relations. But there are those like love and justice that some people think are of objective truths.


Im a biologist not a philosopher so normally I deal with things that are measurable... its late and I should be studying :( Im going to bed maybe none of this is coherent... lol good night </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109350763.0" user="psycho-logical" delta="False">
    <text>Great post. You and I think quite similar in this regard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27114757197.0" user="Jiminy_" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
