<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109097430.0" user="the-incredible-ape" delta="False">
    <text>Absolute morality is a sham.  However, this doesn't exclude the possibility of forming a valid morality on relative grounds. 

Although you're right that morality is human-generated, so what?  Morals have their uses and material values regardless. 

&amp;gt;I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about.

If you don't care about them, no surprise there.  If you do care about them, then why does the (non)existence of an absolute morality matter?  Since we've established that it's your values that matter, if you value someone, *then they matter*.  

&amp;gt;I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others.

This doesn't mean that you can't value a moral code.  You simply need to acknowledge it as your own. 

&amp;gt;How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation.

Easy, but you need to accept it for yourself and acknowledge it for what it is, rather than be told that it's absolute. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109106176.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. I guess to further define my problem: why do others matter to me? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109119338.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>*You* have to look into yourself to see why others matter to *you*. You could be a hermit and then this would be irrelevant. However, I assume you're not a hermit and that you exist in society in which you come into contact with other humans. Certain actions tend to benefit everyone so we call them "good."

Sure, you could be a sociopath and do everything to benefit yourself, but think of the consequences of alienating others. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109138863.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>The consequences are why I act. Is there a difference between acting morally as a means to gain the benefits of morality and acting morally for the sake of "the right thing."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109148904.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>No, there's not really a difference there. No one is keeping track of your internal motives. When I get down to it, most of what I do is selfish in nature (e.g. I look to benefit others, because that action makes me feel better about myself and have a happier outlook. Plus the other person will be more inclined to reciprocate positively.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109158119.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, I agree with this. I guess my view is more common in Reddit than in my local community. Or maybe I've been subconsciously brainwashed by reddit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109121388.0" user="the-incredible-ape" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know, you tell me.  Do you value anyone else's happiness?  If not I guess there isn't much to talk about here.  If so, then why do you? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109135117.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Love my family and my friends. I'm not sure why. I appreciate my parents. I seek to provide for my children and children in general. I figure this is a part of my evolution, as passing down my genes. I have companionship with my friends. Our relationship is mutually beneficial. I feel good when touch and talk to other humans. I appreciate myself when I am in good standing with others. Love and friendship feels engaging, and I naturally feel invested in others. I believe that that investment is self-centered (a product of evolution), even while it may not feel so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109577462.0" user="the-incredible-ape" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I believe that that investment is self-centered (a product of evolution), even while it may not feel so.

Sure, but does that invalidate it as a basis for moral behavior, per se? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109121538.0" user="Otiac" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Absolute morality is a sham. However, this doesn't exclude the possibility of forming a valid morality on relative grounds. 

While your first point is arrogant in the face of a few millennium of thought, I can see your second.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109131814.0" user="going_on_adventure" delta="False">
    <text>What are you thinking of when you say "a few millenium of thought"? I don't see any merit in absolute morality (please define this in case I misunderstood you).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109169113.0" user="Otiac" delta="False">
    <text>It was an attack on absolute morality as the institution of religion, which is where people stake a claim on absolute morality, which would fly in the face of thousands of years of great philosophical thought on the subject by dismissing it as a 'sham', when the sham has literally helped shape the culture and values in which we currently reside as well as what little reasoning outside that sham a person makes to justify subjective morality. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
