<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109142698.0" user="Scottmk4" delta="False">
    <text>Morality is a guide on how to live properly.

There are objective facts about the world around us, and objective facts about man's nature. Why then would it surprise you that there are objective facts about how man should live?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109152753.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>How man should live to fight impermanence. Yes. How man should live to feel good. Yes. How man should live. I honestly don't know. Is morality a guide to living in the most pleasurable way, like an Epicurian. Or is it the right way for me to live, end of discussion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109241384.0" user="Scottmk4" delta="False">
    <text>You've skipped to trying to answer the content of objective morality without addressing the framework for the possibility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109253217.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>I've skipped to question the possibility by asking whether one specific content can be chosen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27110002824.0" user="Scottmk4" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, because there are objective facts about reality, and objective facts about man's nature.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109286346.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are objective facts about the world around us, and objective facts about man's nature. Why then would it surprise you that there are objective facts about how man should live?

Because the first does not entail the second?

&amp;gt;Morality is a guide on how to live properly.

The entire issue is that defining "properly" is impossible to do objectively. It is not possible to produce a logical (or otherwise objective) argument for a particular definition of "properly" being the correct one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109325796.0" user="jmsolerm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why then would it surprise you that there are objective facts about how man should live?

http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/hume-moral/#io

You cannot just jump the gap straightforwardly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
