<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123251717.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21dpmt/cmv_i_do_not_believe_in_any_absolute_morality/">
    <title>CMV: I do not believe in any absolute morality.</title>
    <original_poster>CARTARS22</original_poster>
    <original_post>Probably in reaction to my rebellion to my Christian upbringing, I have a hard time accepting any objective morality. I understand Christian morality, but as a non-christian I recognize my moral feels as a neurological response trained by evolution and society. I don't believe in any connection between myself and those I "care" about. I believe that I (humanity) act on what will have positive effects on my feelings, and that is the only reason I help others. How can there be a morality that stands above my self-preservation. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27109095627.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>In my experience, belief in objective morality is pretty uncommon among non-religious folk. Subjective morality is valid too though. You can recognize an action as only moral in your subjective view, and even recognize that you're doing it because following your subjective morality makes you feel good, and that doesn't make the action any less moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109109296.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. Does that define morality as a self-serving set of ideas? Are moral actions guided by my internal motives to achieve a positive state of mind? Is that morality or just strategy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109122199.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Religious people disagree with this, but in my opinion: Objective morality is bullshit! People follow what they think is objective morality to achieve a peaceful state of mind just like you do. They do social things because it's programmed into them just like it's programmed into you. None of it matters in the grand scheme of things, but we do what we think is right because it helps us have happy, fulfilling lives. ALL morality is just a strategy!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109124010.0" user="CARTARS22" delta="False">
    <text>Yea. That seems to be where I stand. Thanks for the input. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109130659.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Oops, I guess I forgot what the main CMV is haha</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109118315.0" user="Otiac" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and that doesn't make the action any less moral.

This would imply an objective set of standards to work off of, making the point irrelevant from the rest of your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109124956.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not being very articulate. What I mean is it doesn't make it any less valid to define the action as moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109162111.0" user="Otiac" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What I mean is it doesn't make it any less valid

I see, understood. Validity can ultimately mean its usefulness in situation, which is a valid work for this definition, but ultimately without an objective basis to work off of the definitions are moot and ultimately invalid - such is the nature of subjective work. But I understand your argument and appreciate it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109145438.0" user="Scottmk4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; belief in objective morality is pretty uncommon among non-religious folk.

True, but this doesn't speak to the existence or non-existence of objective morality. 

&amp;gt;Subjective morality is valid too though. 

No it isn't. Subjective means a whim not connected to the facts of reality. If morality is subjective, Stalin vs. George Washington is an irrelevant preference no more meaningful than chocolate vs. vanilla. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109155348.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;True, but this doesn't speak to the existence or non-existence of objective morality.

Just trying to make the OP feel better..

&amp;gt;No it isn't. Subjective means a whim not connected to the facts of reality. If morality is subjective, Stalin vs. George Washington is an irrelevant preference no more meaningful than chocolate vs. vanilla.

That's not what subjective means. Something is subjective if it is an opinion. It could be my opinion that killing all humans is just because we are destructive to many other species on the planet and the survival of millions of different organism types outweighs the survival of one. Thus, Stalin is more just for killing tons of humans. That's actually not a totally absurd opinion, and I could see it being in line with someone's morality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109290365.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If morality is subjective, Stalin vs. George Washington is an irrelevant preference no more meaningful than chocolate vs. vanilla.

I don't know where you got irrelevant from. It is relevant to me if someone else has opinions that differ from mine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27109302598.0" user="spyke252" delta="False">
    <text>And to Stalin, it's relevant if someone else has opinions different than him.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
