<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35809601526.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>When people say "white people can't cook", they mean "I have an experience when I saw a white person eat food that I don't like, and so I am going to generalize that to a whole class of people, and it is okay to do so because I can say 'fuck white people' without any societal reprocussions because some grandfather of a grandfather did terrible things in the past".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35811194734.0" user="picklednood1e" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36540848711.0" user="nunnesje" delta="False">
    <text>facts</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36979417001.0" user="tayecio" delta="False">
    <text>If they're American, they probably mean "I've seen a lot of white American food that either isn't seasoned, is only seasoned with salt and pepper, or has too little of anything to make an impact."

Comparing the way I've seen different races and nationalities cook (by cooking videos or irl), white American food frequently appears bland and underseasoned. Even when I eat at white restaurants/houses the food has a greater chance of being bland. It's a generalization, yes, but imho one based in reality and generally unrelated to racism</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
