<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808155884.0" user="WWBSkywalker" delta="False">
    <text>One have to be so careful to avoid being downvoted to death when answering this CMV :)

Actually when I hear people say that "white people can't cook" I associate it with Americans and the British (and relatedly Australians, Canadians &amp;amp; New Zealanders as new migrant countries). It doesn't necessarily mean I agree with this sentiment. However, consider common lists like these just for illustrative purposes only

[https://www.tasteatlas.com/most-popular-food-in-the-world](https://www.tasteatlas.com/most-popular-food-in-the-world)

Americans basically contribute fried chicken, barbeque, burgers, mac &amp;amp; cheese and sweets (milkshake, brownies, cupcake). The English contribute fish &amp;amp; chips. Canadians contribute mayple syrup. 

This gives the Americans and the British a reputation of simplicity of cuisine; and people don't usually associate sweets and desserts with cooking. Interestingly I have never hear people say "white people can't bake" especially when directed to Americans and the British.

For Americans, Canadians, Australians &amp;amp; New Zealanders I think the bias against them comes from the fact that most of their favourite foods didn't come from native ingredients. And of course as a nation they only existed for 500 years (if you include pre Independence for Americans &amp;amp; Canadians), and even less so for Australians &amp;amp; New Zealanders.  Most of the "better" cooking culture have thousands of years of using localised ingredients to develop their cuisine. They have deeper roots to the culture as a result. All the groups I mentioned aside from the British food didn't have this opportunity. The British by their geographical location are limited in this respect as well. I think most of my British friends agree with the blandness of their traditional cuisine as well - aside from baked foods.

So while I don't necessarily agree that "white people can't cook", I can see why the reputation developed, and I consider the "white people" here to include Americans, Canadians, Australians, New Zealanders and the British.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35811933437.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Most of the "better" cooking culture have thousands of years of using localised ingredients to develop their cuisine.

Eh, most popular national dishes originate in the last 100-200 years. The italians didn't have tomatoes before the discovery of the new world, and they didn't become a staple ingredient until relatively recent.

England and US had more sophisticated foods in the past, but they fell out of fashion in favor to more convenient alternatives, probably due to industrialization, population boom, wars, great depression.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
