<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808135671.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, the food in Germany, Ukraine and Switzerland is more uniform and very bland compared to the variety of cuisines in America.

Secondly, the idea of "traditional american" is kinda non-existent.  The things you read when you look about that are largely the things that children of white families ate in the 1950s.  It's indeed not very interesting.  However, were you to walk down the street in most american cities you would see a far greater variety of types of food than you would in all the countries you mentioned, and you'd find food from all the countries you mention.  A city like new york or san francisco, LA, Chicago simply have more varieties of food than you'd find in a city like Berlin of Paris - that's because the people wihin New York have heritage in everywhere other than New York.

In my mind there are no foods more bland and uninteresting than traditional german, or traditional ukrainian food (and I've lived in germany, travelled to Ukraine a dozen times since 1980, lived in France, etc.).  

I think the core problem here is that "traditional american food" just doesn't mean the same conceptually as "traditional german food" - it's really a snapshot from a very particular time from a small segment of the population, and largely oriented around children's foods.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
