<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808111516.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I find it slightly annoying

[...]

&amp;gt;I'm not offended

[...]

&amp;gt;I find it very annoying

Well that was a rollercoaster.

&amp;gt;Maybe this is just stereotypes,

It's ironic that you're complaining about stereotypes while making an argument based entirely on stereotypes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808124950.0" user="picklednood1e" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe that's why I said that this probably stereotypes??? And it's not really an argument, it's more of a remark</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808159232.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>I mean...if you have a problem with stereotypes sweeping you up and inaccurately describing you, maybe the lesson to learn is to not use stereotypes to make these kinds of judgements.

But here's a more substantive explanation: 

We took your food.  If you have it, we do too.  It's ours now.  It doesn't just belong to you.  We might name an ethnic origin, but don't be fooled.  We own it.

I find it strange when Europeans talk about their "national dishes" as if there's some blood-soil-kitchen connection and they own a certain kind of food.  Sometimes they even get mad when other people make it.

Case in point: Pizza.  It's ours now.  It's as American as anything else - it may be derived from Italy, but the people who brought it here became Americans and it's American food now.  And American pizza is better than Italian pizza.  If Italians want to complain...nobody cares. They can call Dominoes and complain.

Same goes with all the "Americanized ethnic foods."  No dude...it's *ours now.*  You don't own it and you never owned it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35809557126.0" user="KatieCashew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I find it strange when Europeans talk about their "national dishes" as if there's some blood-soil-kitchen connection and they own a certain kind of food.

It's particularly ridiculous when some of the key ingredients of these cuisines came from the new world. Tomatoes, potatoes, chocolate and corn all came from the Americas. All those Italian tomato dishes and famous San Marazano tomatoes? They're not Italian. They're south American. After all that's where tomatoes came from. How can Italians claim that as their cuisine when it didn't even come from there? 

Sounds stupid when put that way, but that's essentially the same argument people are making when they say the US doesn't have it's own cuisine. Food travels and changes and becomes something new while still retaining parts of its origin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35810804758.0" user="legal_throwaway45" delta="False">
    <text>I have had a lot of pizza in Italy.  It is not the same as American varieties.  America took the idea of a dough covered with sauce and cheese and spun it in many different directions.

BTW, Brazilian pizza sometimes uses cream cheese and peas as toppings, not bad, but not my idea of pizza.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
