<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808140955.0" user="Nopeeky" delta="False">
    <text>American food is regional, much like the people who settled certain areas.  Around Louisiana- heat is king as are bold flavors like garlic and onion.  American South West is latino inspired.  The American midwest (northern parts) see a huge emphasis from Northern Europe.  The NE coast is seafood and immigrant food, and big time.

There's 6-7 kinds of BBQ and those each have smaller subsets.  In the Carolinas, pork is king but it can be vinegar and pepper flakes based or mustard and black pepper.  Or a tomato/vinegar.

6 kinds of regional pizza, 5 kinds of fried chicken, more ways to cook a roast beef than there are to skin a cat, and I haven't even begun to talk about Indian or Asian influences.


When they say that America is a melting pot, it's most prominent in the foods we prepare.  We have the largest grocery stores with the largest selection of anywhere in the world.  We have everything in our repertoire from dumplings (I can personally make them 5 different ways) to pasta and rice dishes that represent every culture on earth.

Sausages and krauts? Yep

Curries and naan- no problem.


Ramen and pho?  All over the place.

Do we as a general rule make food so hot that it crosses your eyes?  Nope.  Some do, but everytime I've been told that - it's generally in regard to heat level.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
