<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808610714.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I was born in Eastern Europe 

I hate to break it to you, they're talking primarily about Eastern/Central Europeans and Americans of Eastern European descent.  In many Eastern European countries it is common to be uncomfortable with spices and say things like "spices are what other countries have to use because their meat isn't fresh" as an excuse. While most non-white cultures consider spices integral to good cooking and see Eastern/Central European food as bland.  Obviously this ignorance of spices includes some towns in the US as well, but they brought that bland tendency over from the old country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808777528.0" user="OpelSmith" delta="False">
    <text>I came to post this. As an American, my stereotype is northern/eastern European food is very bland</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
