<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808077768.0" user="tubesweaterguru" delta="False">
    <text>You’re fundamentally wrong about traditional American meals. 

We have steaks, hot dogs, burgers, pork, chicken, every kind of meat you can imagine. We have BBQ. Jeez. 

We have hard shell crab and old bay. 

I have grandparents from Italy, so I grew up eating Italian foods...all the time. I’ve never even had a casserole. 

America has every single type of food you could ever imagine. 

Also, have you heard of England?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808095995.0" user="picklednood1e" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I'm not talking about just American foods because I am aware that America has every single type of food I can imagine, I mean traditional or national foods. Do you guys really consider  hot dogs  as a national dish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808104060.0" user="tubesweaterguru" delta="False">
    <text>We’re America. We are a mix of everything...we don’t really have national foods.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808145366.0" user="Melodic_Echidna" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about America is it's really big. So local regions have their own cuisine and it's not constant across the country. The southwest has tex mex. Louisiana has cajun. The northeast has 1001 recipes involving apples and really good lobster. Heck, the city of Cincinnati has its own kind of chili that is nothing like Texas chili that you can only get in the midwest and that a nontrival number of locals have very strong opinions (not to mention a specialized vocabulary) about.The immigrant communities in each major cities have american adaptations to their traditional recipes. Even our pizza has regional varieties.

Before you could ship ingredients wherever you wanted, the cooking people did depended on what you could grow where you were.  And Americas culinary traditions reflect that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808240033.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>Looking for a national dish is like looking for a European Union dish. If you want to look country by country when looking at Europe, that’s more comparable to looking state by state in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808496012.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>Hot Dogs are very much considered a national dish if that could be said of anything.  They are one of the most popular meals in the US and are a typical thing to expect at a large cookout or at a sports game.  There are few dishes that are even worth arguing that they are more American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808710032.0" user="super_poggielicious" delta="False">
    <text>It's entirely dependent on where you're at in the US as to what type of cuisine is considered the local favorite. It's more helpful to think of the US in terms of landmass as 50 smaller countries with 328.2 million of us spread across it. Each one has its own unique take on food. Even regions have things there known for. FYI for your own sanity don't ask which is better on some things lol example being NY pizza vs Chicago pizza. The majority of our ancestors all came from elsewhere so they brought their cultures and food here with them. Our food became a combination of the older cultures that blended. There is west coast food and east coat food. Midwestern state's food choices, Northerners, and Southerners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35809645928.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>mass produced rubbish has good marketing.  That is what gets associated with "America" at big events.

People aren't eating hot dogs all the time.  Though, if you want cheap, easy to prepare food for a large group that is bland enough to unobjectionable to most people, hot dogs are a reasonable choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35810795064.0" user="legal_throwaway45" delta="False">
    <text>A hot dog is a national dish for Americans just as

\-- toad in the hole, black pudding is for the English-- scotch Eggs, haggis is for the Scottish

\-- Flammekueche for the french

\-- sauerkraut for the Germans

All of these dishes have the advantage of being easy to make.  Hot dogs are not that different from German wurst or English sausages, just spiced and cased a little different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
