<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808187051.0" user="SailorSpoon11" delta="False">
    <text>I think its funny that you think pb&amp;amp;j, canned foods, and pre cooked package foods are traditional American meals. I'm not saying people don't eat that stuff here but if you go home for mama's home cookin' its not gonna be peanut butter and jelly. Have you ever been to America, I am genuinely curious?

"Traditional" American foods can mean a lot of things. It can be soul food in the south, gumbo in Louisiana, Texas BBQ, seafood in Charleston, Philly Cheesesteaks, fry bread in Arizona etc, etc, etc. Yes, a lot of our food is influenced by other places because so many of our ancestors come from other places. And some Americanized versions of other country's foods you probably hear about are a straight up abomination. But a lot of is also fantastic. 

I wouldn't limit white people don't use flavor to white Americans because I've been to Australia, New Zealand, Ireland and The UK and found much of traditional food to be pretty bland. (No offense to those places, sorry! Lovely countries)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808210690.0" user="picklednood1e" delta="False">
    <text> I didn't say that I think that those foods are traditional American meals, it's what google said🤷‍♀️
And yes I've been to New Hampshire, Louisiana and Vermont but not for long enough to really understand the culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808269342.0" user="SailorSpoon11" delta="False">
    <text>Hm, I just googled traditional American meals and got very different results. Apple Pie, hamburgers, clam chowder, bagel and lox, Texas chili, hominy and grits, drop biscuits and sausage gravy, deep dish pizza</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
