<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35810613322.0" user="OkeyDoke47" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree about German food, having travelled there I found it very rudimentary and bland at best. French cuisine I found to be overrated. Nice, but not amazing. Myself and the wife made it a point to eat at one expensive French restaurant and we ended up spending about $200 eating food that raised an eyebrow, but not in the way we expected.

England, noted for its boring cuisine, I find incredibly hearty and satisfying. Bangers and mash - it's sausages on a mashed potato base with some onions and gravy on top - sounds dull yet it's anything but. A good beefsteak and Guiness pie with chips - heaven awaits. It may be down to the weather over there - cold and bleak a lot of the time lends itself to warm, hearty pub grub.

I've had little to do with American cuisine or cooking, but I must say that some of it looks great.

I think we equate fine dining with how complicated it was to prepare and cook. Anthony Bourdain was quite the advocate for simple food, some of it with no more than three ingredients. Reading one of his books, he said that whenever he was invited to someone's place for dinner they would work themselves into a nervous wreck with what they would do. He would tell them, ''just cook me your pot roast, or your casserole and I'm sure it'll be great'' (rest his soul).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
