<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808485034.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>The thing you have to remember about the white population of the US is that their families have all only lived in the US for a couple hundred years at the most.  Most people can easily trace their origins to a specific place in Europe and even generations later many people still live in a community of people who come from similar parts of Europe because of the way that immigrants came over in waves.  As a result, many traditional dishes here are variations of dishes in Europe because those dishes were brought over by people from those places and they are still made by their descendants.

In my case, a large part of my family was living in Easter Europe (including the Ukraine) only 120 years ago.  A lot of the traditional family recipes in my family are probably not to different from things you ate growing up.

As a whole, German heritage is represented this way larger than any other group.  Around 45 million people identify as primarily German ancestry in the US and as a result German cuisine is pervasive throughout the US.  Some of the dishes go by different names due to hefty anti-German propaganda during the World Wars, but even a cursory look at American food and German food makes the connection obvious.  Especially when it comes to sausages and bread, there are a lot of very flavor rich styles that have been carried over.

German if far from the only style represented in the core of American cooking this way.  Irish, Italian, and Polish are also examples of groups that came to the US in large numbers and even generations latter are major influences on American culture in general and food choices in particular.  These different styles being combined together is what has become "white people food" in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
