<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35808283912.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>The critique doesn't really make sense. The US is probably the greatest melting pot of different cultures and their various cuisines on the planet. We have amazing regional specialities that are unique to the US giving the melting pot history *but we also have "pure" versions of all the food you can find elsewhere in the world.* You say places like Germany and France can cook, but we have traditional German and French restaurants here, too. The only real difference is that its much easier to find a zillion other different kinds of food here than it is in Germany or France. Thats the one thing I've primarily disliked about traveling abroad - it doesn't matter if it's Africa, Asia, Europe, or South America - i can get traditional dishes just as good as native ones within a 20min drive of my house in the states, but none of those places have the same variety of different foods locally available. For example I can get very good German food in Germany, and I can get very good German food in the US; I can get very good Japanese food in Japan, and I can get very good Japanese food in the US. Where it gets tough is finding good German food in Japan or good Japanese food in Germany.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808343951.0" user="picklednood1e" delta="False">
    <text>But since when is German, French and Japanese food considered as American food?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808436495.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>All American food is descended and derived from other cuisines. A bunch of white second generation Germans cooking German food in America are still Americans, and thus are relevant when we're talking about white Americans being able to cook or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808569645.0" user="AslanLivesOn" delta="False">
    <text>Most people think of American food as junk food. The other stuff you mentined is food adopted from other countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35809313686.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The other stuff you mentined is food adopted from other countries.

Yes. Thats what American food is. Our national cuisine is, probably more than any other country, just a hodgepodge of food from other cultures. Thats why I don't understand OP's point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35809597754.0" user="FernandoTatisJunior" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re saying that American food is all junk food if you exclude most food?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35811335957.0" user="AslanLivesOn" delta="False">
    <text>No I'm.saying most of what foreigners would consider "american food" is junk food and maybe BBQ.

Tne other foods are considered taken from elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35808550224.0" user="ArchieBunkersGhost" delta="False">
    <text>When Hans, Jean Luc &amp;amp; Akiko set foot on U.S. soil and started cooking their dishes. The U.S. is a melting pot. This shows more in our foods than anything. 

Sometimes they would have to make changes for what is available locally. Then you end up with new cuisines. In Louisiana this became Cajun &amp;amp; Creole cuisines. 

I think a lot of people not from the U.S. tend to think of it as just one country with one culture and cuisine. When in reality it's more like 55 countries (can't forget our lil territory buddies) that share a federal government. So think of the U.S. more like the European Union. 

Each state and territory will have it's own cuisine. Some of those will cross state borders as well. Some of those states will have multiple cuisines in different areas. So do countries like France &amp;amp; Italy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35810008111.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>The problem here is that you're thinking of America as an ethnostate, which it is not.  It is a diverse collection of fusion cultures because the US is a culture of immigrants.  What you are identifying as "American food" are just things that are common across these broad cultures, but that doesn't make them important.  It's as if you were trying to identify a European "national" dish.  You end up with generic things like bread because you've washed out all the diversity by taking a satellite view of things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
