<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1234982968.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kf9yyg/cmv_when_people_say_white_people_cant_cook_theyre/">
    <title>CMV: When people say "white people can't cook" they're talking about Americans</title>
    <original_poster>picklednood1e</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry in advance if I make mistakes, English isn't my native language.  I was born in Eastern Europe and I find it slightly annoying when people of color mock white people by saying that we don't spice our food, that we can't cook, have no culture, etc. I understand that it's mostly jokes and I'm not offended, I even find it funny sometimes, but it still gets me thinking. 

If you look at white people from European countries such as Germany, Ukraine, France, Switzerland, etc. you'll see that we have a very rich culture and amazing meals with alot of flavor. Maybe this is just stereotypes, but from the google research I've done about American traditional (if I can call it that) food, it's pretty much stuff like pb&amp;amp;j sandwiches, pies and alot of precooked/canned meals. But seriously, when I think of a traditional American meal nothing comes to my mind, besides the americanized ethnic foods or fast food.

In general, I find it very annoying when people assume that all white people act like white Americans but it stands out the most when people talk about food and culture.

What do you think about this? Does this even make sense?

Edit: I also wanted to add that I'm not trying to offend anyone! I'm here to educate myself and see other's pov.
Edit: After reading the responses I realized that I didn't know that Americans considered foods from other countries as part of their culture, but it makes sense to me now!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35811274496.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>Germans just put Nutella on bread too, maybe pop open a jar of knackwurst and dip it in mustard from a squeeze tube. Their traditional fast food is chopped up sausage drenched in a sweet spiced ketchup out of a bottle, or just a hunk of meat on a roll. All industrialized societies have their convenience food, and you're only seeing our convenience food. 

Of course, even our convenience food can be excellent. You've never had a sandwich as good as a po'boy or Philly cheese steak. Well, unless you've tried a Vietnamese banh mi, and we have those here too. 

Americans have the most awesome pork ribs, and done right they can take many hours to make. We make hamburgers better than anyone else (no, McDonald's is distant disgusting relative we don't invite over at the holidays). Go to the South you have pork that has been slowly smoked for a whole day, shredded, a delicious vinegar sauce added, and put on a bun with pickles. Delicious! Our pot roasts cook slowly in a pot all day with various vegetables to give it flavor, and then you eat the vegetables that have soaked up the delicious juices. 

Go up to the Northeast and some amazing things are done with seafood, especially the lobster rolls and chowders and clam bakes. Go down Louisiana way, and the jambalaya and gumbo will blow your mind, and you didn't know crawfish could taste that good. 

Then you move more West and the Hispanic influence kicks in with some amazing dishes. You know how Germany has amazing Turkish food because of the immigrants? Same here with Mexican and further South. 

We even do the same thing others do, just by a different name. The famous German schnitzel is just a pounded pork steak breaded and fried. Here we call that "chicken fried."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
