<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123507835.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21j797/cmv_there_must_be_some_conspiracy_or_governmental/">
    <title>CMV: There must be some conspiracy or governmental cover-up regarding this missing plane.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no way a plane can go missing in the year 2014 without any official having any clue what happened to it. The globe is surveilled every second. I read my license plate from a Google maps view of my house. The NSA has the power to read every piece of digital communication we send... and yet a plane full of people with phones went missing. That cannot be. 
I just don't understand how a plane can go missing. If they get any information at all from the black box, won't that lead them right to it? If the NSA can read my texts and track my phone, can't someone track the phones of the people on the plane? There is 1000 ways for my government to spy on me. When the boston bomber went missing the swat team used heat seeking technology to find him hiding in a boat in someone's back yard. And somehow a $50 million plane disappeared into thin air. With no crash evidence... no nothing.

Something is up. Not sure what, but somebody is up to something. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27111623325.0" user="TBFProgrammer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I read my license plate from a Google maps view of my house.

Street view is compiled from pictures taken by a google van as it moves through various neighborhoods. It is not up to date information and in many places isn't even recent.

&amp;gt; If they get any information at all from the black box, won't that lead them right to it?

The black box only transmits when it hits water, and has a limited battery/range. You have to find the plane before you can get at the data recorders.

&amp;gt; can't someone track the phones of the people on the plane?

Most were probably off or in airplane mode, so they wouldn't be actively establishing contact with towers, even if they flew within range of them. A satellite phone left on could potentially be tracked, but that's going to be a rarity.

&amp;gt; heat seeking technology to find him hiding in a boat

Requires a very restricted search area, a living person target and few alternative sources of heat.

The tools available for tracking the plane were satellite and radar. Since the plane left its flight path unexpectedly, no one was watching it in real time. This meant that no high accuracy tools were deployed to monitor the path of the plane, since by the time anyone knew something was up, they no longer knew where the plane was. The long delay in determining what had happened each time the plane turned meant that they never caught up.

Under the assumption that this was some kind of navigational error, software and/or pilot, the plane would likely have run out of fuel and crashed into the Ocean. After that, it would sink beneath the waves, leaving no trace other than two underwater beacons from the black box.

The most problematic part is that the pilots apparently couldn't gain sufficient manual control to land the plane or transmit a distress signal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
