<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123507835.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21j797/cmv_there_must_be_some_conspiracy_or_governmental/">
    <title>CMV: There must be some conspiracy or governmental cover-up regarding this missing plane.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no way a plane can go missing in the year 2014 without any official having any clue what happened to it. The globe is surveilled every second. I read my license plate from a Google maps view of my house. The NSA has the power to read every piece of digital communication we send... and yet a plane full of people with phones went missing. That cannot be. 
I just don't understand how a plane can go missing. If they get any information at all from the black box, won't that lead them right to it? If the NSA can read my texts and track my phone, can't someone track the phones of the people on the plane? There is 1000 ways for my government to spy on me. When the boston bomber went missing the swat team used heat seeking technology to find him hiding in a boat in someone's back yard. And somehow a $50 million plane disappeared into thin air. With no crash evidence... no nothing.

Something is up. Not sure what, but somebody is up to something. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27111606552.0" user="AresSab3r" delta="False">
    <text>If they were doing what they were told at the start of every flight, then they should all have had their phones turned off so you wouldn't be able to track them. There is an entire Ocean to search through, so it isn't hard to understand why the plane is hard to find without already having a rough idea where it was. And you seem to be assuming that the NSA is spying on a plane full of Malaysian and Chinese people, which they wouldn't be, and they wouldn't admit to it even if they did because that would probably lead to war with South East Asia.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
