<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="123507835.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/21j797/cmv_there_must_be_some_conspiracy_or_governmental/">
    <title>CMV: There must be some conspiracy or governmental cover-up regarding this missing plane.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no way a plane can go missing in the year 2014 without any official having any clue what happened to it. The globe is surveilled every second. I read my license plate from a Google maps view of my house. The NSA has the power to read every piece of digital communication we send... and yet a plane full of people with phones went missing. That cannot be. 
I just don't understand how a plane can go missing. If they get any information at all from the black box, won't that lead them right to it? If the NSA can read my texts and track my phone, can't someone track the phones of the people on the plane? There is 1000 ways for my government to spy on me. When the boston bomber went missing the swat team used heat seeking technology to find him hiding in a boat in someone's back yard. And somehow a $50 million plane disappeared into thin air. With no crash evidence... no nothing.

Something is up. Not sure what, but somebody is up to something. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27112881549.0" user="Casus125" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is no way a plane can go missing in the year 2014 without any official having any clue what happened to it. 

Why?

&amp;gt; The globe is surveilled every second.

Every second isn't quite accurate, that's a level of data streaming that isn't really practical.  It's also very, very large.  Obscenely large.  And airplanes are not that big in comparison.

&amp;gt; I read my license plate from a Google maps view of my house.

Why would anybody waste a satellite to stare at an empty body of water?

&amp;gt; The NSA has the power to read every piece of digital communication we send

irrelevant

&amp;gt; and yet a plane full of people with phones went missing.

People with phones go missing all the time in urban areas, what's so shocking that a plane goes missing in the vastness of the ocean?

&amp;gt; That cannot be. I just don't understand how a plane can go missing.

Radar is only effective for so far, and without communication to report on your location, it becomes very easy for a plane to disappear.

&amp;gt; If they get any information at all from the black box, won't that lead them right to it?

The black box is not magical, it can't call you up and let you know where it is.  It may have an emergency transmittor, but guess what? That's heavy and does not float, so it won't be able to transmit from the bottom of the ocean.

&amp;gt;  If the NSA can read my texts and track my phone, can't someone track the phones of the people on the plane?

The NSA can read your texts because it goes through a network.  They can track your phone because it is communication with cell phone towers and reports it's location.

In the middle of the ocean there are none of those.

&amp;gt;  When the boston bomber went missing the swat team used heat seeking technology to find him hiding in a boat in someone's back yard.

Because they had reasonable expectations that he would be in the city, and on the run.  They also imposed martial law and ordered all civilians inside their homes, and conducted a thorough door to door manhunt.

&amp;gt; And somehow a $50 million plane disappeared into thin air. With no crash evidence... no nothing.

If a plane crashes into the ocean, it's going to blow into a bunch of tiny little pieces, most of them will sink.  The smaller, floaty stuff will be impossible to notice and will drift for miles and miles on the ocean current.

You're vastly overestimating how useful our technology is, and vastly underrating how large the oceans are, and especially what airplane wreckage would look like in that vastness.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
