<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1241884310.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kjdw2e/cmv_if_you_live_in_a_traditionally_christian/">
    <title>CMV: if you live in a “traditionally Christian” nation you should use Merry Christmas as the default greeting/goodbye unless you’re asked not to.</title>
    <original_poster>physioworld</original_poster>
    <original_post>Basically I think of it similar to misgendering people. In that context use the pronouns of the gender they appear to present as (unless you already know the person’s wishes). If and when someone asks you to use an alternate set, you apologise and change going forward. 

The same should be done with Christmas- in my experience almost nobody has any genuine objection to being told merry Christmas, hell, I was discussing just today with a woman in a full hijab our favourite (largely secular) aspects of Christmas, all the while referring to things as “Christmas XYZ”. However if someone tells me they’d prefer happy holidays then I’ll just switch. Just like pronouns it literally makes no difference to me. 

You can change my view by showing me that knowingly using words that will make someone else feel less welcome or upset is not worth it compared to the potential loss I might feel at using a different term. Of course maybe you can come up with other arguments I’ve not thought of. 

CMV

Edit: this only applies “at this time of year” say more or less the month of December.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35849873131.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;compared to the potential loss I might feel at using a different term.

Which is presumably absolutely nothing at all, so the tradeoff here is really simple and obviously weighted to one side</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849888842.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>I should have said “which one might feel”. I myself feel basically no loss, someone else might say they just life saying that phrase and only get to do it a few weeks a year, so they might see the loss as greater than me?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849901838.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>Still no reason to mandate the expression for other people, which is unnecessarily politicising what is ultimately just personal expression and preference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849913341.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear I’m not trying to mandate anything, I think people should be able to say what they want, in fact you should be within your rights to tell people to go fuck themselves as you walk away. My whole point is that if you choose to wish someone a merry Christmas and they ask you to in future wish them happy holidays, it makes more sense to politely apologise and use the alternate phrase than to dig your heels in and stick with merry Christmas. 

And yeah, it’s a stupid topic and tbh is only really talked about on far right platforms, the whole war on Christmas is a moral panic that really barely exists, but I just felt like putting in my two cents and seeing if I should change them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849918308.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>But your title says that everyone should default to using 'merry Christmas' unless asked not to. But obviously some people just prefer using something else, so why can't they just use something else from the get go rather than waiting to be asked not to</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
