<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1241884310.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kjdw2e/cmv_if_you_live_in_a_traditionally_christian/">
    <title>CMV: if you live in a “traditionally Christian” nation you should use Merry Christmas as the default greeting/goodbye unless you’re asked not to.</title>
    <original_poster>physioworld</original_poster>
    <original_post>Basically I think of it similar to misgendering people. In that context use the pronouns of the gender they appear to present as (unless you already know the person’s wishes). If and when someone asks you to use an alternate set, you apologise and change going forward. 

The same should be done with Christmas- in my experience almost nobody has any genuine objection to being told merry Christmas, hell, I was discussing just today with a woman in a full hijab our favourite (largely secular) aspects of Christmas, all the while referring to things as “Christmas XYZ”. However if someone tells me they’d prefer happy holidays then I’ll just switch. Just like pronouns it literally makes no difference to me. 

You can change my view by showing me that knowingly using words that will make someone else feel less welcome or upset is not worth it compared to the potential loss I might feel at using a different term. Of course maybe you can come up with other arguments I’ve not thought of. 

CMV

Edit: this only applies “at this time of year” say more or less the month of December.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35849877953.0" user="promnv" delta="False">
    <text>Could you clarify this for me? You mean like, person A sees person B on the street, they say to each other "Merry Christmas", instead of "hi" or in addition to "hi"? And then they say "Merry Christmas" again after chatting about the weather instead of bye?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849902226.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Yea that’s maybe slightly misleading by using the word default in my OP...i mostly just mean that if you’re going to express your wish that a person has a jolly old time at this specific part of the year, then merry Christmas is a reasonable default</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35849945739.0" user="Malasalasala" delta="False">
    <text>It's no better a choice than anything like happy holidays or anything either though.

In your misgendering example, it's like getting annoyed that someone hasn't specifically gendered a sentence that doesnt need to be gendered. 

The analogue of the "its Merry Christmas not happy holidays" crowd are the equivalent of the below:

P1: "They're cool, I like them"

P2: "IT'S A HIM, IT'S 'I LIKE HIM'"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
