<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="124602086.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/226nl2/cmv_i_dont_trust_any_scientific_organization_who/">
    <title>CMV: I don't trust any scientific organization who is affiliated with one or more government.</title>
    <original_poster>Trebuchetrebuchaut</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always been very skeptical of government funded research. To me, it seems very counterintuitive to have a likely biased entity handling something that is supposed to be assessed with absolutely no bias whatsoever. It goes without saying, no matter how subtle the influence, government funded science is always funded by people with either militaristic and/or political objectives. 

I want to approach the climate change issue specifically; there are abundant examples of people in science who disagree with man-made climate change, why are these people frequently considered irrelevant by most EPA-like government organizations?


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than just downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27123189764.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>I guess the question is, do you simply distrust *all* scientific organizations? Because all funders of science have agendas and bias. 

You seem to be engaging in a form of [circumstantial ad hominem fallacy](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_hominem#Circumstantial). The bias that someone making an argument might (or might not) have is irrelevant to the claims that they are making. 

It's a bit of a non sequitor in any case, because the motivations of scientists are, largely, not motivated by a desire to please people in power, but rather by a desire to understand how things work. 

It also hardly "goes without saying" that government funded research is "always" funded by people with militaristic or political objectives, except in the most trivial sense that one might consider anything done by a government to be "political" in nature. 

Additionally, "political in nature" is not the same thing as having "political objectives". The government doesn't have "objectives" in any case, though members of the government might. If you look at science funding that has wide multi-partisan support, such as medical research, it's very hard to ascribe any kind of *specific* political motivation to the funding. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
