<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1253030939.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kq0suz/cmv_cooking_up_shit_against_famous_dead_people/">
    <title>CMV: Cooking up shit against famous dead people should be put to a stop immediately, as they are not there to defend themselves and will never be.</title>
    <original_poster>Elegant-Sector8993</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know Charlie Chaplin dated people up to 15 years younger than him, but now and then I always wonder whether some shitheads decided to cook up shit against him because he was dead and there would be nobody to contradict their statements. And then there's Bob Marley, the conspiracies against whom I am having serious doubts. Why would anybody bully his way to the top just for some fat cash, and then slide back to obscurity? And then there is Elvis, who dated virgin girls and fucked them albeit Priscilla herself downplayed these allegations. I do not understand it. Someone help me.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35919304627.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919375881.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919989322.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>What did he say?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35920901126.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/DaiLoDong – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+DaiLoDong&amp;amp;message=DaiLoDong+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/kq0suz/-/gi1fctv/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/DaiLoDong – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+DaiLoDong&amp;amp;message=DaiLoDong+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/kq0suz/-/gi1fctv/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
