<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1253030939.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kq0suz/cmv_cooking_up_shit_against_famous_dead_people/">
    <title>CMV: Cooking up shit against famous dead people should be put to a stop immediately, as they are not there to defend themselves and will never be.</title>
    <original_poster>Elegant-Sector8993</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know Charlie Chaplin dated people up to 15 years younger than him, but now and then I always wonder whether some shitheads decided to cook up shit against him because he was dead and there would be nobody to contradict their statements. And then there's Bob Marley, the conspiracies against whom I am having serious doubts. Why would anybody bully his way to the top just for some fat cash, and then slide back to obscurity? And then there is Elvis, who dated virgin girls and fucked them albeit Priscilla herself downplayed these allegations. I do not understand it. Someone help me.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35919151128.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Why would people spend time and effort fabricating slander about  dead people?

But they do, who is harmed by it? Certainly not the dead person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919367152.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>People believe it, that's the point, and this tarnishes the image of the dead man. How many people believe that Elvis fucked virgin girls in his early twenties, albeit Priscilla was the only one he actually had a relationship with, and she downplayed those allegations? Similarly, too many believe Bob Marley was an eccentric bully who got all the way to the top because of bribery, and this is where I have serious doubts. I decided to post it here to get some other viewpoints.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919765653.0" user="A_Unique_Nobody" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;this tarnished the image of the dead man

think of it this way, say you lived in this neighborhood and there was a guy who always talked shit about you behind your back, but one day you decide to move to a new neighborhood where none of your old neighbors live, the old neighbor is probably still shit talking you, but you wouldnt know or care would you?

its the same thing with dead people, since they are dead it no longer matters what people think of them, they have no honor/pride to damage

"stand amongst the ashes of a trillion dead souls and ask the ghosts if honor matters, their silence is your answer"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35920986367.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>That... is a good point. How to award a delta?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35921105663.0" user="A_Unique_Nobody" delta="False">
    <text>You can copy paste the delta symbol (given in the sidebar) and reply to my comment with that, or you can reply with 
! delta (without the space)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927504502.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Aight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35923400936.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why would people spend time and effort fabricating slander about  dead people?

For political motivation, rewriting history to help bolster their side and knock down the accomplishments of those persons.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
