<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1253030939.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/kq0suz/cmv_cooking_up_shit_against_famous_dead_people/">
    <title>CMV: Cooking up shit against famous dead people should be put to a stop immediately, as they are not there to defend themselves and will never be.</title>
    <original_poster>Elegant-Sector8993</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know Charlie Chaplin dated people up to 15 years younger than him, but now and then I always wonder whether some shitheads decided to cook up shit against him because he was dead and there would be nobody to contradict their statements. And then there's Bob Marley, the conspiracies against whom I am having serious doubts. Why would anybody bully his way to the top just for some fat cash, and then slide back to obscurity? And then there is Elvis, who dated virgin girls and fucked them albeit Priscilla herself downplayed these allegations. I do not understand it. Someone help me.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35919036822.0" user="ghytiy" delta="False">
    <text>Does it really matter if they're dead? 

Think about it this way, if they did nefarious shit in their life and made it past the finish line without controversy, they fully got away with that shit. Talking about it can make things better. The noble lie that all our celebrity people are good is bullshit.

And if they didn't do it, it's not like it's really hurting anyone or anything besides a dead persons reputation, all of which will be forgotten in a couple hundred years anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919046507.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>A dead person's reputation is being slandered and nobody cares?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919079421.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>Voltaire once said "To the living we owe respect, but to the dead we owe only truth"   


or something similar to that.   


Nobody that I'm aware of is advocating lying about the dead. However we do not owe them anything more than the truth. Speaking honestly about who they were and what they did is the entire obligation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919373987.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>In the modern world, though, it is impossible to separate fact from fiction, reality from cookups, and all that. I do not even know anymore whether the allegations against these famous personalities are true or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919424016.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>So should we just not speak about dead people at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919620474.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Not speak *badly*, or cook up shit against them. You can speak of them without cooking up trash about them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919635627.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>So you can lie about the dead, just only positively?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35920990090.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Why lie at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35922656450.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the modern world, though, it is impossible to separate fact from fiction, reality from cookups

&amp;amp;#x200B;

By your previous statement, we can't know if something is true or false when we're talking about people from the past which means everything is a potential lie.   


so if we're saying that , and we're saying that you're not allowed to say bad things about dead people because they might not be true then we either can't say anything about dead people because they might not be true OR good lies aren't a problem</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927495837.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>The first statement is actually correct. We'll never know whether Charlie Chaplin actually dated women up to 15 years younger than him, or if Bob Marley really was a big bully.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927692949.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, we also don't know if George Washington was a faithful and dutiful husband or if he was a philandering scoundrel</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927745267.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>He had an expensive birthday bash while his army starved... is that not knowing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35930826008.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know? If we can't know what people did in the past, then we don't know anything about these people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35932773808.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>We do know something. Charlie Chaplin lived and breathed films. He gave the silent film era the popularity it has now. I believe he was a pedo but we will never know for sure. They are dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35933427092.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>I don't even know what you're arguing at this point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35933558181.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>I mean you did not know that George Washington starved his army while he had an expensive birthday bash, so...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35933706346.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know he did? Maybe someone made that up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35933711759.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Unless you're saying someone decided to forge documentary evidence...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35933761249.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>you mean cooking up shit

this is my point. You've just argued "we can't be sure about the past"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35934306110.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>We cannot, unless there's documentary evidence of it. How do we know Lincoln put a stop to slavery? Documentary evidence! How do we know Charlie Chaplin wasn't a mythological figure? Documentary evidence! And so on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35934368539.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>What do we count as documentary evidence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35934500804.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>In this context? Evidence that has been documented and offered at trial to establish its existence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35934690597.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but the vast majority of what most people do or have done is not documented and offered in trials. 

So that standard doesn't really work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35934785468.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>If you say so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35919685044.0" user="5xum" delta="False">
    <text>What if the truth *is* bad? I presume it's OK to speak badly about Hitler?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35920988156.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Hitler was a nutjob. He's not even in the conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35921049924.0" user="5xum" delta="False">
    <text>Hitler is an extreme example, but my point stands. The question is:

&amp;gt;Is it OK to speak badly about people who were bad and are now dead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927500989.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>Uhm... who was bad back then? Those were simpler times, when all it took was a hat and coat to make the world seem like an alright place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927573957.0" user="5xum" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Uhm... who was bad back then?

Wel... Hitler, for one? Also, you still didn't answer my question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35927739764.0" user="Elegant-Sector8993" delta="False">
    <text>What was your question?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
