<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1256757839.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ks8ojz/cmv_a_deep_state_not_only_exist_in_america_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: A Deep State not only exist in America, it is an inevitable result of the socioeconomic political system of this country.</title>
    <original_poster>gentryadams</original_poster>
    <original_post>When the founding fathers debated on a new federal constitution that would preserve the burgeoning yet fragile Union, their primary concerns were to create a functional democratic government that would pay due respect to State rights,  with institutional check and balances to prevent an over centralisation of power and to protect the rights of individual citizens. The resulting Constitution and the Bill of Rights gave birth to a new form of government that embodied the highest ideals of Enlightenment thinking. Or so we are told.   

This system of governance paid a lot of attention to matters of domestic affairs, yet despite their best intentions, the founders of America did not envision the Union’s eventual development into a global empire. 

The early 20th Century saw the unprecedented destructive powers of modern warfare and the deterioration of the European Powers. From the ashes the US emerged as a new global power and it is at this point, a separation of the Public State and the Deep State began to emerge, much out of necessity. 

At this point it would be useful to define my terms of the Deep State: ‘A perpetual force not influenced by electoral results, that holds great control in determining domestic and foreign action of the State. ‘

I believe there are two facets of this Deep State. The first is indirect and the second is direct. 

This indirect force comprised of Corporate giants, Wall Street interests, International banking interests, the military industrial complex, exerting its control through lobbyists, unelected government officials, organisations such as the Council of foreign relations, Trilateral commission and various foundations representing the disproportionately influential families of America. 

The indirect force combined holds all the keys to power for any politician. They provide campaign funding, the revolving door between government and private enterprise, the coverage and tone of mainstream media. No politician could continue their tenure without the majority support of this indirect force. 

The direct force of the Deep State is mostly manifested through certain branches of the FBI, the CIA and the Military. I believe at this stage, with so much public information about the clandestine activities of the CIA against both foreign powers and domestic citizens, the complicity of J Edgar Hoover in various nefarious plots are strong enough indicators that these organisations are not answerable to average citizens like ourselves. As part fo the executive arm of government, do they see themselves as being subservient to their Commander in Chief? The answer it seems, not necessarily. I believe their true motivation lies in a form of elitism embodied in the continuous  mission of their organisation to protect America’s place at the forefront of global hegemony. 

A great manifestation of the Deep State lies in its pivotal role in the exertion of foreign policies. The CIA which traces its roots to WWII in the capacity of OSS Office of Strategic service was originally a joint venture between the British MI6. When Truman signed into law the National Security act of 1947, CIA was born. In a the Bipolar climate of global power of its time, the CIA was the frontline against USSR in the subsequent decades of the Cold War. It established its global networks through pockets of convenience within the Marshall plan budget and retained solid ties with Wall Street. This is evidenced  by the first civilian appointment to the position of director a Mr Allen Dulles the brother of then Secretary of State under Eisenhower John Foster Dulles, both of whom worked In Kuhn, Loeb and Company, an investment giant in Wall Street with documented ties to Trotsky and Hitler. 

It is well documented today that the CIA was instrumental in financing coup against Mossadeq in Iran 1953, the Guatemalan civil war in 54, the Bay of Pigs in 61, Coup against the socialist government of Allende in Chile circa 72... MK ultra which drugged countless of American citizens with LSD and other psychoactive drugs, illegal wiretapping of various dissident groups, drug dealing in African American neighbourhoods... The list of the most abhorrent criminality is virtually endless. To quote Mike Pompeo “they lied, they cheated, they stole.. “ they should have added murder and torture to the list as well. 

All this is done under the name of America without the oversight of Congress. If that’s not a deep state in manifestation, I don’t know what is. In fact it should not even be controversial to talk about a Deep State that is not accountable to the people, we have ourselves to blame when we let clowns like Donald Trump cheapen the term and deflect us from the real issues at hand. 

The Deep State in this sense becomes a byproduct of Capitalism with Imperialist ambitions, operating unbridled for centuries which inevitably results in the concentration of wealth. This wealth is used to buy up politicians who knows not to bite the hand that feeds them. Institutions born out of elitism that see it as a duty to govern without being influenced by the capricious will of the masses. WIth the appearance of the Public State, America can do no wrong, we could collectively point at the silly Orangutang fresh out of office and use him as a scapegoat for the collective ills of our nation. With each exchange of power the slate is once again wiped clean until it inevitably gets filthy again.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35941607481.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, nothing to really argue. The historical examples are great, the definition is precise and easier agreed upon.  I dont think your idea is radical in the slightest. Maybe its worded provocatively, but this its a story thats played out time and time again, only with different actors throughout the ages. What we supposed to attempt to change your view? America is super free, has a prosperous middle class and is well governed with strategic and forward thing foreign policy? Tbh i wish i could, but i can’t. Elements of such a society exists with American, but we are a long way from reaching such potential.  Also i appreciate how you gave homage to the the deep state was born out necessity. Which leads me to my great dilemma, if not the current system, than which? And how to we get there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35941677935.0" user="gentryadams" delta="False">
    <text>Quite right, nothing I said above that hasn’t been parodied by the likes of South Park, so it should be something common to the American consciousness right? Perhaps, I think we are almost there. 

The election of Trump in 2016 was a great signal, if nothing else, it showed that Americans, especially our youth have had enough. Absent of the corruption brought forth by a cushy middle class lifestyle experienced by our forebears, this need for change I believe will reach a tipping point in this country within the next 20 years. I think first and foremost we need to open acknowledgement of the corruptions inherent in our system, and not let sensationalism and conspiracy theories cloud our thinking. The amount of people who would point to a secret cabal such as the Illuminati, neomarxist, or whatever straw man they want to attack as the power behind the throne should be disregarded. These are the great distractors of progress, they are benefiting from our collective misery.

An honest admission that America is no longer a democracy, that our republic has lost its way, that the people do have the power to reign this in. We are reaching a critical point in human history, in technology, in ecology, the impetus for change is here, what we need to do is to separate the truth from the lies. That would be a huge step forward.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35943305286.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, of course Yes. My “push back” isnt coming from disagreeing with you, its simply bc this is the norm throughout human history, and the last couple hundred years was the exception. (Enlightenment thinking isnt perfect, but its powerful and relatively new. Liberal revolutions have changed history, but old power struggles are still here, and will always be, at least for our lifetimes) So whole heartedly I agree with your sentiment, hell, I think the country is on a collision course with fate is about 5-10, not 20 (though the time frame isnt so important) And I invite you to think about how you might change this nation/world, rather than saying, “American is corrupt, and causing most if not all our problems” id invite you to ponder how to remedy the problems of truth decay, centralization of wealth and power, etc. I think its fairly obvious to many of us that shits fucked for a lot of people, but why shit is fucked is only important if we use the why’s to answer how we can fix it. My answer is getting a lot of people mediating, blockchain for just about everything, and starting a business that solves problems. My heart goes out to you friend and hopefully we can continue pushing back against authoritarian power structures and seek truth in all its myriad forms!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
