<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1256757839.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ks8ojz/cmv_a_deep_state_not_only_exist_in_america_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: A Deep State not only exist in America, it is an inevitable result of the socioeconomic political system of this country.</title>
    <original_poster>gentryadams</original_poster>
    <original_post>When the founding fathers debated on a new federal constitution that would preserve the burgeoning yet fragile Union, their primary concerns were to create a functional democratic government that would pay due respect to State rights,  with institutional check and balances to prevent an over centralisation of power and to protect the rights of individual citizens. The resulting Constitution and the Bill of Rights gave birth to a new form of government that embodied the highest ideals of Enlightenment thinking. Or so we are told.   

This system of governance paid a lot of attention to matters of domestic affairs, yet despite their best intentions, the founders of America did not envision the Union’s eventual development into a global empire. 

The early 20th Century saw the unprecedented destructive powers of modern warfare and the deterioration of the European Powers. From the ashes the US emerged as a new global power and it is at this point, a separation of the Public State and the Deep State began to emerge, much out of necessity. 

At this point it would be useful to define my terms of the Deep State: ‘A perpetual force not influenced by electoral results, that holds great control in determining domestic and foreign action of the State. ‘

I believe there are two facets of this Deep State. The first is indirect and the second is direct. 

This indirect force comprised of Corporate giants, Wall Street interests, International banking interests, the military industrial complex, exerting its control through lobbyists, unelected government officials, organisations such as the Council of foreign relations, Trilateral commission and various foundations representing the disproportionately influential families of America. 

The indirect force combined holds all the keys to power for any politician. They provide campaign funding, the revolving door between government and private enterprise, the coverage and tone of mainstream media. No politician could continue their tenure without the majority support of this indirect force. 

The direct force of the Deep State is mostly manifested through certain branches of the FBI, the CIA and the Military. I believe at this stage, with so much public information about the clandestine activities of the CIA against both foreign powers and domestic citizens, the complicity of J Edgar Hoover in various nefarious plots are strong enough indicators that these organisations are not answerable to average citizens like ourselves. As part fo the executive arm of government, do they see themselves as being subservient to their Commander in Chief? The answer it seems, not necessarily. I believe their true motivation lies in a form of elitism embodied in the continuous  mission of their organisation to protect America’s place at the forefront of global hegemony. 

A great manifestation of the Deep State lies in its pivotal role in the exertion of foreign policies. The CIA which traces its roots to WWII in the capacity of OSS Office of Strategic service was originally a joint venture between the British MI6. When Truman signed into law the National Security act of 1947, CIA was born. In a the Bipolar climate of global power of its time, the CIA was the frontline against USSR in the subsequent decades of the Cold War. It established its global networks through pockets of convenience within the Marshall plan budget and retained solid ties with Wall Street. This is evidenced  by the first civilian appointment to the position of director a Mr Allen Dulles the brother of then Secretary of State under Eisenhower John Foster Dulles, both of whom worked In Kuhn, Loeb and Company, an investment giant in Wall Street with documented ties to Trotsky and Hitler. 

It is well documented today that the CIA was instrumental in financing coup against Mossadeq in Iran 1953, the Guatemalan civil war in 54, the Bay of Pigs in 61, Coup against the socialist government of Allende in Chile circa 72... MK ultra which drugged countless of American citizens with LSD and other psychoactive drugs, illegal wiretapping of various dissident groups, drug dealing in African American neighbourhoods... The list of the most abhorrent criminality is virtually endless. To quote Mike Pompeo “they lied, they cheated, they stole.. “ they should have added murder and torture to the list as well. 

All this is done under the name of America without the oversight of Congress. If that’s not a deep state in manifestation, I don’t know what is. In fact it should not even be controversial to talk about a Deep State that is not accountable to the people, we have ourselves to blame when we let clowns like Donald Trump cheapen the term and deflect us from the real issues at hand. 

The Deep State in this sense becomes a byproduct of Capitalism with Imperialist ambitions, operating unbridled for centuries which inevitably results in the concentration of wealth. This wealth is used to buy up politicians who knows not to bite the hand that feeds them. Institutions born out of elitism that see it as a duty to govern without being influenced by the capricious will of the masses. WIth the appearance of the Public State, America can do no wrong, we could collectively point at the silly Orangutang fresh out of office and use him as a scapegoat for the collective ills of our nation. With each exchange of power the slate is once again wiped clean until it inevitably gets filthy again.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35941866171.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>I think the key part of your claim is that the “visible state” ie the president, government, senate etc are all ultimately accountable to and controlled by the deep state interests and not only that but, crucially, there is nothing they can do to wrest this level of control away from them. 

It’s this last part that seems unlikely to me. Yes, there is a great level of control, but this is only possible thanks to how the legitimate system is set up. If tomorrow a law were passed that set lobbying of and donation to politicians for any purpose was illegal then that would strangle a large part of the control of the deep state interests. If something akin to the fairness doctrine were passed, whereby coverage of political figures in media (social and mainstream) could be made more representative of reality, with fear mongering tactics, for instance, banned, that would also constrain the ability of these interests to affect the levers of power. 

I’m not suggesting that it wouldn’t be hard to change these things, it is incredibly hard, but it is far from inevitable that they exist. The government is the true power (thankfully it is derived from the people) and there are channels that are very much available to massively curtail the influence of these currently very powerful entities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35941886630.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>The deep state truly exists, but they're not the high level officials that change every few years with elections. The deep state consists of the faceless, unelected, mid-level bureaucrats who remain in office regardless of who is in power, into which a cooperative relationship is established.

The deep state, for example, is the reason why companies like Google voluntarily complied with the PRISM project, providing data on American citizens to the NSA even though they were not required by law to do so. One of the largest customers for Amazon is the CIA. Ties like that are the real deep state.

&amp;gt; If tomorrow a law were passed that set lobbying of and donation to politicians for any purpose was illegal then that would strangle a large part of the control of the deep state interests

When you write to your senator because you want them to support or oppose a particular piece of legislation you are lobbying them. Are you suggesting banning that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35942064956.0" user="gentryadams" delta="False">
    <text>In an ideal world sure. I am not saying all legislators are mere puppets with no self agency, rather I am saying that they are rational actors who would presumably act in ways that best serve their self interests. 

In this two party state we live in, campaign funding is needed to contest or keep your seat in the legislature, often that amount runs into the millions. In presidential race the amount is calculated in billions. Only corporations with profit margins of hundreds of millions to billions could justify throwing that kind of money and expect a reasonable return on investment. Without the support of the party apparatus and the donors, the chances of a person making it to the ballot paper is very slim unless they are independently famous and wealthy. 

What are the chances then for 50% of these people who got to their present position to then go against their self interest and vote for a bill that would stop lobbyist and campaign donors? It’s not impossible, especially if We The People got together and fund this, but how likely is that in our skewered economy where the top 1% enjoys all the increase in income year by year and their wealth grows year by Year, whilst the rest of us toil for our next pay cheque? 

Media could be less fear mongering, but all mainstream media is owned by what 4 corporations? Being private enterprises with 24 hour news cycle, sensationalism = profit. Just compare CNN and BBC to see the differences in tone, language and message. 

The Deep state can exist within the public state is because the public state still maintains a veneer of legitimacy. It has de jure power which is illusionary, de facto power is held by those who hold the reins behind the Deep State. The government is the seat of power just that the theatre is owned by the actors in the deep state.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
