<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="125791631.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/22w5fz/cmv_romantic_love_is_a_manifestation_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Romantic love is a manifestation of the broader phenomenon of addiction</title>
    <original_poster>O_OY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I derive this view mainly from observing breakups, and drawing similarities to addiction.

1. When a breakup happens, often there is a craving for human contact (most of the time the subject is craving the ex). This craving is physiologically similar to the one that addiction uses (the VTA pathway).

2. Relationships often have the honeymoon phase, comfortable phase, etc. (I realize I'm not being very scientific here, but romantic love doesn't exactly have many scientific journals on it) This seems very similar to the tolerance that many addicts experience (first experience with a drug seems to be the most intense).

Please CMV! =(</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27134152992.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>It's a pretty tough sell to call something an "addiction" when the vast majority of the population experiences the exact same chemical response in the brain. Isn't it more an adaptive advantage which often results in a higher chance of a couple's offspring surviving until they themselves procreate?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134170477.0" user="O_OY" delta="False">
    <text>So would you say that love is a justifiable usage of the VTA pathway, while addiction is a subversion of that pathway?

Also, withdrawal symptoms that stem from breaking up aren't often seen as beneficial to the subject (depression amongst other things often result). Would that still be considered an adaptive advantage? 

I apologize in advance for seeming uneducated (not in the neurosciences). I'll try my best to read up on the book that /u/Jestercore suggested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134184316.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So would you say that love is a justifiable usage of the VTA pathway, while addiction is a subversion of that pathway?

I think the word "justifiable" is a pretty ridiculous standard to use. It's like asking if it's "justifiable" to use carbon as a basis for biological processes, or if it's "justifiable" that atoms are used to combine into molecules. We don't have a choice as to how we evolved.

&amp;gt;Also, withdrawal symptoms that stem from breaking up aren't often seen as beneficial to the subject (depression amongst other things often result). Would that still be considered an adaptive advantage? 

It's an adaptive advantage for those who can get over the depression and find someone else to mate with. For those who cannot, evolution does not consider it a "loss". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134199258.0" user="O_OY" delta="False">
    <text>My apologies. By justifiable I had meant a possible stressor that caused the evolutionary change to take place. Would you still say that is the case?

It's an adaptive advantage that produces more stressors. How is this an advantage?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134228514.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's an adaptive advantage that produces more stressors. How is this an advantage?

An adaptive advantage has nothing to do with how *comfortable* one's life is. Adaptive advantages are all about successfully passing on one's genes. 

Here's an example: There are two people, each falling in love with a different person. By making emotional bonds with a mate, it increases the chances of having an offspring survive until they themselves can procreate. 

Both of the relationships fail before they produce offspring. Person "A" goes through the "stressors" of depression, overcomes them and successfully pairs and mates with someone else. Person "A" has an *adaptive advantage*.

Person "B", on the other hand, does not overcome the "stressors" of depression, and fails to pair and mate with someone elese. Person "B" does not have an adaptive advantage, and does not pass on their genes.

Because of variation, not every individual gets an adaptive advantage. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
