<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="126209817.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/235449/cmv_money_does_buy_happiness/">
    <title>CMV: Money does buy happiness.</title>
    <original_poster>woflcopter</original_poster>
    <original_post>The term "money can't buy happiness" is, I think, false, mainly now within the past years. 

Let's give a scenario: you graduated college, got a decent $50k a year job and you live with your SO who makes around the same. Uh oh, student loans from college start to haunt you now, as well as car insurance, debt, mortgage, and maybe a dozen other things piling on top of that. Really the only way that you could "fix" this is by paying for it with money. 

And let's say that they somehow get a lot of money. And let's say they live in a world where there isn't really a tax or anything (think simple). They pay off all their debts and ironically all their money from that was the exact amount to pay everything off. They live much happier than before. 

And now you see how money buys happiness. It's true. Money does buy happiness. There are so many situations where money will solve your problems. I'm not trying to say how it's the only cause of happiness: there are things that can make people happy without the use of money, but generally if you have money it'll make you happier. I know that many people with tons of money are also depressed, but when you get a middle aged mid income family paying off all their debts and still being mid income, they are happy. Why? Because money.

---

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27138403529.0" user="Russian_Surrender" delta="False">
    <text>The details of your post are basically correct, but your conclusion is wrong.  *Lack of money* is highly likely to lead to sadness (or, more accurately, *stress* that leads to other things that lead to sadness).  But money only solves specific problems.  You can still have other problems that lead to sadness even with substantial sums of money.

If money bought happiness, why would so many rich celebrities turn to suicide or a drug culture in search of happiness?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138409577.0" user="woflcopter" delta="False">
    <text>But here's the thing: a lot of things now can be solved via money. Millions of citizens in the US are stressed over debt and mortgage which could be fixed by money. Hell, even though I'm not of legal moving age I have things that could solve some of my (lame) problems with money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138410851.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>Couldn't you simply have a system where debt isn't incurred?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138416002.0" user="woflcopter" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138419000.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>What's causing the unhappiness is being in debt. If you could, for instance, have higher education subsidized by the state, then there would be no source of unhappiness in that sense.

On top of this, being relieved from debt doesn't automatically make people happy, it just relieves stress. You could probably weasel it into some form of "happiness", but I don't think that is necessarily the case in the long term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138564808.0" user="niggapleaseweighthat" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that would be amazing. Unfortunately we live in the real world and there is no way to build a system where debt isn't incurred. That would be a sort of Utopian wonderland, and I believe it is impossible.

I do agree that being debt-free does not make people happy, it just removes a source of potential stress. There are still millions of other factors that money could not possibly solve. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138845506.0" user="ArchbishopJeff" delta="False">
    <text>I live in the UK and I pretty much won't have to pay back my student loan, which is pretty great, but I'm still stressed. Stressed about performing well. I think an equally big problem is that there is not enough free counseling and therapy, and we generally have a terrible understanding of psychology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139023538.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>I"m not sure we'll ever get rid of all the stressors in life. Humans are so nuanced by experience that what stresses you probably doesn't stress me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139097402.0" user="TheNicestMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What's causing the unhappiness is being in debt. 

Not exclusively. Lack of access to fresh food, decent shelter, healthcare, entertainment all contribute to unhappiness. The studies on money and happiness show a positive correlation between increased income and increased happiness up to around 70k or 80k per year. Since ~75% of households make less than that  it's safe to say that money *would* buy happiness for the vast majority of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139188969.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>I was referring mainly to their example provided.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140465808.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What's causing the unhappiness is being in debt.

What's causing unhappiness is _worry_. Be that  debt or just not having enough savings to live on forever without having to find a job and thus worrying about the job market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138420282.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>Solving problems with money causes temporary relief, its not a lasting happiness.  I haven't thought about how I paid off my student loan for years, let alone does it make me happy.  I did spend time (but very little money) with some loved ones a few weeks ago and that made me happy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138426272.0" user="woflcopter" delta="False">
    <text>It's not like I'm saying how money doesn't mean happiness: there are a lot of things (like what you mentioned) that can make people happy that don't require money. But saying that money does not equal happiness is false in a lot of cases people face.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138439487.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But saying that money does not equal happiness is false in a lot of cases people face.

Ok, so I give you $X.  You are happy because you pay off your student loan, car insurance, etc.  Now what? What kicks in is Hedoinic adaptation.  http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill

&amp;gt; The hedonic treadmill, also known as hedonic adaptation, is the supposed tendency of humans to quickly return to a relatively stable level of happiness despite major positive or negative events or life changes.[1] According to this theory, as a person makes more money, expectations and desires rise in tandem, which results in no permanent gain in happiness.

When you were a child, you were really excited about a piece of candy.  Now if I give you the same candy, as an adult you don't get that excited.

At most I will give you temporary relief from problems, but this isn't a lasting happiness.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138471702.0" user="woflcopter" delta="False">
    <text>But it is happiness. My dad paid off his students loans and he was incredibly happy for a while. Once you get through a hurdle the happiness is obviously there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138477204.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>Its a short term relief from pain, not happiness.  Years from now you aren't going to still feel good about paying a loan, if you even remember you had a loan at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138566031.0" user="niggapleaseweighthat" delta="False">
    <text>It may not create happiness to pay off your loans, but it certainly must reduce some stress? I know I will be less stressed once I pay these damn loans off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138912742.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>When you were younger, you had a difficult class that was causing you stress (I don't understand the material.  I am spending too much time studying and doing homework for this class.  Will I pass?)  (Or take anything stressful in the past that you have gotten rid of)

Today, would you consider yourself "happy" because you don't have this stress anymore?  Have you even thought about that class since you left it?  If you were to list all the reasons why you are happy, would they include "don't have to take that class"?  Would it include every single stressful thing that used to be in your life?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139195924.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Paying off a debt removes a stressor, but that doesn't mean that you always are free of that level of stress thereafter. New stressors will turn up which will make you stressed again, and those may or may not be the kind that can be relieved by an influx of money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138430333.0" user="xjayroox" delta="False">
    <text>Money may not be able to buy happiness but it sure can buy me all the things that make me happy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138775531.0" user="rhb4n8" delta="False">
    <text>My only question is what problem can't money fix? Lonely? Get a sugar baby. Sick? Best doctors in the world(see magic Johnson.) Fat? Personal chef, personal trainer, or bariatric surgery. You don't look like Barbie? Apparently money can change that now too. Can honestly say I've never had a problem that couldn't easily be solved if I was wealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139205187.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>A sugar baby isn't likely to cure loneliness. It may provide companionship and sex, but the purchaser is likely aware that their companion is with them for the money, and not out of genuine affection. In terms of health, money can help a great deal, but you'll still hit a wall where your ailment is not curable.

Money can make many things a lot more comfortable, and certainly relieves certain kinds of needs and stresses, but it won't meet some of the fundamental needs that lead to happiness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139918260.0" user="rhb4n8" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps I'm a small terrible person but I self actualize on every social level other than sexually so really that would suit me perfectly. I already feel overly compelled to buy women things so it wouldn't really be much different.hell it might actually  be a lot more honest than my present relationships</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139993687.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps. People have all kinds of personalities and needs. It might work for you. I think that for many--perhaps the majority--would find it rather unfulfilling. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
