<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="126209817.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/235449/cmv_money_does_buy_happiness/">
    <title>CMV: Money does buy happiness.</title>
    <original_poster>woflcopter</original_poster>
    <original_post>The term "money can't buy happiness" is, I think, false, mainly now within the past years. 

Let's give a scenario: you graduated college, got a decent $50k a year job and you live with your SO who makes around the same. Uh oh, student loans from college start to haunt you now, as well as car insurance, debt, mortgage, and maybe a dozen other things piling on top of that. Really the only way that you could "fix" this is by paying for it with money. 

And let's say that they somehow get a lot of money. And let's say they live in a world where there isn't really a tax or anything (think simple). They pay off all their debts and ironically all their money from that was the exact amount to pay everything off. They live much happier than before. 

And now you see how money buys happiness. It's true. Money does buy happiness. There are so many situations where money will solve your problems. I'm not trying to say how it's the only cause of happiness: there are things that can make people happy without the use of money, but generally if you have money it'll make you happier. I know that many people with tons of money are also depressed, but when you get a middle aged mid income family paying off all their debts and still being mid income, they are happy. Why? Because money.

---

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27138528107.0" user="PulaskiAtNight" delta="False">
    <text>Haven't heard of [Hedonic Adaptation](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill)? Do you really think you wouldn't get used to having money? Imagine you really, *really* wanted a car. After finally getting the car, you are enraptured with happiness. Then, the happiness fades, and the car is only another part of your life. Sure, you're grateful for it, but when you're sitting in your room alone feeling like miserable shit, your car isn't going to make you feel better. If you can buy whatever you want all the time, the transient happiness gained from purchasing new things will begin to fade until it reaches the point that you need something else to make you happy.

The fact that the wealthy suffer from depression just as the poor do should be enough evidence for this. Every other person out there is constantly participating in the pursuit of happiness. There is no such thing as truly attaining happiness; it's just a chase. If you think you've solved all of your problems, just wait a little bit and many more will bloom to keep you occupied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140466988.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Aaargh. Another Redditor who confuses more earning with more spending instead of more saving.

Imagine you really would not give a fuck about a good car. But you are worried that your job may be automated or outsourced. Worry = unhappiness. But you have enough in the bank to live on for 3 years.  Worry dissolved.

Do you think people play the lottery because they want luxury shit? I play the lottery because I never want to worry anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140651601.0" user="PulaskiAtNight" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Worry dissolved.

You have done nothing to evade my argument whatsoever. The point is that, once the worry is gone, it will instantly be supplanted with a worry about something else. Do you think that every person out there who doesn't have to worry about money to live for the next three years is happy?

What you outlined is nothing more than creating a problem where money is the solution and temporary happiness can be had from it. Is that all you are arguing? If I want ice cream really badly, and I'm pleased when I get some, then does that mean that ice cream can earn me happiness? No, happiness only came from solving a problem.

Money can be the solution to your problem(s). Once that is taken care of, though, you will simply have different problems. This is the pursuit of happiness that I was talking about, and it has rang true for all of humanity. Nobody (maybe Buddhist monks?) has *attained* happiness. You can feel free to strive for money if you want your problems to be based around money, but you are just as free to change your lifestyle so that it is less reliant on money.

Also

&amp;gt;Aaargh. **Another Redditor** who confuses more earning with more spending instead of more saving.

Is called ad hominem. It contributes nothing to an argument other than making you seem slightly close minded.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
