<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="126209817.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/235449/cmv_money_does_buy_happiness/">
    <title>CMV: Money does buy happiness.</title>
    <original_poster>woflcopter</original_poster>
    <original_post>The term "money can't buy happiness" is, I think, false, mainly now within the past years. 

Let's give a scenario: you graduated college, got a decent $50k a year job and you live with your SO who makes around the same. Uh oh, student loans from college start to haunt you now, as well as car insurance, debt, mortgage, and maybe a dozen other things piling on top of that. Really the only way that you could "fix" this is by paying for it with money. 

And let's say that they somehow get a lot of money. And let's say they live in a world where there isn't really a tax or anything (think simple). They pay off all their debts and ironically all their money from that was the exact amount to pay everything off. They live much happier than before. 

And now you see how money buys happiness. It's true. Money does buy happiness. There are so many situations where money will solve your problems. I'm not trying to say how it's the only cause of happiness: there are things that can make people happy without the use of money, but generally if you have money it'll make you happier. I know that many people with tons of money are also depressed, but when you get a middle aged mid income family paying off all their debts and still being mid income, they are happy. Why? Because money.

---

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27138427719.0" user="Shorvok" delta="False">
    <text>Money buys comfort. Comfort doesn't always mean happiness though. 

90% of the time though, if you make a lot of money, you're doing something to warrant it. You're stressed and work long hours.

Money can never make you happy alone, you can still be rich and miserable. Most doctors are a prime example [as pointed out by this article posted today](http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2014/04/14/how-being-a-doctor-became-the-most-miserable-profession.html). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138436475.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>I recall reading somewhere that dentists are one of the professions most likely to commit suicide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138513454.0" user="Rocktopod" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah and I don't know if it was from the same thing but a similar list said shepherd was the happiest profession.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138619473.0" user="ZippityZoppity" delta="False">
    <text>It sure sounds like it would be a happy profession. Very little worries except for those damn wolves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138631360.0" user="Rocktopod" delta="False">
    <text>Fence technology has come a long way.  The wolves don't stand a chance.

Also they all got shot like 100 years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138773351.0" user="totes_meta_bot" delta="False">
    <text>This thread has been linked to from elsewhere on reddit.


 - [/r/nocontext] [Fence technology has come a long way. The wolves don&amp;amp;#x27;t stand a chance.](http://np.reddit.com/r/nocontext/comments/235vbs/fence_technology_has_come_a_long_way_the_wolves/)


*^I ^am ^a ^bot. ^Comments? ^Complaints? [^Send ^them ^to ^my ^inbox!](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=totes_meta_bot)*

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
