<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="126209817.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/235449/cmv_money_does_buy_happiness/">
    <title>CMV: Money does buy happiness.</title>
    <original_poster>woflcopter</original_poster>
    <original_post>The term "money can't buy happiness" is, I think, false, mainly now within the past years. 

Let's give a scenario: you graduated college, got a decent $50k a year job and you live with your SO who makes around the same. Uh oh, student loans from college start to haunt you now, as well as car insurance, debt, mortgage, and maybe a dozen other things piling on top of that. Really the only way that you could "fix" this is by paying for it with money. 

And let's say that they somehow get a lot of money. And let's say they live in a world where there isn't really a tax or anything (think simple). They pay off all their debts and ironically all their money from that was the exact amount to pay everything off. They live much happier than before. 

And now you see how money buys happiness. It's true. Money does buy happiness. There are so many situations where money will solve your problems. I'm not trying to say how it's the only cause of happiness: there are things that can make people happy without the use of money, but generally if you have money it'll make you happier. I know that many people with tons of money are also depressed, but when you get a middle aged mid income family paying off all their debts and still being mid income, they are happy. Why? Because money.

---

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27138425176.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>There is a substantial amount of [empirical evidence](http://weber.ucsd.edu/~aronatas/Kahneman%20et%20al%20Would%20You%20Be%20Happier%20Science-2006.pdf) that beyond a certain point, above-average income makes one unhappier. While the problems that many people have are indeed solvable with money, having money simply means that you have a different set of problems.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138489835.0" user="tutudragon3" delta="False">
    <text>Its a problem I would love to have though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138497878.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking personally, the times when I was poorest are among the happiest memories of my life. I may be speaking through a roseate haze, of course, but money doesn't make as much of a difference as people seem to think it does. You habituate to the status quo. The first time you fly in business class is wonderful; thereafter, it's normal. And then you upgrade to first. And then you fly private. But you get used to it - and at the end of the day, you're still flying in a plane. You're still living in a house, even if it's bigger. Nothing really changes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138518978.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>It's easy to say that once you're there however. I've been dirt poor and I've done pretty well for myself. I could say I was "happier" then, but I was also much younger. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138550309.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>I was born and grew up with money, was poor upon adulthood, and became affluent again without having aged too much. But my views are of course anecdotal and by no means representative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138558208.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>Mine too of course. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138541275.0" user="tutudragon3" delta="False">
    <text>I am not sure how it applies to you but I believe that people always think they were happier in the past than they are now. The grass is greener on the other side effect. As a student, I always  believe that past exams (from previous years) in my courses were way easier than the one I just wrote. My parents keep saying that back home in India, life was so much better but when we actually go there to visit, they keep complaining about everything all the damn time. 

Given the option, let me use a quote from someone on reddit from a similar topic such as this. "Money may not buy happiness, but I would rather by crying in my ferrari than on the street"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139140075.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; flying in a plane

Do cramped legs and a growling stomach make you happy?  An aching bladder from not wanting to squeeze past two other people to use the restroom?  Money gets rid of those.

&amp;gt; You're still living in a house

Do roaches make you happy?  How about the absence of sunlight?  Does being warm in the winter make you happy?  Does having your house broken into or your car stolen make you happy?  Does having to climb over boxes because you have no storage space make you happy?  Does sleeping on a crowded bed make you happy?  How about lead-based paint?  Does tripping on a cracked floor make you happy?  Turning your ankle on a broken stair?  Money gets rid of all of those.

&amp;gt; Nothing really changes.

People do get happier with more money.  They may not be taught how to appreciate it, but money purchases a wealth of relief from persistent, day-to-day problems.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139476614.0" user="itsreallyfuckingcold" delta="False">
    <text>again, once your basic needs are met, moneys marginal value diminishes rapidly. you live in a shitty house, make money and move to a bigger house, but all the houses in your new rich neighborhood are nicer too. bonfire of tje vanities</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139526513.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>Diminishes?  Sure.  But it's being claimed that it goes to *zero*, which I do not at all agree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139750977.0" user="itsreallyfuckingcold" delta="False">
    <text>so to you, more is better then? does mark zuckerberg care if he has 1 more dollar? doe you collect every penny in the street? 
but thats a bit of a dumb argument. a better one is that people like relative wealth more than absolute wealth. this means that people would prefer to live in a house 2000 square meters in a neighborhood of 1500 ms^2 houses more than a 2500 m house thats in a 3000m house neibhorhood. 
so its clear that more is better does not hold, but more than you is better. so unless youre going for wealthiest person in the world, its better to be big fish in a small pond than a huge fish in the pacific ocean</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139814031.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>If that were the case, why do rich people not build large houses in slums?  The answer is that this is nonsense, and that absolute wealth produces positive utility.  That relative wealth also produces utility is not in dispute, but it is clearly not the only factor.  Since absolute wealth also produces utility, money is *in and of itself* a source of utility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140135260.0" user="aardvarkyardwork" delta="False">
    <text>So here's me situation: my wife and I work full time and have a new baby. We also have a mortgage that's pretty substantial, but the house is great. By general definition, we make enough to meet the basics, in that we make our repayments, have food on the table, drive and maintain our car etc. but that's about all. We have to budget every 50 cents. The stress of barely making ends meet makes us both irritable and we fight a lot. The general feeling of not getting enough back for the amount of struggle we put in is depressing. We don't enjoy our lives because most of it is spent making money and thinking about money and trying to save money. It's not because we're obsessed with inflating our bank accounts. It's because it's taken over our lives. Yes, money would make us happy. Not because we can buy lots of stuff, but because we wouldn't have to stress so much and could actually enjoy our lives. We could have a happier relationship. Money may not buy happiness directly but it clears away all the distractions that are standing in the way of happiness. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140464966.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Basic needs met for a month? Year? How much savings you feel safe with in months or years? Aren't you worried that if you don't have a lot of savigns you could lose it? Are you an optimist - it can only get better?

**Why do you think earning more is spending more instead of more savings and safety?**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140464448.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;fly business class.
&amp;gt;bigger house

Suspicion confirmed. That is precisely scaling up spending to earnings.

You should have wrote "the first time when you know can go 2 years without an income" and "when that first small house is fully paid and nobody can take it from you anymore".

**You are writing from the sole viewpoint of the total optimist who never saves because he thinks he will always earn a lot and it is not just temporary luck.**

**You have no idea how much a pessimistic person who is always fearing disaster made happier by savings.**

And the researchers neither.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140481162.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>So I never save, because I think I will always earn a lot and it is not just temporary luck?

Pray tell, stranger, how do you know so much about me?

...this'll be good. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140500075.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If not, why did you bring spending examples?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140510881.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>Because the most salient changes in the life of the newly rich are typically material. I spend a fraction of my net worth annually on my personal expenditures. Even if I lost everything but my cash reserves, I still wouldn't need to work. The financial security has not made me in the least bit happier, either. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27138625778.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The grass is greenest where you water it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139042814.0" user="IllinoisLawyer04" delta="False">
    <text>Does this study account for people who spent their life happy but then realized they were screwed at age 65 because they couldn't afford to retire?  I would be curious to see the same study done on a sample of people around retirement age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27139100471.0" user="TheNicestMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>Those studies show a positive correlation between money and happiness up to about $75k. Over 70% of households in the US make less than that so for the vast majority of people money would buy happiness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140461861.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This evidence does not worth anything, because they did not divide people into groups how they _use_ the money. From your explanation it sounds like they are a bunch of optimists (perhaps Americans, the US is an optimistic culture) who just _spend more_ and _own more_ when they earn more and then have more problems.

So the whole concept of _saving more_ and being happy because you never fucking need to work again at 45 was not investigated.

Studies like that should not be called studies and the authors should be ashamed: confounding factors were not eliminated, thus the causal relationship was not established. The confounding factor is how exactly people use money: spend or save. More stuff or more freedom because not having to work.

We know stress and worry and fear is a huge unhappiness factor. Having money in the bank to live on for 3 years is a huge de-stressing factor. But for that people need not only earn well, but also save well, that is a huge confounding factor that was entirely left out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140481611.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>The Nobel laureate Danny Kahneman, publishing in Science, should be ashamed of himself?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140499915.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Everybody can make mistakes. Assuming earning is spending is a big one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27140511260.0" user="Advokatus" delta="False">
    <text>Except Kahneman didn't do that. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
