<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127371705.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/23u0mx/cmv_the_war_in_afghanistan_was_moral_and_necessary/">
    <title>CMV: The war in Afghanistan was moral and necessary.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>Keyword: was. 
Let me start by saying I think most Americans' POV change with the wind. In 2008, All the democratic presidential candidates ran on the platform of "end the war in iraq, finish the war in afghanistan." Everyone was on board. No everyone wants to end it immediately and a lot of people think it was a bad idea to begin with. I saw a post on here listing the war in Afghanistan was a negative reaction to 9/11. What were we supposed to do, just let al queida flourish in the region?




I don't think hardly anyone was against the war in Afghanistan when it started. The people that attacked us were in Afghanistan and the government there at that time was not capable of doing anything about it. That was not made up. They attack us first, we attack them back. That's defense, not offense. 


The reason the war was a mess was because it was led by George Bush. We stomped Al Queida, but upon invading iraq, they flourished again. Now fast forward 13 years... the war at this point is accomplishing nothing. Bush and Cheney should get the death penalty but that's a whole nother CMV post.

But anyways, if we had not invaded Iraq, we may have completely obliterated al Quieda at least in the region.  That was a worthy mission and if we had stuck to it, it would have worked. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27151013558.0" user="derponia" delta="False">
    <text>Amen.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
