<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127371705.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/23u0mx/cmv_the_war_in_afghanistan_was_moral_and_necessary/">
    <title>CMV: The war in Afghanistan was moral and necessary.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>Keyword: was. 
Let me start by saying I think most Americans' POV change with the wind. In 2008, All the democratic presidential candidates ran on the platform of "end the war in iraq, finish the war in afghanistan." Everyone was on board. No everyone wants to end it immediately and a lot of people think it was a bad idea to begin with. I saw a post on here listing the war in Afghanistan was a negative reaction to 9/11. What were we supposed to do, just let al queida flourish in the region?




I don't think hardly anyone was against the war in Afghanistan when it started. The people that attacked us were in Afghanistan and the government there at that time was not capable of doing anything about it. That was not made up. They attack us first, we attack them back. That's defense, not offense. 


The reason the war was a mess was because it was led by George Bush. We stomped Al Queida, but upon invading iraq, they flourished again. Now fast forward 13 years... the war at this point is accomplishing nothing. Bush and Cheney should get the death penalty but that's a whole nother CMV post.

But anyways, if we had not invaded Iraq, we may have completely obliterated al Quieda at least in the region.  That was a worthy mission and if we had stuck to it, it would have worked. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27150344070.0" user="zzing" delta="False">
    <text>If a man were to attack you, and you blocked a knife strike against you — that is defence. If the attacker started to run away, and you went after them and beat them up, that is offence. To nail this point straight on — stopping or attempting to stop the attacks is the defence, the offence is taking the fight to them. 

Consider the very word you use:
&amp;gt; we *attack* them back.

From the OED: (attack, v.)
&amp;gt;  To fasten or fall upon with force or arms; to join battle with, assail, assault. (The ordinary word to describe offensive military operations.)

It is used to describe offensive military operations. 

I believe the other commenter /u/blackflag415 did add a point about similarity to Vietnam. I agree with that perspective, and it was predicted before.

I don't believe the war was moral — very few wars I can think of were moral — the exception to this thought might be World War 2. The reason why I say the war wasn't moral, is because of the collatoral damage that we knew would occur in any modern war: the non-combatants in the country. 

In the [wikipedia article](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civilian_casualties_in_the_War_in_Afghanistan_\(2001%E2%80%93present\)) on the subject, it says 18k to 20k died since 2001. Was that worth the war to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150409724.0" user="atrde" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair you say stopping attacks is defense. Is taking away their capability to attack us not defense? The Taliban let a terrorist group reside in their country openly and plan to kill Americans. In your analogy you say its wrong to attack when they run. You forget that the person with the knife wants to attack you again but will run after. Should you not go and take the knife?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150435418.0" user="zzing" delta="False">
    <text>Taking away their capability to attack us is not defence, it is offence. To go back to the analogy for a moment, it would be like cutting off a guy's hands so he cannot hold a knife - and thus cannot attack you with a knife.

Your assertion that the person wants to attack you again is baseless. There are many situations where an attack is quite impromptu, and your successful defence has scared them off more than any desire they have for a repeat performance. I would assert that the majority of potential attacks are opportunistic. The ones that would fit your assertion would be targetted attacks.

Naturally there is a grey area here, and I suspect that is where we are talking now. 

On the note about the Taliban: They were not a recognized government by many countries, and they did not even control the entire country. Either way it does not suspend the part about the civilians caught in the middle. There are other ways outside of war to deal with issues with this - surgical strikes, economic sanctions, etc.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150773990.0" user="atrde" delta="False">
    <text>Al quaeda's main goal was to attack us. There is no doubt they would again. As for surgical strikes we are doing that now with drones and no one seems to approve of that. Sanctions also hurt the citizens of a country as much as the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150699637.0" user="billingsley" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  it says 18k to 20k died since 2001. Was that worth the war to you?


no. but like i said, that's because the war was mismanaged by an incompetent president.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150817891.0" user="zzing" delta="False">
    <text>All wars have casualties, this number is actually lower than many.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
