<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127371705.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/23u0mx/cmv_the_war_in_afghanistan_was_moral_and_necessary/">
    <title>CMV: The war in Afghanistan was moral and necessary.</title>
    <original_poster>billingsley</original_poster>
    <original_post>Keyword: was. 
Let me start by saying I think most Americans' POV change with the wind. In 2008, All the democratic presidential candidates ran on the platform of "end the war in iraq, finish the war in afghanistan." Everyone was on board. No everyone wants to end it immediately and a lot of people think it was a bad idea to begin with. I saw a post on here listing the war in Afghanistan was a negative reaction to 9/11. What were we supposed to do, just let al queida flourish in the region?




I don't think hardly anyone was against the war in Afghanistan when it started. The people that attacked us were in Afghanistan and the government there at that time was not capable of doing anything about it. That was not made up. They attack us first, we attack them back. That's defense, not offense. 


The reason the war was a mess was because it was led by George Bush. We stomped Al Queida, but upon invading iraq, they flourished again. Now fast forward 13 years... the war at this point is accomplishing nothing. Bush and Cheney should get the death penalty but that's a whole nother CMV post.

But anyways, if we had not invaded Iraq, we may have completely obliterated al Quieda at least in the region.  That was a worthy mission and if we had stuck to it, it would have worked. 
CMV?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27150327462.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>I (and many other Americans) was against the war in Iraq an Afghanistan from the beginning, so all that apologist "how could we have know it would turn out so bad?" talk gets nowhere with me.  

1)obl was in Pakistan not Afghanistan.

2) no matter where he was it only took a precise strike team to get him, not invading a whole country. 

3) why were we in Afghanistan if not to get obl?

4) anyone with he slightest idea of history would have know that people don't react well to their country being invaded. We had the examples of Vietnam and the soviet invasion of Afghanistan right in front of us.  It didn't take a genius to predict it would devolve into an unwinable guerrilla war exactly as it did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150477807.0" user="ZombieCheney" delta="False">
    <text>1. Osama bin Laden had a close relationship with Mohammed Omar, the spiritual leader of the Taliban, and Afghanistan's *de facto* head-of-state from 1996-2001. Under the Taliban's protection, he set up a network of training camps within Afghanistan. He was present in Afghanistan during the Battle of Tora Bora in December, 2001, and it is only later that he fled Afghanistan for Pakistan. http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-14190032

1. The response to 9/11 was about more than capturing a single man. It was about dealing a decisive blow against any and all *"nations, organizations, or persons"* who *"planned, authorized, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks"* of September 11, 2001.
 http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/PLAW-107publ40/html/PLAW-107publ40.htm

1. We were in Afghanistan to get Osama bin Laden, as well as dismantle al Qaeda's operational support network within the country, and to hold the Taliban responsible for harboring and supporting Osama bin Laden and al Qaeda.

1. I agree, mission creep began to set in, and I believe that the large scale occupation of the country should probably have ceased after we initially dealt with al Qaeda's presence within Afghanistan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150804028.0" user="dukeofdummies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The response to 9/11 was about more than capturing a single man. It was about dealing a decisive blow against any and all "nations, organizations, or persons" who "planned, authorized, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks" of September 11, 2001.

That makes the invasion even worse. [Most Afghans weren't even aware of 9/11 ](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2035160/Most-Afghans-know-9-11-according-disturbing-poll.html)

Most of the country had no reason to fight, nor did they care. Invading causes civilian casualties which causes more people to take up arms in the country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150881946.0" user="ZombieCheney" delta="False">
    <text>I hope you didn't interpret that as meaning the United States decided to engage in collective punishment against the entirety of the Afghan people, because that is not what that means.

It meant that the Taliban, as *de facto* government of the Afghanistan, was considered complicit in the attack by aiding and harboring al Qaeda and Osama bin Laden.

Whenever any country goes to war, the vast majority of the citizens of any of the country involved have absolutely no connection to the reasons for which the war is being fought. And yes, most of any given country is made up of civilians who don't have reasons to fight. 

Any conflict is going to lead to civilian casualties, whether or not it was moral or necessary to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150495959.0" user="Dhanvantari" delta="False">
    <text>regarding 4)

The Taliban were to some extent also seen as foreign invaders, being trained and organised from pakistan. The USA invasion was to some extent preferred because, while the USA was foreign, they were distant while Pakistan borders Afghanistan.

The Soviet Invasion of Afghanistan was to prop up a hated regime, the US invasion of Afghanistan was to remove a hated regime. Vietnam and Afghanistan are extremely different countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150509176.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>The Hamid Karzai regime is also extremely hated.  Sorry im on my phone and can't really search for a source, but much of he country views the as corrupt at best, and completely illegitimate at worst.  If you search some news articles (sorry I know it's a weak response but I'm on my phone) you'll see it's true.  I honestly don't see how what we're doing is any different if we are also upholding a hated regime.

Edit: with regards to Vietnam and Afghanistan being different, I'm referring broadly to the fact that the  us army is unable to fight gurrellia wars nor win hearts and minds.  Especially when we go into a country with no understanding of their culture and the arrogance that "we will be greeted as liberators."  This was a lesson we learned from Vietnam.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27150696759.0" user="billingsley" delta="False">
    <text>OBL was in Afghanistan at the time. They actually had him in sights but lost him because of mis communication. Took another decade to find him again. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
