<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1277501269.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l4laad/cmv_redditors_dont_know_shit_about_money/">
    <title>CMV: Redditors don't know shit about money</title>
    <original_poster>Yaqoob_</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have asked on multiple sub-reddits about the way money works. Its inception, supply, centralisation among other constituents. Most of the redditors answer in jargon language which doesn't serve any use. Divulging a bit, I have also hear that reddit doesn't turn a profit because the audience of reddit are merely keyboard warriors who don't have money to go out there and spend for advertisers to generate cashflow.

Also, kindly do suggest how I can understand things related to money (in simple language)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36081195296.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Most of the redditors answer in jargon language which doesn't serve any use.

Jargon is used in any complicated field. It's use is that it enables you to discuss complex topics without having to explain every other word. It's not good when explaining something to a layman, but imagine you're listening in on two specialist doctors diagnosing a patient. Why would you expect to understand them? They're experts in their field, you're not even in their field. Sure they could explain any of the terms they use, but they don't have to because they know their peers understand it, so it's much more efficient this way.

I mention this because it goes against the topic of your CMV - People who know shit about money are not going to talk about it like a layman.




Another big counter example would be whats going on in /r/wallstreetbets with Gamestop. It's  hard to explain without also explaining a lot of the stock market which is outside the scope of this CMV, but in short a bunch of people in a subreddit identified that Gamestop was clearly failing, and more importantly that a bunch of high profile investors were banking on it failing.  WSB users all invested hard. Not because they believed in the company, not in response to anything the company was doing, but just because they identified the potential of this situation.  The stock soared so high the stock exchange had to shut down. Those traditional investors are out billions.

If redditors didn't know shit about money, how could that have happened?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36081387528.0" user="thetasigma4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If redditors didn't know shit about money, how could that have happened?

Investing in stock has very little to do with money and monetary policy and how it works. 

That you can drive up the price of a stock by purchasing it is also not exactly an obscure piece of financial knowledge and is just a pump and dump to a company that was being shorted. This doesn't require any specialist knowledge and especially none wrt money and monetary policy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
