<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1277501269.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l4laad/cmv_redditors_dont_know_shit_about_money/">
    <title>CMV: Redditors don't know shit about money</title>
    <original_poster>Yaqoob_</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have asked on multiple sub-reddits about the way money works. Its inception, supply, centralisation among other constituents. Most of the redditors answer in jargon language which doesn't serve any use. Divulging a bit, I have also hear that reddit doesn't turn a profit because the audience of reddit are merely keyboard warriors who don't have money to go out there and spend for advertisers to generate cashflow.

Also, kindly do suggest how I can understand things related to money (in simple language)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36079880005.0" user="saywherefore" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly lots of redditors are very bad at explaining concepts of money, but that does not mean that they don't understand the concepts they are failing to explain.

Further, you are likely to get many responses to such a question, and you only need one redditor to both know what they are talking about and be good at explaining. Undeniably it is challenging to distinguish the good from the bad, but that again is not a result of redditors failing to "know shit" about money.

Can you give an example of a single concept that you would like to understand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079897576.0" user="Yaqoob_" delta="False">
    <text>There ain't no single concept I'd like to understand. It is like a spiral where one thing leads to another, turtles all the way down.

It is well enough known that the central banks are owned by member banks which are privately owned. Now considering that fact, why does an average person work for money, while his banker friend doesn't. 

Banks print money as much as they want to. Which leads to the purchasing power of ours to erode. Then why is it we work hard for money &amp;amp; also why is counterfeiting illegal (apart from the point that it leads to devaluation of real money, it is happening anyway)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079924090.0" user="saywherefore" delta="False">
    <text>Ah I know that experience.

Individual bankers do work to earn their salaries, just like any other employee. It is true that banks create money when they give out loans, but this is done in equilibrium as the money is then deleted when the loan is repaid. Further, the amount they can create (lend) is governed by regulatory limits, so the amount of devaluation is still being controlled by the regulator or central bank.

Counterfeiting would not be properly controlled, and would not be subject to deletion at the end of a fixed term. This is an important distinction.

But this is all an aside to my central argument: the fact that you cannot get good explanations of concepts around money is not evidence that people on reddit don't understand money. Do you see my argument?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079934385.0" user="Yaqoob_" delta="False">
    <text>So are the only methods one can earn money is through the following:

1. Ownership of capital
2. Providing goods &amp;amp; services</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079950422.0" user="saywherefore" delta="False">
    <text>3. Crime

But yes, those are the ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079953793.0" user="IeuanTemplar" delta="False">
    <text>The central bank doesn’t print as much as they want to, they are authorised by the government to replace damaged notes etc. and they are authorised to release extra currency when it’s needed. But the bank doesn’t just.... make it all up. 

Banks are mostly owned by trusts and dividends, you can buy shares of a bank. 

There’s then the whole thing of the difference between a high street bank, and the central bank. 

Then there’s the “devaluation of real money” which is almost always because of inflation. 

Counterfeiting is illegal because the currency is owned and operated by the government, you just printing your own money isn’t trading in money that the government owns and operates, it’s you just printing pieces of paper and calling it currency. It’s fake, and fraud. Especially when you then use the money, you are defrauding the person you are giving the money to. I wouldn’t be happy if someone paid me with fake money that I couldn’t spend. 

The whole “bankers don’t work hard, I do, and it’s wrong” is a completely new topic. It’s like landlords, they make money by owning something. They don’t “work” for the money, they just own a piece of paper that proves they own a building, then someone else pays them to live there. If I had enough money in stocks and shares that the profit from that means that I can quit my job and have my life paid for, I’d be in the same position as the landlords or bank owners. It’s part of the whole, once you have enough of something, it makes it’s own money. 

And bankers do work, usually the bankers that are your friends, are investment bankers. Who move other peoples’ money around and try to buy things that will make money and sell things before it loses money, and take a % of the profit. 

As far as I know, nobody is printing money and paying themselves with it just because they can. And if they are, it’s just as illegal as if you did it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
