<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1277501269.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l4laad/cmv_redditors_dont_know_shit_about_money/">
    <title>CMV: Redditors don't know shit about money</title>
    <original_poster>Yaqoob_</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have asked on multiple sub-reddits about the way money works. Its inception, supply, centralisation among other constituents. Most of the redditors answer in jargon language which doesn't serve any use. Divulging a bit, I have also hear that reddit doesn't turn a profit because the audience of reddit are merely keyboard warriors who don't have money to go out there and spend for advertisers to generate cashflow.

Also, kindly do suggest how I can understand things related to money (in simple language)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36079894584.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Thing is that money is actually complex topic with layers. Most topics are like this. When you ask expert about a topic they are familiar with they expect certain level of basic knowledge from you. They are not going to tell you that money is used as medium of exchange and you can buy things with it. This is what we tell our three years old. They assume you know this already. But then we go to more complex topics like how central banks and it's monetary policy works. These topics cannot be explained unless you have solid understanding of basic terms.

TL;DR: You are asking people to explain something complex without using complex terms. This can be done but experts expect you to know terms already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079902194.0" user="Yaqoob_" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. But those terms can be replaced with lucid language too. An expert doesn't necessarily has to use pretentious language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079915692.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>This is the thing. "Jargon" or "Pretentious language" is there not to confuse you or make experts feel superior. It's a short hand. i.e. we can say "reddit is trying to get more money from advertisers than it costs to run reddit services" or we can say "reddit is trying to make profit". That's almost three times shorter and gives the same information. But you have to know what "profit" is and if you ask experts about how to run your business they expect you know what "profit" is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079926929.0" user="Yaqoob_" delta="False">
    <text>Alright. I will refer the definitions. But atleast explain me the useful stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079983287.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>It's impossible to explain the "useful stuff" unless we first explain the terms. Experts assume you know your terms before hand and will use those terms or "jargon" when explaining things. If you want answers in simple English ask from ELI5.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079922888.0" user="IeuanTemplar" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not that the language is pretentious, it’s correct. 

The topic of money, is massive. And wrapped around that is the legal and correct definitions of everything. 

You can, 100%, google the words and find out what they mean, but you can’t explain it in any detail without the correct names for things. 

The other problem is that the experts THINK in complicated terms, because they’re experts. Asking them to translate it all for you is actually a hard thing for them to do. It’s easier for them to explain it as simply as they can, and then you take that information and learn it and analyse it and learn what it means. Which includes some more research. 

You want a massive topic that has been studied by people their entire lives, broken down into an internet post that you can read once and know about, what you’re asking for is a lot, and I don’t know it’s possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106159013.0" user="YardageSardage" delta="False">
    <text>Try to explain all of video gaming without using any of the following "jargon": 

RPG, FPS, 4Ex, EXP, platformer, roguelike, metroidvania, soulslike, lives, respawn, NPC, quest, bot, developer, mod, graphics, skins, achievements, Nintendo, console, anticheat, launcher, eshop, permadeath, save point, reload, 1up, inventory, button-mash, co-op, multiplayer, single-player, minigame, or easter egg.

To a non-gamer who knows nothing about video games, these are all "pretentious language" that they don't understand. But how could you hope to explain something as complicated and diverse as *all* of video gaming if they refuse to let you use any of these terms?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
