<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127745300.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2420wk/cmv_i_think_victims_can_be_blamed_but_the_reason/">
    <title>CMV: I think victims can be blamed, but the reason we believe they shouldn't be for rape and they can for theft is because we expect people to never rape regardless of the victim's behaviour, but consider stealing sometimes appropriate.</title>
    <original_poster>cmv_t</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now - I wouldn't tell a person who was raped that they were responsible for it. While I think they may be causally responsible for it - their culpability is a different question altogether. 

Many of the behaviours which increase the chances of rape are very enjoyable including but not limited to

1) Drinking

2) Having sex

3) Partying

4) Pushing social boundaries

These are social practices which people like to involve themselves in, even if they increase their chances of being raped. 

I think this is reasonable, and most people would like social sanction for involvement in these activities without a negative judgement of "asking for it", even if they did increase their chances of being raped. 

And this is entirely separate from the danger of being raped even without involving yourself in activities which increase your chance of being raped. 


On the other hand - people treat theft more casually. 

As a society - we have come to believe that the onus is on the person who owns a property to secure it, and we are also more cavalier towards theft. 

"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy. 

I've known people who have shoplifted once or twice. A pack of gum here, a cola there. 

Now imagine if there was a society where people left their doors unlocked and were generally not afraid of theft. 

This is viable in small communities, and I have seen it in poorer areas like slums where people have little and for people with so little - theft is a graver sin than it would seem for most. 


Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they *were* causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

The alternative would be developing strong attitudes toward theft (as one of the worse things you can do) - which is typically how these communities tend to work. 

Victim blaming with rape would mean adopting the former attitude rather than the latter, and comes at the cost of losing social sanction for certain events

Especially in the cases of partying, dressing "provocatively", and casual sex - these are behaviours which have - for a long time carried a negative value judgement, especially for women. 

So I do think that victims of rape can be causally responsible for their rape, but they shouldn't be blamed in spite of it. 

Edit: To be clear I am saying that how much a victim could have mitigated their risk is not relevant. We ought not to treat rape like theft. 


Edit 2: 


I've seen a lot of responses talking about how much can are responsible. I think this is an unproductive argument. 

If I insult someone's mother and they punch my face, am I responsible? I would say I definitely "had it coming" (circumstantially, of course).

People do account for other people's behaviours all the time. 

I don't think it is particularly important how much I caused something to happen in the cause of rape, while it pertinent in the case of punching someone in the face. 


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27154068977.0" user="MikeyDeez" delta="False">
    <text>Could you give me a way that a potential victim of rape or theft who you call "casually responsible", could cause the crime to happen in an way if the perpetrator didn't make the choice to?

**I'd argue that your term "casually responsible" is pretty much bullshit in a criminal application, because you're only casually responsible after the fact, and in order to be "casually responsible" you need to first have someone who was completely responsible.**  ***Then*** **you can pick and choose where something** ***might*** **have gone wrong if someone had acted differently.**

There's almost no line that can be drawn where someone's otherwise legal and moral behavior could have possibly maybe prevented a crime to themselves or others if they had done something different in hindsight.

Could a victim have drank less and worn a more conservative dress? Yes? "Casually responsible!!" Could a person walking down the hall have noticed a girl was too drunk to be consenting to that guy carrying her back to the room and intervened? Yes? "Casually responsible!" Could a seasoned bartender have possibly noticed that guy looked rapist-y and called the cops? Yes? "Casually responsible!"




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154084194.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>I don't buy the idea that you can only be held responsible if you can completely, totally responsible. 

If you want to draw a causal graph like this one

http://www.pitt.edu/~druzdzel/gifs/tireex.gif

One can often reasonably determine that removing some node would have an effect on the outcome, but whether this action should be expected of someone or not is a different question. 

I don't think every action which reduces risk is a reasonable expectation. 

This is exactly the idea of culpability and responsibility. I think it is reasonable to expect people to secure their belongings, but not reasonable to expect them to drink less or dress less provocatively. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154096584.0" user="MikeyDeez" delta="False">
    <text>Where is human choice accounted for in that graphic?

Correct me if I'm wrong, but we aren't talking about circumstances leading to a flat tire, we're talking about the choices made that lead to an occurrence of a crime?

Are you suggesting it's the thorn's/glass's choice to penetrate the tire?

And those bottom three nodes are results, not factors.  This graph is not applicable.

And again, **regardless of any other choices made, you cannot be in any way responsible for a crime that someone did not make the choice to commit.**

You're using "casual responsibility" to criticize in hindsight choice factors (of which there are an infinite amount of) that you deem may or may not have prevented a crime.  None of these would be factors if the crime wasn't committed in the first place. 

Where or how would you draw a line? If a bus driver hadn't cut the rapist a break when he was .10 short on fare for the ride to the crime scene...*casually responsible!*  Maybe if daddy had brought the rapist to that carnival 30 years ago when he was a kid...*casually responsible!*

It's all speculation, and all casual responsibility in your examples are contingent on *one* choice to commit the crime.  All the "casual responsibility" choices in the world can't be responsible for a crime someone doesn't choose to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154119605.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying we can't reasonably predict people's behaviours?

Then we may have a fundamental disagreement. 

We expect people to not hurt other people by their speech and actions. 

Do you not think you're responsible for someone's feelings being hurt if you disparage what they do in front of them?

If you insult their mother and they punch you in the face do you not think they were responsible. 

Questioning how responsible you were is  hard game to play and ultimately not helpful. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154191133.0" user="MikeyDeez" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, please.

You're offering scenarios where **retribution** is the primary drive for the offence!

Are you suggesting that my mere existence is inviting crime?!  There are actions someone can take and refrain from that make them an easier target, but those conditions don't make them responsible for being chosen as a target and assaulted.

A person living their life, without infringing on someone else or *doing* something *to* someone to incite action is not responsible for violent crimes against them.


Yes, I would agree with your last statement, as its the crux of my argument.  **Assigning blame ex post facto is ludicrous and too subjective.**  


Again; I ask where **you** draw the line in your crazy notion of "casual responsibility" for rape.

I gave you a few examples of how someone can look back in hindsight and determine where changing a circumstance here or there might have effected a different outcome.  

You're making a mistake when you think that this practice means you can reliably and consistently determine who is responsible for what.

You're basically going to end at the "rape is a gift from god" argument. Ultimately **he** is the only one who can control every circumstance; therefore **all of my actions are simply god's will**, he's ultimately casually responsible! Heck, "it's Obama's fault for not making free prostitution mandatory and legal; he's casually responsible for my circumstances where I have to resort to rape!"

A person, in hindsight, has an infinite amount of areas to lay casual responsibility.  **Ultimately**, the "responsibility" lies with the person who had a choice to commit the action in question; especially in cases like rape or theft.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
