<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127745300.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2420wk/cmv_i_think_victims_can_be_blamed_but_the_reason/">
    <title>CMV: I think victims can be blamed, but the reason we believe they shouldn't be for rape and they can for theft is because we expect people to never rape regardless of the victim's behaviour, but consider stealing sometimes appropriate.</title>
    <original_poster>cmv_t</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now - I wouldn't tell a person who was raped that they were responsible for it. While I think they may be causally responsible for it - their culpability is a different question altogether. 

Many of the behaviours which increase the chances of rape are very enjoyable including but not limited to

1) Drinking

2) Having sex

3) Partying

4) Pushing social boundaries

These are social practices which people like to involve themselves in, even if they increase their chances of being raped. 

I think this is reasonable, and most people would like social sanction for involvement in these activities without a negative judgement of "asking for it", even if they did increase their chances of being raped. 

And this is entirely separate from the danger of being raped even without involving yourself in activities which increase your chance of being raped. 


On the other hand - people treat theft more casually. 

As a society - we have come to believe that the onus is on the person who owns a property to secure it, and we are also more cavalier towards theft. 

"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy. 

I've known people who have shoplifted once or twice. A pack of gum here, a cola there. 

Now imagine if there was a society where people left their doors unlocked and were generally not afraid of theft. 

This is viable in small communities, and I have seen it in poorer areas like slums where people have little and for people with so little - theft is a graver sin than it would seem for most. 


Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they *were* causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

The alternative would be developing strong attitudes toward theft (as one of the worse things you can do) - which is typically how these communities tend to work. 

Victim blaming with rape would mean adopting the former attitude rather than the latter, and comes at the cost of losing social sanction for certain events

Especially in the cases of partying, dressing "provocatively", and casual sex - these are behaviours which have - for a long time carried a negative value judgement, especially for women. 

So I do think that victims of rape can be causally responsible for their rape, but they shouldn't be blamed in spite of it. 

Edit: To be clear I am saying that how much a victim could have mitigated their risk is not relevant. We ought not to treat rape like theft. 


Edit 2: 


I've seen a lot of responses talking about how much can are responsible. I think this is an unproductive argument. 

If I insult someone's mother and they punch my face, am I responsible? I would say I definitely "had it coming" (circumstantially, of course).

People do account for other people's behaviours all the time. 

I don't think it is particularly important how much I caused something to happen in the cause of rape, while it pertinent in the case of punching someone in the face. 


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27154036169.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy.

This is a juvenile phrase used by 7 year olds when they took someone's toy.  This is not applicable to any adult situation and has no basis in law

&amp;gt;Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they were causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

Is leaving your door open a crime?  Since it's not, why should it be tangibly punished?  Why should dressing a certain way give people a reason to attack you?  If rape victims can be responsible, name something where being raped makes sense as a consequence.  

Why should something that does not directly affect you give you a reason to commit a crime against someone?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154056269.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure if you're agreeing or disagreeing with me. 

But I'm neither condoning theft nor rape. 

What I am claiming is that we normalise attitudes towards theft because in general - it isn't too bad, and the things we do to avoid it don't significantly impact the way we live. 

Rape on the other hand is almost always life changing, and to "secure" yourself against it will require a significant change in quality of life. 

As a result we have adopted a value system which places the onus on preventing theft on the victim, but not in the case of rape. 

&amp;gt;Is leaving your door open a crime? Since it's not, why should it be tangibly punished? Why should dressing a certain way give people a reason to attack you? If rape victims can be responsible, name something where being raped makes sense as a consequence.

A dorm is a very good example. 

In general - until there is a theft - people are usually pretty cavalier about leaving their doors open if they're around. 

This has benefits because it makes for a closer knit community, but this might not exist all the time and there might not be a significant cost to securing valuables. 

I also disagree with your assessment that its something only a 7 year old would say. 

What would you do if you saw a 20 on the street?

&amp;gt;Why should dressing a certain way give people a reason to attack you? If rape victims can be responsible, name something where being raped makes sense as a consequence.

If someone isn't careful with their drink, they might be roofied. 

Alcohol increases the chance of being raped, and imbibing it may increase chances of someone being taken advantage of because of impairment. 

So the person who is impaired is causally responsible, but constant vigilance is a tremendous impact on quality of life and I don't think its worth it, and so I don't buy into the idea that safeguarding against rape is worthwhile. 

Its a similar situation to the overblown idea of stranger danger. 

Talking to strangers is amazing, and you can limit your chances of being involved with stranger danger if you don't interact with anyone. But what a terrible life that would be. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154065494.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're not understanding my point.  Why does not taking those precautions make them responsible for something illegal done against them?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154133645.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Lets not discuss legality here. I don't think I'm sufficiently qualified and rape is a legal morass encumbered by he said she said they said.

But do you think if you call Susan a bitch, and she slaps you you weren't causally responsible?

Now if she murders you on the other hand - you were still causally responsible, but I don't think you should be blamed for the latter, but you should be blamed for the former. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154140522.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Lets not discuss legality here. I don't think I'm sufficiently qualified and rape is a legal morass encumbered by he said she said they said.

If you don't want to discuss legality, then I don't want to debate with you.  The whole reason the concept of victim blaming exists is because they are victims of something illegal.  Whether the action is illegal is completely relevant and we're all working under the assumption that a crime was committed.

&amp;gt;But do you think if you call Susan a bitch, and she slaps you you weren't causally responsible?

No, you weren't casually responsible because you did not endanger her in any way that would warrant a physical response.  You shouldn't do it, but you aren't responsible.

&amp;gt;Now if she murders you on the other hand - you were still causally responsible, but I don't think you should be blamed for the latter, but you should be blamed for the former.

Why are you making this distinction?  In both, according to you, you are the cause of the anger and it's not in your control how she responds, so </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154151649.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Do you honestly believe that the only reason victim blaming is an issue is because of legality?

&amp;gt;Why are you making this distinction? In both, according to you, you are the cause of the anger and it's not in your control how she responds, so

Because we have reasonable expectations for what people will and will not do. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154155376.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>And many of those reasonable expectations are in the form of law, for example I have a reasonable expectation for people not to murder me.  And also, just because you expect someone to do something, does not mean it's okay to do something.  Calling you a bitch does not make you lose control of your hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154158382.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry - are you claiming that people base their behaviour solely on what is legal and what is illegal. 

It is possible to break the law and not cause harm and cause harm and not break the law. 

I would also think it unreasonable if they told my family about things they didn't know that I didn't want them to know. That's disproportionate retribution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154178212.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm saying the law is based on what people expect people's behavior to be.  And if our debate is now about morality, I'm done because that is not what we're supposed to be discussing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154056855.0" user="help-Im-alive" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're missing the point. There are certain behaviors which make you more likely to be the victim of a crime. That doesn't absolve the criminal, but it's still true. If you leave your car unlocked, there's a higher chance someone will steal your bag out of the passenger seat. If you go to a frat party and get wasted, there's a higher chance you will get raped. Is it your right to leave your car unlocked or go to any party you like or drink as much as you like? Absolutely. But in reality these things increase your odds of negative consequences. 

I think OPs goal was to point out the differences in how we treat certain crimes because of this. If you leave your car or house unlocked and something gets stolen, the general feeling of society is that you were being careless and you could have prevented it if you had wanted to. However, in the case of rape people like to say that its victim blaming to point out that a change in behavior would have prevented the crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154062045.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there are things you can do to prevent that, my point is why does not doing those things make you responsible for something committing a crime against you?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154065824.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think one can be held responsible for?

Clearly your actions have consequences. But I don't think one should be held responsible for any and all consequences. 

I find it perfectly reasonable that we don't hold victims of rape responsible for their rape, and hold victims of theft responsible for their irresponsibility. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154069754.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>People can be held responsible for something they directly affected and did so consciously.  Leaving a door open did not make the robber steal or trigger a stealing instinct and they did not leave the door open so someone may rob them.

I find it unreasonable that we victim blame anyone, whether it be victims of rape or victims of theft.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154074520.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>You're claiming that one cannot be responsible for negligence?

Do you think that if someone neglected to clean the floor, and someone broke their hip after they slipped should not be held accountable?

Clearly we hold people responsible for actions they didn't directly cause. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154076338.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, they absolutely directly caused it.  Them not cleaning the floor directly lead to someone breaking their hip, assuming they didn't choose to slip and break their hip.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154087052.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>What if they had no idea that the other person will be there?

The law has provisions for "attractive nuisances"

http://definitions.uslegal.com/a/attractive-nuisance/

Because the scope of behavior we expect is not contingent just on direct causation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154090182.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If they had no idea that a person would be there, then they did not consciously endanger someone.  If they had reason to believe a person should be there, then they consciously took a risk of endangering someone and therefore is responsible.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154113192.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>So you do place weight in expectations. 

&amp;gt;If they had reason to believe a person should be there, then they consciously took a risk of endangering someone and therefore is responsible.

One can be reasonably expected to account for other people's actions. 

I just don't think that in the case of rape this is a fair expectation. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154116872.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I place weight in expectations when the expectation result in directly causing something.  They should place weight in expecting if people are going to walk through because the amount of people who slip and fall is directly caused by you and your expectation.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154684552.0" user="SpydeTarrix" delta="False">
    <text>This is a totally seperate analogy that doesn't fit with theft or rape.  its like saying that if you wear a short skirt, someone will get a boner and accidently fall boner first into your vagina.  

yes, the owner of the floor is responsible.  But the rape victim is not.  The person who fell was injured based on an accident.  Had the person seen the wet floor from accross the room, then piledrived the ground and broken their hip, it would be a much closer analogy to what you are trying to get at. 

wearing a short skirt doesnt make men lose all agency of their bodies. just like leaving your door unlocked doesnt make a theif suddenly become a mindless stuff stealing zombie.  this is the system that operates behind the issue of victim blaming.  once you start blaming the victim, you are saying that people lose control of their bodies when certain things are said, certain clothes are warn, or doors are left unlocked.  it simple isnt the case.  and it doesnt make sense.  the rapist/theif actively chose to rape/steal. 

how is it anyone else's responsibility other than the rapist/theif?

The fact that there are steps you can take to minimize your chances of being stolen from/raped does not mean that the victim is the party who is responsible for ensuring rape/theft dont happen.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155065013.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>What I was trying to say was that we hold people responsible for other people's actions. 

If something I said, or did or the way I behaved caused someone else to feel bad - I think I am partly responsible for it, and I think I should be blamed for it.  

However - I don't think I should be blamed if I caused someone to rape me, even if I was in some way a trigger for it, and even if I knew that my actions might have those consequences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155914026.0" user="SpydeTarrix" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with everything you just said.  If you attack someone verbally, you should be at least partially responsible for how they feel about it. I also agree that i should not be to blame if i get raped, because i did nothing to deserve being raped.  

I can simply exist, and that be enough for someone to rape me.  I shouldn't have to stop existing so that I don't get raped.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154074267.0" user="help-Im-alive" delta="False">
    <text>A train is illegally travelling down the tracks you are standing on and you can see it coming. If it hits you because you didn't move off the tracks, are you responsible? I realize this is hyperbolic, but the point is that if you have a reasonable suspicion that something will happen and do nothing to prevent it, you are responsible for it to some degree. The train is hyperbolic because it's a certainty. However, let's say you knew there was a 20% chance that an unlocked car would be robbed in a certain neighborhood, but only a 2% chance for a locked car. If you leave your car unlocked, then you are knowingly increasing your risk of being robbed tenfold. I'd consider you to be responsible for that increased risk. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154082568.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you are responsible because if you stay in front of a train you know 100% that that train is going to hit you  (edit - I didn't see the illegal part, so I'm going to add that there must be a reason to expect a train to travel towards you and you must have means to escape (like the ability to step to the side.)).  I mentioned in another comment that for someone to be responsible, they must have directly caused a consequence and consciously did so.  Unless you have some sort of mental defect, you consciously decide to stand in front of that train, knowing it will directly lead you to be hit by the train.  The certainty doesn't make it hyperbolic, it makes it an entirely different situation

Leaving your car door unlocked does not make someone break into your car.  Leaving the door unlocked does not affect the robber in any way until he actively tries to break into the car.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154105753.0" user="help-Im-alive" delta="False">
    <text>So is it the fact that a robber has agency that bothers you? The train can't have any responsibility because it's a train, therefore it all falls to you. But a robber can, so it all falls to him? 

Maybe in the grand scheme of things, that's valid, but on a personal level the robber is as much of an externality as the train. You can't control either, but you can make reasonable assumptions and act accordingly. And if you don't, then you are partially responsible for the results.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154111977.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the robber can control themselves.  The train can't. (well the conductor can, but a train can't stop on short notice)  I'm not saying it's not a good idea for people to look their doors and watch their drinks, but failing to do so does not make then responsible because they did not cause anyone to commit any crime against them.  You can't control the train or the robber or the rapist, but the robber and the rapist can control themselves.  That's why they are responsible.  You're not giving me any reason to believe that the person who didn't lock their doors consciously and directly caused a robbery to occur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154205930.0" user="MikeyDeez" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem in assigning blame/responsibility in hindsight is twofold:

1) All the victim-based responsibility is pointless, and *only* exists after the robber/rapist commits the offence.  I can leave a car unlocked all day, and it's not going to *make* anybody rob me.  The moment somebody *chooses* to rob me, my actions can be framed ex post facto as having responsibility.

2) There's a near infinite amount and locations where "casual responsibility" (as OP describes it) can be placed ex post facto/in hindsight if we assume responsibility lies wherever someone's unwitting choices that ended up facilitating the crime were made.

Maybe the bus driver cut the robber some slack when he was $.25 short on fare for the ride to the crime scene. The bus driver made a choice that facilitated the crime, even if they had no idea they were doing so.  Maybe someone shared a link with the robber showing them what cars don't have alarm systems built in.  I can assign "casual responsibility" to them!

You can make the argument that a reasonable person might know what and what may not lead to a crime (leaving a door unlocked), but that area gets *really* effing gray when rape is called into question.

I as a man can wear clothes that show off my chest.  Am I "casually responsible" if this "triggers" someone to rape me?  I see hundreds of people getting intoxicated in bars every weekend, are they all casually responsible if someone victimizes them on the way home?

It's just such a silly, arbitrary game to play in hindsight that I think it's more logical left un-entertained. I'm *not* saying we can evaluate choices that may or may not have facilitated a crime like rape; I'm saying that placing blame is arbitrary and near-impossible to do consistently, objectively, and reliably, **and in all cases** entirely contingent upon one person's responsibility: the perpetrator. 

Casual responsibility before the fact: Will choosing to wear a low-cut shirt get me raped? *Who knows?*  Will that guy choosing to rape me get me raped? *Yes.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154322133.0" user="howbigis1gb" delta="False">
    <text>Well - to be fair the law is interested in these things. 

As a parallel - there are laws against entrapment. 

We recognise the fact that someone can be led into doing something. 

From the wiki:

&amp;gt;In criminal law, entrapment is a practice whereby a law enforcement agent induces a person to commit a criminal offense that the person would have otherwise been unlikely to commit

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entrapment

Such an act can lead to evidence being deemed inadmissible.

Its not entirely a silly game to play whether you led someone to do something. 

That said - its highly unlikely that a victim of rape "entrapped" their rapist, but we do recognise that people can be led into committing actions they would not commit otherwise.  

I don't know if this is particularly meaningful when discussing rape as a social issue instead of a legal one. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154351130.0" user="MikeyDeez" delta="False">
    <text>While "entrapment" doesn't mean "led into a crime" as much as "the crime wouldn't have occurred otherwise" I definitely see what you're saying.

I do think in the context of rape it's a bit different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154091231.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>A human isn't the same as an unstoppable train. In a rape, the rapist is also a thinking, feeling human being, not a robot or animal who responds to stimuli and has zero self-control. Blaming the victim for a rape in any capacity is an insult to men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154101937.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Blaming the victim for a rape in any capacity is an insult to men.

Not all rapists are men!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154103078.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not, but they are in the fictional scenarios you guys are conjuring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154114471.0" user="help-Im-alive" delta="False">
    <text>And yet we blame the victims of theft to an extend depending on circumstances. We tell them they were being careless by not locking up and that they shouldn't be surprised it happened. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154062136.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think OPs goal was to point out the differences in how we treat certain crimes because of this. If you leave your car or house unlocked and something gets stolen, the general feeling of society is that you were being careless and you could have prevented it if you had wanted to. However, in the case of rape people like to say that its victim blaming to point out that a change in behavior would have prevented the crime.

I was trying to argue this, but a slightly deeper point. 

I don't think safeguarding from theft significantly affects quality of life, but when people enjoy various activities that increase the chance of being raped, and not involving yourself in those activities makes for a more boring life. 

I don't think many would argue that locking their house impacts their life in any meaningful way. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154807672.0" user="crisisofkilts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  There are certain behaviors which make you more likely to be the victim of a crime.

There are certain behaviors that make you more susceptible to anything. If you drive your car, there's a higher chance you'll be involved in a car accident. If you live in a polluted city, there's a higher chance you'll develop asthma.

But is a driver in any part responsible for a car accident based solely on the fact that he was driving a car at the time? That's about as silly as blaming the victim of a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154095366.0" user="just_foo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; [Finders keepers, losers weepers] is a juvenile phrase used by 7 year olds when they took someone's toy. This is not applicable to any adult situation and has no basis in law

While I generally agree with you, I'd like to point out that most jurisdictions recognize [salvage rights](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_salvage) to varying degrees.

There are a variety of other legal mechanisms that recognize certain rights of people using property over rights of people who ostensibly own the property (i.e. [squatting](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Squatting) and certain types of [easements](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easement).

So 'finders keepers losers weepers' does in fact apply in some scenarios.

That being said, I'm having trouble extracting a coherent argument out of OP's post. The presence of mitigating factors in a perpetrator's decision-making process has no bearing on the victim's culpability, even if the victim is unwise or irresponsible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154101158.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm...that's actually pretty interesting.  For salvage rights, I think the difference is you didn't cause the property to be lost or taken.  For easement, you're not attempting to possess the land over the actual owner and for squatting, your not taking it away from someone who actively owns it, so there is no "loser"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
