<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127745300.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2420wk/cmv_i_think_victims_can_be_blamed_but_the_reason/">
    <title>CMV: I think victims can be blamed, but the reason we believe they shouldn't be for rape and they can for theft is because we expect people to never rape regardless of the victim's behaviour, but consider stealing sometimes appropriate.</title>
    <original_poster>cmv_t</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now - I wouldn't tell a person who was raped that they were responsible for it. While I think they may be causally responsible for it - their culpability is a different question altogether. 

Many of the behaviours which increase the chances of rape are very enjoyable including but not limited to

1) Drinking

2) Having sex

3) Partying

4) Pushing social boundaries

These are social practices which people like to involve themselves in, even if they increase their chances of being raped. 

I think this is reasonable, and most people would like social sanction for involvement in these activities without a negative judgement of "asking for it", even if they did increase their chances of being raped. 

And this is entirely separate from the danger of being raped even without involving yourself in activities which increase your chance of being raped. 


On the other hand - people treat theft more casually. 

As a society - we have come to believe that the onus is on the person who owns a property to secure it, and we are also more cavalier towards theft. 

"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy. 

I've known people who have shoplifted once or twice. A pack of gum here, a cola there. 

Now imagine if there was a society where people left their doors unlocked and were generally not afraid of theft. 

This is viable in small communities, and I have seen it in poorer areas like slums where people have little and for people with so little - theft is a graver sin than it would seem for most. 


Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they *were* causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

The alternative would be developing strong attitudes toward theft (as one of the worse things you can do) - which is typically how these communities tend to work. 

Victim blaming with rape would mean adopting the former attitude rather than the latter, and comes at the cost of losing social sanction for certain events

Especially in the cases of partying, dressing "provocatively", and casual sex - these are behaviours which have - for a long time carried a negative value judgement, especially for women. 

So I do think that victims of rape can be causally responsible for their rape, but they shouldn't be blamed in spite of it. 

Edit: To be clear I am saying that how much a victim could have mitigated their risk is not relevant. We ought not to treat rape like theft. 


Edit 2: 


I've seen a lot of responses talking about how much can are responsible. I think this is an unproductive argument. 

If I insult someone's mother and they punch my face, am I responsible? I would say I definitely "had it coming" (circumstantially, of course).

People do account for other people's behaviours all the time. 

I don't think it is particularly important how much I caused something to happen in the cause of rape, while it pertinent in the case of punching someone in the face. 


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27154104213.0" user="Taramonia" delta="False">
    <text>So what is exactly your opinion here? You say yourself rape victims shouldn't be blamed. If a theft was considered appropriate(such as stealing food to feed your family) that has nothing to with blaming the victim, only absolving the perpetrator of the crime. Since when does anyone but a few backward people blame victims for a crime committed against them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154136459.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>I'd have no bones calling someone who didn't lock their cycle an idiot while I would never call someone who was raped an idiot even if they could have adopted different behaviours to avoid it. 

I think someone ought to lock their cycle if they didn't want it stolen, but I don't think people ought to care about their risk of being raped. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154161739.0" user="Taramonia" delta="False">
    <text>Okay your topic seemed to imply a sweeping generalization of societal opinion when we are just talking about yours. However, you still haven't answered why you believe it right for theft victims to be blamed or rape victims to not be, even though you admit both situations preventive measures can be taken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154168667.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>In general I think rape is less morally defensible than theft, I think mitigation of theft requires significantly less effort and affects your quality of life less. 

The question of whether something is theft or isn't is often characterised by the lack of efforts to secure things. 

If I park my cycle outside my apartment and someone takes it - its not clear if its theft or not. 

For example - I could put stuff out when I'm moving and expect people to take it. 

If I didn't want people to take it - they wouldn't be out, or they would be secured. 

There is an entire industry devoted to security, and lockpicking is a skill people invest time in for fun and theft.

Also - are you claiming that people don't treat theft differently than rape - so I am making a generalisation, but I don't think its inaccurate.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154209902.0" user="Taramonia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I park my cycle outside my apartment and someone takes it - its not clear if its theft or not.

No, it's crystal clear: someone took something they knew did not belong to them. We're not talking about leaving trash and stuff and the curb and people taking it (this is actually against the law in many places unless you have some sort of notice saying people can take it). If there is an entire industry devoted to security then how does this reinforce the idea that mitigation of theft requires *less* effort? I think you're white knighting a bit here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155082001.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>So you do believe there are some unspoken cues where you would assign blame to the person who was stolen from. 

My curb is right outside my apartment. 

But lets say you just left your cycle on the curb and went in, and someone took it. 

You might have a hard time convincing the police to take action. 

Additionally - a person with your stolen property, depending on how much effort you took to get it, and how it was passed on to them may get to keep it. 

http://blogs.lawyers.com/2013/04/who-owns-stolen-renoir/ is an interesting example of this. 


An entire industry is devoted to making it easy. For someone to secure against theft - they can use these solutions which required significantly less effort. 

Now if you were living in a society where theft was not the norm, you'll find it much more frowned upon. 

Moving from that society to one of constant security is a tragedy, and similarly - moving from a society where people feel free to do as they like socially to avoid rape to one of paranoid constant vigilance is also a tragedy. 

We already live in a society of constant security though, but not one of constant vigilance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155158621.0" user="Taramonia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So you do believe there are some unspoken cues where you would assign blame to the person who was stolen from.

No, I never said that and you are *still* avoiding my question, you use ridiculously flawed logic that also has nothing to do with your original argument or the matter at hand. Im done with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154240692.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; lockpicking is a skill people invest time in for fun and theft.

Minor nitpick: Lockpicking these days is really mostly for hobby/fun; it takes too long to be practical for theft, when things like bump keys are say to make and require less skill and more hammer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155056368.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
