<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1277501269.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l4laad/cmv_redditors_dont_know_shit_about_money/">
    <title>CMV: Redditors don't know shit about money</title>
    <original_poster>Yaqoob_</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have asked on multiple sub-reddits about the way money works. Its inception, supply, centralisation among other constituents. Most of the redditors answer in jargon language which doesn't serve any use. Divulging a bit, I have also hear that reddit doesn't turn a profit because the audience of reddit are merely keyboard warriors who don't have money to go out there and spend for advertisers to generate cashflow.

Also, kindly do suggest how I can understand things related to money (in simple language)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36079890302.0" user="WWBSkywalker" delta="False">
    <text>Have you tried  r/AskEconomics? I'm based in Australia and I use and contribute to r/AusFinance. Presumably you have a subreddit that's similar. It's a matter of asking the right subreddit I expect.

Source: I'm in the finance profession.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36079904569.0" user="Yaqoob_" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I did. No satisfactory reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36080126539.0" user="WWBSkywalker" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand why this can happen.

I know sometimes it is hard for me to give answers on reddit simply because of the lack of context, and inability to answer at the right level - this happens in real life in my job as well. So I'll always try to understand context and the level of knowledge the questioner operates at. E.g. If I know the question comes from a student not understanding an economic class subject, vs a narrow question on tax in a particular real world situation, I can answer appropriately. I commonly ask why the questioner is asking the question as an example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36081561942.0" user="aussieincanada" delta="False">
    <text>No satisfactory reply to what question?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
