<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127745300.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2420wk/cmv_i_think_victims_can_be_blamed_but_the_reason/">
    <title>CMV: I think victims can be blamed, but the reason we believe they shouldn't be for rape and they can for theft is because we expect people to never rape regardless of the victim's behaviour, but consider stealing sometimes appropriate.</title>
    <original_poster>cmv_t</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now - I wouldn't tell a person who was raped that they were responsible for it. While I think they may be causally responsible for it - their culpability is a different question altogether. 

Many of the behaviours which increase the chances of rape are very enjoyable including but not limited to

1) Drinking

2) Having sex

3) Partying

4) Pushing social boundaries

These are social practices which people like to involve themselves in, even if they increase their chances of being raped. 

I think this is reasonable, and most people would like social sanction for involvement in these activities without a negative judgement of "asking for it", even if they did increase their chances of being raped. 

And this is entirely separate from the danger of being raped even without involving yourself in activities which increase your chance of being raped. 


On the other hand - people treat theft more casually. 

As a society - we have come to believe that the onus is on the person who owns a property to secure it, and we are also more cavalier towards theft. 

"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy. 

I've known people who have shoplifted once or twice. A pack of gum here, a cola there. 

Now imagine if there was a society where people left their doors unlocked and were generally not afraid of theft. 

This is viable in small communities, and I have seen it in poorer areas like slums where people have little and for people with so little - theft is a graver sin than it would seem for most. 


Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they *were* causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

The alternative would be developing strong attitudes toward theft (as one of the worse things you can do) - which is typically how these communities tend to work. 

Victim blaming with rape would mean adopting the former attitude rather than the latter, and comes at the cost of losing social sanction for certain events

Especially in the cases of partying, dressing "provocatively", and casual sex - these are behaviours which have - for a long time carried a negative value judgement, especially for women. 

So I do think that victims of rape can be causally responsible for their rape, but they shouldn't be blamed in spite of it. 

Edit: To be clear I am saying that how much a victim could have mitigated their risk is not relevant. We ought not to treat rape like theft. 


Edit 2: 


I've seen a lot of responses talking about how much can are responsible. I think this is an unproductive argument. 

If I insult someone's mother and they punch my face, am I responsible? I would say I definitely "had it coming" (circumstantially, of course).

People do account for other people's behaviours all the time. 

I don't think it is particularly important how much I caused something to happen in the cause of rape, while it pertinent in the case of punching someone in the face. 


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27154071019.0" user="looseleaf" delta="False">
    <text>Someone [posted something very similar](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/240x9w/cmv_i_think_that_victim_blaming_when_it_comes_to/) 9 hours ago. There are a few arguments in there you might find useful. 

Please describe how anything beyond drinking and partying (assuming drugs are involved) makes women more statistically likely to get raped. 

Finders-keepers doesn't make sense when applied to rape, as while someone can assume the item is owned by someone else, they cannot find to owner to affirm this is the case. With rape, the victim physically has to be present and even if they cannot give consent, the perpetrator cannot assume that they might have surrendered ownership of their body, so the finders-keepers concept cannot apply. 

We can lock our doors and secure our possessions, but even that will not completely prevent theft. We are not forced to lead drastically different lives by taking a few seconds to hide things of value and using locks. We are less sympathetic to those who do not secure their valuables and get robbed because we feel as though they didn't take very basic steps to prevent it. Additionally, we don't view stealing a packing of gum and casing a house on the same level. To keep with the level of "deeply personal and invasive", you should compare people's cavalier attitudes towards stealing with grabbing someone's ass at a bar, which people tend to care far less about. 

The things you believe cause rape are not nearly as simple and fool-proof as simply securing possessions. As most rapes are perpetrated by people the victim knows, the idea that rape can be prevented without completely altering how people live their lives ignores the reality of the situation.

edit: link fixed

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154075135.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>you linked to your user page</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154080233.0" user="looseleaf" delta="False">
    <text>whoops. I'll fix that. Thanks for pointing that out. 

Edit: fixed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154108867.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Let me be clear. 

I think it is always unreasonable to victim blame when it comes to rape.

I just don't agree with the reasoning that is often given. 

I am not making absolute claims on what does and doesn't increase the chances of rape. 

But what I am saying is that its a good thing we don't treat rape like we treat theft. 

Theft isn't as bad a crime, and there are many instances when we are perfectly happy turning a blind eye to theft. 

I don't want to make accusations here, but I would wager that in the course of your life you may have picked up a pen when signing a form, or taken a coke from a malfunctioning machine. 

I'm not especially interested in what does and doesn't increase your chances of rape. 

***Even if*** there exists behaviour which increases your chances of being raped - I don't think it is reasonable to expect people to not indulge in that behaviour. 

I think it is viable t

&amp;gt;We can lock our doors and secure our possessions, but even that will not completely prevent theft. We are not forced to lead drastically different lives by taking a few seconds to hide things of value and using locks. 

I don't believe I disagree - securing your things is not too much of an inconvenience. 

But that is also because we live in a society where we don't think of it as a big deal. 

In my example of the community where people don't lock their houses - by starting to place the onus on people to lock their houses, there is a price to be paid in terms of trust and general stress.

By shifting the onus on the victim we are requiring significant changes to their life - which I do not think is reasonable - *just* for a slightly lower risk of getting raped. 

I've often been confronted by people who say "a ha - so you do admit that they increased their chances of being raped". 

Well - maybe, but I don't think it is reasonable that people believe that the only aim of people is to live a minimum risk life. 

I think it is perfectly reasonable that people indulge in certain behaviours even in spite of a slightly (or even large - doesn't matter) risk of being raped. 

This is exactly the kind of mentality which I object to when people say that some writer who criticised muslim extremism had to expect a fatwa. 

Well sure - they knew it, and they did it in spite of it because their expression is valuable to them. 

I don't think people hold the idea of locking their house so dear, and I find it perfectly reasonable to expect people to take reasonable safeguards against theft, but not rape. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154135275.0" user="looseleaf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is exactly the kind of mentality which I object to when people say that some writer who criticised muslim extremism had to expect a fatwa.

There is a difference between preventative actions to reduce a risk rather than creating a risk. One is merely trying to minimize, the other is acting in a way that creates a very reasonable expectation of risk. I do not think you can claim that drinking and partying, which many people do without ever being raped, is analogous to a person making statements that almost always incite a negative response. 

We don't see someone who has their car stolen despite locking their doors as causally to blame for not having a steering wheel lock, if steering wheel locks aren't considered reasonable preventative measures in that area. Yes, they could have been safer, but we acknowledge that they didn't need to do *everything* in their power to prevent the theft, just what is reasonable. If prevention is an unreasonable request, then how can we see the victim as possessing causal blame? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154149691.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Whether something is a reasonable expectation or not is a different argument. 

If one could reliably say that a certain action could mitigate rape - I don't think it is a fair expectation to expect people to do it. Whether they do or do not is entirely up to them.

Creating vs reducing risk is a rabbit hole. 

But lets roll with your example - someone created risk by writing a book - so does that mean they ought not to have done it. That somehow they are to be "blamed" for the risk they created?

&amp;gt;We don't see someone who has their car stolen despite locking their doors as causally to blame for not having a steering wheel lock, if steering wheel locks aren't considered reasonable preventative measures in that area.

Right - and I don't believe I disagree. I believe that there are reasonable safeguards against theft.

There may be against rape, but what I'm saying that most safeguards against rape take the cost of sever lifestyle impediments. 

And in general - we expect people not to rape, but we don't in general expect them not to thieve.

&amp;gt; If prevention is an unreasonable request, then how can we see the victim as possessing causal blame?

Causality is amoral. Personal responsibility is a different concept. 

As another example - if someone goes to school walking through a minefield - knowing that there's a 2% chance that they'll die. 

If they die - do we hold them accountable - they know they stood the risk. 

They were in fact causally responsible for taking a course of action which increased their chance of death. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154694261.0" user="SpydeTarrix" delta="False">
    <text>Having read through your posts here, you keep making the same underlying assertion that is blatantly false: rapists cannot control their own actions.  

In the mine example, it is not the mine's fault that it exploded.  If the kid steps on the mine it WILL go off.  Period.  It does not CHOOSE to go off.  So your example makes no sense, because there is 0 blame that can be placed on the mine. 

The rapist can make his own decisions.  In order for the rape to occur, no matter the situations surrounding it, there is no crime unless the rapist actively chooses to commit it.  A dozen women could walk in front of my completely naked or dressed in the sexiest outfits i could imagine.  And I would absolutely not rape any of them.  More than once my wife has basically done just this: dressed up, been ready and raring to go, but she had just gotten out of surgery not long ago, so when we started it hurt her and she said stop.  you know what i did? i stopped.  She said stop, i stopped.  We were already having sex when she said stop.  If anything, you could say that i would have been in a more primal/instinct driven mindset than just looking at naked women.  but i still stopped.  because i have my own agency. 

The rapist has to actively choose to commit the rape before there is any crime.  

Did you also know that most rape is from a relative or friend that the victim knew well? Most rape comes from people that the victim has associated with for a long time.  The "roofied in the club wearing a short skirt" story of rape is a lot rarer than you probably think.  

In the case above, the victim could be in sweats and a big old sweater wearing no make up just watching a show on the couch.  And yet she is still the victim of rape.  Not becuase she was responsible, but because the rapist made a decision.  

The same can be said for a theif.  He has to choose to steal, otherwise it never happens.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155071704.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Why is agency important?

So lets say instead of mines there were drones? Would the situation change?

Would you hold this girl responsible for not reducing her chances?

I'm saying its completely unproductive to play this game and unreasonable to expect people to behave in a way solely to reduce their risk of something bad happening to them. 

Certainly all theft isn't the same either. 

We are comfortable assigning blame depending on the situation. 

If you drop a 100 dollars on the floor, and someone picks it up later - is it theft?

But if you leave your car unlocked and someone drives away with it - is it theft?

You don't think there's a difference between the former and the latter?

I reject the hypothesis that you can't reduce your risk. 

I also reject the hypothesis that we should uniformly expect people to reduce their risk. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27155912358.0" user="SpydeTarrix" delta="False">
    <text>So, is the point of your CMV that we should treat rape like theft? Or theft like rape? Because otherwise i really dont see what you are getting at.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
