<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="127745300.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2420wk/cmv_i_think_victims_can_be_blamed_but_the_reason/">
    <title>CMV: I think victims can be blamed, but the reason we believe they shouldn't be for rape and they can for theft is because we expect people to never rape regardless of the victim's behaviour, but consider stealing sometimes appropriate.</title>
    <original_poster>cmv_t</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now - I wouldn't tell a person who was raped that they were responsible for it. While I think they may be causally responsible for it - their culpability is a different question altogether. 

Many of the behaviours which increase the chances of rape are very enjoyable including but not limited to

1) Drinking

2) Having sex

3) Partying

4) Pushing social boundaries

These are social practices which people like to involve themselves in, even if they increase their chances of being raped. 

I think this is reasonable, and most people would like social sanction for involvement in these activities without a negative judgement of "asking for it", even if they did increase their chances of being raped. 

And this is entirely separate from the danger of being raped even without involving yourself in activities which increase your chance of being raped. 


On the other hand - people treat theft more casually. 

As a society - we have come to believe that the onus is on the person who owns a property to secure it, and we are also more cavalier towards theft. 

"Finders keepers, losers weepers" is a phrase reflective of that philosophy. 

I've known people who have shoplifted once or twice. A pack of gum here, a cola there. 

Now imagine if there was a society where people left their doors unlocked and were generally not afraid of theft. 

This is viable in small communities, and I have seen it in poorer areas like slums where people have little and for people with so little - theft is a graver sin than it would seem for most. 


Now if there was a theft in such a community - the reaction could be one where the person who was stolen from could be blamed . After all - they *were* causally responsible. This would lead to more people locking their stuff, and it is not clear to me that it is a better situation because the members of this community likely enjoyed the feeling of trust, and leaving their things unsecured.

The alternative would be developing strong attitudes toward theft (as one of the worse things you can do) - which is typically how these communities tend to work. 

Victim blaming with rape would mean adopting the former attitude rather than the latter, and comes at the cost of losing social sanction for certain events

Especially in the cases of partying, dressing "provocatively", and casual sex - these are behaviours which have - for a long time carried a negative value judgement, especially for women. 

So I do think that victims of rape can be causally responsible for their rape, but they shouldn't be blamed in spite of it. 

Edit: To be clear I am saying that how much a victim could have mitigated their risk is not relevant. We ought not to treat rape like theft. 


Edit 2: 


I've seen a lot of responses talking about how much can are responsible. I think this is an unproductive argument. 

If I insult someone's mother and they punch my face, am I responsible? I would say I definitely "had it coming" (circumstantially, of course).

People do account for other people's behaviours all the time. 

I don't think it is particularly important how much I caused something to happen in the cause of rape, while it pertinent in the case of punching someone in the face. 


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27154057965.0" user="GeorgeMaheiress" delta="False">
    <text>What does "causally responsible" mean? It certainly can't mean "primarily responsible", because clearly the victim is not that. If it means "engaged in an activity where there is a non-zero risk that someone might harm you" then that's well, everyone all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154068544.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>Not a nonzero risk, but a heightened risk. 

Can one expect to be raped if one indulges in this behaviour?

One can often answer the question with a yes, but I don't believe that said activity shouldn't be done because of it. 


On the other hand - many activities increase your risk of theft, and I am perfectly comfortable asserting that those activities should not be done. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154079451.0" user="GeorgeMaheiress" delta="False">
    <text>What does "expect" mean? My understanding is it means a high (&amp;gt;50%) probability of something happening, and I dearly hope and believe that there are very few situations people get into where there is such a high chance of being raped. Why on earth would they? And what monstrous society would we live in where such situations were common?

And why are you so willing to judge victims of theft? If someone is walking home alone at night and is mugged, it is not their fault. Yes they're aware that being alone and unarmed makes them vulnerable, but they have to live their lives anyway and accept the risk, we all do. People don't need to be told not to take *unreasonable* risks, we all have our own self-interest at heart. And we certainly don't need people dictating what we should and should not do "for our own good". We can decide for ourselves what is and is not an acceptable risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154115070.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>That's a random bar you're setting. 

But lets roll with your example. Even if someone did something which increased their chances of being raped by 100%, they shouldn't be held responsible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154134345.0" user="GeorgeMaheiress" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just trying to pin down what you're saying. It sounds like you're saying that although pragmatically rape victims should not be blamed for their assault, internally you still hold them somewhat responsible for choosing to engage in activities you deem to be too risky.

I asked what you mean by "expect" because I think you're using it in a fuzzy, undefined and therefore unfair way, essentially meaning "something *I* wouldn't do". If someone enjoys "partying" so much that they're willing to do it even though you believe it increases the chance that they might be attacked, why judge them for that? It doesn't to my mind take away from the injustice of sexual assault at all. One might even argue that these people are courageous to live life fully despite the risks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27154178633.0" user="cmv_t" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm just trying to pin down what you're saying. It sounds like you're saying that although pragmatically rape victims should not be blamed for their assault, internally you still hold them somewhat responsible for choosing to engage in activities you deem to be too risky.

That's not exactly what I'm saying. I'm saying its reasonable that they don't base their behaviour on their chances of being raped. 

I think its unreasonable to not account for the chances of your belongings being stolen. 

&amp;gt;I asked what you mean by "expect" because I think you're using it in a fuzzy, undefined and therefore unfair way, essentially meaning "something I wouldn't do". 

No - I'm not talking about my expectation. I'm talking about theirs. And I do think that many people do take precautions - they watch their drinks, they're mindful of their surroundings. 

I don't think I would "blame" anyone if they didn't do these things, however.

&amp;gt;If someone enjoys "partying" so much that they're willing to do it even though you believe it increases the chance that they might be attacked, why judge them for that? It doesn't to my mind take away from the injustice of sexual assault at all. One might even argue that these people are courageous to live life fully despite the risks.

That is actually what I'm arguing - their risk assessment of the situation need not preclude them from participating in those activities. 

It is entirely unproductive to discuss how they could have mitigated the rape. Apart from the practical considerations of accuracy - people want to indulge in certain activities, and I think its not fair that we assign blame if people do those things. 

I don't know if I'd call it "courage", but that's a minor objection at best. 

Just because people *could* reduce their risk of something doesn't mean its fair to expect them to do so. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
