<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36096212411.0" user="Ecoronel1989" delta="False">
    <text>Having to learn both system means that they can keep some old habits or measures the same, while at the same time they are able to easily understand the otherwise worldwide standard.  The UK and Canada may keep the imperial system around for historical/cultural reasons, but have incorporated the SI standard because it is objectively better.  The US is stubborn and only learns the inferior method, which is a disservice to it's citizens since many struggle to understand the SI system later on.  It's better to learn both and only learn the inferior of the two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098693691.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the US is stubborn and only learns the inferior method, which is a disservice to its citizens since many struggle to understand the SI system later on.

Well for one, the US does teach its citizens the metric system. That’s how I know it. Two, who is it doing a disservice too? As I said, most people just don’t need to know it. The two biggest groups I can think of are scientists and those who love/work/travel internationally. For scientists, well as I said, they do teach metric. It’s a large part of science classes so I would be quite impressed if someone passed a science class without knowing metric, much less got a science degree. As for other citizens who don’t pay attention in science class or forget the system because they never use it, well learning new things is a part of traveling/living/working internationally. Generally you need to learn the language, culture, maybe even history, what’s the big deal adding learning metric. After all, people always push it as being easy to learn, shouldn’t be that big of a deal for travelers to learn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098951672.0" user="Ecoronel1989" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct that the SI system is taught in school s, but it is not adopted into the culture, which makes teaching it easily forgettable.  You point out that scientist are also taught the SI system, but you're kinda overlooking engineering.  Engineers have to learn two systems since they have to do computations for the public sector, but may have to do conversations if they are working with non US companies.  This has caused some issues, where there was miscommunication about what units were being used in collaborations between us and non us engineers.

You're also right that traveling has other complications such as language barriers, but this only compounded by having different units.  For example, if you buy a car in the US, it is likely that your odometer measures speed in mi/hr.  Now taking that car in a road trip to Canada you run into an issue  because their speed laws are written in km/hr.  Though you may speak English in both countries, you run into not being able to know if you're going the speed limit.  Conversely, you are able to drive a car from Canada to Mexico, and though you may not speak Spanish you can abide by the speed limit since both use the SI system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
