<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36096307308.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>One of the main reasons Canada uses some imperial units in every day live is because our culture is so closely connected with the US. If the US switched to metric, then this would change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098543760.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>Ya I understand why, and I’m not saying it’s Canada’s fault, I specifically said it wasn’t, but that doesn’t make the system not illogical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36100392577.0" user="crisro123" delta="False">
    <text>Well yes it is illogical but the point is that Canada isn't choosing an illogical system for the fun of it.

We really have no choice due to how strong the influence from the US is since Canada isn't exactly boarded by many other countries.

This leads to cases where Canadian have no choice but to learn bits and pieces of two measurement systems due to circumstances outside of their contol.

Wood for example is almost exclusively sold in Imperial measurements because this makes the same material usable in both Canada and the US. 

So what should Canada do to solve this issue? Sell all wood in Metric only and alienate the entire US market?

I'd also argue that knowing more is better than knowing less so while Americans usually make excuses for why they don't need Metric people in Canada just learn whatever Imperial is needed for their personal/professional needs.

Knowing and being able to use 2 measurement systems isn't illogical but refusing to learn one which like 90% of the world uses certainly is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36104856768.0" user="SapperBomb" delta="False">
    <text>You keep referring to Canada using 2 systems but we technically use only one. The official system of measurement in Canada is metric. The government, military and most large businesses have moved to metric. Using imperial measurements is unofficial, you will still find it used by older generations because culturally we are still in transition.

And just so your aware your country uses 2 systems as well. Alot of STEM industries and schools use metric because they have to if they are going to integrate into the international system that is why metric is called SI (System d'International). The US military heavily uses the metric system. You guys are in transition as well, your just much further back than the rest of the world, that is not a dig on you or the US, I'm from an let generation that grew up with imperial units.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
