<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36096688286.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>As a young Canadian I really only use imperial in three instances:

1. Talking about height or weight with older people who grew up using imperial 

2. Baking because so many recipes come from the US and are in Imperial 

3. Work because I work in industry and we deal with Americans who only understand imperial and are unwilling to change</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098556194.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>Ya but I’m talking about Canada as a whole, not just individuals. Like there are individuals in the US who primarily use metric, should we not criticize the US system of measures because of that? And whenever I see any media, TV, YouTube, etc. I definitely see a lot of imperial, so I don’t think your experiences extend to the entire country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098587647.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>It definitely extends to almost all young individuals. Even your info graph basically works out to the three points I made I just explained why those are the exceptions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36309764088.0" user="creeper321448" delta="False">
    <text>For the first one, I've never met anyone in Canada who won't use feet and pounds. Even my 14-year-old cousin who is Canadian has no idea what you mean if you say his weight in kg and height in cm.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
