<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36096218788.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it better to be consistently bad?

Isn't it at least slightly better to sometimes be good? At least it's half a step in the right direction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098514549.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>But I wouldn’t consider imperial bad per se. while I acknowledge overall metric is superior to imperial, that doesn’t make imperial bad. It is still a working system of measures that has worked for a long time. If it is so bad, why is it still used by countries where everyone is taught metric? Is English a bad language just because things don’t make as much sense as languages like Esperanto?

And I would say it’s better to just have an ok system then switching between an ok system and a good system. You can’t just take the average of the two systems and say that’s how good the new system is. Using multiple systems adds likely unnecessary complexity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098936635.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; while I acknowledge overall metric is superior to imperial, that doesn’t make imperial bad. 

I mean, if you have two options, one of which is better than the other. The other one is bad in comparison. 

&amp;gt; And I would say it’s better to just have an ok system then switching between an ok system and a good system 

Why?  "Using multiple systems adds likely unnecessary complexity."?

Using your analogy, does that mean bilingual countries are worse than monolingual countries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36098954566.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>Well the countries themselves aren’t worse but their system of communication is if people are forced to learn 2 languages. Just like I’m not saying Canada or the UK are worse, just their system of measuring is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36099098573.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but their system of communication is if people are forced to learn 2 languages

Why do you think this? As a bilingual person, some ideas are better communicated in different languages, and since you grow up fluent in both, switching between them is effectively effortless.

While this doesn't completely translate to units, since I'd argue metric is straight up superior, so using imperial in addition to metric is worse than just using metric. I'd say growing up having at least the intuition of using metric in addition to imperial is better than only knowing imperial.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
