<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36097345869.0" user="LeMegachonk" delta="False">
    <text>In Canada, only the metric system has been officially taught for 40+ years.  My children (who are both young adults) really only know metric with very limited exposure to US measures.  My younger daughter (18) recently had to do a US standardized test and asked me what a yard was.  Knowledge and use of US measures is slowly fading away as the people who grew up learning it leave us.

As far as usage goes, what do you mean?  *Everything* official is in metric in Canada.  Everyday usage is something else entirely and people use all kinds of non-standard measurements for that.  When driving you're told to keep a certain number of "car lengths" behind traffic.  That's not a recognized way of measuring anything and has no singular meaning.

Lastly, since when is being able to measure using two different systems of units a disadvantage or a bad thing in any way?  People who are fluent in metric *and* US units have a distinct advantage over those who only know one.  Especially when that one differs from what almost every other country has adopted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
