<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281806005.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l75jud/cmv_while_the_gme_squeeze_is_a_powerful_display/">
    <title>CMV: While the GME squeeze is a powerful display of retail trader’s power, there is no endgame that doesn’t result in them losing massive amount of money.</title>
    <original_poster>ticklemytaint340</original_poster>
    <original_post>The GameStop squeeze carried out by r/wsb and others demonstrated the power of retail traders and seems like a fair punishment on market makers and hedge funds that have taken advantage of the stock market for ages, but there is no way that it will end well for them. Sure, a lot of stock brokers have lost millions on shorts because retail traders refuse to sell and are still buying, but they can afford to do so because they have enormous amounts of cash to rest on and because GME is clearly overvalued. GME’s market cap is several times its revenue, and the only reason it is that high is because of the artificial demand created by internet communities. At some point, sellers are going to fold and GME is going to collapse, and everybody that purchased it when it was overvalued is going to lose massive amounts of money, while Wall Street short sellers laugh their way to the bank.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36106346619.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36107954794.0" user="ihatedogs2" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ObligationGlad – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+ObligationGlad&amp;amp;message=ObligationGlad+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/l75jud/-/gl4sbcr/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
