<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281410057.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l6x2bt/cmv_imposing_extreme_regulatory_controls_on_the/">
    <title>cmv: Imposing extreme regulatory controls on the stock market would benefit the economy for most people.</title>
    <original_poster>brickses</original_poster>
    <original_post>The fundamental virtue of the stock market to the economy is that it:

* Allows any person to easily invest their wealth in capital ventures for profit (the basis of our capitalist society).
* Efficiently grants the leverage to secure capital to the firms which investors believe have the most propensity to produce value to society.
	
Imposing even the most drastic regulatory constraints on the market would not fundamentally impact these benefits, and would only impact the ability of traders to extract arbitrage out of the market at the expense of other investors.

Liquidity has no significant inherent value to the stock market in terms of it's value to the economy as a whole.

Prohibiting the use of all speculative instruments/derivatives and imposing small per-trade tax would not negatively impact the stock market in it's value to most people, it would reduce the volatility of the market and the likelihood of national or global market events, and if anything it would increase the returns of low risk index funds and value investments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36104108020.0" user="aussieincanada" delta="False">
    <text>So the major issue with this view is that you wish to ban derivatives. These are extremely good insurance policies for manufacturers of commodities. A farmer with a shed full of hogs needs to secure atleast $10 per pork belly otherwise he won't have enough cash to cover his farm for the next cycle. 

He is worried about the current price of $15 per pork belly and decides to purchase a derivative to lock on this price. There are legitimate uses of derivatives.

Your other points could be debated but they are more speculative in nature that requires smarter people than I to guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36105542258.0" user="brickses" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;[Derivatives] are extremely good insurance policies for manufacturers of commodities.

Surely this risk mitigation could be achieved through more traditional insurance models without being significantly disruptive. The effect should be the same but would limited to hedging the risk for the people who own the hogs. Letting others who have no stake in the market hedge against it is like letting random people take out an insurance policy against me crashing my car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106382835.0" user="aussieincanada" delta="False">
    <text>Derivatives are the insurance policy. Your issue with who can/cannot hold instruments is a completely separate issue. Parties are buying insurance policies on everyone's car, not your individual car. They are commodities after all. 

Can a chef or food wholesaler buy insurance on the price of pork?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
