<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281806005.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l75jud/cmv_while_the_gme_squeeze_is_a_powerful_display/">
    <title>CMV: While the GME squeeze is a powerful display of retail trader’s power, there is no endgame that doesn’t result in them losing massive amount of money.</title>
    <original_poster>ticklemytaint340</original_poster>
    <original_post>The GameStop squeeze carried out by r/wsb and others demonstrated the power of retail traders and seems like a fair punishment on market makers and hedge funds that have taken advantage of the stock market for ages, but there is no way that it will end well for them. Sure, a lot of stock brokers have lost millions on shorts because retail traders refuse to sell and are still buying, but they can afford to do so because they have enormous amounts of cash to rest on and because GME is clearly overvalued. GME’s market cap is several times its revenue, and the only reason it is that high is because of the artificial demand created by internet communities. At some point, sellers are going to fold and GME is going to collapse, and everybody that purchased it when it was overvalued is going to lose massive amounts of money, while Wall Street short sellers laugh their way to the bank.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36106395908.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>What if the endgame is to provoke a regulatory response? Alot of what I'm reading is people throwing  a couple hundred in there just for the bare opportunity to fuck over a hedge fund.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106430598.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>That’s all well and good if the people buying GME see that as their goal, but I very highly doubt that all of the 10 or so billion dollars that were pumped into it were to elicit better regulation. And regardless, that’s like saying that the 2008 collapse was worth it since we got better regulation, or really any major accident that resulted in positive change. Your argument is basically that the titanic was worth it because hey now cruises have more lifeboats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106490700.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't you being reductionist to say that there is only one endgame when there is an amalgamation of 10 billion in capital?

Your assumption is that everyone is in this thing to make money, but there's some real joker types jumping on board too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106540964.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not, because it is fairly clear to see that GME is ridiculously over valued, and I believe that most of WAB is aware of that as well. Sure, there might be joker types who lose a couple hundred, but there are people who will lose their savings over a huge prank, that lost money will line the pockets of short sellers, however much they have already lost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106593529.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>Refusing to ascribe varied goals to a widely disparate group of individuals is not reductionist?

Given the rank market manipulation going on today by the brokerages and trading platforms, do you consider it possible for investors to incorporate vindictive outrage into their investment strategy? Perhaps they could sell a portion to cover their investment and hold the rest specifically to screw over the shorts?

Class action lawsuits have already begun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106678882.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not reductionist because similar things have happened multiple times and there is generally the same outcome. When the dotcom bubble burst and during the subprime mortgage crisis the only people who won were those that saw it coming, wether they sold before, shorted, or did both. Both were caused by overvaluation, and the current scenario is a smaller version of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106703492.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>according to Oxford:

Reductionist -  a person who analyzes and describes a complex phenomenon in terms of its simple or fundamental constituents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106723542.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I’ll give you that one, my general argument might be a bit oversimplified, but hey Occam’s Razor. And regardless, I stand by the fundamentals of this scenario being nearly identical to this before it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106895493.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>I think a more comparable scenario is the VW short squeeze that saw hedge fund managers lose 30 billion. In this case, it's an amalgamation of redditors rather than porsche, but the fundamentals are quite comparable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36107038528.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you that it is similar in that both saw a surge in demand due to a short squeeze, but the GME squeeze has the additional demand created by thousands of people throwing cash at a meme stock, further inflating its value. And regardless, the end result is the same, with VW stock also collapsing after the squeeze was over, costing investors millions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36114410917.0" user="ticklemytaint340" delta="False">
    <text>Idk if this thread is still active, but I’ve done some reading on the VW squeeze and found a few key differences. The VW squeeze was caused due to Porsche covertly buying around 70% of VW, leaving very few stocks available. This led to a short squeeze when those who sold shorts covered their positions and the price shot up. This means that the only people who lost money where the short sellers, as Porsche had purchased their shares before the squeeze. With GME we have people that are still trading and pushing the price higher than what would occur if it was just a short squeeze, so they stand to lose as they are buying when GME is already overvalued. They are also have far more at stake than a hedge fund would, as they are betting their own savings and a vast majority of them likely own exclusively GME.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36108392445.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36109278422.0" user="david-song" delta="False">
    <text>If the regulation stops another 2008 crisis from happening then anyone who invests $40k and loses every penny is still in the black in the long term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106566303.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>I'm very curious where this whole desire to fuck over hedge funds is coming from in the first place. Like, I don't think the average redditor could even tell you what a hedge fund *is,* let alone why they're bad or worth fucking over. But they all seem certain it's a righteous crusade.

I suspect this is more of a post hoc justification for something that's fun and potentially lucrative, and hedge funds are acting as a stand in for the vague idea of wall street shenanigans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36106659201.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>There's actually a reasonable explanation imo, many young americans were negatively impacted by the 2008/2009 housing collapse and there is alot of residual anger at the perception that nobody was held responsible for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36108661370.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>This is exactly what I mean when I say I suspect they're acting as a stand in for some vague Wall St. shenanigans, unless hedge funds were uniquely responsible for '08, which I don't think is true.

I think it could also be the case that many people just find the concept of short selling unsavory, in the same way nobody likes the guy betting the "Don't Pass" line on the craps table.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36109506415.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that the majority find the concept of short selling immoral, but the idea of shorting 140% of the total shares? Therein lies the outrage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36110301760.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>So... is it the shorting, or is it the ‘08 financial crisis?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36112790395.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>Why not both?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36113005999.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>Both are reasonable as like, general complaints about Wall Street, but neither is an argument against the point I made in my first comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36113090065.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>What was your point again, that the average redditor is an idiot hopping on a bandwagon? I thought we were having a conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36113136457.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>That in this crusade against hedge funds, hedge funds are being used as a stand in for a vague notion of “Wall Street bad.”

&amp;gt;I thought we were having a conversation

Aren’t we?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36113275571.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>Well, like in all non-homogenous groups you're going to have a variance in reasons for participation.

I wouldn't call it a crusade against hedgefunds specifically, but rather a groundswell of resistance against the hypocrisy of a financial sector that opines the benefits of a free market while actively engaging in collusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36114025617.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I wouldn't call it a crusade against hedgefunds specifically, but rather a groundswell of resistance against the hypocrisy of a financial sector

Exactly my point and, IMO, why the message falls flat to anyone not already primed to be vaguely anti-financial services to begin with. There are obviously legitimate criticisms to be made, but my sense is that most people who are vocally on the side of WSB right now *don't actually know what those criticisms are.* See the weekly CMV threads about "the stock market is a casino for rich people" for an example of a common but incorrect criticism.

&amp;gt;while actively engaging in collusion.

This part rings true in terms of the Robinhood/Citadel relationship, for example. But there's no collusion inherent in short selling; there is, however, at least *some* measure of collusion inherent in a short squeeze.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36114889511.0" user="drschwartz" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with your opinion regarding the message failing to register with those that aren't primed to be anti-financial services. My opinion is formed like yours on the basis of anecdotal evidence, but the financially literate people that I discuss these matters with IRL aren't dismissive of the reddit mob or sympathetic to a hedge fund that would put itself in the position Melvin did. 

They acknowledge the important exposure this is giving to an unfair market where hedge fund managers can call in personal favors to manipulate their way out of a poor decision. Lots of speculation on which side the regulators will come down on and compounding results from that outcome, whether WSB will retain influence over a union of capital, etc etc etc

They also acknowledge that there is a ton of risk in GME and either got in early or are sitting on the sidelines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36115464424.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the financially literate people that I discuss these matters with IRL aren't dismissive of the reddit mob or sympathetic to a hedge fund that would put itself in the position Melvin did.

Yes. There are miles of grey area between "fuck hedge funds amirite?" and being completely sympathetic to over-leveraged traders.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
