<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281806005.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l75jud/cmv_while_the_gme_squeeze_is_a_powerful_display/">
    <title>CMV: While the GME squeeze is a powerful display of retail trader’s power, there is no endgame that doesn’t result in them losing massive amount of money.</title>
    <original_poster>ticklemytaint340</original_poster>
    <original_post>The GameStop squeeze carried out by r/wsb and others demonstrated the power of retail traders and seems like a fair punishment on market makers and hedge funds that have taken advantage of the stock market for ages, but there is no way that it will end well for them. Sure, a lot of stock brokers have lost millions on shorts because retail traders refuse to sell and are still buying, but they can afford to do so because they have enormous amounts of cash to rest on and because GME is clearly overvalued. GME’s market cap is several times its revenue, and the only reason it is that high is because of the artificial demand created by internet communities. At some point, sellers are going to fold and GME is going to collapse, and everybody that purchased it when it was overvalued is going to lose massive amounts of money, while Wall Street short sellers laugh their way to the bank.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36107466408.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>The endgame was tomorrow. The short sellers are required to cover their bets before 4PM. That meant paying Wall Street Bets users for their shares. The price might have jumped to $1000. But in the end, the hedge funds would have been saddled with $1000 stocks that are actually worth far less, and retail traders would have had cash.

The only problem now is that because Robinhood banned buyers of GME, but not sellers, the price tanked. That gave the hedge fund managers all day to cover their shorts at ultra-low prices. Tomorrow Robinhood will re-allow trading on the stocks, but there won't be any shorts left. No shorts means no short squeeze.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
