<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281806005.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l75jud/cmv_while_the_gme_squeeze_is_a_powerful_display/">
    <title>CMV: While the GME squeeze is a powerful display of retail trader’s power, there is no endgame that doesn’t result in them losing massive amount of money.</title>
    <original_poster>ticklemytaint340</original_poster>
    <original_post>The GameStop squeeze carried out by r/wsb and others demonstrated the power of retail traders and seems like a fair punishment on market makers and hedge funds that have taken advantage of the stock market for ages, but there is no way that it will end well for them. Sure, a lot of stock brokers have lost millions on shorts because retail traders refuse to sell and are still buying, but they can afford to do so because they have enormous amounts of cash to rest on and because GME is clearly overvalued. GME’s market cap is several times its revenue, and the only reason it is that high is because of the artificial demand created by internet communities. At some point, sellers are going to fold and GME is going to collapse, and everybody that purchased it when it was overvalued is going to lose massive amounts of money, while Wall Street short sellers laugh their way to the bank.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36106769700.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>I think the original endgame was to screw over the hedgefunds and force them to lose money on the shorts. I think the intent was always disruption with a chance of making some cash, and in that respect they are winning. From my understanding, as long as they hold the stocks long enough the short-sellers will have to buy them back at whatever price. The risk for WSB is only however much they put it, while the financial exposure for the short sellers is almost limitless. If your goal is to cause disruption for lulz, it's actually not a bad position. 

Of course, timing is important and anyone coming in later hoping the stock will keep rising have more risk, but still not as much as the short sellers. 

But now with the controversy surrounding Robinhood and Citadel, I think WSB just got potentially more bang for their buck, almost assuredly putting some of these companies in both financial and regulatory trouble. And now with politicians taking notice you even get potentially more wall street disruption.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
