<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162939321.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>I think the best argument against this (and other requirements for voting) is that once requirements of any sort are set in place to vote, it's easier to corrupt the process by changing the requirements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162941383.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>But we already have requirements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162942861.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>That's true.  I disagree with virtually all of them other than age and being a citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162944521.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>This seems a bit incongruous. Your argument against this is that requirements can be warped to make things unfair, but you support some requirements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162954948.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>It's a tough position to be in, because I agree that requirements can be warped to make things unfair.  However, certain restrictions are still necessary, and the key is to find the "perfect medium."

The age requirement is the trickier of the two, because when you have an age requirement, it can be moved and manipulated.  People have talked about increasing the voting age, and that's something I'm very uncomfortable with.  However, I also think that allowing 4-year-olds to vote is utterly ridiculous.

It's the same thing with citizenship.  I think it's obvious to most people that visiting Candians or Germans or Russians shouldn't be allowed to vote in American elections, however having citizenship as a requirement (and presumably some sort of proof of citizenship as a requirement) allows the vote be manipulated.  We see this in states passing voters ID laws that seem to be more designed to disenfranchise legal voters than to prevent voter fraud.

Even the simplest of requirements on voting can be manipulated to pervert the process, so I'm opposed to any requirements besides the bare-minimum to prevent obviously ineligible people from voting.

The situation we currently have with voter eligibility is maybe imperfect, but adding more requirements to voters only allows for the system to be even more corrupted.  That's why I'm opposed to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162964552.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>But calling any requirements bare minimum implies there is a good minimum. We use age and citizenry to essentially prove that someone is fit to vote and that they have the interests of society at heart; I'm proposing a simpler proof of the same thing. You could even abolish the age and citizenship requirements by imposing the federal service requirement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163049401.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>How is your requirement simpler?

Also, I'm not sure if I agree that "We use age and citizenry to essentially prove that someone is fit to vote and that they have the interests of society at heart."  I think age and citizenship are used to simply insure that a voter is indeed a member of society, not that they're in any way a "good" voter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163054295.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>My requirement is singular; service allows voting. Demanding a certain age and citizenship alone is more complex; it becomes more complex still if we forbid, say, imprisoned felons, as we do now. 

I think we agree on the purpose of age and citizenry; we just use different words for it. Ensuring that someone is a member of society seems, to me, to ensure a degree of fitness to vote; I'm simply suggesting that proving a degree of selflessness ensures a higher degree of fitness.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
