<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27163194682.0" user="PotentNative" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with both aspects of your premise: 

1. A democracy does not need selflessness to work. It's a system by which a society can mould itself to the aggregate view of its members. Every member of society should have a say in what the outcome should be, as it is something that directly affects them. Sometimes, selfish interests need to be weighed against each other. 

2. Military service is not an indication of selflessness any more than any other profession that serves society. I'm sure there are selfless individuals in service, just as there are selfless folks who are doctors, entrepreneurs, environmentalists, clerics, musicians etc. The society is best served by people choosing their jobs by their abilities and passions (market inefficiencies in the economy aside).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163484483.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>1. I agree. A democracy does not need selflessness to work. But such a democracy would, I think, work better. Under this system, everyone CAN have a say. You just need to prove that you have the interests of the society at heart.

2. As it currently stands, I agree. Because the service jobs we have are not set up to provide any such assurances. My postulation is that they could be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
