<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27163446310.0" user="rainwood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom.

Agree completely. 

&amp;gt; Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others.

Wat?

You started off on such the right foot and then like IMMEDIATELY veered off in an unrelated direction towards... military service?

Which is it? Do you believe democracy should be tempered with wisdom or do you believe democracy should be tempered with altruism? 

I can see a direct corollary to an educated populace making for a better democratic society.

I can equally see a direct corollary between a society "voted on" only by those who were deemed to "benefit" that society.

Let's pause for a second and consider a different society than Starship Troopers. We will call this one Space Sparta.

Now in Space Sparta, it was established centuries ago that the right to vote was granted only to citizens, and that citizenship was given only to those who served in the military. If you can't defend your home, what right do you have to determine what happens in it, right?

Now let's also say that in these modern times, the Space Spartans get together and realize "Hey. We're letting like... a lot crippled and disabled and 'worthless' people live today. You know what? I'd like to propose a law! If you can't defend your home, you shouldn't get to control what happens in it right? Well why should you get to just consume its resources and contribute nothing? I say we put to death everyone who is incapable of fighting for the glory of Space Sparta!!"

You, as it turns out, are crippled now. Largely because an IED exploded near your home when you were a child, before you were of age to serve in the Spartan Military.

This new law passes with almost unanimous support, because the only ones who can vote are not negatively impacted by the law.

Oh hey, look. You're cripple. You can't vote. You are now put to death.

Is this a "better society" in your view?

Now before you say no, stop and think /from the societies point of view/. The society is full of big strong individuals who can and do fight for it's safety and security. Among each other, things are great and the camaraderie is real and thorough.

And after the "Purge of the worthless" (which you were in, mind you, through no fault of your own), the country is actually... doing much better by really any metric. Less strain on the hospitals, less mouths to feed which means lower demand for foodstuffs, more medicine available for fewer people which means cheaper medicine.

Things are really great for Space Sparta. And all it took was a bit of kid-glove genocide. You know, for the good of society.

Just because you are willing to work out and help a society doesn't mean that society wants that help or values your effort. The number of illegal aliens in this country who make it better by working jobs that literally nobody else will do are still despised by the very people they benefit. 

I think it was Alabama instituted stupid harsh penalties for illegal aliens, and so most everyone of the migrant laborers left the state for safer pastures. And as a result, crops rotted in the fields, because even though the state is suffering from crippling unemployment, doing nothing is still more dignified than picking crops. Doesn't matter that society was worse off because of the law. Doesn't matter the people being targeted weren't working against society.

Hell, many of the people who voted FOR the law were former military servicemen. Simply because you served your country by fighting for it should not grant you any special powers over everyone else who lives there.

You have two choices here:

1) Your government needs to pay people who are randomly born in your country and decide they don't want to live there anymore to relocate.

2) You don't disenfranchise the population based on arbitrary criteria.

If you're not doing either of those things, I don't know how you can claim to be operating a democracy when people's opinions aren't being heard.

The reason children aren't allowed to vote is ignorance (you really do need an educated population for democracy to work!) alone.

The reason the voting age is 18 is because it's arbitrary. 

The reason some convicts don't get to vote is because America isn't a real democracy.

The reason some blacks currently can't vote is because America continues to be discriminatory with it's policies in an attempt to sway the way votes are counted and available. (For example, a recent redistrciting of Georgia made the pre-change value of a black vote worth about 2/5 the post-change value of a black vote. You may remember this as the famous 2/5ths compromise in the constitution, where our artful statesmen determined that black people are worth 2/5ths of a white person.)

You may be tempted to say "Well if education is important we should have a test!"

We've had those too, and they we're largely used as tools to specifically disenfranchise black voters (who were the only ones who really needed to take these tests at the time). And, as you might expect, they were specifically designed to make everyone fail. I mean look at this shit: http://boingboing.net/2013/09/23/take-the-impossible-lit.html

Today, you have to serve in the military to vote. Tomorrow, you need an IQ of at least 150 to vote. The next day, you need to be from a wealthy and influential family who owns land and therefore has a stake in the goings-on of the country.

When you are old enough to legally make decisions on your own, you should be old enough to vote. Basically when you are capable of being dependent on yourself, you should have a say in what happens to you. Everything else is a form of arbitrary discrimination where you are telling me what's good for me.

Which is fine and all, but that's not really a democracy as you're using the term. It's more of a parental state. (Not now children, the Army Adults are talking and don't have time for your opinion.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163486883.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't think such a society would be better, because it lacks its humanity. From the original post: "But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish." There are plenty of jobs that people of any sort can do to benefit to society or, more to the point, to prove their dedication to it.

I think comparing this system to our current immigration law is somewhat invalidated by the fact that you and I both (apparently) agree that our current immigration law is messed up, while we clearly disagree on the proposal here (which I feel that I may have explained poorly). The idea isn't to make some sort of super-race, which wouldn't work, because literally anyone can gain the right to vote; they just need to be willing to prove their dedication. No physical or mental requirement exists.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
