<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162988672.0" user="Russian_Surrender" delta="False">
    <text>Who's to say that military or other "public service" serves the country more than something else that you wouldn't included?  Would the country be better off if Bill Gates and Steve Jobs had spent 2 years in their early 20's in the military?  Or is the country better served by having them do what they actually did?  And is there any way that you could have possibly predicted the future at the time and known which would have benefited society more?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162991258.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying there's no other way to benefit society; I'm saying that this would prove a degree of selflessness. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163030042.0" user="paratactical" delta="False">
    <text>Why is selflessness a desireable trait for voters? Aren't there other factors that would be more relevant or easier to measure to determine the most desireable voters? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163033457.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Because it prevents, or at least discourages, people fro making selfish decisions. Ideally, it would mean that people would make decisions with the interests of society in mind. And I'd be more than happy to listen to any other factors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163039022.0" user="paratactical" delta="False">
    <text>But why is selfishness a bad trait for voters? If all voters are equally selfish and perfectly educated and vote for what is best for them, you end up with a candidate that is best for the most people. 

As far as other criteria, why not something as simple as who is the most informed about the political issues relevant to the election? How you make the determination of what criteria to use is based on what value you want your voters to have. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163045014.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>That all seems to require an equal degree of selfishness and education, which seems unlikely. 

The criteria you propose is certainly interesting, and potentially valid. I don't suppose you'd care to do a CMV about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163051582.0" user="paratactical" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you can prove selflessness to a degree of certainty that should be requisite for limiting something as important as voting. Education is something that can be measured and selfishness is natural. 

And it's not my view. I think the idea of restricting voting rights is abhorrently unAmerican and completely amoral. I'm just trying to point out that even if your overarching theme is a good one, your justifications and foundations are unstable and lacking. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163057070.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that selfishness is natural. That's what I'm proposing we try to overcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163059833.0" user="paratactical" delta="False">
    <text>Requiring service to vote is not selflessness; it doesn't "overcome" selfishness; it's just a way of exacting a price for selfishness. If the goal is to promote selflessness, this is probably the worst possible approach that could be taken. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163061600.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>At the risk of sounding amazingly sarcastic, I would really like to hear another method for ensuring a degree of selflessness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163078591.0" user="paratactical" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that you can't measure, ensure or prove selflessness if the proving of it reaps a reward. By there being something that *is gotten* by the actor, it cannot be selfless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163081222.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm simply arguing that the benefit to the actor is rather less than the cost. That seems to prove a degree of selflessness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163129508.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Almost anything that doesn't amazingly skew the voter demographics to "people that would have enrolled in the military anyway"? Seriously, mandatory military service is such a bad idea.

In fact, we could just ask people going into the booths if they wanted to improve society and anyone that responds "fuck society" (sarcastic or not) would have their vote nullified. I think this would work several orders of magnitude more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163125473.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Um, it doesn't mean that *at all*. Anyone can pretend to be selfless for 2 years. We already have a huge number of people enrolling in the military for completely selfish reasons, so that's a flawed idea to begin with.

Even assuming every member of the armed force did do it for selfless reasons, that in *no way* implies that they would continue to do selfless things afterwards.

Further, I'm not even convinced that restricting voters to "altruistic people" would even be all that beneficial. A majority of the time, what's good for one individual would be good for most individuals: voting selfishly is good for everyone... In fact, it's sort of the *purpose* of voting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163477271.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it's fair to compare the current military system to this proposal; our current system isn't designed in any way to prove a person's loyalty to or interest in the society. It's a job, plain and simple. And I disagree that voting selfishly is the point of voting; I can think of plenty of laws that are good for the individual or minority that are bad for the whole. Look at the largest organized voting body; the AARP. They've managed to keep medicare afloat, when we all agree it isn't sustainable. It's going to die, and the longed we wait the more pain it will cause. But they manage to keep it around, year after bloody year.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
