<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162952873.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't paying your taxes be a selfless act? And if not, if you do not take any selfless act for whatever reason and cannot vote, then are you exempt from all taxes? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162956971.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think of paying taxes as being selfless, because there is a punishment for not doing so. Giving a homeless person food would be selfless, but not if you're being forced; you're effectively being forced to pay taxes. So paying taxes, since it isn't selfless, wouldn't (under this system) allow you to vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162977966.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>If you enlist in order to vote, how is it selfless?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162980537.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Because the costs of the service would, in theory, outweigh the personal benefit you might derive from a selfish vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163035396.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>If the benefits do not outweigh the cost, what incentivizes paying the cost?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163039730.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>The ability to improve society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163066703.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Could I not improve society just from voting?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163071106.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely. And, ideally, you would do it from a provably (somewhat) selfless viewpoint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163184107.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>So if someone hasn't served their country for two or more years they do not deserve to vote?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163483771.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>The premise here is more that those who would choose to serve are more fit to vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163867524.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>So you are saying that someone who hasn't served does not deserve to vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163920291.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that voting should be a privilege, not a right, and that you should have to earn the privilege by proving that you are willing to put the welfare of others ahead of your own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163938822.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>1. I think the vast majority of people will think you are wrong solely because they think voting is a right, not a privilege. Think about it, why should people *not* have a say in how they are governed? 

2. Many many people put the welfare of others ahead of their own without doing some kind of national service, why should they have to do anything different just to have a say in how they are governed?

You seem to have this view that as a general rule Americans are petty, selfish, and prone to voting against the best interests of the country. I do not think this lines up well with reality and even if it did encouraging people to give a few years of service wouldn't fix this.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163545430.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't paying a cost in order to vote encourage *more* selfish voting rather than less?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163575907.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a cost so much in a monetary sense; it's a cost to oneself, a way of proving that you place the welfare of society ahead of personal welfare or gain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163597002.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and in general, I'd propose that having performed whatever tasks are necessary to benefit from an achievement encourage one to make it as self-beneficial a use a possible.  The lack of it being a monetary price doesn't change that such people will feel entitled to vote in rules that benefit themselves or detriment those who have not paid the price.

To bring it back to fiduciary terms, I counter-propose:

If you fall in to money unearned, you're more likely to use it selflessly - you have no sense of ownership over that money, so barring survival needs, you're more likely to lend it to friends, give it to family, etc.

Otoh, if you worked hard for that money, you're more likely to hoard it.  Giving it away is counterintuitive - you worked for your money, why should someone else not also do the same?  You perceive ownership as a reward for your hard work, and therefore are less likely to use it to benefit others without also benefiting yourself (i.e. if you loan out money, you're more likely to charge interest).

The general value you propose is that people should vote without a sense of personal stake in what they vote for.  You then require people to place a personal stake (risking their own lives through military service) in order to vote.

Selflessness comes from abundance - people don't give away things they need; they give away their excess.  If voters become more scarce, then voting becomes more and more necessary.  Adding a cost, whether monetary or not, increases the odds that the vote will be used selfishly, rather than selflessly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163599557.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like a rational person with a lot of self-interest would simply not volunteer for difficult, unpleasant duty for two years just to gain a single vote; no one changes policy with a single vote. Only rational people with at least some degree of social responsibility, or irrational people, would volunteer. Either way, we end up better off than we are now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163615673.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It seems like a rational person with a lot of self-interest would simply not volunteer for difficult, unpleasant duty for two years just to gain a single vote

I suspect this is an error in your assumptions.

In the system you propose, only those who serve can dictate the manner in which they are governed.  Therefore, military service is the means to self-governance.  A rational person with a lot of self-interest will want the right govern themselves, and therefore enlist.  Your system makes serving in the military an action of self-interest, rather than a selfless one.

At the same time, limiting the number of people who can vote increases the value of each individual vote (i.e. one vote out of four is more valuable than one vote out of a hundred), so serving becomes *more* rational under the system you propose than it might otherwise be.

Compounded, the truly selfless people that you are seeking - those that put the needs of the unit above their own needs of survival or prosperity, will generally end up sacrificing themselves to save their companions - they'll be the guy going "No, no, you run, I'll stay here and cover your retreat".  So the likelihood of selfless people surviving to the point of getting to vote is generally less than it is for people with greater self-interest.  Thus, the most likely soldiers to survive are the ones that can act fairly selfishly within the system to increase their odds of survival, and then will have an sense of entitlement to use the vote to benefit themselves.

Lastly, I don't know that increasing the power of an irrational vote improves society in any way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163617098.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I think we may have very different views of how things play out on battlefields, of just how many of these people would actually be in life-threatening situations, and of how well people who live and work together get to know each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163618772.0" user="jpariury" delta="False">
    <text>Well sure.  If we had identical views, I wouldn't be trying to change yours.  ;)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
