<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27163036802.0" user="soiltostone" delta="False">
    <text>It makes sense that people who opt into an organization must contribute something in order to have a say in the operations of that organization -- such as paying dues or providing labor. The problem with applying this logic to citizenship is that citizenship is not, practically speaking, something that most people opt into.

If a person is defaulted into group membership, is it right that they should have to pay dues to be a complete member of that group? Why should a person have to contribute in a material way just to have rights in a group they did not specifically ask to be a member of?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163040718.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that we do make people pay dues to be members of a society they default into; taxes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163045469.0" user="soiltostone" delta="False">
    <text>You only need to pay taxes if you participate in the economy. That participation is opt-in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163048950.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I would imagine that extremely few people are citizens and do not participate in the economy in any way. I would have a hard time naming even one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163078217.0" user="soiltostone" delta="False">
    <text>I should clarify: I meant working for income -- not merely making transactions, but I get your point if you are including sales tax. Sales tax is paid to the government by the seller though technically.

Disabled people can vote, but do not usually pay taxes. Same goes for people on welfare and unemployment. There are lots of people who do not earn money but still vote -- homemakers, students, etc...

Anyway, you are assuming that the way this is handled now is fair. Perhaps it is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163082516.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm absolutely including sales tax; income tax alone is hardly the only source of income to the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163146646.0" user="soiltostone" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but that is payed by the seller to the government for the right to conduct business. This is getting into the weeds though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
