<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162956043.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>You know starship troopers was a satire of a fascist society right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162957970.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Are you considering this a clarifying question?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162966894.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just wondering if you are aware of the background of the film and honestly think something  from a movie designed to portray fascism is a good idea.

Others have addressed more rigorous arguments.  

If you want more evidence that it's a bad idea just look at the film, they go to war and basically do genocide on the bugs.  We get no evidence that the asteroid was sent by the bugs other than the government run propaganda service, which doesn't portray any alternative views.  That's  not the kind of society I want to live in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162970198.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm more than aware of the background of the film, which I also didn't bring up. I specifically referenced the book, which is rather different. I don't really consider the behavior of insects in a sci-fi film good indicators of a political idea's value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162984219.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>Eh...have you read Henlein's other books?  Basically Ayn Rand in space.  He's super militaristic, and was super pro-Vietnam (that turned out really well).  

How long do you think it would be before the people that could vote would just pass a massive tax on the people that can't vote?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162985881.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine that the entire theory that the people who can vote have proven a degree of selflessness would preclude the tax, not to mention the part about "No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162997507.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters.

I'm saying how long do you think that would last if one group had all the political power?  In every case in history a disparity between political power has also meant a disparity in rights, freedom, economic status, etc.  How do you expect your society to be different from every other society in the history of humanity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162998967.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>So your question is how one society would differ from every other society in the history of humanity? Isn't that basically saying that all societies have something in common. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163003695.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly what I said - all societies have something in common in that power corrupts.  Democracy attempts to overcome this trend by diffusing power into the most people possible.  Your society would recreate a vast power differential, and therefore a vast possibility of corruption.   Therefore my question is why do you think this vast power differential would not be exploited?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163005710.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure how it would create a vast power differential. Literally anyone that wanted to vote would be able to earn the capacity to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163038282.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously some would be more able to than others.  For example, what about poor people who have to work to support their family and couldn't afford to take 2 years off.  Or disabled people.  Or people with children.  They would have no voice in your society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163039374.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>A paying job seems like a good way to support a family for two years. I can think of a dozen things off the top of my head that disabled people could do to serve society. Plenty of people with children serve the military even now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163063675.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>The military has to pay now because it's volunteer, if it wasn't they wouldn't have to pay so much.  Even now many military families live in poverty.  

Where are the taxes to pay all these millions of a people a decent wage coming from?  Likely the first act of your society would be pass a tax on the people who choose not to serve.  

Also I don't see how you have established that those who serve in the military somehow have more intelligent or better view of political issues than anyone else.  For example, the Iraq war was a terrible decision, but if received higher levels of support from veterans both before and during the invasion.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163070333.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically said in my very first post that "No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters." I would include such a tax under this. The money to pay these people would come from the same place as money to pay for 911 operators, firemen, and other public servants comes from now. Consider the benefits to society; consider what it would mean to have a massive workforce at the command of every municipal government to undertake even massive public works projects.

I never claimed that people who serve in the military are more intelligent or having superior political views; but if you want to bring up the war in Iraq, I would counter that plenty of veterans opposed the war, and plenty of civilians supported it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163090458.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I specifically said in my very first post that "No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters." I would include such a tax under this. 

I understand you said this.  But what if a new tax was proposed?  Who would stop it?  The people who would be taxed have no vote.  Your ideal is alright in theory, but in reality don't you think people would try and exploit it?  Look at the Jim Crow South - the whole time whites were claiming that everything was "separate but equal" but the reality was that it was completely unequal and blacks had no way to defend their rights because they had no vote.  

&amp;gt;I never claimed that people who serve in the military are more intelligent or having superior political views;

Why restrict the views of people who don't serve then?

&amp;gt;I would counter that plenty of veterans opposed the war, and plenty of civilians supported it.

Anecdotes aren't evidence; surveys indicate(d) significantly higher support overall among military veterans.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163095760.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>In reality, no. I think that if we make a degree of selflessness a prerequisite for voting, then I think we can preclude these people from taking advantage of those who cannot vote. Particularly since anyone could gain the ability to vote.


Because the point is to restrict voting to people who have proven a degree of selflessness.

I agree that anecdotes aren't evidence. Suggesting that the war in Iraq was bad seems anecdotal; that seems like a hard thing to boil down to a binary "good" or "bad".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163121453.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because the point is to restrict voting to people who have proven a degree of selflessness.

Do you have any evidence that military service = selflessness?  Because all the evidence I've seen indicates that veterans are guilty of the same human flaws as everyone else.  

All service to the government indicates is a belief in the methods, ideals, goals of that government.  It is very dangerous for a  democracy to eliminate from the electorate anyone who thinks critically or skeptically about that government.   
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163475546.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I don't imagine we should eliminate people who think critically. I myself have quite a few issues with the government. As it stands, no, I have no evidence that people who currently serve have a significantly higher degree of selflessness; of course, that's not what we try to achieve with them either. I'm not saying veterans are some kind of saints. I'm saying that a system that sets up a job where the alternatives are more attractive, where the only benefit is being able to vote, shows that the person willing to do the less lucrative, less pleasant job has a strong motivation to want to vote; I think that such a motivation has a better than average chance of being a positive one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163030751.0" user="BorinToReadIt" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't read his books. However...

&amp;gt;Basically Ayn Rand in space. He's super militaristic, and was super pro-Vietnam (that turned out really well).

I'm confused by this. If the second sentence is meant to clarify the first, than you have a misunderstanding of Ayn Rand's views of the military. From my understanding she was fundamentally against war and opposed the use of military force in all circumstances other than the immediate defense of one's country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163046963.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously it's not an exact comparison.  For one, he is a much, much better writer.  

He wrote some books that were super militaristic such as Starship Troopers.  However he wrote others that were highly libertarian in nature such as The Moon is a Harsh Mistress where the moon  has a revolution because the "takers" or whatever on the Earth are exploiting the moon.  

I've read like 4 or 5 of his books, and that was several years ago so I don't remember exactly.  Look at his wiki page for a better explanation of his views.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27164116909.0" user="ETERNAL_EDAMNATION" delta="False">
    <text>Someone really doesn't like ol' Ayn, huh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27164359195.0" user="Neoprime" delta="False">
    <text>Only in the movies.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
