<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162974218.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>Having the counrty's best interests at heart does not automatically make one a good voter. To be a good voter one must be well-informed, open to new ideas, and capable of thinking critically. Serving in the military proves you are none of these things. Going to college usually helps with all of them. 

Also I don't really think anyone votes for anything they think will be bad for the country. Conservatives vote conservative because they think that conservative policies are best for the country. Liberals vote liberal because they think that liberal policies are the best for the country. More people voted for Obama than Romney because more people thought that having Obama as president would be better for the country than having Romney as president.

So basically your idea here would "fix" a problem that I'm not convinced exists and wouldn't solve the bigger problem of uninformed or closed-minded voters who make decisions based only on biased information.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162979644.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that having the best interests of the country at heart does not necessarily make a good voter. But it will do somewhat better than we're doing now. 

I agree that people don't vote for things because they think they're bad for the country. I just think that some people vote for things that are at the best interests of themselves, or at least their own communities; look at senators that vote to support appropriation of tanks that army doesn't need or want, just because their constituents build them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162991900.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text> &amp;gt;I just think that some people vote for things that are at the best interests of themselves, or at least their own communities; look at senators that vote to support appropriation of tanks that army doesn't need or want, just because their constituents build them.


I fail to see how your rule would stop this kind of behavior. Even veterans want there to be jobs in their local communities both for other retired military personnel and for their friends and families who haven't served. I know a lot of veterans and many of them still vote for the guys who promise jobs. Veterans are great, and their service to their country is admirable, but at the same time they are not magically better than everyone else at making good decisions.

Looking specifically at the United States, such a rule would also have an interesting effect of taking away the ability to vote from a lot of demographics. Do you really think that preventing the most educated segment of society (most people with college educations don't join the military) from being a part of decisions is a wise choice? I certainly don't. What about pacifists? Does having a personal belief that violence is never the answer mean you should never be able to have a say in government? What about the physically disabled who cannot serve in the military? Why should paraplegics be disenfranchised?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162995713.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that veterans are magically better than other people, but I am proposing that they have proven a degree of selflessness. 

I'm not preventing any segment of society from voting; I can't think of any segment that is incapable of performing federal service. I can think of plenty of things for pacifists or the highly educated to do. Or the physically disabled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163022431.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not saying that veterans are magically better than other people, but I am proposing that they have proven a degree of selflessness. 

I don't make the assumption that most people are selfish to a degree that they would vote against the best interests of their country. Therefore proving some degree of selflessness doesn't strike me as something that is necessary before people should be able to vote. And soldiers can be just as selfish as anyone else. In theory all of them volunteered because they love their country, but what about the guys who really just wanted to be in the Army? If being a soldier was your dream job and you joined up, how does that make you any more selfless than the guy whose dream job is to be an engineer? Why should you be able to vote and him not be able to vote?

&amp;gt;I can think of plenty of things for pacifists or the highly educated to do. Or the physically disabled.

In the military? You can think of things that pacificists can do in the service of an organization whose primary function is the application of violence? I get that not everyone is on the frontlines shooting people but at the same time I don't think that people who abhor violence want to play a support role in it either. And sure you can think of things for the highly educated to do in service of their country but that would necessitate them giving up on years of time they could potentially spend working or doing research. You would be forcing educated people to either be able to vote **or** put their skills to use in a productive manner. I think this is silly.

I think your idea would disenfranchise more good voters than it would bad voters. I think that even if you make room for them with other kinds of service than the military you will still see college educated people serving proportionally much less than you would see non-degree holding people. I think you would also see the same effects with women.

I also think that as a general rule taking away the vote from a great proportion of society is *not* a good way to go about ensuring better elections.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163026575.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt a lot of guys really dream of being in the army. 

Yes, in the military. Or other public service jobs, like 911 operator (as referenced in the original post). As to the highly educated, you might look at the office of naval research, among other organizations. The military has plenty of research projects that would challenge even the most intelligent individual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163033081.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I doubt a lot of guys really dream of being in the army. 

I know a lot of people who did growing up, and many of them are currently serving. From my high school class of 88 there are five people who are currently serving in the military (two marines, three army), all of whom wanted to be soldiers since they were kids.

&amp;gt;The military has plenty of research projects that would challenge even the most intelligent individual.

But does the military want Archeologists? What about Biologists? What about people who are experts is Astrophysics or cancer research? Just because there are jobs for "smart people" doesn't mean there are jobs for everyone. Just because the military has research projects doesn't mean any old scientist would be in their element. Imagine someone who just got their PhD in Astrophysics was given the choice between accepting a research position aimed at trying to understand the universe and helping the Navy decide what the best kind of weapons to deploy in different situations. Sure, the second one isn't necessarily going to be easy, but at the same time it is **not** something they are passionate about, and I really don't think that it would be fair to make them choose between doing something that they love (which also expands the realm of human knowledge) and being able to have a say in what goes on in the country. It isn't about being challenged, it is about doing what you love.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163038211.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>5.7 percent of the population seems like a pretty good ratio; if they're all some kind of insane, selfish psychopaths, it still seems like they would have a hard time getting anything passed, even if they all worked together.

I'm sure that the military and various public service organizations can find things to do for people of any discipline, particularly if they have a massive repertoire of people of every discipline and the concurrent instruction to serve society in as many ways as they can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163102751.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>- Virtually everyone who is employed is already helping society in some way, shape, or form.

- In the example of my graduating class you would be restricting voting to the *least* educated 5.7% (everyone else went to college).

- If people start volunteering for service in order to vote, is it really selfless?

- I do not believe that people voting *not* in the best interest of the nation is a problem in the United States.

- I therefore do not believe there needs to be a solution to this problem.

- I don't see how taking votes away from large swaths of the population makes democracy work better.

- I do not think that veterans make better voters than other citizens.

- More generally, I do not think that a person needs to demonstrate selflessness in the form of giving several years of their life is necessary for a person to be a good voter.

- I do not think that giving several years of your life unselfishly guarantees you will be a good voter either.

- I *do* think that education is a much more pressing concern with regards to voters than selflessness, therefore if I were to pick a single factor and restrict voting in a similar manner I think restricting voting to college graduates makes a hell of a lot more sense then restricting voting the military or other service veterans.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163109354.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>1. I agree. The point is not to help society; that's a side effect. The point is to prove a degree of selflessness.

2. This implies that no one else would perform public service, and that people who join the military are fundamentally the least educated people in the country. Both of which I disagree with. 

3. Yes, because the costs outweigh the benefits.

4. I disagree.

5. See above.

6. This would not take away votes from anyone; anyone would be free to serve to gain the right to vote.

7. Neither do I, right now. But this is an irrelevant comparison, since a veteran now is not the same as someone who served under the proposed system.

8. I don't think it's necessary either, but I think it's an improvement on the current system.

9. I don't think it guarantees anything either. I simply think it provides a massive degree of assurance; nothing is perfect.

10. I agree that education is a pressing concern. Imagine a massive corps of people whose only function is to serve society; I'm sure a large contingent could be detailed to provide education. Sounds like a great job for all the highly educated people who would want to serve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163179988.0" user="rampazzo" delta="False">
    <text>1. I think your "prove a degree of selflessness" is completely unnecessary.

2. My point was not that nobody else would perform public service, but rather than nobody else does right now. Any different group of people who would serve in the future would be doing so *in order to vote* and not in order to selflessly give themselves to their nation.

3. No, because for their service they are gaining the ability to govern themselves which I do not believe is insignificant. You seem to believe that voting is so important it should only be done by those who have proven themselves worthy, but at the same time it is so worthless that nobody would serve just to vote. I am failing to understand how you can hold both positions.

4. Do you have any evidence that people are voting for things they don't think are for the good of the country? I know super conservatives and super liberals and people everywhere in between and the one thing all of them have in common is that they want what is best for America. People who don't want to act in the best interests of the country do not vote.

5. n/a

6. This would take away votes from literally everyone who has not served who can currently vote. There would be people who can vote now who would not be able to vote in your hypothetical government. That is called taking away votes.

7. What happens the first year such a system is put into place? Everyone who is not a veteran or in the military is disenfranchised. For everyone who isn't a young adult and who doesn't yet have a vote they will in all likelihood never be able to vote again.

8. I disagree that it would be an improvement because it would disenfranchise millions of voters for very little gain.

9. A massive degree of assurance of what? That voters were possibly selfless at one point in their life? That's not good enough.

10. We already have a large contingent of society detailed to provide education: teachers. My problem with the idea of drafting a massive corps of people whose only function is to serve society is that most people go about serving society their entire lives. Firefighters, mailmen, police officers, politicians, nonprofit workers, factory workers, farmers, mechanics, plumbers, bank tellers, scientists, doctors, and more all serve society 5 days a week for decades of their lives while also living their own lives and making families and settling down. Why must two years of this service be done while giving up everything else if they are just going to be doing the same kinds of things in order for them to vote?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163483438.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>1. Okay.

2. But the fact that they're willing to undergo this sort of thing to gain the right to vote suggests, to me, that they have a strong interest in making society better.

3. I agree. Voting is very valuable. But someone who does not regard it as such, or who regards it as being valuable only as it affects them, would not take a job like this when better and easier jobs are available in the private sector.

4. I don't think it's possible to prove what's going on between someone's ears.

5. N/A.

6. Yes, it is called taking away votes. To be clear, I'm not proposing instituting this tomorrow; like any large change, it would have to be done in stages.

7. Please see #6.

8. Again, I'm not for excluding anyone that wants to serve to vote. As to the gain, I simply think that someone willing to give of themselves for two years shows that they have strong interest in voting well. I doubt they would stop at their interest there. They would probably be a well-informed, well-motivated voting body.

9. "Good enough" seems rather arbitrary. To me, our current system isn't "Good enough".

10. A lot of those jobs sound like perfect qualifiers. I know that every firefighter I know cares very deeply about their community; there's no other reason they would take that crappy paycheck for the hard of a job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163150303.0" user="Gilanguar" delta="False">
    <text>Just want to interject into this conversation. I think you've got a personal view that being in service is a selfless act and is the epitome of the kind of role a human can play for his country. But I don't understand why, it's no different than any other job in the public sector. Sure you might get blown up or shot but that is known before you sign up. Why is it any different than becoming a school teacher who also can be shot or killed in their job. 

The only difference I know of is military life you adhere to a cult like obedience to a command structure and often the work requires going abroad. If anything I would say long times of being away from their home country and hence having less contact with the political landscape of the time should prevent active service men and women to vote? Obviously this is ridiculous but it's just as logical a conclusion as you have derived. 

I think you need to find answers to 2 fundamental questions before going down the line of thinking you are now: 

Is being selfish actually bad in the context of choosing how the government should facilitate it's people.

Is any type of job objectively more selfless than any other, besides just exploring your own feelings for the military.  

Just as an addendum I respect the military as much as any other job but I believe if globally humans decided to stop joining up with national, religious and private groups for the sole purpose of perpetuating conflict the world would be a better place. A dictator is just an angry man shouting if he has no armed forces to support him. The effort put into developing tools to kill each other could be directed into much more worthwhile goals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163481086.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I think you may be confusing my attitude towards service now with the proposed system. I don't think service now is much different than a private sector job. 

To your two questions, yes. I think it's self-evident that a selfish voter is a worse voter than a selfless voter. And yes, I think that a job can be made to give a strong indicator of a degree of selflessness. Suppose you could get a job flipping burgers, or a job working at a city soup kitchen. The burger job is 9 to 5, pays 8 bucks an hour, etc. The soup kitchen job is twelve hours per day, you get room and board, and you have to obey orders and wear a uniform for two years. What's the advantage to the soup kitchen? Only the right to vote at the end. Sure, some people will go through it for other reasons. But I think that only someone with a good degree of interest in making a better society will make up the bulk of those that make it through.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
