<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="128623708.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24kuos/cmv_i_believe_that_to_vote_people_should_prove_a/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that, to vote, people should prove a degree of selflessness (shamelessly stolen from starship troopers)</title>
    <original_poster>incruente</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that democracy is the worst system of government we have...except all the others (another shameless theft of a quote). But, like all things, democracy should be tempered with wisdom. There are already requirements to vote; being an adult, being a citizen, not being a felon (in some cases). I think that, in order to vote, you should have to prove that you have the interests of society at least partly in mind. In the book starship troopers (which is on the recommended reading list for the navy....weird much?), you have to serve society in a real, tangible way in order to vote. In the book, it's referred to as "federal service". In real life, I think the Swiss have it (mostly) figured out: mandatory military service (but for men only, which is why I said "mostly"). But for those unwilling or unable to perform military service, perhaps other public service for, say, two years; work as a 911 operator, or even for public works. But have a job assigned to you and serve the people, to prove you're not totally selfish.

Thus, the voting body is made up of people who are provable capable of giving of themselves for others. No other rights or privileges would separate the voters from the nonvoters. 

As an added bonus, if we did mandatory military service, we could have an unbelievable state of military readiness in this country. Imagine if even 50 percent of all our people were armed and had combat training. The military would be massive, but could serve a lot of functions; municipal construction, disaster response, even things as mundane as sorting recycling. Believe me, the military already does a lot of mundane stuff. Imagine a country where everyone that chose to serve would be trained and equipped to serve their country, and every person that voted would have proven that they had the best interests of society at heart.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27162956078.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that this is a massive waste of human potential for almost no gain.

We *really* don't need every 18 year old to spend 2 years of their life in the military. Our military is already far, far, more powerful than it need be for any legitimate purpose. 

There's a reason that humans specialize, and that's because it's efficient. 

By making national service mandatory, you're proposing that we destroy 2 / (65 - 22) = 4.6% of the total productivity of the country's post-college population by having it dedicated to tasks that the vast majority of these people are not particularly suited to perform. 

For such a large investment of the national productivity, you would hope that we would gain some kind of advantage for this, but instead, we'd end up with *exactly* the same populace that is now eligible to vote being eligible to vote.

If you make it optional, you get an even *worse* result: only the people who have enough of an ideological reason to waste 2 years of their lives get to decide how everyone else lives. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162962891.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it would destroy productivity; I already mentioned that the military could be turned to a great deal more than they already are. Imagine a workforce of hundreds of young men and women in every community ready to tackle any large task it needs done.

And you wouldn't end up with the same populace eligible to vote; I may have been unclear. While I applaud the mandatory service of the Swiss, I was bringing it up primarily as an example of the benefits of a large body of military members. Under the system being proposed here, public service would be voluntary; the benefit for volunteering and serving would be the right to vote. I don't know how you could call this a waste of two years without calling every military and public service job a waste.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162982238.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Then you still end up with voting being restricted to people that care about voting enough to expend 2 years of their life gaining the right to do it. 

If you do this, you're going to have a bad time. You will end up with only people that either a) have nothing better to do with their time or b) have a large ideological reason to justify the expense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27162984391.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm still not sure why you consider this "nothing better to do with their time". Can you really name anyone that has done better things with their entire lives than the things we could task people with for two years?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163000300.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Either someone has a large reason why they want to spend 2 years of their time gaining the right to vote (in which case, I sincerely distrust their ability to fairly govern others), or they are doing it because they don't have any pressing reason to do anything else... like, for example, having a job, or an avocation, or any kind of motivation to succeed in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163003541.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Why would you distrust a person's ability to fairly govern others if they were willing to suffer through a job you clearly disdain in order to prove their worth to vote?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163007291.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Because I distrust their motives for taking such an insane action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163009524.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Then why do you trust any of the motives people have for voting now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163024333.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Because they don't have to overcome a giant hurdle in order to vote. 

I think it's a natural question to ask: "Why have you invested 2 years in your life in order to have the right to tell other people how to live?". I don't expect to like the answer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163031407.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine the answer would vary. Mine would be along the lines of "Because I wanted to earn the right to try to improve the country".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163043700.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>"And what, pray tell, do you mean by 'improve'? And why are you spending so much of your life to improve it? Is it really that broken? What do you think is broken about it?"

Honestly, do you not worry at all that people who will give up 2 years of their life to vote, in cases when they have something more productive to do with their time, have motives that might not be completely noble from the perspective of everyone else?

How many people would do this just out of some kind of noble impulse? Damn few. 

What you're actually going to get is skinheads, religious fanatics, and other people out to "save the world" from their limited perspective of what is wrong with it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163048075.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I would mean improve, as in make it as much better as possible for the most people. I don't think wanting to improve society bears explanation; it is its own end. I think many things about society are broken; our treatment of prisoners, our financial system, our attitudes towards the homeless.

Again, I don't think that, properly done, this is less productive than anything else people might do. And if people want to balance out "skinheads" and others they disagree with, it's as simple to counteract as it is now; vote against what they think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163057528.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>No, with your proposal it's *not* as simple as it is now; it's "work your ass off for 2 years doing something you probably don't want to be doing and then vote against them". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163058343.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>"Simple" and "easy" aren't the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163105270.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Regardless, your proposal massively skews the voting population towards the disaffected, especially the massively disaffected (given the degree of service you're proposing).

I claim that doing this will result in very chaotic and ultimately very poor outcomes of the political process.

Another point is that this is ultimately equivalent to a massive poll tax (of a magnitude equal to the value that the person could have generated in the same time).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163111197.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>A poll tax favors the rich or those with otherwise disposable income; this favors no socioeconomic class. If anything, it seems to benefit the poor; if they could make more money serving, it's more of an incentive to them than a rich man who could make more money not serving and surrendering his vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163502257.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it does! if your parents are rich, you can afford to go do 2 years of service because you don't have to worry about money or anything. Not to mention your rich powerful parents will get you a cushy job in the military.  If you have a single mother that needs money to feed your younger siblings and house them then you'll have to take a more lucrative job. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163504307.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm wondering about this society where the rich parents control what job their kid gets in the military but the more lucrative jobs are open to people whose single mothers are desperate for money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163505854.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>what are you talking about? You're the one who made the scenario where you would be paid better to do any other job than the military service required to vote, otherwise it's not really a sacrifice right? That means that the poor kid would make more money doing any other job and come out ahead for his family.

do you seriously not think that rich, powerful people get their kids in cushy jobs in the military in order to pad their political resume</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163507516.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I absolutely think that rich, powerful people manipulate the system. That seems like a problem with our system now. So I don't really see it as a valid objection to the proposed system; it's a problem either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163508972.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>It's a problem because you said that class wouldn't matter in your system and it obviously does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163511189.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Class wouldn't be a relevant factor in getting a vote; anybody of any class could earn the right to vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163511888.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>As I pointed out, no. The poor would have to work real jobs and the rich could sit idly by in a cushy job in the military with no money concerns.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163513669.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>These seem like valid concerns, but not crippling ones. Nothing that can't be compensated for. Simply disallow external funding while serving (you already can't have cash or external assistance in boot camp), and make sure the wage is sufficient to qualify as, in your view, a "real job".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163514339.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>If it's a real job that anyone is guaranteed to get then it's not a sacrifice. You can't have it both ways, either you have to sacrifice something to be allowed to vote or you make it good enough where everyone does it and we're in the same place we are now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163515155.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I think you and I may just have different approaches to a "real job".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163516038.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>We're talking about income here. Set the pay for military service too low and it disenfranchises the poor. Set it too high, and it's not a sacrifice so your system is useless. I don't believe that there's a middle point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163516545.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand that position, although I respectfully disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163519682.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>So what is the middle point then? how do you scale it for every different region of the country? Your view is super idealistic and wishy washy. Give some concrete examples. How much is the salary? If every single 18 year old decides to do it can the program handle it? Can everyone stay longer than the 2 years if they want? How are you going to pay for it? Who's going to pay for these community projects? (it's not like towns don't want cool things like parks, they just can't afford them) how is it implemented? what if I'm 19 the year this gets put into place, do I have to do military service for 1 year to keep my right to vote? What about everyone older than that? I'm almost 30 do I get to vote? I didn't do any military service.

Basically anyone can say anything but if you don't have the mechanisms in place then your plan just falls apart.

I can say something like: "Ok, in my system, everyone is fed and housed and has access to any medical procedure they need. People only have to work 3 days a week and the rest of their time pursuing individual pursuits. Education at every level is free and discussions are encouraged at every level of society. We don't need any military because everyone is so happy that our system spread to the entire world any now everyone is one big community, we get projects done "

but without any real plan on how to do it, it's just bullshit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163522547.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>If you're asking for concrete examples of a system that has never been implemented, I can't help you. The system should be designed so that it can handle every 18 year old; after all, we have schools that can handle an entire populace, so a system can be designed to handle everyone. The salary, as you point out, should probably vary, depending upon such things as the region of the country. I don't see why we should stop people from serving longer if they choose. We'll pay for it the same way we currently pay for any municipal job, primarily through tax revenue. Ideally, the bulk of these jobs will generate a good deal of value; soup kitchen labor, city maintenance labor, firefighters, etc. I'm not sure how the 19 year old thing is a question; I've never said the two years have to start at 18. If you start at 19, you go for two years. And I've also said that, like any large change, this would have to be done in stages.

The system you describe sounds wonderful. Less the absence of the military, it sounds rather like Walden two, which I understand is currently being implemented at the Los Horcones intentional community. They've made it work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163526639.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>Ideologically I agree with everything you say. It would be fantastic to have a better sense of community and volunteerism. Intentional communities (that are run well) seem like utopias to me. If we could learn to just share a bit more and be less selfish the world would be a much better place.

 I just don't see how forced military service is the best way to achieve that. You'd have to tax people upwards of 50-60% to enact the system you're proposing. With all that money we could have universal health care, free university education, a minimum income so people could work less and devote time to other pursuits (sure some people will be selfish in their endeavours but others won't be). The way to a better society is through a higher standard of care for everyone. If everyone is housed, healthy, fed, and has the option to be college educated then you'll start to see the changes you want. I'd also add that wealth inequality is a pretty big problem but that's not the discussion here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163528507.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I think that a lot of our ideas could overlap. This volunteer corps could provide health care, education, all sorts of things that we all agree that we all want but are constantly bickering about how to pay for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163531509.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I don't see why we should implement something with the potential to disenfranchise certain people when a more direct route would  eliminate that risk and probably be way cheaper. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163111515.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Imagine a workforce of hundreds of young men and women in every community ready to tackle any large task it needs done.

Just a question: who feeds and houses all these people for two years? You seem to be saying "well, let's just expand military to other things". What things? How many things? If the government could fund this then we wouldn't have so much shit wrong that we have currently.

Otherwise, this sort of sounds like a **job**. You're basically saying people should work for two years in certain positions to earn the right to vote. What qualifies a task as "selfless"?

Can't I just take a personality test to show that I'm not a sociopath?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163474409.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>The military would feed and house them, as it does its people now. I couldn't name how many things we could expand them to. As to which things? Sorting single stream waste recycling. Providing earthquake, tornado, and other disaster response. Municipal construction (parks anyone?). Reclaiming abandoned structures. Maybe running errands for the disabled. Meals on wheels. Working in soup kitchens. I'm sure we could both think of more.

Yes, this would very much be a job. But the idea is that this job would be difficult enough compared with its wage that the alternative in the private sector would be rather more lucrative; thus, the cost to the individual would outweigh the benefit. 

I don't think we even have a particularly accurate test for sociopathy. And even if we did, not being a sociopath is not the same as not being deeply self-involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163285680.0" user="HilariousEconomist" delta="False">
    <text>You might get marginal gains from having 18 year olds do depression era construction work but compared to 2 years of school or private sector work + the money and time required to train these people I think it would be economically damaging. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163484881.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure why having 18 year olds do public works is "depression era". Do you think all construction work is depression era, or just when teenagers do it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163727287.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>I assumed he meant work for the sake of work. Sending people off to do jobs that aren't really very important just so they can get a paycheck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163751825.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't want these people to do useless work; aside from being a massive waste of manpower, I think people appreciate their work when it has meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27164221058.0" user="HilariousEconomist" delta="False">
    <text>I mean now days teens have much more productive things to do than maintain parks and dig ditches</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163572466.0" user="mariesoleil" delta="False">
    <text>If it's work that's currently done by paid employees, that will destroy all those jobs. Why would you keep city staff if you can just apply to use a pool of free labour?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163575021.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>The labor wouldn't be free; these people still need to get paid to do their jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163578357.0" user="mariesoleil" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think places with military/civil service pay. Now you're also suggesting that they all get paid? Market rate + room and board?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163585063.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Market rate plus room and board would be more than they would get at a private sector job doing the same thing; that would completely void this as proof of any degree of selflessness. The job needs to be difficult, demanding, and less financially rewarding than an equivalent private sector job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163587762.0" user="mariesoleil" delta="False">
    <text>So it would indeed be a cheaper pool of labour that would destroy the current labour market?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163589405.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>The cost to, say, the city is not made up solely of the price of labor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163591823.0" user="mariesoleil" delta="False">
    <text>Currently the city has city workers to drive street sweepers and snowplows. Why would they continue the employment of those city workers when civil service youth are available? Why would that not save the city money?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163594751.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>Suppose the volunteer corps charged the same fee as city employment; the city would then have no financial incentive to go either way. But even if it chose to keep its own employees, the volunteer corps could be used for other functions. I know a lot of cities have problems finding ways to sort recycling. Some cities have had a lot of luck with manual trash removal from streets. Or consider construction (a shocking number of the bridges in our country are sorely in need of repair), disaster response, or community service. Can you honestly not think of anything constructive for a large contingent of mostly young, able-bodied people to do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163597946.0" user="mariesoleil" delta="False">
    <text>I can think of many many constructive things to do, and I agree that those are all important things that need to be done. My point is that currently, those jobs are done by members of the general labour force. If those jobs will now be done by someone else, those jobs disappear. For example, most cities contract out recycling sorting. That recycling centre is going to lose their contracts and have to fire people if the cities can force 19 year olds to do the work. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163600525.0" user="incruente" delta="False">
    <text>I can think of plenty of constructive things to do that, right now, aren't being done at all. I've lived in several cities that don't contract out recycling, because it's too expensive; they just haul everything to the dump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163381586.0" user="amaxen" delta="False">
    <text>True, there would be an economic loss.  The question is, would 2% lost productivity be worth it if you had better/more responsible governance?  I can see scenarios where the answer might be 'yes'. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27163792147.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>If it could do that, then perhaps. However, unless you make it mandatory, only people with agendas will do it, and I would claim that's inevitably going to lead to far, far, far, worse and less responsible governance (and far riskier, because if it does happen that some very bad agenda takes hold, it's not easy for less motivated voters to simply go to the polls to outvote the extremists). 

And if you do make it mandatory, you have the same voter base that we have now... no gain (in that respect).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27164434122.0" user="amaxen" delta="False">
    <text>Bad agendas are not unique to limited franchises.  There are many examples of bad agendas in democracies. 

The question is whether the system of government has better agendas, more often, than what currently rules. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
