<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1287751445.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/laozdh/cmv_american_right_wingers_should_support/">
    <title>CMV: American right wingers should support Russia/China/Iran against their own country.</title>
    <original_poster>Ion_12</original_poster>
    <original_post>I should start off by saying, I don’t really lump libertarians or NeoConservatives into the “right wing”.

When it comes to social “degeneracy” (LGBT rights, interracial relationship legality, feminism, etc), America is light years ahead of the rest of the world. Even America’s “right” party voted in support of these things. But, in countries like Russia, China, and Iran, these things are either illegal, or heavily frowned upon. 

The way America is set up, it is essentially impossible to turn the country into a right wing authoritarian state. If one wants something like that, they should support the other world powers to weaken America on the world stage, or support them to overthrow the American government, and promise full support if those countries are willing to put them in power.

It makes no sense for American “nationalists” to support their country at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36140858238.0" user="Icelandic2211" delta="False">
    <text>" Even America’s “right” party voted in support of these things. "

You have no clue about reality.  Trump supported gay marriage in the 1990's long before Obama or either Clinton or Biden.  The first time Obama/biden were elected they were anti gay marriage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36142210840.0" user="Life_in_progress1" delta="False">
    <text>More republicans are anti-gay than democrats, and that’s been a trend for decades. Don’t know Why you’re trying to list specific politicians when people are talking about political parties

Downvote all you want, the facts are facts and easily assessable on the internet. Cherry-picking your favorite politician doesn’t prove anything about the general party</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36146779271.0" user="Icelandic2211" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; More republicans are anti-gay than democrats

I am not a republican and that has not been my experience.  republicans tend to say individuals should make decisions in their own lives.  Democrats are the ones that generrally say government should make your decisions for you.  Read up on slavery if you want a classic example of how the democrats think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36143671035.0" user="Mr_Manfredjensenjen" delta="False">
    <text>Trump was a Democrat in the 90s, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36146724433.0" user="Icelandic2211" delta="False">
    <text>Trump was a New York businessman in the 90's.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
