<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1287751445.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/laozdh/cmv_american_right_wingers_should_support/">
    <title>CMV: American right wingers should support Russia/China/Iran against their own country.</title>
    <original_poster>Ion_12</original_poster>
    <original_post>I should start off by saying, I don’t really lump libertarians or NeoConservatives into the “right wing”.

When it comes to social “degeneracy” (LGBT rights, interracial relationship legality, feminism, etc), America is light years ahead of the rest of the world. Even America’s “right” party voted in support of these things. But, in countries like Russia, China, and Iran, these things are either illegal, or heavily frowned upon. 

The way America is set up, it is essentially impossible to turn the country into a right wing authoritarian state. If one wants something like that, they should support the other world powers to weaken America on the world stage, or support them to overthrow the American government, and promise full support if those countries are willing to put them in power.

It makes no sense for American “nationalists” to support their country at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36143718657.0" user="Mr_Manfredjensenjen" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not realize America's RIGHT strongly opposed interracial and gay marriage and that they did NOT vote to legalize either? 

FYI: The United States Supreme Court ruled that gay marriage bans infringe equal dignity -- that ruling legalized gay marriage -- and the Supreme Court ruled in Loving v Virginia that miscegenation laws are unconstitutional which legalized interracial marriages. THE RIGHT OPPOSED THE COURT CASES EVERY STEP OF THE WAY. In fact, the Right would criminalize these marriages if they could. 

WHY DID YOU WRITE: "Even America’s “right” party voted in support of these things" when it is not true--the Courts did it against the Right's wishes?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
