<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1287751445.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/laozdh/cmv_american_right_wingers_should_support/">
    <title>CMV: American right wingers should support Russia/China/Iran against their own country.</title>
    <original_poster>Ion_12</original_poster>
    <original_post>I should start off by saying, I don’t really lump libertarians or NeoConservatives into the “right wing”.

When it comes to social “degeneracy” (LGBT rights, interracial relationship legality, feminism, etc), America is light years ahead of the rest of the world. Even America’s “right” party voted in support of these things. But, in countries like Russia, China, and Iran, these things are either illegal, or heavily frowned upon. 

The way America is set up, it is essentially impossible to turn the country into a right wing authoritarian state. If one wants something like that, they should support the other world powers to weaken America on the world stage, or support them to overthrow the American government, and promise full support if those countries are willing to put them in power.

It makes no sense for American “nationalists” to support their country at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36140944765.0" user="TheJuiceIsBlack" delta="False">
    <text>You are straw manning conservatives.  

According the Oxford English Dictionary - conservative means:  

&amp;gt;	(in a political context) favoring free enterprise, private ownership, and socially traditional ideas.

Ignoring the fact that you some how dismiss the importance of the free enterprise and private ownership aspects of conservatism - traditional social ideas in the United States are totally distinct from traditional ideas in these other places.  

Comparing the position of US conservatives (who at *most* oppose state sanctioned gay marriage) to the position of Iran (being openly homosexual can mean government sanctioned execution) is patently ridiculous.  

Additionally - comparing the stance of conservatives in the US on women (which is at *most* opposing abortion and third-wave feminism) to the stance of Iran on women (hijab is required in public and women are denied basic equality under the law) is similarly absurd.  

Being a conservative just means that you have less faith in the government to effect things like social change without trampling on individual rights.  

&amp;gt;	social “degeneracy” (LGBT rights, interracial relationship legality, feminism, etc)

I don’t know of any conservatives who oppose traditional feminism (i.e. equality for women) or interracial relationships. My wife and I are both conservative - she is from India and I’m from the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36140947416.0" user="Ion_12" delta="False">
    <text>I mean far right, apologies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36140950670.0" user="TheJuiceIsBlack" delta="False">
    <text>Define far right?

Edit:  To be concrete - what percentage of Americans do you think fall into the category you’re describing?  

I have a strong suspicion that the ones that hold the views you are professing or either vanishingly small or non-existent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36168138101.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Comparing the position of US conservatives (who at most oppose state sanctioned gay marriage) to the position of Iran (being openly homosexual can mean government sanctioned execution) is patently ridiculous.

#

&amp;gt; Additionally - comparing the stance of conservatives in the US on women (which is at most opposing abortion and third-wave feminism) to the stance of Iran on women (hijab is required in public and women are denied basic equality under the law) is similarly absurd.

That's his point though. If current US Republicans/neoconservatives are very lenient on feminism, LGBT, and racemixing while Russia/China/Iran are more strict, why would an actual conservative support the status quo GOP?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36172099679.0" user="TheJuiceIsBlack" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	why would an **actual conservative** support the status quo GOP?

You’re committing the no true Scotsman or appeal to purity logical fallacy.  

US conservatives and Iranian conservatives (for example) on average hold very different beliefs.  That’s because a “conservative” or “progressive” policy position is always relative to the societal context under discussion. There is no measure by which an Iranian conservative is closer to some ideal definition of conservatism than an American conservative.  

Indeed many “progressives” in Iran may still hold theocratic beliefs that would be abhorrent to American conservatives.  

Does this make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
