<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168817396.0" user="Rogueasaurus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

To me, you just made the case against yourself.  While I concede that losing any unique person and their potential insights is a loss to science and humanity, that must be weighed against the cost of human suffering.  Your own argument here is suggesting that women who "simply did not care that new life was created within her" should be a mother.  That sounds like a terrible environment in which to bring a child.  

I know that the logical next step is that the child will be adopted by parents who do want it and all will be fine.  Except that for 9 months, when almost all of that child's development is going on, they are under the sole protection of a woman who doesn't care about them.  She may not make regular visits to her OB, she may not make healthy diet and lifestyle choices which could influence the baby's development

In what you posted, it *sounds* like you want to punish the woman for having unprotected sex. What's more important, punishing the woman or protecting of the child?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
