<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168256818.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and will eventually become a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I've never understood the "will eventually become a unique person" argument because, no - it won't become a unique person if it is aborted. Conception is the *first step* towards birthing a person but it sure isn't the last. It isn't like you could remove a sperm and egg from the mother and nine months later get a child.

&amp;gt; I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception.

Regardless of the choices she made leading up to the pregnancy, she still has the choice over her body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168280793.0" user="tokewithnick" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; she still has the choice over her body.

This is the strongest argument against OP's view. I would even go as far as considering a woman's uterus as a "zone" (for a lack of a better word) where only the mother has any saying over the unborn fetus' rights. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168313140.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>Ok let me change that, it IS a unique person with a unique set of traits.

Regardless of the choices she made leading up to the pregnancy, she still has the choice over her body.

Wasn't the choice over her body the choice to have sex and risk being pregnant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168314479.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Ok let me change that, it IS a unique person with a unique set of traits.

One person's right to life does not trump another person's right to their own body.

&amp;gt; Wasn't the choice over her body the choice to have sex and risk being pregnant?

Nope, the choice over her body is to allow another person to use her body to grow within it. She is not making *this choice* when having sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168323212.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>With your logic, when someone gets in a car drunk and kills someone in an accident, was it their choice? they certainly risked having it happen but didn't care about the consequences. They choose to do it, despite the risks, which is just as bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168325999.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; With your logic, when someone gets in a car drunk and kills someone in an accident, was it their choice? they certainly risked having it happen but didn't care about the consequences. They choose to do it, despite the risks, which is just as bad.

And by your logic, if anyone that person harmed needs the driver's organs or blood - the government should force it upon them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168328948.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>Please explain how that is my logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168342420.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>person A gets drunk/has sex

as a result person B is injured/is created

Your logic: person A should give organs,blood/ carry person B

By getting drunk/having sex person A has accepted consequences of injury/creation. Has person A accepted giving up their body for person B? 

Why in one situation and not the other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168350049.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>That is the most screwed up logic of yours, these two situations can't even be compared due to different consequences. The consequences of the drunk situation don't even exist while the ones of the pregnancy ones do exist today</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168351366.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; that consequences of the drunk situation don't even exist

Are you saying that drunk driving doesn't result in situations where people may require medical attention up to and including organ transplants or blood?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168359237.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying the consequences of governments forcing the criminal to give blood and organs doesnt exist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168360792.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>but do you think it should?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168367999.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, because *even criminals* have the right to their body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168521281.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's literally the point of the analogy.   The consequences don't exist because it's a bad policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168357778.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>Explain?

As far as I can see they're reasonably comparable (although not perfect)

In both cases person A has done something that effects person B

In both cases person A can either save person B (by donating organs/blood or carrying) or let person B die/not exist (by not donating or not carrying)

So if you think a woman should *have* to carry in that situation, do you not have to believe that people should *have* to donate blood/organs if they cause an accident? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168436522.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that the drunk driving victim can obtain blood/organs from any donor, however the person inside a pregnant mother only depends on the mother so has no social/health network to fall back on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168445545.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>like I said, not perfect. But it shows that in some cases we can cause things to happen to others and not forced to be responsible for the consequences to that person, so why is pregnancy different? 

Especially when you add the fact that most people don't view a fetus as a person at all.

It is making someone more responsible for cells than they are human beings they might injure. 

What if, on the side of the road with the paramedics, it turns out you have the persons blood type. The paramedics don't have enough with them. The person will die without blood. They are 100% reliant just on you? Should you *have* to donate your blood?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168453814.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But it shows that in some cases we can cause things to happen to others and not forced to be responsible for the consequences to that person, so why is pregnancy different?  

Because unlike your analogy, pregnancy isn't the result of an accident.  

But let's concede that for a minute.  
In an drunk run-over, the culprit can go to jail (violation of freedom) or at least pay fines and treatment (violation of property).  

So yes, in your analogy there is a precedent of your choices ending up with your rights being limited or punished.  Why is pregnancy different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168457780.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>rights is different to bodily autonomy. We don't make you give up your body for anything other than pregnancy. Why? 

And in the analogy the accident was caused by drunk driving: an irresponsible choice, equated to unprotected sex. Unprotected sex doesn't always lead to pregnancy, drunk driving doesn't always lead to a car crash. But those outcomes are not unexpected from those actions.

Like I said, it's not a perfect analogy because nothing is, pregnancy doesn't have an analogue. 

But why does this fact mean we're ok with massively invading a person's right to control what happens to their own body? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168467057.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We don't make you give up your body for anything other than pregnancy. Why?  

Because no other choice is life-giving?  You have to admit it's quite a unique situation.  

&amp;gt; We don't make you give up your body for anything other than pregnancy. Why?  
&amp;gt; pregnancy doesn't have an analogy  

You have the answer right there.  

&amp;gt; Unprotected sex doesn't always lead to pregnancy, drunk driving doesn't always lead to a car crash. But those outcomes are not unexpected from those actions.  

I see a difference.  Unprotected sex has a biological purpose which is procreation.  Protected sex is for fun.  
The purpose of drunk driving is the same as driving, it's to get form A to B.  

&amp;gt; why does this fact mean we're ok with massively invading a person's right to control what happens to their own body?  

Your choices and outcomes can lead to violation of your rights, from property (a fine) to your life (death sentence).  I find it reasonable.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168470294.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>Will you stop picking apart the analogy, I've said in every comment it's not supposed to be perfect.

Yes pregnancy is a unique situation. But why do we let a unique situation invade the bodily autonomy of a human being when it doesn't have to? 

I can't think of any other circumstances where we'd force something like that on an adult. An unwanted, unneccessary and long term invasion of someone's body? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168472326.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>I already answered that, should I repeat myself or is there a part that was confusing?  I am happy to clarify but not repeat.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168481515.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>you're answer was essentially 'because we should' or 'actions have consequences' when really having a baby doesn't have to be a consequence of getting pregnant.

that's not really an answer.

If a woman becomes pregnant. At that point no baby exists. It can't exist without her, it is not a person - it's a blob of cells. 

Why does this blob have more rights than the woman? The woman doesn't need the blob, the blob won't know or care if it goes away, there is a reasonable (1/4 ish) chance the blob will spontaneously abort anyway. So why is it right to force this woman to turn the blob into a human unnecessarily? We're not running out of humans or anything, it's needless and no one wants it. 

It seems like it's just creating misery for the sake of some perceived karmic justice: but it's not like sex is *wrong*

Wouldn't it be better to let that woman get an abortion and then only bring wanted children into the world? I know there are very few people alive now who think they'd be better off not born, but surely everyone would agree that it would be better for all children to at least be born wanted? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168498281.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; you're answer was essentially 'because we should' or 'actions have consequences'  

I think I was a bit more verbose than that, are you really trying to understand my responses or are you only repeating points until I agree with you?  

&amp;gt; when really having a baby doesn't have to be a consequence of getting pregnant  

It actually is.  

&amp;gt; If a woman becomes pregnant. At that point no baby exists. It can't exist without her, it is not a person - it's a blob of cells  

It's a matter of definitions.  
Regardless of what you consider the blob to be, it's a voluntarily initiated process that by default will end up in a human being.  

&amp;gt; It seems like it's just creating misery for the sake of some perceived karmic justice: but it's not like sex is wrong  

Watch it, don't bring in strawmen or I'll be implacable.  I have never judged sex as an act or talked about karma.  
If a person has all the tools to have sex that doesn't conduct to pregnancy then having sex without them is as an unnecessary risk as drunk driving.  

&amp;gt; surely everyone would agree that it would be better for all children to at least be born wanted?  

I am not taking this argument into consideration, I think they deserve a chance to want themselves.  As someone who has undergone fertility treatments and adoption processes (all unsuccessfully) I have been exposed to the network underlying what happens with unwanted children, and most *are* wanted.  

&amp;gt; Why does this blob have more rights than the woman?  

Not *more* rights, it's actually even less rights as they have no property, opinion and cannot go anywhere.  But you can't put some person's convenience over some future person's life.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168501647.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>i want to reply properly as this is interesting but its 1:30am here and i need to sleep, plus i'm probably not thinking/comprehending as well as i should be, being all sleepy and all </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168326699.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>When it comes to being drunk, there is a legal requirement for intent that doesn't exist when drunk, which is why many places have implemented vehicular homicide laws that remove the intent part from the actual homicide.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168465338.0" user="fayryover" delta="False">
    <text>Let's say person A drunk drives and casues person B to be injured. A is required to pay B's medical bill's and will probably have more financial obligations to B besides those. A will also go to jail for injuring or killing B. However if B needs a new kidney  and a blood transfusion due to the actions of A, A is not obligated to give B his kidney or give blood even though A could live without it and is the cause that B needs it. This is the same as woman A is not required to donate her bodily resources to fetus B even though it is partially her fault B needs those resources.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168433456.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; One person's right to life does not trump another person's right to their own body  

Why not?  Where do you get this from?  If someone holds you (like a bear grasp) you can't automatically kill them.  

&amp;gt; allow another person to use her body to grow within it. She is not making this choice when having sex.  

Any adult having unprotected sex is deciding to expose themselves to this.  Exceptions would be rape, a minor who in theory does not understand this and contraception failure.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168468394.0" user="fayryover" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Let's say person A drunk drives and casues person B to be injured. A is required to pay B's medical bill's and will probably have more financial obligations to B besides those. A will also go to jail for injuring or killing B. However if B needs a new kidney and a blood transfusion due to the actions of A, A is not obligated to give B his kidney or give blood even though A could live without it and is the cause that B needs it. This is the same as woman A is not required to donate her bodily resources to fetus B even though it is partially her fault B needs those resources. 

my example from above.

I am not the person you replied to, I just wanted to give example to what they meant.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168477756.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>Person A's rights to property (fines and bills) and freedom (jail) are violated.  Why do you claim that one cannot violate someone's right to protect someone else?  

The only difference is that the person to be protected is 100% dependent on the mother, and the decision she took has a biological purpose of procreation, so in this case the process was a reluctant success.  

In the drunk driving case the purpose of the process is to get form A to B and it failed.  

I would say the analogy even falls short in proving my point, not countering it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168558116.0" user="fayryover" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Person A's rights to property (fines and bills) and freedom (jail) are violated. Why do you claim that one cannot violate someone's right to protect someone else? 

no, you don't have a legal right to that property, it's a priveledge as it can be taken away due to your actions. You do have a right to your bodily autonomy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168767199.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>Where did you get that distinction from?  

If you run someone over you will have money or property removed from you, including your freedom.  If you murder someone you might even get your life taken from you.  

Why if you make decisions leading to pregnancy you are suddenly immune from rights limitations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169989275.0" user="k9centipede" delta="False">
    <text>When I have vaginal sex with a guy, there is a risk that he could slip and we end up having anal sex. But that doesn't mean I'm consenting to anal, and I would have a right to be upset and demand he remove himself from my ass if such a thing happened.

consent to one thing isn't consent to all things. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170347491.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>I can agree with you, but I can't see the point, if you please explain I am happy to discuss.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170389647.0" user="k9centipede" delta="False">
    <text>Just because I know that pregnancy is a possible risk when having sex doesn't mean I'm consenting to pregnancy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170620835.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>Not very good logic there.  The fact you flip a coin doesn't mean you consent to getting tails?  If you drive drunk doesn't mean you intend to crash?  

Taking a conscious risk makes you responsible of the outcome.  The fact you have access to contraception means that havin unprotcted sex is an unnecessary exposure to risk.  How can you then claim the right to be immune to consequences?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170904763.0" user="k9centipede" delta="False">
    <text>Contraceptions aren't 100%. Unprotected sex doesn't result in babies 100% of the time. Why is the life of a fetus created despite use of your preferred methods worth less than the life of a fetus created when no specific contraception is used. Either the fetus is a life that should be protected no matter the situation of its creation (rape included) or its not. 

If someone was conceived during rape and the mom decided to carry to term but then the baby just kept reminding her of the guy, could she kill it at 8 months old? If not, why is it okay to kill it before its born. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170921487.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Either the fetus is a life that should be protected no matter the situation of its creation (rape included) or its not.   

I don't subscribe to this absolutism, I consider it a false dichotomy.  Every right has its limitations depending on circumstances.  

&amp;gt; Why is the life of a fetus created despite use of your preferred methods worth less than the life of a fetus created when no specific contraception is used  

If you have made all what is reasonable to avoid pregnancy I don't think you should be forced to carry it.  

&amp;gt; If someone was conceived during rape and the mom decided to carry to term but then the baby just kept reminding her of the guy, could she kill it at 8 months old?  

Depends, I'd say yes tentatively but happy to change your mind.  What do you think?  Why?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168371411.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It isn't like you could remove a sperm and egg from the mother and nine months later get a child.

What if we could? What if a we had a perfectly functioning artificial womb that could take a sperm and egg and create a human being in 9 months.

Would that change anything in your argument?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168385514.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>Well the situation I can see occuring with this is kind of dystopian

The same number of women will still not want to complete their pregnancy.

Do we have the ability for the state to grow every unwanted fetus into a baby and then look after it? 

If we do, great. Every embryo gets a shot at life, women don't have to go through the trauma of wondering if she's a murderer. 

But. Do the women want their offspring to exist at all? Do they have any right to argue it if they've brought it into existence? In this case they're getting rid of a life that could live quite happily without her, so it seems wrong to allow her to have a choice about it.

And what if the state doesn't have the ability to look after every fetus-baby? 
How do we decide who's fetuses get to grow into a baby, and who gets a standard abortion?

Does it cost more to get the baby artificially wombed? Meaning abortions for the poor, morally fine lack of pregnancies for the rich? Or do we let the woman have a say (i don't mind if mine dies)? I imagine those women will get villified even more than they do now, and oh my god the guilt.

Or do we implement a genetic screening programme and essentially practice eugenics. Do we tell the women? What if their future children end up marrying a brother/sister? What if they find out that their genes weren't acceptable?

Essentially I hope we create absolutely perfect contraception before we sort this technology out. Because so much dystopia. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168430196.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; she still has the choice over her body  

Sure, but I can still consider abortion from consensual unprotected sexual intercourse wrong.   

In the same way ones right to own ones body cannot override someone else's right to live, once the default outcome of a pregnancy situation that was created by the mother's choice (unprotected consensual sex) is a healthy birth it should remain that way.  

A similar example is a person that goes into a dangerous situation, like a fire, and rescues someone.  As he/she is walking out and now out of danger, he/she can't just decide it's not convenient to carry this person and drop them on a spike and kill them.  Sure, he/she controls the body and forcing them legally to carry someone is unfair, and if the rescue attempt hadn't happened the victim would be dead anyway...but you get my meaning.  
The analogy is only to show a case where someone's decision to carry someone else can't be ended on a whim, so the other person's life now supersedes your right to comfort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168663895.0" user="Smilge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;can't be ended on a whim

This is basically the sticking point for me. I think it's terrible that some women use abortion simply as a means of birth control. But I know that there are cases that I would find abortion an acceptable choice. There are women who struggle and cry and feel terrible but have the abortion because they think it is the best option given their particular circumstances.

It always leads me to the same question: Who should be in charge of deciding if abortion is justifiable in each particular case, the woman or someone else? And I just can't believe that someone else would know a woman's situation better than she would in the vast majority of cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168781058.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Who should be in charge of deciding if abortion is justifiable in each particular case, the woman or someone else? And I just can't believe that someone else would know a woman's situation better than she would in the vast majority of cases.  

I agree it's the core issue.  

However we do this on a regular basis.  At what point can a man steal, kill, assault, vandalize or other questionable act?  Does someone else know the individual's situation better than the individual?  Maybe for some gang member breaking into your car and stealing the laptop has huge gains and it's very small loss for you.  

So I don't think it's hypocritical to make someone responsible (limit rights) for previously made decisions.  If you ask me I'd draw the line at allowing abortions freely for rape, incest, below age of consent, contraception failure, risk of mother's health and other situations where it's clear that he mother didn't make a conscious consent to unprotected sex (a male that knowingly used a failed condom, for example).  This would require a court order I'm afraid.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168793255.0" user="Smilge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;However we do this on a regular basis. At what point can a man steal, kill, assault, vandalize or other questionable act? Does someone else know the individual's situation better than the individual? Maybe for some gang member breaking into your car and stealing the laptop has huge gains and it's very small loss for you.

I don't think those are equitable comparisons. All those things are taking away from another person. Abortion doesn't take away from another person. If you see a fetus as a person, how could you justify ending that person's life for any reason?

I can't think of a good example of an action that is equitable to abortion, and I'm not sure there is one. It's something that gets much more emotional and complex than a simple crime can give credit for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168803763.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you see a fetus as a person, how could you justify ending that person's life for any reason?  

Not quite a person, but a potential person, starting from negligible at the moment of conception and almost a full person moments before normal delivery.  

The inflection point is somewhere on that continuum, and I can't be sure where.  I like 12 weeks, but happy to move it.  

&amp;gt; I can't think of a good example of an action that is equitable to abortion  

Same here.  I can think of examples where individual rights are removed because of decisions you made previously though, so the argument "woman has the right to decide about her body" is rather weak.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168681604.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a minor.  My mom has to feed me and whatnot.  If I get hurt and she's the only person whose blood I can accept, she can refuse.  She can kill me by her choices about her body.  Just like abortion.  Only pregnancy sucks way more than blood donation.  Yet you want to force pregnancy on her.  Do you also want blood donation laws that would make her do it if it was the only way for me to live?  What kind of world would that be?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168783610.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I get hurt and she's the only person whose blood I can accept, she can refuse  

Speculation.  You are already an autonomous human being and it's unlikely you will be in a situation where only your mother's blood can save you.  

&amp;gt; Do you also want blood donation laws that would make her do it if it was the only way for me to live?  

No, we already have blood banks for that.  

If you refine your argument a bit I am sure I can respond or concede a point, but your analogy is simply too removed from abortion of a pregnancy process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169285126.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>My point is not likelihood.  It is if this situation WERE to occur, would you force my mom?  Say I have O- and the blood only has AB+.   You're missing my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169298112.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It is if this situation WERE to occur, would you force my mom?  

No.  

However if she is the one that caused your sickness consciously I would either fine her or put her in prison.  She would lose some of her rights due to her decisions.  

In the case of pregnancy, the mother decided consciously to create this dependent being and she just can't kill it on a whim.  There isn't the option to seek alternatives, like transplant the being to another womb including an artificial one (when this technology is available I think it will be a good way out), so I think it's reasonable to say you are stuck. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169552272.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>What if she was raped?  Then she didn't make me on purpose.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169608965.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>In that case I would find abortion a perfectly reasonable option.  Same for contraception failure, health risk or if she was below the age of consent.  

I am not an extremist, I don't consider life holy, I just think we should weigh cost-benefit from the outside with a pragmatic mind.  You are not entirely free to do whatever you want so forcing someone to do something is part of living in society.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169672559.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>So the life of an adult is worth more than that of what you believe to be a little child?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169691986.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>In ways.  For example an adult has more rights, for example property, work, and other rights.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169709254.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>But we prefer to save the lives of children over adults though.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
