<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168371136.0" user="hermithome" delta="False">
    <text>Some clarifying questions:  

1.  Does this mean that you are against artificial insemination? With artifical insemination, several eggs are fertilized, but most aren't used, simply discarded. 

2.  What about women who have unsafe consensual sex because they aren't properly informed about sex? Are they as blameless as women who have safe sex and women who are raped?

3.  You say that uniqueness is at issue. But that fertilized egg is just as unique if the couple used birth control and it failed, or if a woman was raped. Take a look at the hierarchy here: a woman has unsafe consensual sex and her life and agency are worth less than an egg, but if she has consensual sex or is raped, her life and agency are worth more. The uniqueness of the egg is the same in all of these scenarios. So why the heirarchy? What moral scale are you going for here?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
