<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168676339.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>In AP Biology, I learned that about 2/3rd of pregnancies are terminated.  By the body.  The egg may fertilize and even multiply, but the woman's body is basically like, "Hell mom. That's missing chromosomes.  It'll die.  I'll kill it now.". Not always missing chromosomes.  Sometimes the gametes end up with three sets.  Meiosis messes up sometimes.  Yet I never heard a pro-lifer cry about all those innocent babies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168713794.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>Because it is out of our control. Yes the body may not go through with some pregnancies, but those things are out of our control. We have control over killing a fetus in a healthy pregnancy, however.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168735473.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>If you believe abortion is murder, wouldn't you donate to research to prevent the death of OVER HALF THE BABIES IN THE WORLD?  Wouldn't there be commercials about this atrocitie?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
