<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168292435.0" user="matthona" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and will eventually become a completely unique person 

the key part is 'eventually', to focus on what MAY eventually happen seems to be missing the point, she may have a miscarriage in which case a person would have never developed </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168306199.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>MAY? I'm pretty sure that normal pregnancies WILL result in a unique person. you can't assume it MAY not become a person or assume that it will be a miscarriage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168432303.0" user="matthona" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't assume it would be a miscarriage, as you have noted, there was more than one 'may' in my reply... you on the other hand did not include any 'may' in yours, so who exactly is assuming? here's a hint, it's not me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168457339.0" user="millol" delta="False">
    <text>[About half of fertilized eggs die and are aborted during the first trimester without the woman even knowing.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miscarriage#First_trimester)

So about half of normal pregnancies will not result in a unique person. They will result in spontaneous abortion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
