<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168251805.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Until that baby is born, it is physically a part of the mother's body. Why should the mother not have the right to decide what she can do with her own body?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168302285.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't she take the chance of having that child? If she didn't want to have a child, why have sex with the risk of it?

Also what about at 9 months? I'm not saying that there are abortions at 9 months, but with your logic, you must still support an abortion at 9 months because the baby is still attached to the mother.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168357254.0" user="Jashinist" delta="False">
    <text>So whether aborting the fetus is right or wrong is whether the mother used contraception? So you take no objection to the actual killing of the fetus itself? 

What constitutes as contraception? Pulling out? Washing herself after? Rhythm method? Obviously many of these are faulty, so I'm confused as to your position.

Either you're somehow believing that contraception is 100% effective and therefore sex on it is fine since there's no fetus involved, or you're not bothered about the fetus being aborted, it's more a moral issue involving the mother (AKA, as long as she attempted contraception she at least tried to prevent the fetus from being created).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
