<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168384753.0" user="gottarespondonce" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to respond to this from a different angle, which is to question why on earth consensuality would matter if this is your belief system. You're arguing that a fetus should be preserved because it has significant value (uniqueness). Sure, that's an argument. But that value is in no way influenced by the nature of its conception. A baby conceived in a back-alley rape is just as unique as one conceived by two loving parents. If you believe the law should protect one fetus on that basis, it's just as reasonable the law protects all of them.

Why is murder wrong? Because we as a society believe human life is valuable. If I said "I'm going to kill my neighbor, but it's okay because he was conceived in rape", no one would ever defend me. And once you have an agreed-upon definition of life (newborn), virtually everyone would agree all the same standards apply (i.e. no one sane would argue "It's okay to kill a 2 month old baby, so long as it was conceived in a rape." Therefore, if you believe a fetus conceived consensually has value worth protecting, and if a fetus conceived non-consensually is identical, the non-consensual fetus deserves the exact same protection.

Otherwise, you're basically saying "It's okay to kill babies but only if they're rape-babies." And that's a position more indefensible than being pro-life or pro-choice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
