<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168584680.0" user="msing" delta="False">
    <text>Creating a new set DNA doesn't mean a new life is formed, it simply means different strands of DNA annealed together. I've worked in a recombinant DNA lab, where we commonly 'graft' on pieces of foreign DNA onto a host, essentially creating a vehicle to produce specific proteins -- I don't instantly get life after the reaction.

&amp;gt;that woman simply did not care that new life was created within her

This changes the onset of life, or at least from your perspective. The current guidelines for abortion are not from your perspective, but on the basis on concept of life for the ability of the embryo to survive on its own. The first trimester ? Not likely to survive on its own. The second trimester ? maybe not. The third trimester? maybe.

&amp;gt;and chose to have sex in the first place.

Sex isn't exactly a individual choice. It's a mutual decision made by both partners with some degree of coercion and emotion. I don't necessarily have the same condition where one choice I make can put my life on standstill for the next 9 months, or the next 2 years or etc. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
