<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168285389.0" user="Abstract_Atheist" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need more of a foundation for your position than just that the fetus will become a unique person. Why does it matter if they will become a unique person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168309065.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think there's anything special about the creation of a person? You think it is ok to just get rid of it after the mother chose to have sex and risk the fetus in the first place? Do we really value pleasure over life itself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168315374.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>well not everyone defines the first few cells as life. If those first few cells are destroyed, to many people no life has been lost and no unique person has been destroyed.

The issue is that some people see it as 'life itself' other people see it as 'hey a cell culture' until variously arbitrary amounts of time.

If your argument is purely based on your belief of where that line is, it's hard to argue because everyone's starting at different starting places and belief isn't something easily changed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168331577.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>life


1.
the condition that distinguishes animals and plants from inorganic matter, including the capacity for growth, reproduction, functional activity, and continual change preceding death.
---------

I believe a fetus is capable of all of these things such as reproduction of it's cells, growth, organ activity like the heartbeat, and change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168338159.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>So that's word for word from the google definition and you missed out: 

2, the existence of an individual human being or animal.

Many people would argue that a fetus isn't an individual. It doesn't have the capacity to grow or have functional activity without one specific host - it's mother. It can't grow in 'any' human - it needs this one woman. It isn't individual from her. It doesn't have functional activity at first, it takes a while for a heartbeat, longer for brain and lung activity. 

The point at which life begins is hotly debated even by experts. I think if the answer were a simple google away this would be much less of a topic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169009008.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>Never seen anyone arguing that plants are dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169021588.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>I just took the same google definition that OP used (it's not *my* definition). It's obviously flawed, sort of my point - defining life is tricky, a misplaced word can alter the definition completely and if we had the definition down we wouldn't be arguing about things like abortion because we'd know categorically if the fetus fits the bill of 'life' (edit: perhaps 'a life' rather than just 'alive' - tumours are obviously alive but not 'a life' for example). but yeah, it would make more sense to say an individual human being or animal or plant or bacteria or fungus or protozoa etc

I assume when they say 'or animal' they mean 'or organism' 

Unless of course it's talking about life in a more spiritual sense, OP used the phrase: Do we really value pleasure over life itself? 
In this sense OP seems to be talking about a more significant/spiritual version of life, since we're absolutely willing to kill trees to read books for pleasure and unless you literally only eat to survive you obviously kill things for pleasure too. Maybe this definition is doing the same?

Defining life is complex: no definition is going to be good enough. Hence this argument.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169090562.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>I see. Anyway I haven't seen anyone claiming that fetus isn't ,,life". I don't think that would work with our biologic knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169099188.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>no, but whether it is 'a life' is different which is what OP seemed to be implying (after all if destroying 'life' was the issue OP couldn't remove tumours, get piercings and would mourn every time they got a cut or a woman got a period losing an unfertilised egg) 

Tumours are alive, but we happily remove them. A person is a life, we don't agree that killing them is OK largely. However a tree is also a life and we kill them fairly nonchalantly. Where on that spectrum does a fetus fall? It's alive, but only as long as it's attached to another life (tumour-like) so is it a life? If it is a life is it more tree-esque or person-esque or somewhere in the middle? 

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169109448.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>Are sesame twins a life? They are alive only as long as attached. I think they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169113941.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>I think siamese twins is a bit different because it depends entirely on the twins. Some can be separated with surgery and live happily: they've grown everything they need to live separately. A fetus hasn't, at certain points it doesn't have brain activity or lung activity or a heartbeat - the mother does all those roles. However conjoined twins do have at least some of those functions.

For conjoined twins that share core components I guess the issue is more whether they're **a** life or **2** lives? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27169184867.0" user="millol" delta="False">
    <text>Also, the siamese twins would most likely be co-dependent. A mother is not dependent on her fetus, making it more tumor- or parasite-like. Both siamese twins might benefit from each other.

Disclaimer: There are surely cases where one siamese twin benefits more than the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170447216.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>If there's a possibility for one twin to deattach from the other which would case death of the other, would you allow? Following your reasoning you would, which isn't good for me (not that I'm a sesame twin).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170454522.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>like I said, I think siamese twins are a very different example.

But there are cases where surgery has carried a risk of one dying, and indeed one has died during/after surgery. So it's not like there's anything banning this surgery if there's a risk. This is much more common when twins are separated in their infancy - ie they take more risks with babies. So the world is willing to split siamese twins with a risk of one dying. 

But it's obviously a very different case because at the point siamese twins will be separated they are born and sometimes adults. Will we can argue over the semantics of alive, a life or 2 lives: there are definitely two fully functioning brains with two personalities if we're talking about adults. 

It's an inherently different situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170482994.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;like I said, I think siamese twins are a very different example.

You claimed that's it's the case because fetus can only live if it's attached to another living organism, I don't really see why it's different. Maybe because siaseme twin isn't responsible for condition of 2nd twin (like mother is for fetus). And I'm not talking about infancy surgieries etc. I'm just asking if one, ,,main" twin is allowed to decide to deattach the second one if this causes his death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170500593.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>like i said, it's different when the two minds are adult because then we have the argument of what is alive, a life, two lives, a person and two persons all rolled in to one issue. So we're adding the complication of 'personhood' into the mix.

In general in adulthood if both twins have cognitive abilities (ie they both talk, have feelings etc) then they both have to decide because they're considered two people even if they share the majority of a body. Even if it's just one head essentially attached to another body - if the head has a 'person' it gets a decision.

If the twin doesn't act like a person, it doesn't grow, doesn't think, doesn't move, doesn't talk, isn't responsive: then i think it's removed without moral issue.

But again, this is a very different situation because we're talking about two people at equal stages of development sharing a body that have already turned into viable humans. Rather than a group of cells that's debatable whether it's a person in it's own right at the beginning of sharing a woman's body. Furthermore the siamese twins are already successfully, albeit not 'normally' developed. If left alone they live as viable humans. The fetus is not successful. If left alone it still needs to turn into a viable human. So the operation of separating a twin kills a person that has already developed, whereas an abortion prevents a 'person' from developing to viability. They are very different situations. 

But this all loops around to my initial point. Life, personhood etc is all very hard to define. No definition is applicable to every situation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170523519.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>In that case we have to explain what is ,,person", what does it mean to be successfully developed, why one has to be person in order to have right to life, why ability to talk or having feelings is even relevant etc... I don't think your arguments are clear. Therefore I'd act as in ,,in dubio pro reo" rule and would not allow abortion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170528954.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>well that's what the whole abortion debate is isn't it? What people consider 'a life' what people consider 'a person' when people consider the fetus to have the right to life over the woman's right to her body.

The lack of knowledge, ambiguity and confusion over these very subjective states are exactly why this debate exists in the first place. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170559158.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>Actually I don't think I lack knowledge or am confused about this. Fetus is human as it belongs to homo sapiens and I don't think we should be allowed to kill other people without really good reason (not wanting to be pregnant isn't one of them).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27170741829.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>But while it has human DNA people don't see it as a person, they don't think it deserves the same rights as adult, fully developed persons.

Not saying your view is wrong, or what my view is. But essentially the whole argument boils down to subjectivity. If you're not willing to admit that it's subjective, you're not going to get very far arguing your point </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27175929775.0" user="swafnir" delta="False">
    <text>Actually I consider argument that people don't see it as a person as subjective and my argument, as completely based on biology, pretty objective. At least more objective than the former.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27175932295.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>well it's objective that it's true biologically but subjective if it matters to people, if that's what they consider important etc. It's no more a 'right' answer than viability etc since it requires people to agree that that is the important factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168771082.0" user="TheHumbleSailor" delta="False">
    <text>Under that definition you just described every once living entity that you have ever eaten. It's not a useful definition because cows (for example) have cells that reproduce, grow, have organs like a heart and yeah they change, yet you'd still accept the killing and eating of beef. Definition 2 is better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168863111.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You don't think there's anything special about the creation of a person?

Why is it special? What about it, specifically, makes it special?

&amp;gt;  Do we really value pleasure over life itself?

I kill the ants in my kitchen when they bug me. Have you ever swatted a mosquito? I could make the same argument for you here - that your own personal comfort or pleasure is more important than those animal's lives. 

But clearly that's ridiculous. Those are just bugs. So it's not life that we value, it's human life, clearly. But why? What is that factor that makes humans have value when bugs don't? Is that quality there as soon as the sperm meets the egg?

I would argue that it's not a matter of valuing pleasure over life. It's a matter of believing that what you're destroying when you have an abortion is not a person in a meaningful sense. It's not that we're killing people in cold blood, it's that we disagree that anyone is dying. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
