<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="129158977.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/24wbpd/cmv_i_believe_that_abortion_as_a_result_of/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that abortion as a result of consensual sex (without contraception) is wrong.</title>
    <original_poster>BreakinMyBallz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel as though women who choose to have sex without the means of contraception, simply don't care if they get pregnant. They put their pleasures over the risk of having a child and having it terminated. 

I feel as though, when the sperm and egg mix, they create a completely new set of DNA, DNA that has never been the same in the entire history of our species and is a completely unique person (I'm not Theist, I try to base my arguments on the uniqueness of each person)

I don't see any way for someone to justify abortion when it is the result of sex without contraception. That woman simply did not care that new life was created within her, and chose to have sex in the first place. We argue it's a woman's choice for abortion? No, It's a woman's choice to have sex without the means of contraception.

-------
Clarification - I believe contraception is OK because new life with unique DNA and a unique person has not been formed and therefore will not be removed from the world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27168340081.0" user="BreakinMyBallz" delta="False">
    <text>Also something for you guys to think about. What is different from aborting a 2 month old fetus or a 9 month old fetus? I mean it is still part of the mother, it's still in her body, so by a lot of your logic, she should be able to abort it? But once that umbilical cord is cut, suddenly it is an individual human being?


If you argue that the 2 month old fetus isnt human life yet, why is it not? It fits this definition of life - life - noun - the condition that distinguishes animals and plants from inorganic matter, including the capacity for growth, reproduction, functional activity, and continual change preceding death.

So what is so different between a 9 month old fetus and a 2 month old fetus that makes the 2 month fetus not a human, and therefore justifiable to kill?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168352694.0" user="sheep74" delta="False">
    <text>I already argued your definition of life further up.

The difference is viability.

At one point the fetus *can* survive outside of the mother. At this point it's generally considered wrong to abort because now you're killing something that could have survived with care from others rather than just this one individual human.

In general we don't allow early voluntary c-sections at this point. In general it's accepted that the mother has usually had enough time to decide if she wants the baby at this point. And it's a burden to the state to bring a baby into the world that needs a lot of care, when a few extra weeks would cut its care down massively. It's also a more dangerous procedure for the mother. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168361150.0" user="JustaCucumber" delta="False">
    <text>Most people would say that the difference is that the 9 month old fetus can survive outside the mother's body, and therefore has more rights than the 2 month old. I think people generally don't think of an abortion as a mother killing her child, but rather a mother simply removing a small cluster of unwanted cells from her body, not too different from getting a haircut or trimming her fingernails.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168462172.0" user="krausyaoj" delta="False">
    <text>A mother who does not want her baby should be able to abort a fetus of nine months old. While it is a human life it is not a person. Cutting the umbilical cord does not make it a person, that takes a few more years of growth.

Humans are born premature and development continues outside the womb. We kill pigs for food but they are more intelligent than most three year old humans, http://www.unleashed.org.au/animals/pigs.php

&amp;gt; Pigs are smart—smarter than dogs and even 3-year-old children! And get this—they like playing computer games! It's true. But despite being just as intelligent and social as dogs and cats, in Australia pigs suffer terribly and don’t get the same legal protection as your family pet. Imagine if we had laws that only protected some people...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168620707.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Infanticide is a somewhat different issue from abortion though. Do you not agree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168655914.0" user="krausyaoj" delta="False">
    <text>No, I do not agree. I think abortion is moral because infanticide is also moral. Both involve the killing of human non-persons. I think bodily autonomy is not a sufficient reason for abortion to be moral.

Persons are defined independant of species as efforts to define non-human persons. From http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/10/when-is-a-person-not-a-human-when-its-a-dolphin-or-chimp-or/?_php=true&amp;amp;_type=blogs&amp;amp;_r=0

&amp;gt; This is especially true with research about cetaceans, because the discoveries of marine mammal scientists over the last 50 years have made it clear that whales and dolphins share traits once believed to be unique to humans: self-awareness, abstract thought, the ability to solve problems by planning ahead, understanding such linguistically sophisticated concepts as syntax, and the formation of cultural communities.

Human babies do not meet these requirements of person until about 18 months. From http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/great-kids-great-parents/201211/self-awareness

&amp;gt; The Developmental of Self-Awareness The neurobiological and psychological triggers for self-awareness have not yet been clarified. What we do know is that this occurs around 1 – 3 years. The child begins to know her own name and refer to herself by name. The child will begin to look in the mirror and realize she is looking at herself.  She will also make clearer her own likes and dislikes, needs and wishes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168667292.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's an interesting position. I take person to be synonymous with human. Where would you draw the line at personhood though? 18 months?

I define bodily autonomy as the criteria of personhood, which is why I draw the line at birth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168683556.0" user="krausyaoj" delta="False">
    <text>I would draw the line when a human can recognize themselves in a mirror or communicate using a human language.

Humans are born premature compared to other mammals which is why I think birth is too soon to say that a human is a person, http://boingboing.net/2013/05/03/baby-humans-are-premature-fet.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168711732.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>My problem with using neurological development as a criterion is that there is a lot more fuzziness overall, that's why I don't consider it.

Is neurological maturity the underpinning for your argument regarding the altricial status of human infants?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168593933.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's interesting that you bring this question, because someone else was grilling me on this a little while back.

I think there is a difference between something that is alive and something that is human. A human by definition is alive, but not everything alive is human.

The line that I have drawn was that a baby is human, i.e. personhood was given at birth. When pressed, I gave the moment that the baby drew its first breath.

Now, the question that stumped me was this: Is it alright to bin a baby born not breathing?

I can't answer that question because I don't have the know-how to distinguish between a live baby that has difficulty breathing and a stillborn. On a more fundamental level, my criterion that a baby is not breathing is flawed in the sense that not having taken its first breath, a medical doctor is under no obligation to offer any assistance to the baby since it is by definition not human (never mind that most if not all doctors *will* offer such assistance).

I'm pretty sure my position is right though, that birth is the definition for personhood rather than conception. Debating the grey areas around that line in the sand is the issue, but I didn't expect the answers to come easily anyway. Unfortunately, I had no epiphanies from the discussion earlier.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27168858385.0" user="Uof" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody really argues that a fetus is not alive. It clearly is. That doesn't make it an individual person.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
