<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173548526.0" user="rly________tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) 

She's in an actual, literal, tower

&amp;gt; and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Gothel isn't her mother. Rapunzel reunites with the Queen at the end of the film. 

That aside, that you can infer metaphors from a certain piece of media doesn't mean it was the creator's intent. It's like how I can infer societal collapse and the grinding, pervasive degradation of the human spirit when I watch something like The Bachelorette, but I wouldn't argue that the creators *intended* that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173605803.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>The entire point in a metaphor is that you say something literally to imply something non-literal.

Gothel is not Rapunzel's biological mother but in the story she is Rapunzel's "adoptive" (albeit by kidnapping) mother. Also it could be a metaphor for an abusive biological mother.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173669023.0" user="rly________tho" delta="False">
    <text>But the issue is that you can spiral out on this pretty easily until you reach a point where you're actively looking for pieces of media to place a template onto, rather than drawing out a message from the piece itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173712523.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Sure you can and that's the whole point. Looking for different interpretations of various pieces of media is a lot of fun and one of the patterns is that every Disney Princess can be considered a metaphor for mental illness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173736651.0" user="rly________tho" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that you can do this for literally every character in every film ever made, if you're dedicated to doing so. 

You chose Disney princesses, but you could be making the exact same argument for Schwarzenegger characters, or Adam Sandler movies. You could say that all of cinema is a metaphor for mental illness as a whole.

Is that reasonable, do you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173764067.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you can. But that doesn't contradict anything I have said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173788038.0" user="rly________tho" delta="False">
    <text>You need to focus on the question I asked about how reasonable this is. 

So for example, the Death Star is a metaphor for the womb, and the emperor is a metaphor for tokophobia. Luke represents castration anxiety and Darth Vader is a metaphor for racial tensions in America. Leia's hair is a metaphor for the American failures in Vietnam. Han Solo is a metaphor for market deregulation. 

How reasonable am I sounding here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173799459.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Not very, but that is because you are clearly deliberately picking an obscure and ridiculous interpretation. It would be entirely reasonable to interpret Darth Vader, Luke Skywalker, and Ben Solo as having signs of BPD, however.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173824306.0" user="rly________tho" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that's not very fair. *My* interpretations are ridiculous, but *yours* are reasonable? 

Do you see the issue here? When you say "Every Disney Princess could be **reasonably** interpreted as a metaphor", it raises the question "to whom?" That you think it's reasonable is clear. But it seems odd to believe one's own interpretation is the only reasonable one, does it not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173860545.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't assert that the *only* reasonable interpretation of Disney princesses is as a metaphor for mental illness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36176046239.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>But you also have not given any reason for why it even is a reasonable interpretation either. Your same process can be applied to any character ever and you say that is unreasinable. Do you not think that the same process you use producing results you do not like may mean your process is flawed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173968939.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure the person you're talking to is self-aware enough to recognize the double standard they've created. Good luck though!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173832198.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, you can. But that doesn't contradict anything I have said.

No, but it does contradict your *implication*.

When you say "every disney princess is a metaphor for mental illness" it sounds like you're making a statement about *disney princesses*. It's like making the statement (making up stats) "70% of Irish people drink alcohol at least once a week" if that's *also* true of all ethnicities. It's not *literally false*, but it implies that you're making a statement about Irish people when you actually aren't.

In other words, using your reasoning, your statement is true in the literal sense, but it's meaningless because it provides zero information about disney, or princesses, or disney princesses.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
