<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173729506.0" user="Gormac_Five" delta="False">
    <text>Fairy tales are meant for children and are often stories told to help them navigate the world. The story of Belle is actually about the Beast (although Disney would have you believe otherwise). Belle doesn’t grow a whole lot- the Beast *does* though. The ways a child’s mind could relate to this story are vast. The beast is unjustly punished as a child for something he didn’t know was wrong, but gains redemption. The beast makes conscious efforts to better himself. The beast learns to let go, to accept himself, and to find love even though he is a beast. As with most fairy tales it is also good for puberty- you might feel like a beast now, but you won’t always be one, especially if you work on yourself. Of course, you could also resonate more with Belle, who is the embodiment of the values of patience, sacrifice, intellect, and generosity. She stands up for what she believes in, even though villagers make fun of her, and she still saves her dad and finds love in an unlikely place. 

Cinderella is a story that is good for children who are angry with their parents. It’s good for children who are, sadly, in abusive homes (the lesson here being to keep your chin up, and accept help even from unlikely sources like a fairy god mother, and you are still lovable even if your parents are shit). It’s also good for essential life tips like keeping cinders out of your hearth, but I digress. 

Ariel is a puberty/love/freedom story, and the original is pretty dark. But in this one, the idea relayed to the mind of a child would be more like, “separating from your parents and undergoing puberty/a drastic shift in your body could be painful and scary but ultimately it is worth it and everything works out in the end.” 

Rapunzel, again, is similar. Notice the theme of being trapped? All of these prince/sses are trapped in some way or other (trapped in a tower, in a mermaid body, in poverty, in a palace, etc etc). This story is exceptional though because Rapunzel uses her own body to escape. Another puberty thing. Also hugely empowering for a developing mind to see in a story that a physical body can have power- children are pretty weak. 

Viewing fairy tales through the lens of an adult and trying to diagnose fairy tale characters with disorders is antithetical to the point of fairytales. The characters are given juuuuuuust enough personality to be interesting, but little enough personality that a child could insert themselves into the story wherever their psyche sees fit. The main relationships fairy tale characters have are with *parents or guardians/captors*, and later a romantic interest (which is a whole other subject I could go on and on about). Cinderella doesn’t have *friends*, she has a fairy godmother. Ariel has sidekicks but not *friends*. None of them have coworkers or really any social interactions that are meaningful outside of what I mentioned previously. 

Fairytales are archetypal stories for children. And because they are so simplistic and we can’t view them outside a very narrow (and often fantastical) scope, not only is it pointless to try to diagnose them with things, it goes against WHY fairytales appeal to children in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
