<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173569699.0" user="LetMeNotHear" delta="False">
    <text>What about Kiara?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173594201.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>She impulsively falls in love with a guy she only barely knows and who is conspiring to murder her father. This shows impulsivity, attachment issues, an excessive need for romance/attention and remarkably poor judgment. Any number of disorders may explain this (bipolar, BPD, HPD being the most obvious examples).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173604171.0" user="LetMeNotHear" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, come now. She didn't know about the plot to kill her father. And impulsivity, need for attention and poor judgement aren't necessarily symptoms of mental illness. They're also symptoms of adolescence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173705943.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Even when she learns about the plot to kill Simba, Kiara is still in love with Kovu. That shows a level of codependency and poor judgment that is way beyond the scope of normal adolescence. Also at the end of the Lion King 2 she appears to married or corronated or similar in the ceremony where Simba, Nala, Kiara, and Kovu all roar in succession from the top of Pride Rock. That implies that she is at least old enough to be considered an adult (i.e. not an adolescent) by the society she is in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173747721.0" user="LetMeNotHear" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even when she learns about the plot to kill Simba, Kiara is still in love with Kovu.

You'll have to remind me how this played out. I thought she was made rather distraught by the revelation and only continued their relationship after learning he'd abandoned the plot he was forced into.

&amp;gt;Also at the end of the Lion King 2 she appears to married or corronated or similar in the ceremony where Simba, Nala, Kiara, and Kovu all roar in succession from the top of Pride Rock. That implies that she is at least old enough to be considered an adult (i.e. not an adolescent) by the society she is in.

1; We don't really know what that ceremony was analogous to. It could have been the Lion equivalent of a declaration of amnesty for all we know.

2; Even if it was a wedding, there's places where adolescents get married. Hell there's places where people are married before they're adolescents. Plus wasn't the whole beginning of the plot about how her dad's overprotective with her acting like a teenager about it. Simba's giving her instructions and she has to repeat them to show she understands. She's treated like an adolescent and acts like an adolescent for the whole movie.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
