<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173490179.0" user="jt4" delta="False">
    <text>Rapunzel was in a literal tower in most interpretations of the work.

Since you've said this applies to all Disney princesses, I'll throw in Moana, Merida, and Jasmine as not having issues I can see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173576056.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>The point in a metaphor is that you say something literally that you mean non-literally. So yes, in the telling of the story it is a literal tower but it could be seen as representing the mental tower of anxiety and codependency on an abusive mother.

I've responded to Moana and Jasmine elsewhere on this thread.

Merida turning her mother into a bear is very unusual. Perhaps it shows an unhealthy mother-daughter relationship where she sees her mother as brutish and bear-like. Or perhaps an obsession with having to do things a particular way in case she accidentally causes something extremely bad (and extremely unlikely) to happen (OCD).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36176108374.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>She does not see her mother as bearish. It was an accident. Her views on her mother had no bearing on exactly what happened to her.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
