<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173712779.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>When we watch these films what we don't see is a world around the princess seeing the princess as mentally ill.  If these behaviors were to be brought into our world the mental illness would be clear - the dissonance between thinking/behavior of the princess and the social world would be dramatic and we'd see them clearly as mentally ill.

The majority of mental illness - and especially the ones you're likely to find in this set - are "social diseases", assuming you believe cognitive psychology and aren't a pure behaviorist.  So...when your actions "work well" deeply in your social world you're not really mentally ill at all.  You know this almost instinctively because your brain mostly doesn't see mental illness - not just because the princess has charmed you with her ... charm, but because the world around isn't phased by the behavior that in a different context would be regarded as crazy-pants-diagnosable.

So...i think the answer is that it's NOT this sort of metaphor at all because were it the message would be the mental illness is a successful social strategy. Further, it seems you're drawing a line around what you include in your de-suspension-of-disbelief that includes only the princess, but not the world of the princess and I don't think you can talk about mental illness without the social context.

Of course...on the other hand...yeah, they are totally fucking nuts, but that is a less interesting comment :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173757266.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps a reason that we don't see much of a disconnect between the princess' thoughts and the worlds around them is that we are seeing it from the princess' perspectives. They would not see the disconnect between their beliefs and the world around them because many mental disorders are ego-syntonic.

Also there clearly are disconnects between the princess' perspectives and the responses of the societies around them. For example, when Rapunzel goes to the Snuggly Duckling for the first time and expects a warm reception from lovely people and is actually met with thugs who try to mug her until they get distracted and do a spontaneous dance number.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173880047.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>That did cross my mind, although generally in "fantasy" there is much effort in creating a "world" and we can't really know if that world has a specific creator that is in the story.  I'd like to be able to turn on the 7 year old girl brain that must exist deep inside my middle-aged-man head to think about that idea!  But...sure, maybe.  However, I don't think there is anything presented to the audience to make us think - we never get a glimpse behind the mental illness to what we'd assume is a "realer" set of responses and thoughts of the people/animals in the society of the princess.

In your thugs example, things start getting awfully thousand-levels-of-deep since we'd then have to imagine that these aren't _really_ thugs, they are actually the "normal perspective" of the society.  It is after-all not crazy to have scared/surprised/awful reactions to thugs, definitely not a sign of mental illness.  They have to _not be thugs_ for her behavior to indicate mental illness.  That seems like more of a leep.  We can't start saying that false expectations or shitty experiences that are surprising is a sign of mental illness on its face.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173940770.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps, but look at the broader context- Rapunzel starts the movie by singing about how she's "stuck in the same place she's always been" and wondering "when will my life begin?" because she's been constrained to a tower ever since she was abducted by Gothel. Clearly the tower is causing her dysfunction and distress in her daily life so the only thing needed to deduce that Rapunzel is mentally unwell is to observe that the "tower" is likely a metaphor for the overwhelming fear caused by an anxiety disorder or the restriction and repetitiveness of obsessive compulsive disorder. 

There's a clear and sound argument that Rapunzel can be seen as a metaphor for a mental illness.

But specifically in the context of the Snuggly Duckling, she's being shown to be naïve and dangerously trusting because the people in the Snuggling Duckling *were* going to mug her until she convinced them not to by talking about her dream to see the lanterns. The point is not that those who frequent the Snuggly Duckling aren't thugs, but rather that they *are* thugs but that thugs are also human too with dreams and aspirations and a lot in common with you. It's also a cheap gag for comedic effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36174046448.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't those reasonable, healthy responses to being _trapped in a tower_?  Being distressed is not disease if there are stressors, it's the healthy response.  

I don't think it's a particularly sound argument.  Certainly it would lost on the target audience, and it is certainly unreasonable with regard to author intent, since "mental illness" doesn't exist in the times of Grimm authoring.  It might _serve_ as a metaphor if thats what you want, but as a form of literary interpretation it seems awfully far fetched.

Being naive isn't mental illness, and that an isolated young person would encounter and be surprised by the complexity of the real world is not a bright light toward the idea of mental illness metaphor if you ask me.

But...it's all interesting to think about and I'm enjoying it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36174099154.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps those are reasonable responses to being trapped in a literal tower but interpreting the tower as a metaphor makes the whole character seem like a metaphor for someone overcoming anxiety or OCD. 

Also a reasonable response to a particular situation can still develop into a mental illness. PTSD is a normal response to trauma, but it's still a mental illness. Even interpreting the tower as literal, it still informs us of Rapunzel's mental state and explains why she is sometimes paranoid about innocuous things and at other times is completely comfortable in situations which clearly pose a threat to her safety, both of which are symptoms of various mental illnesses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36174170021.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>If you goal is to find how this could be a metaphor for mental illness you're gonna find it.  It could also be a metaphor for being trapped as a women with the only out being marriage.  I mean....that's a much more reasonable interpretation, if less interesting.  

The problem is that no character in ... well ... anything isn't subject to this metaphor, which makes it not a great interpretation.  Characters in fiction are always hyperbolic, emphasizing some aspect of  human experience so we connect.  You're describing character driven storytelling as a whole it seems to me.  I could this with superheros, or with villains, or with mob characters and so on.  If the goal is to fit _characters_ to a mental illness metaphor it can always be done because characters are almost universally not like real people, otherwise we'd be bored out of our skulls reading them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
