<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173488531.0" user="leonardsansbees" delta="False">
    <text>For Belle, the scene with the villagers is actually them singing about how weird she is, so that doesn't follow. Your other examples I can see, but there's a lot more princesses out there, so: 

Moana seems totally healthy to me. Her beliefs about saving her people aren't grandiose because they actually happen so She's right. 

What about Jasmine? She's as well adjusted as one could expect based on her life situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173550716.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>One of the DSM diagnostic criteria for NPD is "a belief that they are special and can only be understood by similarly special people". It's entirely consistent with NPD for Belle to imagine that the other villagers just don't understand her because from her perspective she's better than them. They also sing about how she's beautiful and she sings about how she wants "so much more" than everyone else in her village (entitlement). Also Gaston, Beast, and Lumiére show signs of classical, covert, and communal narcissism respectively so it makes sense in context.

Moana is a complex one. Her belief that the ocean is going to destroy the islands and everyone she loves could be seen as anxiety or paranoia. Te Kā is a metaphor for PTSD and dissociative identity- Maui caused her trauma (stole her heart) and so Moana's obsession with restoring Te Fiti's heart could be seen as a metaphor for codependency with with a trauma victim. 

Jasmine "falls in love" with a man she just met who lied and manipulated her from the start. She clearly has boundary issues which are typical of HPD or BPD. Viewing the whole movie from the perspective of Jasmine having HPD makes a lot of sense- perhaps her "suitors" are just visiting her father for various political reasons and she only believes they are trying woo her because of her pathological desire for attention and romance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173928927.0" user="engagedandloved" delta="False">
    <text>The DSM also states in order for someone to be diagnosed with a mental health issue they must meet at least 5 of the listed characteristics/criteria for most of these disorders. None of them exhibit at least 5 traits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36176003822.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Jasmine "falls in love" with a man she just met who lied and manipulated her from the start. She clearly has boundary issues which are typical of HPD or BPD. Viewing the whole movie from the perspective of Jasmine having HPD makes a lot of sense- perhaps her "suitors" are just visiting her father for various political reasons and she only believes they are trying woo her because of her pathological desire for attention and romance.

Most of the diagnoses you put forward are only possible if you ignore what actually happens in the story. When you consider your source material to be false, there is literally no limit to what kind of things you can imagine into it which have no actual basis. 

Jasmin is not imagining the suitors, they are explicitly stated as suitors with a reason for them to be there. To believe otherwise is just making things up. She never even displays any attention-seeking behavior. In fact, she explicitly tries to be normal and fit in for a while. Having any desires at all is not a cause for a diagnosis, especially when the one thing she desires is the antithesis of the main sign of the disorder.

&amp;gt;Te Kā is a metaphor for PTSD and dissociative identity- 

Or, you know, just being angry. You do not suddenly get over PTSD like what happened in the movie so it really doesn't fit the story.

You can view just about anything as being a disorder. You could view a man shopping for food as being an analogy of the sin of gluttony but everyone needs to eat so it really doesn't make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36176630222.0" user="cape_of_good_hope" delta="False">
    <text>You have to exhibit way more than one symptom to be diagnosed with any mental disorder. One symptom means nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36183673593.0" user="I_onno" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't uncommon for people who grow up in small towns to want to move to a city or a new region. I don't think that means Belle has mental health issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
