<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173638931.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>Literally any story that involves humans will have some emotions or personality characteristics that *just maybe might sorta kinda give a little indication that it's potentially possible* that it's about mental illness, because symptoms of mental illness are mostly just common human emotions that are extreme enough to cause distress or disorder.

You can be self-obsessed or vain without having NPD. You can worry without having an anxiety disorder. You can be impulsive and reckless without have BPD.

I think it's unreasonable for you to conclude that every Disney Princess can be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness because you're using a bar for what behaviors or emotions constitute mental disorders that is far, far lower than any diagnostic criteria and that simply fall in the realm of "the everyday human experience."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173899491.0" user="Th3CatOfDoom" delta="False">
    <text>It's kind of like astrology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36175886068.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>You shall be surprised by an unexpected occurrence today.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
