<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1299493392.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/lhonio/cmv_a_better_way_to_pay_for_college_would_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: a better way to pay for college would be a wage percentage system</title>
    <original_poster>SaltySpursSupporter</original_poster>
    <original_post>instead of needing to take out thousands of dollars for student loans, maybe this is a better idea. instead of needing to pay money outright, negotiate a percentage of your future wage. depending on the program you're entering and the amount of years in that system, you can negotiate the percentage and the amount of years. if the person has a minimum wage job for the chosen amount of years, that's still all they get. i'm sure there are problems here that I haven't thought of. you're welcome to change my mind.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36216760521.0" user="S7EFEN" delta="False">
    <text>this is how a lot of programming bootcamps work. people hate it generally, and it tends to be relatively predatory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216775189.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>Can you please explain how it’s predatory? Would be interested to know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216808105.0" user="S7EFEN" delta="False">
    <text>These contracts typically come with harsh penalties for dropping out. Like, you sign up for a bootcamp and if you then drop out of the bootcamp you owe massively more than it is worth (as you likely aren't paying, or are getting a "big discount" on the bootcamp due to your plan to pay through future wages).

 If you complete the bootcamp and get a good job you owe them a large chunk of your wage for a long period of time. 

Some of them take this further and actually make themselves responsible for your hiring. Revature is one I ran into when I graduated, theyll "pay for your training" by requiring you to move cross country (giving you like a few hundred bucks to relocate), pay you minimum wage during your 8-12 week bootcamp, then get you a job. In turn you get 50k a year which grows to... 60 or 70k a year after that? However, theyre 80-120k+ contracting you out after you complete your bootcamp. And if you drop? 20k is how much youll owe for that training. Note, revature ONLY takes people with a 4 year degree in the first place. Many do not and thus are even worse in terms of the contact you get.


Like, overall the revature example isn't really predatory, or I guess it's debatable on that term- it's just an absolutely awful deal for 95% of people. Everything is laid out clearly, it's not a scam or anything.

It's a good idea overall I guess, just the way it is implemented not so much. These companies pull back WAY more from you than they realistically should with these income sharing / repayment agreements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216853748.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>Very interesting. I would suggest that the hiring system after college is independent of the university. Maybe that would relieve some of the power the university has.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217345690.0" user="Medianmodeactivate" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't sound bad. Drop out, get your employer to front the 20K fee or just get a loan for it yourself and get the 120K</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
