<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1299493392.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/lhonio/cmv_a_better_way_to_pay_for_college_would_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: a better way to pay for college would be a wage percentage system</title>
    <original_poster>SaltySpursSupporter</original_poster>
    <original_post>instead of needing to take out thousands of dollars for student loans, maybe this is a better idea. instead of needing to pay money outright, negotiate a percentage of your future wage. depending on the program you're entering and the amount of years in that system, you can negotiate the percentage and the amount of years. if the person has a minimum wage job for the chosen amount of years, that's still all they get. i'm sure there are problems here that I haven't thought of. you're welcome to change my mind.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36216594449.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>So... Public education funded by taxes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216622909.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>No, an individual contract entered into by the two parties. You can have different percentages, length if years. If you don’t want to go to college, it doesn’t cosy you anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216640068.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>That is called taking out a loan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216659685.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so how do we select the people working out the percentages and managing the contracts? I guess we could have people volunteer, and then we take a poll about which ones we actually want to do that. And then, all those people will have to have somewhere to meet to discuss the actual particulars of the system; maybe one city with a good airport. And then *they* will have to take a poll on the percentages and rules so that all of those volunteers can get on the same page. And then, after a set length of time, we will have to see if we like what they did, and take another poll to see if we want to send those people back to work on the next batch of bills and contracts. 

Seems like it has potential, but I don't think American's will go for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216681003.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe if you enter a higher paying system, you can shorten length and increase the percentage. In something like medicine where you don’t make a lot as a resident, you can extend the length. It will depend on the value of the program you’re entering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216723011.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>I think you missed my point. You are trying to reinvent the wheel. We have a government, and we have income taxes. We can have our government institute graduated income taxes (or some other funding system) to pay for university without having to invent a massive new bureaucracy for individually negotiating every single citizen's individual tax rate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216761997.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>But what about people who don’t go to university? Do they still pay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216797709.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>People who have children get a tax credit. People who do not, do not receive one. Invert this for college expenditures. People without college expenditures get a credit to offset the deducted amount, and people with college expenditures do not. 

Or, we could all just decided that a generally well educated citizenry benefits even those without an education, and everyone pays. We could even add programs for those non-college bound people so they can get value from their future taxes as well. That is how we do it for primary schools, and it works fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216936811.0" user="JimboMan1234" delta="False">
    <text>We all pay for the Fire Department whether we need them or not. The point is that they’re a freely accessible public resource.

If public college is paid for by tax dollars (which would only cost roughly 1% of the total budget) then anyone can take a college class at any time. A janitor, security guard, etc. could go take a class on Political Theory or Macroeconomics in their free time at no personal cost to themselves. That’s ultimately very, very good for society. Making it cost anything at all, even if it’s just a % of wages, is an incentive against education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36218500709.0" user="VOTE_TRUMP2020" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, currently, [there are 24 states wherein community college is free to attend.](https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/careers/24-states-where-you-can-attend-community-college-for-free/ss-BB17VhvV#image=27) And in the 26 states that don’t...depending on your household income, you might qualify for a partial or full amount of FAFSA along with any state grants and additional scholarships. If the student does extremely well at community college...then they can then get scholarships from there as any schooling and grades before community college are not looked at. Also, not all colleges are tens of thousands of dollars to attend per year...you can look for affordable colleges and universities in the state or region (as some border and regional states will give you in state tuition despite not living in state) where you live and you can actually get a bachelor’s degree for a reasonable price. Going into a field that is both in high demand and decent paying for whatever your cost of living would be certainly helps:

https://www.educationcorner.com/most-affordable-universities.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36223220180.0" user="sokuyari97" delta="False">
    <text>Why stop there? Shouldn’t all job training and licensure also be tax payer funded? These are forms of learning. 

I think that would create a system where the people who benefit the most from education who are also more likely to have wealth, also get a lot of taxpayer funds allocated to them. 

I personally prefer a system where higher education has SOME reasonable cost associated to it. A method I think is better is to have a percent of earnings for a number of years, but have the max payout capped, and the minimum salary floored. This prevents people from being taken advantage of, while not requiring people to take on debt to pay for college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217475081.0" user="IlIIIIllIlIlIIll" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of the OPs proposed system is individual colleges and people can make/accept their own rates, not that there is a universal set percentage by government. It's the same way government doesn't mandate tuition costs right now, it's set by each school.

As others have pointed out, this already occurs for some schools, and there are benefits and drawbacks to it. But saying it has to, or ought to, be decided by government is off the mark.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217498067.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Their proposed system is an attempt to find a better way to pay for college. I am suggesting that we already have a better way, and that is publicly funded higher education. There is no need to devise a new system to pay for college, since we can leverage our existing systems to accomplish the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217522556.0" user="IlIIIIllIlIlIIll" delta="False">
    <text>This whole CMV is somewhat moot as this practice already exists for many schools. I'm criticizing you saying that to do this it has to go through government: it already doesn't.

We can argue about the pros and cons, but it is simply wrong to say that an earnings based college payment system requires government setting the standards for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217566013.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Most four-year universities are public institutions; the government is already involved. Also, I am not saying that the government *must* do these things, just that it is already set up to manage similar types of graduated, income based withholding schemes. We don't need to completely upend the entire system when we can take advantage of the institutions that we already have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217673950.0" user="IlIIIIllIlIlIIll" delta="False">
    <text>I was initially responding to your comment [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/lhonio/cmv_a_better_way_to_pay_for_college_would_be_a/gmygpgl), which was framed as necessary for government to be involved.

For public schools I agree it's just moving money around since the government is involved. For the thousands of private schools, though, they can give this payments an option, and some already do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217732311.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>I was being glib, and purposely gaming out a system for administering such a payment proposal on a national level that would end up looking like how we already elect people to spend our tax dollars. I recognize that this is not the *only* alternative way for college to be paid for, but for the sake of this discussion, it is the alternative I chose to present.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217340336.0" user="Pismakron" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So... Public education funded by taxes?

Except that the factory worker is not paying for someone elses useless degree in gender studies or culinary arts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36217370798.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? Maybe that factory worker would like to learn about intersectional feminism so he can better communicate and empathize with his recently out of the closet daughter. Or maybe he wants to eat some of that fancy-ass molecular gastronomy he saw on the tv. He is getting value from those people's degrees in those instances, why shouldn't he contribute? Should he just read technical bulletins and eat tinned meat for the rest of his days?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36218138908.0" user="enzovrlrd" delta="False">
    <text>Many large universities in Brazil are public. It takes a great deal of preparation to get into them, making it so that poor people very rarely get into the most disputed courses. It has several flaws too, lack of motivation by professors (many have little incentive to actually have good classes and only focus on research), problems with funding, infrastructure being bad and so on.

I went to private college and faced none of those problems... but I did have to pay for it, so in a way it balances out. In my limited view, the current american system is not inherently bad, it's the amounts that became surreal - though that is not a specific issue with higher education and happens as well in other sections.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36218197152.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>That is interesting. I am only really familiar with the US education system, in which the opposite is somewhat true. Private is way more selective and expensive, and public is, well, public. There are still admission requirements, but they are pretty achievable if you pay attention for 70% of high school.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
