<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1303734472.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/lk7jyg/cmv_we_need_antibias_training_against_age/">
    <title>CMV: We need anti-bias training against age evaluation based on color</title>
    <original_poster>oracvlvm21</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many animal species, including humans, have lighter fur/hair and skin as youngsters. Even the Nazis "saved" little blonde kids who later, to their dismay, turned brunette as they matured. Human adult males, unlike chimpanzees, have been shown to have a preference for younger female mates. This would mean that the joke/meme that blondes are sexier or more desirable, would just be a short cut for saying that men erroneously perceive blondes as younger, which was already their subconscious preference. (Unlike chimpanzees which prefer mature females who have already borne offspring.) In another vein, police often treat black girls as being older than their actual age and hold them to a higher standard than lighter girls. The police could be subconsciously equating dark fur/hair with maturity and misjudging human age. I think we humans in general have a subconscious bias in equating lighter color with youth.  If this is the case I could see how subconscious anti- bias training would be useful for teachers, police, judges etc so children are held to an appropriate and equal developmental standards.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36250155133.0" user="paulsmt" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to provide some scientific evidence for this wild theory you just wrote. 

Racism has nothing to do with ageism. It's just pure racism. 

&amp;gt;police often treat black girls as being older than their actual age and hold them to a higher standard than lighter girls.

Again, some peer reviewed studies or statistics showing this is remotely true would help your point. 

&amp;gt;The police could be subconsciously equating dark fur/hair with maturity and misjudging human age.

Or they could be racist, which we have plenty evidence of. Treating someone as older give them the latitude to mistreat them. 

&amp;gt; I think we humans in general have a subconscious bias in equating lighter color with youth.

I think you just dreamed something that has no real bearing in reality. 

&amp;gt; If this is the case

It doesn't seem to be, unless you have some research to share.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36250217338.0" user="oracvlvm21" delta="False">
    <text>If animals and people are subconciously biased regarding fur color for a biologically plausible reason, then racism is linked to agism as long as color is a variable of race.

There have been many things on-line after a 9 year old was arrested and pepper sprayed in Rochester. I was quoting the studies they mentioned.  Ill have to retrace my steps to find what exactly those are instead of just taking their word for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36250255797.0" user="paulsmt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If animals and people are subconciously biased regarding fur color for a biologically plausible reason,

That's a big if. Unless you have some reliable research to back up your opinion, that's just an opinion and not a fact. 

You can't base a full theory on an unproven opinion. 

It's like saying, if water burns like gasoline, then I can fill my tank with water and drive around. 

&amp;gt;I was quoting the studies they mentioned.

I didn't see any links to any studies in your original post. 

Besides, the 3 officers that have been suspended for failing to follow procedure. They were just being abusive to an uncooperative minor.

You're trying to make a generalization out of one incident.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36250492976.0" user="oracvlvm21" delta="False">
    <text>
That there are no studies doesnt make the idea wrong, just unsubstantiated. A person can make an intuitive argument and chain of reasoning.  Theories are usually created and then experiments or studies are done to test its validity.  Im confused why it would make any difference that its an opinion. This forum is to change views, which are opinions, not to change facts.
Are you aware of any studies that would contradict the possibility of color bias in vertebrate mate selection or perception of age?

I went to look up the study about black children being adultified that I referred to. It was by Georgetown Law Center on Poverty and Inequality in 2017.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36256582188.0" user="paulsmt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A person can make an intuitive argument and chain of reasoning. 

You need some sort of evidence for any kind of reasoning to follow. 

If the argument has no foundation, you can't. 

&amp;gt;Theories are usually created and then experiments or studies are done to test its validity.

Theories start from observable phenomenon and then a possible explanation for the phenomenon. 

You have no evidence that humans in general believe blondes are younger and dark hair/dark skin people are older for mating reasons. 

You went on a wild chase saying light fur color = attraction therefore young, without any evidence of any of that. 

There are studies that show blond WOMEN (but not men) attract more mates but the reasons have nothing to do with age. 

https://www.bustle.com/articles/174831-why-are-people-attracted-to-certain-hair-colors-what-science-knows-about-the-phenomenon

&amp;gt;The Attraction To Blondes May Also Be Based On Rarity

blond hair and light eye color are recessive genetically speaking, therefore rarer. The rarity makes it attractive. 

&amp;gt;Bias Against Redheads May Be Both Genetic &amp;amp; Societal

Redheads show lack of genetic diversity, therefore less attractive. 

Some of the same conclusions here

https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/slightly-blighty/201509/which-hair-color-induces-the-strongest-physical-attraction

&amp;gt;Are you aware of any studies that would contradict the possibility of color bias in vertebrate mate selection or perception of age?

I can't prove a negative. "Are you aware of any studies that prove me wrong" is not a valid inquiry in a debate. You came up with the theory, you need to come up with the evidence.

It's like me saying there's an undetectable dark matter comet that's going to hit Earth in 30 days and it will be a ELE. Do you know of any studies that disprove that? 

&amp;gt;I went to look up the study about black children being adultified that I referred to. It was by Georgetown Law Center on Poverty and Inequality in 2017.

You need to actually read the study and not reach wrong conclusions from headlines. 

https://www.law.georgetown.edu/poverty-inequality-center/wp-content/uploads/sites/14/2017/08/girlhood-interrupted.pdf

&amp;gt;Black boys are more likely than their white peers to be misperceived as older, viewed as guilty of suspected crimes, and face police violence if accused of a crimes.

What the study concludes is that many black kids are seeing as more mature than white kids, making easier to attach guilt to their actions. The root is racism and not sexual. It affects black boys AND girls.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36251693697.0" user="bio-nerd" delta="False">
    <text>A white grandparent will never treated by the police the same way as a black man in his 20s. A black 9 y.o. does not look like an adult. Ageism is not a factor here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
