<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1303734472.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/lk7jyg/cmv_we_need_antibias_training_against_age/">
    <title>CMV: We need anti-bias training against age evaluation based on color</title>
    <original_poster>oracvlvm21</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many animal species, including humans, have lighter fur/hair and skin as youngsters. Even the Nazis "saved" little blonde kids who later, to their dismay, turned brunette as they matured. Human adult males, unlike chimpanzees, have been shown to have a preference for younger female mates. This would mean that the joke/meme that blondes are sexier or more desirable, would just be a short cut for saying that men erroneously perceive blondes as younger, which was already their subconscious preference. (Unlike chimpanzees which prefer mature females who have already borne offspring.) In another vein, police often treat black girls as being older than their actual age and hold them to a higher standard than lighter girls. The police could be subconsciously equating dark fur/hair with maturity and misjudging human age. I think we humans in general have a subconscious bias in equating lighter color with youth.  If this is the case I could see how subconscious anti- bias training would be useful for teachers, police, judges etc so children are held to an appropriate and equal developmental standards.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36250445455.0" user="TheLastCoagulant" delta="False">
    <text>Northeast Asians (Korean, Japanese, Chinese) are seen as younger than their age and still experience racism. 

The age thing isn't the cause of racism, it's the result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36250547266.0" user="oracvlvm21" delta="False">
    <text>I assume you mean discrimination against Asians in the US?

I dont tend to believe the age thing is the result of racism because I personally experienced hair color bias in my culture as a child and we kids were from the same race.

I dont think we know if Asians being perceived as younger lets them be held to the younger age standards as children in their own cultures? I wonder if there is any interracial/interethnic color bias within each of these Asians countries among the same ethnicities.

It would be interesting to see studies considering asians of different colors, such as in India, for example whether or not the darker Sudras and Untouchables are seen as older than their age, IN INDIA.

The study by the Georgetown Law Center on Poverty and Inequality in 2017 studied the adultification of black children in the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
