<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="131286507.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/265xbf/cmv_largescale_societal_collapse_is_inevitable/">
    <title>CMV: Large-scale societal collapse is inevitable, and we are past the point where it can be stopped or significantly remedied.</title>
    <original_poster>moonmixer</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am strongly convinced that sometime within the next century, industrial society as we know it will either collapse or begin an inevitable and possibly irreversible decline (at least for a long period of time). The result will be something resembling the fall of the Roman Empire, but on a larger spatial scale (most of the earth, if not all of it).

A) Global warming exists, is snowballing out of control, and very little is being done in terms of future damage control. Notice that I did not say "to stop it": an integral part of my belief is that global warming is past the point of being stopped, and that we are already destined for disastrous consequences. We are not adequately preparing for these consequences, we are essentially ignoring them.

B) Wealth inequality is at an all time high, and another great depression looms. The most powerful economies in the world are controlled by a small subset of insanely rich companies/individuals, which are not concerned with the welfare of the common citizen in a great enough way to be meaningful. We did not fix the problems that caused the economic crisis beginning ~2008, and if anything they have become worse, placing more money in the hands of individuals that are too self-interested to spend it well. This leads to my next point...

C) Dissatisfaction with the status quo (amongst the middle and lower classes, especially on the international scale) is at an all-time high. I am not talking about the dissatisfaction of "first world problems," but of the violence exhibited by terrorist organizations (Boko Haram being the most recent and startling example). The hegemonic economy of the USA and its allies has been in place for too long, holding down smaller and poorer countries to the point where the damage is done. There is enough hate for the "Western World" to destroy it, should the correct opportunity arise. This also pertains to the most economically suppressed/oppressed in the USA, Mexico and Canada, drug cartels, street gangs and the like.

D) We are overdue for a severe plague. This point is related to point A: increasing occurence of natural disasters and destruction of infrastructure will lead to an outbreak of an already virulent and drug-resistant strain of TB, influenza (H5N1, etc.), or some other disease (ebola, malaria).

Together, I think these factors present a grim case for continuance of an industrial/scientific global community. 

I might also add point E: nuclear war. I don't think mutually assured destruction is *likely* to play out, but the possibility always exists, at which point we not only face societal collapse but the end of the human race.

So please... CMV?

edit: These are a lot of points, so I'll name the two that I think are the most threatening, those being A and B. D is also very threatening, but I think the possibility of enacting damage control and quaratines can save a large part of (at least, the industrialized) world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27189702130.0" user="JoshuaZ1" delta="False">
    <text>Some of these are more problems than others. There's a decent argument that having nuclear weapons has actually lead to peace, because major powers are afraid of engaging in a direct confrontation. This is the [nuclear peace hypothesis](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclear_peace). And in fact, by many metrics the last sixty years has been one of the most peaceful times in recorded history (see Steven Pinker's "The Better Angels of Our Nature" for example). Unfortunately, this may be the mother of all [survivorship  biases](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias), if species once they develop nukes do frequently wipe themselves out, the only observes around will note that their species have been very peaceful after the construction of nuclear weapons. 

If one is seriously concerned about nuclear weapons, one should also be particularly concerned about events in the last few months: At the end of the Cold War, the various former Soviet states gave up their nukes in exchange for various promises from Russia and the US. Ukraine was one of those. The lesson that any country thinking of either developing or giving up nuclear weapons must now conclude is that giving up nukes for paper assurances is not a good bargain. The more recent nuclear states like North Korea, India, Pakistan and Israel must be very aware of this at this point.

&amp;gt; We are overdue for a severe plague. 

I don't think this makes sense. This sounds a bit like the [gambler's fallacy](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gambler%27s_fallacy). Moreover, as more and more of the world is explored, the remaining resevoirs for potential new hidden diseases becomes smaller However, there is a potentially relevant issue here that goes in the other direction: modern transport networks allow diseases to travel much faster: in particular, a novel air born disease would have a fun time with airplanes. Even without airplanes, this connected infrastructure makes for serious problems: in many parts of Africa, HIV has spread in part [via long distance truck drivers](http://www.theafricareport.com/East-Horn-Africa/long-distance-truck-drivers-are-spreading-hiv-museveni.html). Note that this is actually to some extent the opposite of what you seem to be worried about: here the presence of infrastructure makes disease spread easier.

&amp;gt; Wealth inequality is at an all time high

Do you have a citation for this? Also, is it that much of a problem? To some extent, in order to have extreme wealth inequality one needs advanced technology and prosperous societies. In say a simple tribal culture, the level of difference between the top 1% and the rest won't be large for the simple reason that there's not much stuff to go around. Similarly, one can imagine a far future culture where the lowest standard of living is close to that of a millionaire now, but the wealthiest people own their own planets. In that case, the wealth gap would be even larger, but I'm not sure it would be a problem or lead to instability. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189738914.0" user="moonmixer" delta="False">
    <text>First, already got my view changed. But thanks for your comprehensive response.

The wealth inequality was a bit tacked on, and probably the least of my concerns.

Travel infrastructure is one thing to be concerned about when it comes to disease, the other thing being extreme drug resistance. Specifically, strains of extremely drug resistant TB and influenza have been developing worldwide due to incorrect use of antibiotics. [Here](http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0000309#pone-0000309-g001) is a study on multi-drug resistant potentially plague-causing bacteria.

As far as nukes go, I'd be interested to hear your thoughts on the efficacy of "nuke shield" missile defense systems. I'll also need to read up more on nuclear peace... it seems unlikely that nukes could lead to full-scale nuclear winter. Call me an optimist, but I don't see it happening. Nuclear winter is in no one's best interest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189748841.0" user="JoshuaZ1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As far as nukes go, I'd be interested to hear your thoughts on the efficacy of "nuke shield" missile defense systems

There's an argument that missile defense systems actually are destabilizing: if one buys in something like mutually assured destruction then they now make it possible for a country to launch a large-scale attack on another and possibly survive the counter-strike.

&amp;gt; it seems unlikely that nukes could lead to full-scale nuclear winter. 

Nuclear winter isn't the only problem created by nuclear weapons. Moreover, it is worth noting that one doesn't necessarily need to have a complete destruction of humanity to have an irrecoverable collapse event. This has been pointed out by Nick Bostrom, a philosopher at the Future of Humanity Institute (which spends its time thinking about these issues). He's pointed out that human civilization got to its current status by bootstrapping with easily accessible coal and oil, and most of the technologically easy to access  coal and oil is now exhausted as are some other helpful resources, like most peat and large parts of forests. It is possible that we simply won't have the energy available to return to current tech levels. 

(Incidentally, if people really are concerned about this sort of thing they can take concrete steps by donating to the [Future of Humanity Institute](http://www.fhi.ox.ac.uk/)). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
