<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="131286507.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/265xbf/cmv_largescale_societal_collapse_is_inevitable/">
    <title>CMV: Large-scale societal collapse is inevitable, and we are past the point where it can be stopped or significantly remedied.</title>
    <original_poster>moonmixer</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am strongly convinced that sometime within the next century, industrial society as we know it will either collapse or begin an inevitable and possibly irreversible decline (at least for a long period of time). The result will be something resembling the fall of the Roman Empire, but on a larger spatial scale (most of the earth, if not all of it).

A) Global warming exists, is snowballing out of control, and very little is being done in terms of future damage control. Notice that I did not say "to stop it": an integral part of my belief is that global warming is past the point of being stopped, and that we are already destined for disastrous consequences. We are not adequately preparing for these consequences, we are essentially ignoring them.

B) Wealth inequality is at an all time high, and another great depression looms. The most powerful economies in the world are controlled by a small subset of insanely rich companies/individuals, which are not concerned with the welfare of the common citizen in a great enough way to be meaningful. We did not fix the problems that caused the economic crisis beginning ~2008, and if anything they have become worse, placing more money in the hands of individuals that are too self-interested to spend it well. This leads to my next point...

C) Dissatisfaction with the status quo (amongst the middle and lower classes, especially on the international scale) is at an all-time high. I am not talking about the dissatisfaction of "first world problems," but of the violence exhibited by terrorist organizations (Boko Haram being the most recent and startling example). The hegemonic economy of the USA and its allies has been in place for too long, holding down smaller and poorer countries to the point where the damage is done. There is enough hate for the "Western World" to destroy it, should the correct opportunity arise. This also pertains to the most economically suppressed/oppressed in the USA, Mexico and Canada, drug cartels, street gangs and the like.

D) We are overdue for a severe plague. This point is related to point A: increasing occurence of natural disasters and destruction of infrastructure will lead to an outbreak of an already virulent and drug-resistant strain of TB, influenza (H5N1, etc.), or some other disease (ebola, malaria).

Together, I think these factors present a grim case for continuance of an industrial/scientific global community. 

I might also add point E: nuclear war. I don't think mutually assured destruction is *likely* to play out, but the possibility always exists, at which point we not only face societal collapse but the end of the human race.

So please... CMV?

edit: These are a lot of points, so I'll name the two that I think are the most threatening, those being A and B. D is also very threatening, but I think the possibility of enacting damage control and quaratines can save a large part of (at least, the industrialized) world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27189576710.0" user="Palidane7" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know much about Global Warming, but I'm extremely skeptical that the damage is irreversible.

Wealth inequality? Uhh, yeah, it exists, like it always has. I would like to see you cite a source for it being at an all time high, as that seems extremely unlikely. Everyone and their dog has a different opinion on what caused the Recession, so I'm not exactly sure what you're alluding to...

Dissatisfaction with the status quo? Are you freaking kidding me? Can you name a single point in human history where everyone was cool with the status quo? I'm pretty sure terrorism is down across the board. Oh no, smaller and poorer countries don't like "the Western World"! What are they going to do? Absolutely freaking nothing, because they are small and poor. What the hell is South America and Africa, and maybe parts of Asia going to do against Europe and the US? And how do you even know they "hate" us? You got a source for that? I would think a poor African villager would rather spend his time surviving than hating some distant land of a distant people that he hears have it better than him.

Last I checked, plagues didn't happen on timers. We have made about a million and a half groundbreaking medical discoveries since the last real plague, and I see zero reason why we should be worried about some sudden outbreak coming out of nowhere. I mean, the CDC does exist for a reason, and to quote Cracked: "They tend not to fuck around. Seriously, it's on their business cards!".

It's kind of sad that nuclear war is the most legitimate concern of yours. The thing is, Nukes are not necessarily a problem, as long as only rational people have them. Right now, there are only two countries that A). Have nukes and B). Are retarded enough to use them. So yeah, we should keep an eye on Iran and North Korea, but they've had nukes for years, and they haven't used them yet.

Look man, you just have to look on the bright side of life. Sure, we will face challenges in the future, but we have overcome much worse, and there's no reason to think that we can't handle all of the above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189643994.0" user="moonmixer" delta="False">
    <text>No need to be harsh, I named ALL my concerns for the sake of completeness. 

This being said: 

In terms of plague, we have never before seen THIS amount of drug-resistance in disease, mostly because we have never before used this amount of drugs to treat diseases. Drug resistance is of growing concern (even for the CDC), I don't think you should ignore it.

The damage from global warming might not be *fully* irreversible, but I'm talking about ENOUGH damage to cause societal collapse. 

Edit: its not like i'm cowering in a corner waiting for the world to end. I live my life as if I'll be able to live it for 200 more years. Problem is, I might teach myself some survival skills if I have to start providing food for my family and friends. The danger from drought and natural disaster to food production (coincidentally, the one point I made that you didn't know enough about to answer) is the largest danger from global warming that we face.

Another edit: woulda given you the delta, but for your abrasive tone and incomplete answer... someone else gets this one man. Your points on wealth inequality and dissatisfaction with the status quo were almost identical with those of the "winner," except for the "freaking kidding me"s. "It's kind of sad" that you had to be so rude about it :/
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
