<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="131286507.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/265xbf/cmv_largescale_societal_collapse_is_inevitable/">
    <title>CMV: Large-scale societal collapse is inevitable, and we are past the point where it can be stopped or significantly remedied.</title>
    <original_poster>moonmixer</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am strongly convinced that sometime within the next century, industrial society as we know it will either collapse or begin an inevitable and possibly irreversible decline (at least for a long period of time). The result will be something resembling the fall of the Roman Empire, but on a larger spatial scale (most of the earth, if not all of it).

A) Global warming exists, is snowballing out of control, and very little is being done in terms of future damage control. Notice that I did not say "to stop it": an integral part of my belief is that global warming is past the point of being stopped, and that we are already destined for disastrous consequences. We are not adequately preparing for these consequences, we are essentially ignoring them.

B) Wealth inequality is at an all time high, and another great depression looms. The most powerful economies in the world are controlled by a small subset of insanely rich companies/individuals, which are not concerned with the welfare of the common citizen in a great enough way to be meaningful. We did not fix the problems that caused the economic crisis beginning ~2008, and if anything they have become worse, placing more money in the hands of individuals that are too self-interested to spend it well. This leads to my next point...

C) Dissatisfaction with the status quo (amongst the middle and lower classes, especially on the international scale) is at an all-time high. I am not talking about the dissatisfaction of "first world problems," but of the violence exhibited by terrorist organizations (Boko Haram being the most recent and startling example). The hegemonic economy of the USA and its allies has been in place for too long, holding down smaller and poorer countries to the point where the damage is done. There is enough hate for the "Western World" to destroy it, should the correct opportunity arise. This also pertains to the most economically suppressed/oppressed in the USA, Mexico and Canada, drug cartels, street gangs and the like.

D) We are overdue for a severe plague. This point is related to point A: increasing occurence of natural disasters and destruction of infrastructure will lead to an outbreak of an already virulent and drug-resistant strain of TB, influenza (H5N1, etc.), or some other disease (ebola, malaria).

Together, I think these factors present a grim case for continuance of an industrial/scientific global community. 

I might also add point E: nuclear war. I don't think mutually assured destruction is *likely* to play out, but the possibility always exists, at which point we not only face societal collapse but the end of the human race.

So please... CMV?

edit: These are a lot of points, so I'll name the two that I think are the most threatening, those being A and B. D is also very threatening, but I think the possibility of enacting damage control and quaratines can save a large part of (at least, the industrialized) world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27189602158.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The sky is falling! The sky is falling!

Yeah, people have been saying it's the end of society since there has been a society. 
There have been worse times than this globally and society always adapts and moves on. This will be no different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189636851.0" user="moonmixer" delta="False">
    <text>The sky is falling is a much more persuasive argument when it is literally happening.

You have successfully ignored all my arguments and done nothing to convince me... good job?

Edit: at least respond to point A, global food production is likely to take a hit due to drought and natural disaster. Ignoring this possibility and then being facetious about it makes you look like an ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189643307.0" user="Benjamin_The_Donkey" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The sky is falling! The sky is falling!

In that same vein, I could just as easily argue that you're burying your head in the sand and assuming problems will just get fixed because "society always adapts and moves on". </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
