<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="131286507.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/265xbf/cmv_largescale_societal_collapse_is_inevitable/">
    <title>CMV: Large-scale societal collapse is inevitable, and we are past the point where it can be stopped or significantly remedied.</title>
    <original_poster>moonmixer</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am strongly convinced that sometime within the next century, industrial society as we know it will either collapse or begin an inevitable and possibly irreversible decline (at least for a long period of time). The result will be something resembling the fall of the Roman Empire, but on a larger spatial scale (most of the earth, if not all of it).

A) Global warming exists, is snowballing out of control, and very little is being done in terms of future damage control. Notice that I did not say "to stop it": an integral part of my belief is that global warming is past the point of being stopped, and that we are already destined for disastrous consequences. We are not adequately preparing for these consequences, we are essentially ignoring them.

B) Wealth inequality is at an all time high, and another great depression looms. The most powerful economies in the world are controlled by a small subset of insanely rich companies/individuals, which are not concerned with the welfare of the common citizen in a great enough way to be meaningful. We did not fix the problems that caused the economic crisis beginning ~2008, and if anything they have become worse, placing more money in the hands of individuals that are too self-interested to spend it well. This leads to my next point...

C) Dissatisfaction with the status quo (amongst the middle and lower classes, especially on the international scale) is at an all-time high. I am not talking about the dissatisfaction of "first world problems," but of the violence exhibited by terrorist organizations (Boko Haram being the most recent and startling example). The hegemonic economy of the USA and its allies has been in place for too long, holding down smaller and poorer countries to the point where the damage is done. There is enough hate for the "Western World" to destroy it, should the correct opportunity arise. This also pertains to the most economically suppressed/oppressed in the USA, Mexico and Canada, drug cartels, street gangs and the like.

D) We are overdue for a severe plague. This point is related to point A: increasing occurence of natural disasters and destruction of infrastructure will lead to an outbreak of an already virulent and drug-resistant strain of TB, influenza (H5N1, etc.), or some other disease (ebola, malaria).

Together, I think these factors present a grim case for continuance of an industrial/scientific global community. 

I might also add point E: nuclear war. I don't think mutually assured destruction is *likely* to play out, but the possibility always exists, at which point we not only face societal collapse but the end of the human race.

So please... CMV?

edit: These are a lot of points, so I'll name the two that I think are the most threatening, those being A and B. D is also very threatening, but I think the possibility of enacting damage control and quaratines can save a large part of (at least, the industrialized) world.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27189580785.0" user="SurrealistSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, in my more melancholic hours, I very much feel like you do. Alas, it is a very romantic notion that humanity will hit a 'reset' button and start again. I, for one, believe any change will take a long time and will be gradual. But let's take it point by point: 

**A)** Global warming. Indeed, *if we assume science remains as it is over the next century*, we are past the point of no return. Mankind is, nevertheless, a rather inventive species and should things reach the boiling point (no pun intended), I firmly believe we will find a solution. Two supporting arguments: some of the most inventive periods in our history came at times of crisis - World War II, as an example. Global warming can develop into such a crisis. Secondly, there are various [geo-engineering projects proposed](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_proposed_geoengineering_projects), such as sulfate aerosols, which have a sound scientific backing and could provide an effective 'quick fix'. I know it feels wrong to 'cheat' our way out of global warming, but there is a strong possibility that exactly this will happen. 

**B)** Wealth inequality. This has been a problem throughout history. The Egyptians had it, the Ottomans had it, the Russians had it, the English had it (and still have it). It's nothing new. We perceive it as increasing after a period of relative socialism in the West but, frankly, I don't think the problem is any worse than it was during feudal times. If the gap becomes too large, a popular movement will restore the equilibrium, like it always has throughout history. Sure, there might be a period of instability, but a return of the dark ages is a rather gloomy prospect. If anything, we would see changes similar to those in Russia and China as they moved away from monarchy towards state capitalism. 

**C)** Dissatisfaction with the status quo. This is a cop-out, I think. Sure, the period of Western dominance might end, but would this cause a 'large scale societal collapse'? That's a bit presumptuous. There are plenty of other countries in the world whose economies would adapt to new circumstances. Sure, the era of relative prosperity in the West at the expense of the developing world might end, but that still leaves 6 billion people doing the same as or perhaps even better than before. The West does not equal global society. As for violence and terrorist organisations... human history is littered with wars and conflicts. In fact, we are probably living in times safer than ever before. There have always been groups of maniacs and there probably always will be. One of them is yet to cause global disintegration. 

**D)** A global plague. Really, this brings me back to point A). With our medical know-how, I would place any bets in the 'we'll develop a vaccine/solution fairly quickly' column. 

**E)** Nuclear war. A valid concern. 'Nuclear shield' would be my answer, as these are quite advanced these days. 

At any rate - my two cents. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27189657375.0" user="moonmixer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#8710;

So far, least abrasive (for some reason I drew out the assholes with this post) and most complete response in the thread. I'm not always so melancholy, but sometimes I decide that the risk is great and that perhaps, preparation for the worst isn't a terrible idea.

I won't say preparation is a BAD idea now that you've convinced me, but I certainly feel better about it (and less scared). Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27190037019.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like you have been a victim of sensationalistic fear mongering. I suggest you take the articles you read on Reddit or see on the news with a grain of salt, and A LOT of skepticism. Try to find key buzzwords like "catastrophe" or "global disaster" or any other "end of the world" rhetoric, and then you'll be able to more easily weed out the bullshit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27190264544.0" user="moonmixer" delta="False">
    <text>It's  not just "articles on reddit and the news." I study science, and there are published journal articles describing the type of catastrophes we might face in the coming century resulting from drought and natural disaster. 

This being said, there's a difference between acknowledging the possibility of hardship and assuming industrial society will collapse. That difference was highlighted by the post I awarded the delta to. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
