<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197033372.0" user="jmsolerm" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like your problem is that you think you have a problem (and the problem you think you have and the problem you have are different).

Masturbation is generally healthy, and a couple times a week prevents prostate and even heart problems. It's a physical necessity, not like food or sleep, but closer to sunlight.

You are trying to achieve an unhealthy ideal, seeing *every* day you don't fap as a great success. And I understand the satisfaction, I do nofap months now and then.

But those months are *exceptions*, tests I do to myself to check my mental and hormonal balance, as well as my self-control. It *is* satisfying when I accomplish it, but after that, I go *completely* guilt free.

&amp;gt; This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you.

tl;dr: what's bad for you isn't masturbation, but feeling masturbation is bad.

EDIT: And perhaps that you think the state of mind after orgasm is negative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197038916.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I masturbated three or four times a day. I need help. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197056535.0" user="jmsolerm" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, that is kind of excessive, but not worse than my teen self (I think I got to 4 daily for a while). And still, that doesn't mean masturbation is bad. Following my sunlight analogy: the fact that there are people addicted to tanning beds doesn't mean some sunlight isn't healthy.

I recommend you visit /r/sex if you think you do need help. But in general, just cutting out something generally healthy that you have a strong urge to do is not a good idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197060748.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just gonna cut down. Once a week or so. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
