<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197116001.0" user="TheSicilianDude" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's a sweeping generalization to say that masturbation is bad. I too was a member of /r/NoFap but left it because I don't think total abstinence is really the answer.

You could look at masturbation the same way you look at a lot of other things that can be addicting (drinking, watching TV, salty foods, smoking weed, video games, etc.) Some people would say that these things *per se* are bad. I don't agree. I think they are all fine *in moderation.* But in excess, they are bad. Too much drinking leads to alcoholism. Too much TV/video games, and especially weed, leads to laziness. Too much salty food just isn't healthy.

Too much masturbation desensitizes the penis, and you become very addicted. When you actually get with a sexual partner, you'll probably have a hard time getting it up. When I masturbate a lot, I also feel pretty out of it during the day. And I don't like that.

But the big takeway I got from /r/NoFap was cutting down on my masturbation. And it was a good thing. Each time I did masturbate was better, and it became much less of a habit that I HAD to do before bed. I also started having more sex because I put more effort toward meeting women.

So, masturbation by itself is not bad for you. When you just HAVE to do it all the time, that's when it gets bad. Because it's a sign you've become addicted, and then comes the opportunity for you to practice self-control. If you are masturbating excessively (more than once per day is too much. I even think once per day can be too much), make efforts to cut down on it. 3-4 times a week would be a good start.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
