<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197013417.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>I would simply argue that your experience is subjective.  That is to say, it may be bad for **you**, but that doesn't mean it's bad for **me**.  If it has that effect on you, then more power to you for stopping, but it doesn't make **me** feel depressed.  It just has a different effect on different people.

I can't argue about your personal experience.  It may very well be that you're a lot happier without it, and I'm genuinely happy that you figured that out, but to say that by extension, it's bad for ME would be like a lactose-intolerant person telling me that milk is bad for me because it makes them feel sick.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197019454.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>Can't argue with that. Different feelings for different people. 

I feel a lot more better without it, that's for sure. I feel better without it than I do with it. I guess that's what makes me stop. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197032183.0" user="rynomachine" delta="False">
    <text>If you feel better when you don't do it, why did you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197035729.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>Why do people smoke when they know it's bad for them? It's addictive because it feels good. It's hard to quit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197039241.0" user="rynomachine" delta="False">
    <text>I think it only makes you feel bad because you've attached a stigma to it. You feel bad because you believe you deserve to feel vad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197040880.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>The real question is here is:  do you feel bad *because* it is a goal of yours not to do it?  For example, if I gave myself the goal of not drinking orange juice (or whatever) and become really invested in seeing this through, if I give in and break my "streak" of orange juice free days, I'll feel bad about this.  The reason I feel bad is because I failed at my goal, not because there is something to the orange juice itself that is bad.  

So is masturbation bad for you, or is it just that you've given yourself this goal and are *making* it bad by making the act of masturbating a personal failure?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197047899.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>Dammit people. Stop making me question what I think, but, yes. I think you and a few others are right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197305896.0" user="kataskopo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Stop making me question what I think, 

Well, you are in change my view! If we didn't, we wouldn't be here.

I think you need to look hard and honestly at yourself and ask you why do you think masturbation is bad for you.

What I do when I want to figure things out, is to start talking with myself about. Just talk about it, what it feels and how it feels and why.

Don't sugar coat it or try to be polite with yourself, be blunt and say why don't you like it (that's why I recommend you to do it with yourself, because only yourself will be there to judge you)

Really, be honest, why does it feel bad? Say whatever you think, and keep refining that thought until it matches whatever is you are feeling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197062265.0" user="liMePod" delta="False">
    <text>The placebo effect is a real thing. If someone tells you that no masturbating will make you feel better and you believe them, next time you go without masturbating you will feel better regardless of whether or not it has any basis in fact. 

Confirmation bias means that once you have decided that not masturbating makes you feel better, you will convince yourself that you feel better when you abstain, regardless of whether you actually do or not.

Edit: added example: If there were an active subreddit called nowifi, that was convinced that turning off their wifi was making them feel better, they're not lying: it actually may. But the lack of wifi is not what's causing them to feel better, its their conviction that turning off the wifi is beneficial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197063990.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I was just thinking about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27198115023.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>Does that mean that /u/scottevil110 changed your view? After all, you said that Masturbation was bad for US, but now you say you can't argue with what he said.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
