<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197921608.0" user="Inceptagon" delta="False">
    <text>You could replace masturbation with any bad habit and you could make the same argument. 

It's not about *what* you're doing, it's about the fact that you feel bad that you're failing at self-control. 

I think there's also something that sex does for you chemically. The rush of endorphins and dopamine you get from an orgasm can cause you to feel deep shame under certain circumstances, rather than comfort and satiation, but I'm not an expert, so research it deeper if you want.

A bad habit, any bad habit, is composed of a trigger, a ritual, and a reward. If you figure out what the trigger is, or if you figure out how to circumvent the ritual, or how to get your reward from a different source, you can break the habit. Your trigger for arousal and masturbation might be an image on a web site you visit frequently, or a desktop wallpaper in your rotation, or someone you see in real life. After that trigger happens, you can't take your mind off of it until the ritual and the reward is over with.

But if you were a member of /r/NoFap then it's probably nothing you didn't already know.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
