<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197164318.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>I've read much of what you've said here, and it appears that your real objection to masturbation is basically religious.  Let me try this.

OK, it's a sin and you're a sinner.  Will you not be a sinner if you stop masturbating?  Sure you should try not to sin, clearly you do care about that, but you will never, ever stop sinning.  Own it.

The guilt you feel is out of proportion to the sin.  Why is that?  Are you worried about the judgement of others?  If you're having this much difficulty, do you really believe most others are having an easier time of it?  Likely anyone who is judging you is lying about their own success.

Take a look at the flair in /r/nofap.  You see a few high numbers, and lots and lots of numbers under 30.  Those people are having as much trouble as you are.

Keep trying, set a goal and try to achieve it.  There's nothing wrong with not masturbating, but there's no reason to feel as badly as you describe when you do.

Be a good person, try to be a better one.  Jesus will forgive you, so shouldn't you forgive yourself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197176619.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I'm atheist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197407544.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>Me too.  I was taking a shot. 

Seriously,though, what's the thing about it that warrants the self flagellation? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27200014935.0" user="123123123213123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;OK, it's a sin and you're a sinner. Will you not be a sinner if you stop masturbating? Sure you should try not to sin, clearly you do care about that, but you will never, ever stop sinning. Own it.

Using the same argument you can tell OP that it's ok to steal or murder, since "he's a sinner anyway".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27200390670.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>Quite the conundrm, unless you accept that some sins are worse than others.   

Truthfully, I was not really being sincere.  There is nothing wrong with masturbation.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
