<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197018713.0" user="eggies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself.

Personal experience: when I hit adolescence, I developed a quick temper and became a roiling ball of frustration. When I added regular masturbation to my routine, a lot of those feelings got channeled away into happy orgasms, and my temper settled out. 

Of course, correlation does not imply causation, and it is possible that my angry adolescent phase was short for other reasons.

But I have more personal experience: when it has been a few days since I have had sex or masturbated, I find that I've got a little bit of an edge of irritation going on. I get frustrated or angry more easily. Having sex or masturbating generally makes those feelings go away. I travel through life on a much more even keel when I masturbate regularly. I'm better able to focus on goals and tasks that do not have anything to do with sexy times.

I will note that all this works better if I take the time to enjoy masturbating or having sex. Quickies are okay here and there, but taking time to enjoy things generally tends to lead to calmer, more focused periods after.

I also sleep better, and take more naps.

None of this is scientific. But I suspect your feelings of depression and shame arise from your attitudes toward masturbation, rather than from harm in the act itself. It's just solo sex, after all. I think that a lot more harm comes from trying to control your sex drive for whatever reason: it's much better to incorporate that drive into your routine, enjoy the pleasurable things your body can do, and get on with your life.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
