<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197033369.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You, personally, have connected a sense of achievement to not masturbating for a while. That is why it is stressful to you. I have not, masturbation is nothing to me but a pleasant pastime.

In fact, masturbating is healthy due to the prostate and stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197037045.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I've been told. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197040549.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So you agree that masturbation is not inherently bad for a person? That it is only bad for you due to the connection you've made?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197047029.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I- I think. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197057998.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'd advise you to try a period with max masturbation. See how many you can cram into an hour, a day, or a week! Get a new sense of accomplishment.

Or don't. I dunno.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197908880.0" user="tenpoundpen" delta="False">
    <text>As a man who "only" masturbates once or twice a week... That sounds very tiring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27198142759.0" user="Dulousaci" delta="False">
    <text>You'll get in better shape then.

Personally, I'd be more worried about chafing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
