<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197004066.0" user="SOLUNAR" delta="False">
    <text>you really made no argument as why its bad for you.

You just describe your sad you broke your streak, okay.

So why is it bad for you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197011025.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>I feel sad and pretty disgusted with myself when I masturbate. When I didn't I felt more focused, less anxiety, more emotions towards people, just better in general. While I masturbated I felt none of this except more anxiety. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197060502.0" user="help-Im-alive" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so there are really only two healthy options here. Either stop doing the thing that makes you feel bad, or stop feeling bad about it. It's not unhealthy. There's no physiological difference between cuming in your hand and cuming in a vagina, so unless you have some sort of heart condition you aren't hurting yourself in any way. The only reason not to is because you feel like you aren't supposed to (hence the guilt). 

Maybe it's a religious thing and you think Jesus is judging you. Maybe you think only lonely perverts masturbate so clearly you're no better than them. Maybe you think if anyone knew they would judge the fuck out of you and so you should be doing the same. In the end, though, none of that is true. Sure, some people would judge you but some people should fuck off. If it doesn't hurt you and it doesn't hurt anyone else and no one even knows about it anyway, then do what you want and don't worry about what anyone else would think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197629478.0" user="TsukiBear" delta="False">
    <text>So your problem is not masturbation, it's *anxiety*.

All you've done is use jerking off as your fall guy for your mental illness.  See a doctor, ask about medication, and follow the advice they tell you.  Anxiety is an illness, just like anything else.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
