<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197410041.0" user="DreamCatcher24" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that it isn't masturbation itself that is affecting you but how you perceive it. You have a view that it isn't good for you and that it is desirable for you stop doing this. So when you fail, you naturally feel gloomy. For instance, a common thing for people is to change their diet. They may want to stop drinking Coke or Pepsi. When they have a can of coke or pepsi they will then feel down about it because it was made to be an imperative goal to quit. You are in the same boat. Now coke and pepsi are bad for various reasons, but I do know people that drink it once in a while and are in fairly good shape.

For whatever reason you dislike masturbation, it is your perception of it that makes it bad. It isn't inherent in the act itself. Many people do lead healthy lives. Although in certain cultures it is viewed as sinful. So why do you think masturbation is inherently bad? Don't tell me it makes you depressed, because you have socialized yourself to feel this way. How would tell someone you enjoys it that it is bad?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
