<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="132059005.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/26mhdp/cmv_i_think_masturbation_is_bad_for_you/">
    <title>CMV: I think masturbation is bad for you.</title>
    <original_poster>TextingWhileDriving</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to be part of the /r/NoFap community and felt good about it. I had a sense of pride when a day passed without masturbation squeezed in there. However, I never went longer than 2 weeks without masturbating. Each time I masturbated I felt a sense of dread and depression, knowing I would just masturbate again sometime later. 

Today I broke my 4 day streak. I feel depressed and stressed. This basically confirms how I felt about masturbation in the beginning. It's bad for you. You could change my view with study's or from experience yourself. Go ahead and try changing my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27197064604.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How about this: I agree that someone should never have to do something they don't want to do.  Whether you hate or enjoy masturbation, it should never be something you feel compelled to do.

However, maybe take it in a slightly different view: maybe the fact that you feel you *need* to masturbate means you may be lacking somewhere else in your life.  Do certain situations trigger your urges?  Are you bored, listless, etc?

This is going to sound weird, but when I wanted to stop masturbating, the two things I found most effective were going to art galleries and leaving an abusive partner.  I didn't have enough beauty in my life and I had someone making me feel like crap everyday.  Reversing those trends has made me a healthier person.  But without wanting to give up masturbation, I never would have discovered I needed those things.

So no, masturbation isn't bad for you, but it is a warning sign that something's not right in your life.  As for what that is, I suggest counseling or some deep introspection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197069800.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>That's it! I need to find things to do to not masturbate. I'm always bored and have to be occupied to stop. Genius! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197090186.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Good luck, my man!  Fair warning, life improvement doesn't happen overnight, but if you find a hobby that occupies you and improves you as a person, it will hopefully go a long way towards making you a happier person who doesn't need something else to fill their life.  And if you get it free through your school or workplace, counseling never hurts.  

Again, best wishes and here's to a healthier you!

EDIT: added the word "counseling"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27197103277.0" user="TextingWhileDriving" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!

http://i.imgur.com/ZKui4Hg.jpg</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
