<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1333574087.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m1z4cn/cmv_we_should_allow_trans_women_in_us_womens/">
    <title>CMV: We should allow Trans women in US women’s sports to gain more viewers.</title>
    <original_poster>handologon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let’s be honest here: no one was talking about US women’s sports before Trans women starting joining the teams. 

Only 4% sports coverage has been devoted to women athletes. But now that Trans women are coming out to play, maybe it’ll be more interesting? I honestly was against the idea of Trans women competing in women’s teams until I realized this. 

Allow a limit of 1-2 Trans women per team so they don’t completely dominate, but it is enough to make people actually want to watch. The increased coverage can make more money for Colleges and official leagues, allowing biological females in leagues to make more money. In order to evenly disperse transgender athletes, there can be full ride sports scholarships given at each university for one to two transgender student. Of course biological females will get full ride scholarships as well, and likely there can be more given out due to more viewers. If our concern is safety, extra safety measures can be put in place. Also we should only start this with non-fighting sports, so no wrestling, cage fighting, or boxing. 

This is the video that inspired my thoughts:
https://youtu.be/iJe82yniZQo

Does this make sense? If not, change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36427988382.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think a transgender woman wants to be explicitly identified at every turn as trans rather than a woman? If their entire career (and education if on scholarship) rests on being known as the trans member of a female team, rather than a female member of a female team, I can't imagine they'd be very happy. It's still clearly putting them in a third category, which is exactly why they feel persecuted by current systems.

I'm not arguing one way or the other in terms of allowing them play. It just feels like there are two sides:

* Pro: They're women, let them play.
* Anti: They're not women, don't let them play.

And your argument simply says: They're not women, but let them play. You see how neither side would accept this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428009932.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>I recognize they are women, but they have biological differences from people born as female. If they don’t want to be seen as “the trans member”, they don’t have to compete.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428054288.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>The system you're suggesting doesn't work if no trans person signs up. And they won't because by their standard you aren't acknowledging they are women. From your perspective, it might seem like enough recognition, but you need to look from their perspective. To them, a trans spot on a professional team or a trans player scholarship might as well be saying "Here's your not-a-woman position/scholarship". There's still a clear line between them and female players.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428087850.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>I know of a lot of trans women who acknowledge there is a difference between them and biological females and they're not threatened by that. They are proud to be trans women. And if they can get special scholarships for trans athletes? I don't see the issue. It's as if you're implying there's something wrong with being trans, that being a biological female is the only good way to be seen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428169790.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>You keep using the term "biological female", I haven't so I don't see how I could imply anything about it.

Trans women identify as women. They want to play all/any position(s) on a female team and apply for female sports scholarships. You're suggesting they can't and should have trans positions/scholarships instead. That is a refusal to acknowledge their identity and will alienate them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428279422.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>So calling them a trans woman is me not acknowledging their identity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428346745.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>Denying them female roles/opportunities is not acknowledging their identity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428384545.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, please tell what roles and opportunity I'd be denying them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428405011.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>Non-trans roles on female teams. 

Non-trans female sports scholarships.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428504969.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>They are trans women. They have different struggles, different lives, different journeys, very different upbringings than bio females. Why should they be treated just like bio females in sports when the differences are significant? They have the advantage. 

[https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/trans-women-retain-athletic-edge-after-year-hormone-therapy-study-n1252764](https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/trans-women-retain-athletic-edge-after-year-hormone-therapy-study-n1252764)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428534282.0" user="NegativeOptimism" delta="False">
    <text>Because that's what they want. If you can't give them that, then the system won't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428181772.0" user="TragicNut" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to come off very harshly because you're also speaking on behalf of a lot of people who do **not** feel the same way as **you** clearly do on *our* behalf.

Speaking as a trans woman, fuck that tokenism shit.

Do I think that there's something inherrently "wrong" about being trans? No.

Do I think that it's a shitty situation that I don't want rubbed in my face over and over again? Yes.

Do I think that being continually outed as being trans would be harmful in today's environment? Absolutely. Especially at a high school and college level.

I sure as hell didn't want to be transgender, life would have been so much easier if I were cis, but that's not the hand I was dealt. Instead, I get to deal with a major medical condition which carries a fairly heavy social stigma in many circles for the rest of my life. I do not \_want\_ to be read as trans and treated differently because of that. So, I'm proud to be myself. At the same time, I don't want to be seen as trans, I want to be seen as a woman.

I am well aware of the biological differences between a trans woman and a cis woman. Do they automatically correlate to an advantage in athletics as you are asserting? No. If it did, we'd have seen statistically significant evidence of it by now. Instead we are only hearing about anecdotes where a single trans woman manages to win at a lower level and gets raked through the coals for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428370501.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>You know what's interesting? I don't think anyone would be talking about transgender women in sports if they weren't already competing previously in the men's teams. I don't think anyone would notice if someone was just trans, privately, and then tried out for a women's team. 

But it seems that either they themselves tell people they're trans, or people already knew. So what I'm suggested wouldn't be about outing transgender women, if they wish to remain anonymous they absolutely could. But I think sports teams and directors do need to know in order to be fair, because there are and have been proven advantages. [https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/trans-women-retain-athletic-edge-after-year-hormone-therapy-study-n1252764](https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/trans-women-retain-athletic-edge-after-year-hormone-therapy-study-n1252764)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428093375.0" user="TDHawk88" delta="False">
    <text>That's quite literally textbook "separate but equal". To say "I think you're a woman, but not enough that I think that you should be treated equally to a woman" is just more thinly veiled discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428245554.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>How is it "quite literately textbook separate but equal" when I'm saying they should literately be on the same team? I don't think you know what "separate but equal" actually refers to...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428446869.0" user="TDHawk88" delta="False">
    <text>To clarify, 'they should be on the same team' does not equate to 'a limited number should be permitted on the same team' which is what you are actually saying. You say they should be treated the same but then state how trans women should be treated differently at the same time. 

You clearly state if they don't want to be "the trans member" then they just shouldn't play. That is explicitly creating a separation while claiming equality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428466509.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, because they are trans. So if you don't want to be trans on a team, then I guess you can't be trans on a team. It's not like they're going to wear a badge that says "trans woman", no one would need to know unless they say it or it's already apparent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428484831.0" user="TDHawk88" delta="False">
    <text>But you point out that teams should only have a limited number of trans people. In order to mandate how many trans people are permitted on the team, you'd need to know who on the team is and is not transgender. If no one needs to know...how are you planning to limit how many can be on a given team?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428520058.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, I'm sorry I misspoke. The sports directors do need to know, because the trans women do have an advantage in general. But it will be private information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428502418.0" user="TDHawk88" delta="False">
    <text>And 'yeah because they are trans' being seen as a valid excuse (when it's literally not a valid reasoning at all) to do something different is literally the point. If you're limiting what a segment of the populace can do and saying the reason for that limitation is they belong to that group, that's literally discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428542069.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>Sports teams are already segregated and discriminated. Why do you think that is?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
