<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1333574087.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m1z4cn/cmv_we_should_allow_trans_women_in_us_womens/">
    <title>CMV: We should allow Trans women in US women’s sports to gain more viewers.</title>
    <original_poster>handologon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let’s be honest here: no one was talking about US women’s sports before Trans women starting joining the teams. 

Only 4% sports coverage has been devoted to women athletes. But now that Trans women are coming out to play, maybe it’ll be more interesting? I honestly was against the idea of Trans women competing in women’s teams until I realized this. 

Allow a limit of 1-2 Trans women per team so they don’t completely dominate, but it is enough to make people actually want to watch. The increased coverage can make more money for Colleges and official leagues, allowing biological females in leagues to make more money. In order to evenly disperse transgender athletes, there can be full ride sports scholarships given at each university for one to two transgender student. Of course biological females will get full ride scholarships as well, and likely there can be more given out due to more viewers. If our concern is safety, extra safety measures can be put in place. Also we should only start this with non-fighting sports, so no wrestling, cage fighting, or boxing. 

This is the video that inspired my thoughts:
https://youtu.be/iJe82yniZQo

Does this make sense? If not, change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36428178002.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>How is it going to make a difference.  I'm not going to throw on the WNBA because there is a woman who can play like a man.  They are still not as good as the men because if they were they would be in the NBA.  And in the women's sports people watch, it could ruin those, as there isn't a level playing field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428407098.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>Because it gets people in general talking. It's something interesting, a reason to watch. Sometimes sports drama is what really draws people to watch any sports.

And that's why it should be leveled out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428455862.0" user="h0sti1e17" delta="False">
    <text>I watch one game. I watched Vanderbilt because of their woman kicker.  One game for the novelty. I am not watching Vanderbilt football because they are awful.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
