<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="133919084.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27qcmk/cmv_homeless_spikes_are_just_plain_wrong_they/">
    <title>CMV: Homeless spikes are just plain wrong. They should never be installed.</title>
    <original_poster>8ackFr0mTh3D3AD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe homeless spikes are wrong.

http://www.channel4.com/news/londons-anti-homeless-spikes-criticised

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/homelessness-spikes-outside-london-flats-spark-outrage-on-twitter-9506390.html

http://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/jun/09/boris-johnson-calls-removal-anti-homeless-spikes

I think homeless spikes should be removed. I believe you will always have rough sleepers (although we could probably drastically reduce the amount in the UK) and as such should not introduce such measures.

I just don’t get the justification.

EDIT: Anybody who wants can sleep in my garden, or outside my house. If I didn't live with someone else who'd be worried about getting his stuff pinched I'd let anybody who asked sleep in my house, although I wouldn't let them have my room n I'd keep the door locked. There is very little to steal that I own.

I've never owned a car, never will, I just cannot justify it morally because of the environmental damage they cause. If I did own one I would let people sleep in it.

I do see a massive difference between putting spikes in what is a pubic place (regardless of who 'owns' it) and not letting homeless people sleep in your house though. I think it's moot.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27215400587.0" user="shadowcat0204" delta="False">
    <text>Just wanted to add that I think your anger is misplaced. You are angry that homeless are being mistreated, but instead of being angry at the people putting these up on private property, you should be angry that homeless people have to resort to sleeping on private property. Why not direct that energy towards getting better mental health care, more or better-funded shelters, etc.?

Also, if you say that there will always be rough sleepers, even if there are enough beds to hold them all in shelters in the city, then I say that a property owner definitely has the right to make sure they don't sleep on his property. That person is choosing to trespass, essentially, when they have somewhere else they could sleep. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215664195.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>There will always be people who fall through the cracks. Shelters are often dangerous, and so some are pushed out as they are unable to defend themselves. If you institute sufficient security so as to make them safe, you'll necessarily be pitching others out of the shelters and on to the streets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215760998.0" user="atfire" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you'd necessarily have to throw people out (in theory at least). But even if you do, that's their choice to do whatever got them thrown out. You chose to get into a fight/sell drugs/do whatever got you thrown out. Those who don't have control over their actions shouldn't be in a shelter, they should be receiving help (mental healthcare, rehab) so that they can be. In this ideal world where shelters are safe, I don't think it's necessary to exclude the people who currently make them unsafe, other than those whose needs would be better met by other community programs. Ergo, there don't *have* to be people falling through the cracks (again, in theory. In practice, I agree hands-down, but still think we should be working to keep it from happening). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215781704.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Of course we should work to keep it from happening, but it still will for some people, who will then have to find shelter in odd places like where those spikes were installed.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
