<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="133919084.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27qcmk/cmv_homeless_spikes_are_just_plain_wrong_they/">
    <title>CMV: Homeless spikes are just plain wrong. They should never be installed.</title>
    <original_poster>8ackFr0mTh3D3AD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe homeless spikes are wrong.

http://www.channel4.com/news/londons-anti-homeless-spikes-criticised

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/homelessness-spikes-outside-london-flats-spark-outrage-on-twitter-9506390.html

http://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/jun/09/boris-johnson-calls-removal-anti-homeless-spikes

I think homeless spikes should be removed. I believe you will always have rough sleepers (although we could probably drastically reduce the amount in the UK) and as such should not introduce such measures.

I just don’t get the justification.

EDIT: Anybody who wants can sleep in my garden, or outside my house. If I didn't live with someone else who'd be worried about getting his stuff pinched I'd let anybody who asked sleep in my house, although I wouldn't let them have my room n I'd keep the door locked. There is very little to steal that I own.

I've never owned a car, never will, I just cannot justify it morally because of the environmental damage they cause. If I did own one I would let people sleep in it.

I do see a massive difference between putting spikes in what is a pubic place (regardless of who 'owns' it) and not letting homeless people sleep in your house though. I think it's moot.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27215353599.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>You get certain rights that apply to physical property that you own. One of those rights is the right to keep other people from using that property. If someone doesn't want homeless people sleeping on their property they are completely within their rights to do whatever they want to discourage that short of physical violence. 

Some homeless people are totally harmless. Some have dangerous mental health issues. Some do drugs. Some piss in the street. It's completely reasonable to not want homeless people on your property because you don't want to deal with the latter three cases.

Homeless people do need *somewhere* to go. But no individual property owner is responsible for giving them that place.

Furthermore, you can't even be sure that someone putting in homeless spikes is a bad person. What if they volunteer at soup kitchens, donate to homeless shelters, and advocate for getting homeless people the help they need, but still don't want random people sleeping on their property?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215365282.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If someone doesn't want homeless people sleeping on their property they are completely within their rights to do whatever they want to discourage that short of physical violence. 

I don't believe in god given rights, I think it is a nonsense idea.

&amp;gt;Homeless people do need somewhere to go. But no individual property owner is responsible for giving them that place.

We are all responsible for tackling the homeless problem.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215370244.0" user="VegetableRights" delta="False">
    <text>Hang around near places where the spikes have been installed and invite the would-be inhabitants of the spiked areas home with you, in that case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216010452.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>you would be amazed at what I am personally prepared to do to help my fellow human being.

I don't think that changes anything though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215371786.0" user="vokrama" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We are all responsible for tackling the homeless problem.

Sure, but I don't think having them sleep next to the door of apartment buildings is a good way to tackle the homeless problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215375527.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about legal rights, not god given rights.

Tackling the homelessness problem means improving mental health care, funding housing programs, and dealing with the root sources of the issue. It doesn't mean enabling homeless people to sleep on a particular patch of ground. That doesn't make them not homeless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215531968.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>Your second point is absolutely true. Homelessness needs to be tackled on an institutional level. But what about in the meantime? We can't expect the homeless to just disappear until the situation's been sorted out. The moment we decide that a problem is the obligation of no one in particular, we've effectively given up on it being solved at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215543575.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>That is true, but there is such a thing as public land. Even if every square foot of private property had these spikes installed, there would still be places for the homeless to sleep while society gets around to figuring out how to get them homes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216100745.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>They would be forced to sleep out in the open though, without any shelter against wind, rain, or snow. Their quality of life would be substantially worsened while society puts off doing anything about homeless people because it costs too much money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216567591.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>But is that *wrong*? Is it an individual property owner's duty to improve the lot of the homeless? I have extra blankets. Do I need to give them to the first homeless person I see because it will help them keep warm? Or is it up to me what I do with my private property? Sure, I'm probably a better person if I let the homeless sleep on my doorstep and bring them hot chocolate in the morning and help them work on their resumes, but that doesn't mean I am failing in a moral or ethical duty if I don't provide those things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216582413.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Is it an individual property owner's duty to improve the lot of the homeless?

Making some effort to help those less fortunate than you is a sign of goodness.

&amp;gt;I have extra blankets. Do I need to give them to the first homeless person I see because it will help them keep warm?

Not to the first homeless person you see, though donating spare stuff to a charity can help them a lot. 

If you left your blankets out and left some nettles in them to deter homeless people I would think you were being somewhat rude.

&amp;gt;Or is it up to me what I do with my private property?

If you actively harm people who try to use your private property you are violating your moral and ethical duty. Suppose someone, homeless or not, tripped and fell onto your spikes- you could seriously injure them. Seriously injuring people over a few dollars is immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216635242.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Making some effort to help those less fortunate than you is a sign of goodness.

I agree. But absence of extra goodness is not in itself a failing. We all have people we could be nicer to, social ills we could be doing more to solve. 

&amp;gt; If you actively harm people who try to use your private property you are violating your moral and ethical duty. 

I disagree on three points with this. Putting in spikes isn't actively harming anyone. Shooting people on your property with a paintball gun is active. Setting an elaborate hidden trap is a clear attempt to cause harm. Spikes are merely a property feature that could harm someone under certain circumstances but are not intended for harm, just deterrence.

Someone sleeping in my doorway is not using my property in any way that my property is intended to be used. I'm also not obligated to let people film movies on my property.

Even if both of these weren't true, I disagree that I'm failing in any kind of duty. My private property is my private property and if I want to make the entire thing an unlivable hellscape because that's how I prefer it that's perfectly ethically correct. As long as it isn't interfering with anyone else's property I don't understand why I have an obligation to complete strangers to render my property suitable for their use, to which I object. 

Seriously injuring people over a few dollars is immoral but neither issue is relevant here. It's not about money, it's about keeping people off my property. And the spikes pictured could hardly cause serious injury. They would be uncomfortable to lie on for extended periods, but even tripping and falling onto them is unlikely to do more injury than just falling onto hard ground unless you hit one at the exact right angle. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216669639.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I agree. But absence of extra goodness is not in itself a failing. We all have people we could be nicer to, social ills we could be doing more to solve.

To some degree. But if I get the sense that you are massively against any sort of reasonable effort to avoid harm or any effort to help people then you get to the point of antisocial. There is a basic level of goodness that we expect all productive members of society to meet. I don't want to interact with someone who is going to severely hurt me and random bystanders over what they feel are their rights if we cross them or are unlucky enough to wander into them.

&amp;gt;Spikes are merely a property feature that could harm someone under certain circumstances but are not intended for harm, just deterrence.

"I didn't intend to harm them" isn't really a defense when you know the direct result is likely to be frequent harm for people who try it out. If you purposely cause pain to people you are well below the social standards for acceptable behavior.

&amp;gt;My private property is my private property and if I want to make the entire thing an unlivable hellscape because that's how I prefer it that's perfectly ethically correct.

As a social human being you are required to make a reasonable effort to avoid harming people. If a kid wanders into your garden to pick up a ball they shouldn't die. If a member of the police has to enter your house they shouldn't be severely injured. Saying "It's my property therefore I can severely hurt people." has the predictable result that a lot of people will be severely hurt and injured.

 If the result of your morality is that anyone who crosses you is injured then your morality is somewhat immoral, and if contested will likely be declared illegal. Any moral system which is so twisted that people not harming you is an excuse to harm them is going to cause you issues in polite society.

&amp;gt;It's not about money, it's about keeping people off my property.

Your precise reasoning for hurting people is noted. It being your property isn't a good excuse to actively harm people.

"And the spikes pictured could hardly cause serious injury. They would be uncomfortable to lie on for extended periods, but even tripping and falling onto them is unlikely to do more injury than just falling onto hard ground unless you hit one at the exact right angle."

They look quite sharp, if you fell hard you could get one stabbing into you, especially if you were elderly. You could easily trip on one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216699619.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>But I'm not setting traps. I'm not shooting tresspassers. I am preventing one particular use of my property, a use which does not happen accidentally, unlike a ball in the garden.

And again, those spikes are not that dangerous. They make that area a less comfortable place to sleep. They're not a deathtrap. 

Stop with the hurting and harming. [Here is a picture of the spikes](http://i.imgur.com/qPJNrF6.jpg). They are not in a location anyone is likely to trip into. There is no reason for anyone to even stand in that location. They are relatively dull. If you somehow fell on one it would probably cause a bad bruise but is looks unlikely to even draw blood. But it's very unlikely you would fall on one because they're in a small area in a corner. 

I am not sure we can discuss this issue at all because you are framing it in terms of making your property a massive active health hazard to anyone who comes near it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216733177.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not shooting tresspassers. I am preventing one particular use of my property, a use which does not happen accidentally, unlike a ball in the garden.

You should note that the spikes are right over the keypad to enter. They are a hazard to anyone who is trying to enter and has to walk on them. They are an indiscriminate hazard that people are likely to often encounter. 

&amp;gt;If you somehow fell on one it would probably cause a bad bruise but is looks unlikely to even draw blood.

Depends on your skin toughness. Oldies would be worse off, likewise anyone heavier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216682140.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's heavily a question of empathy. If a person doesn't really care if they harm people because they have reasons that don't involve harm to you how can we trust that they as a person will not actively harm us if we cross their morality? An absence of extra goodness in that sense is a failing, we do have to feel that a person is safe to interact with, that they won't shoot us if they feel hurt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216703549.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>That seems wildly out of line. There's no active harm going on. A person says, "I will not let you on my property. If you attempt to use my property in this specific way that I have banned, you may cause harm to yourself. This is obvious," and you believe they will shoot someone who hurts their feelings? 

How are you making the leap of logic from "I have a right to prevent others from doing this and if they insist on doing it they might get hurt" to "I have the right to hurt anyone who upsets me?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216728167.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How are you making the leap of logic from "I have a right to prevent others from doing this and if they insist on doing it they might get hurt" to "I have the right to hurt anyone who upsets me?"

They're not ethically that different, murdering or injuring people because of minor violations of your property rights or small amounts of cash are both similarly unethical to hurting people because they make you feel bad (by violating your property rights).

You noted before that we had a basic standard of goodness to follow. If you put the onus on others to avoid common breaches of etiquette or you will severely harm them then you are an active danger to those around you and are not meeting your requirements. 

Death or injury shouldn't be a predictable consequence of, say, someone being a child and being unaware of your rules, or drunk, or old and blind. If death or injury is a predictable consequence of your actions then I view that as unethical, as murdering people and injuring them is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216745548.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>Sleeping on someone else's doorstep isn't a common breech of etiquette. It's an uncommon action taken only by a certain segment of society who knows very well that what they are doing is considered by most people to be wrong. I can say this with some confidence because it's illegal; if someone were sleeping where those spikes are you could have them arrested for tresspassing and/or loitering.

The spikes aren't a hidden or unpredictable consequence of this action. It's more akin to someone open carrying. If you try to mug that person, you might be shot. This is not antisocial behavior on the part of the person with the gun. There is nothing in that to suggest that by accidentally offending them or breaking some rule of theirs that is not also widely held by society you will be shot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216764824.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sleeping on someone else's doorstep isn't a common breech of etiquette.

Walking on their property is, and the spikes could easily trip up a person. That's my issue with setting traps in public places. It's an unpersonal (unlike a policeperson) punishment that will screw over a lot of people.

Plus, if they do try to sleep on it they'll have large amounts of pain inflicted on them, whereas jail generally doesn't deliberately hurt people. 

It would obviously be better if there was some middle ground between jail and doing nothing.

&amp;gt;If you try to mug that person, you might be shot.

If someone is trying to inflict violence, and potentially death on you, it's more justifiable defending yourself- a life versus a life is a fairish trade. If you shot a person who was sleeping on your porch I would view that as more questionable.

A gun, and spikes, shouldn't be used unless you want people who interact with it to die or be injured. I would view someone sleeping on my grounds as a minor ethics violation, not a shootable offense- you may differ. Your willingness to murder and hurt people when you are not threatened makes you less safe to be around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216779823.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the spikes count as a trap because they are *obvious*. If they were hidden in a flower bed I would agree that they are bad. 

It's only going to screw over the people who are intentionally doing the thing you are trying to prevent, the thing that also happens to be illegal. Or, possibly, people who are unlikely enough to trip on them, but you seem to view that as a way more probable event than I do and I don't think we're ever going to see eye to eye there.

I wouldn't shoot someone sleeping on my grounds. I wouldn't set hidden spike traps. The obvious spikes are almost certainly not going to hurt anyone because people will see them and choose to not lie down on them.

You keep talking about hurting. Would you find this equally unethical if they had put a cement slope on the ground to make it impossible to sleep on it without rolling off into the street? I see the spikes in the same way - they aren't hurting someone who unknowingly lay down on them because you can't *unknowingly* lie down on them. They are simply making the area impossible to sleep on in the same way a ramp would.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216796195.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think the spikes count as a trap because they are obvious. If they were hidden in a flower bed I would agree that they are bad.

Having a trap out in the open doesn't make them not a trap, especially since people frequently walk home at night. They won't necessarily see them. 

&amp;gt;Or, possibly, people who are unlikely enough to trip on them, but you seem to view that as a way more probable event than I do and I don't think we're ever going to see eye to eye there.

I've been on one and stumbled. I wasn't injured beyond some scrapes, I managed to dodge putting my hand on a spike, but yeah, they're pretty easy to miss in the dark.

&amp;gt;I wouldn't shoot someone sleeping on my grounds. I wouldn't set hidden spike traps. 

Yay for no wanton murder, and the spikes are hidden in the dark.

&amp;gt;Would you find this equally unethical if they had put a cement slope on the ground to make it impossible to sleep on it without rolling off into the street?

I would see that as less unethical, although, again, I imagine it would serve as a less common trap for people with poor balance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216829583.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>I usually don't throw myself bodily down on a surface I intend to lie on, but typically walk over to it, sit down, and then lie down. Which would make the spikes an uncomfortable surprise but not an injurious one.

I think we're just going to have to agree to disagree because our main issue seems to be with our relative judgement of the general public's competence and frailty. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216836929.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>It's not really a huge issue of disagreement- even if in most cases people are fine, if someone is tired or drunk or old or childish they may get hurt. 

You assume general competency of the public and if they hurt themselves, well, if you did that, you'd be fine. You don't really consider worst case scenarios important. I think it's very important to consider those, even on private property. That would make it quite scary to be with you- what if i didn't do something completely competently by your books and was seriously injured?

And as I noted, I have tripped on one. They are quite prevalent in some places, and easy to trip on if it's dark.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216861705.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>Are they? I assumed they were a new thing given the level of outrage.

I just don't think we need to drunk-proof and elderly-proof the world in order to be ethical beings. Old people and drunks can get hurt falling down a normal set of stairs but that doesn't mean we keep stairs out of all public places. Accidents happen. If something serves a utility that is greater than the possibility of the accident, it's still worth it. I'd rather risk an elderly person tripping on out of the way spikes than risk them getting assaulted by a drunk homeless person sleeping in my entryway. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216884652.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>They've been around for 20 years.

&amp;gt;I just don't think we need to drunk-proof and elderly-proof the world in order to be ethical beings.

Another reason why I view this as extremely unethical, a general lack of consideration for vulnerable people.

&amp;gt;Old people and drunks can get hurt falling down a normal set of stairs but that doesn't mean we keep stairs out of all public places.

We often make ramps to allow easy access for them and disabled people, or elevators. People do care for others.

&amp;gt;I'd rather risk an elderly person tripping on out of the way spikes than risk them getting assaulted by a drunk homeless person sleeping in my entryway.

I'd rather donating my blanket to the homeless person and giving them somewhere else to sleep, and also helping the elderly person to not trip. There are choices outside extreme violence and severe injury.

Besides which, as an impersonal device, I wouldn't be surprised if the spikes caused more injuries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216977870.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>We make ramps and elevators but we don't eliminate stairs. The stairs and the hazard they represent still exist.

You can donate a blanket to someone and still get assaulted by them. While I am sure there are many homeless people who are wonderful human beings, in general people did not get into that state by being properly functional upstanding members of society. 

I'm willing to bet money that homeless people cause more injuries than the spikes do. But as there's unlikely to be good statistics on it that's not a realistic bet to keep.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216009711.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>legal rights are just a made up thing. I used to have a legal right to own slaves, doesn't mean that was right.

I'd argue the right to private property will go the same way at some point, but that is another CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216012604.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>If you believe in neither god given rights nor legal rights, what is your basis for calling something "wrong?" You need some kind of moral or ethical framework in order to call things right or wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216020008.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I believe in ends rather than means. I don't think anything is inherently right or wrong beyond it's consequence.

I don't like the idea of static fixed rights that are timeless or universal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216021585.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>So are you a utilitarian? The greatest good for the most wins? If installing homeless spikes makes a homeless person only slightly unhappy, because now they have to move down a block, but makes me very happy, because now I don't have to deal with homeless people sleeping in my doorway, then installing spikes is the right thing to do because the net affect is for good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215379342.0" user="ThoughtRiot1776" delta="False">
    <text>So you'd be cool if a guy randomly starting to sleep on your porch every night?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216010581.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>yes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215385620.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Then should I be able to freely come in to your home and sleep in your bed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216010953.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>no, but outside my house, in a public place, regardless of what it says on my mortgage, yep.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27231284139.0" user="euler2718" delta="False">
    <text>How about on your porch, a private place? Or in your living room, a private place? That would be the equivalent, because the store owns the property. It isn't public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215391513.0" user="tit_wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't believe in god given rights, I think it is a nonsense idea. 

Why did you infer "god given rights" from "rights"? The person probably meant legal rights, or general ethical rights insofar as private property is concerned. I think it's rational to argue that people are allowed to treat their privately owned goods/properties as they see fit, as long as it doesn't harm another person - and preventing people from sleeping on your property doesn't exactly fall under harming them (unless you really, really want to make a convoluted, backward argument for that).

 &amp;gt; We are all responsible for tackling the homeless problem. 

That's a completely separate point, and also it's not inherently true. *Society* is responsible for tackling the homeless problem, assuming that society (at large) wishes to reduce its poverty - in which case, it doesn't really matter *who* tackles it, as long as something is being done. However, even if you want to claim that everyone needs to do something in order for homelessness to go down (which seems fallacious), it does not logically follow that preventing homeless people from sleeping in certain areas worsens homelessness. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216012483.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why did you infer "god given rights" from "rights"?

Because you can't have inherent rights without god. Anything else is just a social construct. I used to have a legal right to slaves and to rape my wife. Legal rights are not by definition correct.

&amp;gt;preventing people from sleeping on your property doesn't exactly fall under harming them

I think it bloody does, if the only safe place I can find to sleep has got ruddy great spikes and I have to sleep in the city center and get the shit kicked out of me by drunk yuppies I think I'm being harmed.

&amp;gt;preventing homeless people from sleeping in certain areas worsens homelessness. 

Anything that removes a persons autonomy in such an involuntary way almost always harms them.

I do claim that everyone needs to do something in order for homelessness to go down, especially the owners of private property who are unjustifiably wealthy, especially in that bloody Landan where I believe the spikes are.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215618783.0" user="funchy" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a "god given right".  It's that the person who worked hard to have their own home has a right - recognized legally and socially - to asking people they did not invite to leave their home.

You're also ignoring that some people (often times women)  genuinely feel scared when a strange man is seen lurking in the alcove in front of their homes door.  Maybe it is just an honest guy who has a run of a bad luck and just wanted somewhere to sleep.  But we don't know that.   A strange man in the shadows of a doorway could be a stalker, a rapist, or a robber.  Why should a woman be forced to get in such close proximity to a man who may be a threat, just so she can get into her home - a place of safety?

Yes homeless people are everyone's concern.  I don't think anyone here is wishing terrible suffering on all homeless.   But you're oversimplifying the issue of homeless people if you think they're all ordinary guys,  just like you but down on their luck temporarily.   In my area there are shelters but for safety reasons they can't have people with treatable behavior issues (serious drug addiction or mental illness).  They direct addicts to resources to help them get clean.  But not all people WANT to live the mainstream lifestyle.  They would rather sleep out in the cold in freezing temps and not have any rules.   And as a society we can't force them to seek drug addiction or mental illness treatment.   There are resources.   Some choose not to use them.  If they choose not to get help, I don't know if I can feel bad for them when the alcoholic is found frozen to death on a sidewalk?

Where do you draw the line between society's obligation to help homeless people and an individual homeless persons right to refuse any outside intervention? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216015214.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's not a "god given right". It's that the person who worked hard to have their own home has a right - recognized legally and socially - to asking people they did not invite to leave their home.

I think the only rights that exist are god given, anything else is a social construct in a state of flux.

I'm not saying you can't lock your door. I'm against spikes.

&amp;gt;They would rather sleep out in the cold in freezing temps and not have any rules

I think they is a myth and a lie some down and outs tell themselves and others to cope with how they live.

&amp;gt;I don't know if I can feel bad for them when the alcoholic is found frozen to death on a sidewalk?

Spend some time with the homeless and attempt to be a better human being if that is how you view the suffering of others, that is cold.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27231285357.0" user="euler2718" delta="False">
    <text>So your what your saying is that you can't protect your outside property with spikes, but you can protect your inside property with locks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215673531.0" user="smapple" delta="False">
    <text>How many homeless people are you housing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216016151.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>I'd house a ton if I could. Housemate would go spare. As many as they want can have my garden. Fuck they can pinch the veg out of it anytime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215845578.0" user="aardvarkious" delta="False">
    <text>So you would be fine with a homeless person sleeping in your backyard? Or coming in and using your couch every night? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216016546.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. And they could have the couch tbh as well, I'd lock my bedroom door but I'd be down with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216157391.0" user="BrawndoTTM" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't believe in God given rights, then what gives homeless people the right to sleep on other peoples property?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216172339.0" user="fetal-juice" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, but if you don't believe in the right to control the land you pay for, then the whole concept of money becomes obsolete. 

Why should I bother paying for my own rent or mortgage when I can just come sleep on your porch? Why should I work 50 hours a week to be able to afford somewhere to sleep, when someone else can just come along and take up residence there for free?

The homeless need help, but not installing homeless spikes isn't helping them. Letting them sleep in your garden or porch isn't helping them in the long run. We pay taxes - a greater percentage should go to helping the homeless population rather than us as individuals having to feel responsible for where a homeless person sleeps. I have my own shit to deal with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215587618.0" user="Unconfidence" delta="False">
    <text>Am I mistaken, or are these spikes being put into public property areas?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215597873.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>You are mistaken. So far as I can tell from the articles and pictures these were installed outside a block of flats, most likely by the landlord. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216043717.0" user="abittooshort" delta="False">
    <text>The spikes are on private land in the doorway of some flats. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215946121.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Homeless people do need somewhere to go. But no individual property owner is responsible for giving them that place.

So, as a society, we need to provide X - but no individual needs to provide any part of X. 

See the problem here? 

And I think there's a line between going out of your way to provide X and going out of your way to *deny* X, while being a dick about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215963652.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>Public land exists. Every single individual and business could stud their property with spikes and there would still be places for the homeless to sleep. In fact, most of them already sleep in public parks. At least around here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216017062.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>it's risky as fuck sleeping in public parks. One of the biggest dangers you face on the streets is being beaten to a pulp by drunks in the evening for a laugh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216100467.0" user="Perite" delta="False">
    <text>But is a park any more dangerous than the entrance way to a private apartment block? They're both out in public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216124849.0" user="ignotos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But is a park any more dangerous than the entrance way to a private apartment block?
 
Probably. Darker, more isolated etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216227480.0" user="km89" delta="False">
    <text>These things also increase the risk of a crime occurring. Granted, a homeless person isn't likely to have much worth stealing, but if people are, as /u/BackFr0mTh3D3AD said, going to beat them up for a laugh, I don't doubt robbery would happen.

This, plus the uncomfortable but true fact that people would be incredibly uncomfortable stepping over homeless people to get to their houses, which in turn would possibly significantly reduce the business's profit--after all, it *is* a business. 

Then there's the uncomfortable truth that drug addiction and crime follows homeless people, as a group. That's not something I can blame the landlord for not tolerating. While each individual homeless person may not be like that, some are, and eventually they will be attracted to that spot.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216017423.0" user="Dack105" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly what the government is for, just like as a society we need roads, bu no individual needs to provide roads,  just like as a society we need health-care, bu no individual needs to provide health-care.

Any intelligent government of a developed county provides these things, and the existence of homeless people is why we have [welfare](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welfare).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216020314.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>We all provide roads by paying enough tax that the government can fund their construction. 

There is very clearly nowhere near enough funding to house the homeless, and nobody is being taxed enough to provide said funding, thus the obligation is left hanging. 

Nobody's even suggesting that landowners spend additional money to house the homeless - only that they quit being dicks about *spending money to deny them shelter*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216167108.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;only that they quit being dicks about spending money to deny them shelter.

Even though we agree that not enough is being done to house the homeless, it still doesn't mean that individuals have to have that forced upon them.

You may see them as dicks, but really they are well within their right to use their property as they see fit, and *protect* (if homeless people were dangerous) their tenants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216213904.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>We aren't arguing the legal right, we're arguing dickitude. 

And nothing you've said makes it any less dickish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219464275.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>If I live as a tenant in a building and a landlord installs something to maintain a higher level of quality of life and *possibly* reduce the chance that a *dangerous* homeless person (not that most or even many are) could injure me, I wouldn't consider him a dick.

Actually, if I'm the owner of a building and a homeless person tries to give me a hard time because I ask him not to trespass on my property, I'd consider *him* a dick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219977122.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that's convenient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220677322.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>Is it?

If I was a landlord, it is partially my responsibility to keep my tenants in a clean and safe environment.

If that means no homeless people using my property without my permission, how does that make me a dick?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216223339.0" user="km89" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So, as a society, we need to provide X - but no individual needs to provide any part of X.
See the problem here?

No. It's not my responsibility to ensure that potholes on the roads are filled, nor to go chase criminals--but it is the responsibility of all of society to ensure that these things are paid for and taken care of. That's the *point* in having a government.

While I can understand why this situation comes across as dickish, I can also understand exactly why this action was taken, and I think everyone can see that.  

It's unfortunate and wrong that homeless people don't have more support, but as /u/TryUsingScience said, no individual property owner is responsible for that, any more than any individual car owner is responsible for the maintenance of the roads they drive on. This is exclusively a government problem.

That being said, perhaps an argument *could* be made for the responsibility of people who see this type of problem to argue at the government until they actually do something about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216235236.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>It is your responsibility to fill potholes, though.  

And mine. And his. 

Luckily and conveniently, there's a way to evenly distribute that responsibility across the entire populace. It's called *taxation*. 

Though we don't all have to grab a shovel, we do have to fork over a percentage of our income to pay for this service that our society needs - discharging our obligation in a reasonably fair and reasonably efficient way. 

If the funding for homeless shelters were sufficient that nobody *needed* to sleep rough, then again, we'd have no obligation left to discharge in that department, and we could exclude people however we wanted without being dicks. 

As that's not the case, as we hang onto our $37 a year each (or whatever it would actually cost), then our responsibility is unfulfilled, and our obligation remains outstanding. 

In such a case, the least, the *very least* of our duty to society we can do is to *not fucking make it worse*. 

If you're not going to pull your weight, get out of the fucking way. 

Talk about remedial ethics. Jeez. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216356093.0" user="km89" delta="False">
    <text>There is an issue with what you're saying. While I agree with you 100%, there is a lot of merit in the argument that the government as it is is incredibly wasteful, and that there is plenty of funding--its just not getting to where it is supposed to be, or to where it should go. 

Further, you are only thinking of the homeless people here. This situation takes place outside of an apartment complex. Ethically, is it right to allow a potentially dangerous situation outside of people's homes? For their children to be exposed to the inevitable drug and alcohol use that follows homeless people as a group? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27217400856.0" user="pocketknifeMT" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Luckily and conveniently, there's a way to evenly distribute that responsibility across the entire populace. It's called taxation.

There is nothing even about taxation. Most systems actually herald their progressive tax system as a good feature.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
