<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="133919084.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27qcmk/cmv_homeless_spikes_are_just_plain_wrong_they/">
    <title>CMV: Homeless spikes are just plain wrong. They should never be installed.</title>
    <original_poster>8ackFr0mTh3D3AD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe homeless spikes are wrong.

http://www.channel4.com/news/londons-anti-homeless-spikes-criticised

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/homelessness-spikes-outside-london-flats-spark-outrage-on-twitter-9506390.html

http://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/jun/09/boris-johnson-calls-removal-anti-homeless-spikes

I think homeless spikes should be removed. I believe you will always have rough sleepers (although we could probably drastically reduce the amount in the UK) and as such should not introduce such measures.

I just don’t get the justification.

EDIT: Anybody who wants can sleep in my garden, or outside my house. If I didn't live with someone else who'd be worried about getting his stuff pinched I'd let anybody who asked sleep in my house, although I wouldn't let them have my room n I'd keep the door locked. There is very little to steal that I own.

I've never owned a car, never will, I just cannot justify it morally because of the environmental damage they cause. If I did own one I would let people sleep in it.

I do see a massive difference between putting spikes in what is a pubic place (regardless of who 'owns' it) and not letting homeless people sleep in your house though. I think it's moot.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27216295592.0" user="Geohump" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever the reason for it, the spikes are a bad idea. its makes the surface just plain dangerous for anyone who falls, or a package that needs to be set down, or a resident who wants to step out of the rain for a moment.

very much not thought through.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
