<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="133919084.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27qcmk/cmv_homeless_spikes_are_just_plain_wrong_they/">
    <title>CMV: Homeless spikes are just plain wrong. They should never be installed.</title>
    <original_poster>8ackFr0mTh3D3AD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe homeless spikes are wrong.

http://www.channel4.com/news/londons-anti-homeless-spikes-criticised

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/homelessness-spikes-outside-london-flats-spark-outrage-on-twitter-9506390.html

http://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/jun/09/boris-johnson-calls-removal-anti-homeless-spikes

I think homeless spikes should be removed. I believe you will always have rough sleepers (although we could probably drastically reduce the amount in the UK) and as such should not introduce such measures.

I just don’t get the justification.

EDIT: Anybody who wants can sleep in my garden, or outside my house. If I didn't live with someone else who'd be worried about getting his stuff pinched I'd let anybody who asked sleep in my house, although I wouldn't let them have my room n I'd keep the door locked. There is very little to steal that I own.

I've never owned a car, never will, I just cannot justify it morally because of the environmental damage they cause. If I did own one I would let people sleep in it.

I do see a massive difference between putting spikes in what is a pubic place (regardless of who 'owns' it) and not letting homeless people sleep in your house though. I think it's moot.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27215359088.0" user="Misogyny-Man" delta="False">
    <text>I see no problem with those at all. Private property owners can do whatever they want so long as it is legal. I would not want a stranger sleeping in my car and I would not want one sleeping on my property.  

What you should have a problem with is lack of housing options for homeless people, not a private owners protection against violation of their rights as property owners.

The justification is that not only do homeless people not have a right to sleep on private property, a private property can have anything they want installed.

If you have never had homeless people rough sleep in your residence, I might, might understand why you think these are wrong. But they can be dangerous, smelly, unhygienic, intoxicated or worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215362227.0" user="8ackFr0mTh3D3AD" delta="False">
    <text>I sleep out with the homeless once a year. I don't think you are correct in anything you have said about.

&amp;gt; dangerous, smelly, unhygienic, intoxicated or worse.

Thats just you're average Friday / Saturday night reveler.

Why reduce the overall utility of a space by making it impossible for someone to sleep there? I understand better provision for the rough sleepers would be ideal. But we don't live in that world yet. Why make their lives worse?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215388031.0" user="Misogyny-Man" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I sleep out with the homeless once a year. I don't think you are correct in anything you have said about.

We had a guy sleep in the lobby of our apparent complex for a couple of days. It was in the middle of summer and nobody realized until a guy went down for his early shift. He confronted the man, the man appeared apologetic and went away. Later that night the guy checked downstairs and sure enough, the man was sleeping there again, except this time he was drunk. We had to call police to take him away. 

A week later our lobbies windows were broken in the night, now I can not prove it was the homeless man but he is the only one I can think of. Some homeless are addicts, and some are very unhygienic. 

&amp;gt;Why reduce the overall utility of a space by making it impossible for someone to sleep there? I understand better provision for the rough sleepers would be ideal. But we don't live in that world yet. 

Lets assume you have a car. You don't use it in the night, why not let a guy or two settle down in there when you aren't using it.

Heck, I doubt you use your kitchen or living room when you are asleep. You could probably house at least ten homeless there. 

But you don't. You have locks on your house and car, you expect your private residence to be yours. Nobody has the right to sleep there, or technically even bee there without your permission. 

&amp;gt;Why make their lives worse?

Why make their lives better at the expense of private property owners?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215795365.0" user="Cyridius" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Lets assume you have a car. You don't use it in the night, why not let a guy or two settle down in there when you aren't using it.

&amp;gt;Heck, I doubt you use your kitchen or living room when you are asleep. You could probably house at least ten homeless there.

&amp;gt;But you don't. You have locks on your house and car, you expect your private residence to be yours. Nobody has the right to sleep there, or technically even bee there without your permission.

This is a slippery slope fallacy. Just because I think it's OK to let them sleep outside, where they can conceivably do very little harm, doesn't mean I would let them sleep in my house or car where they can do something like steal, or harm me.

&amp;gt;Why make their lives better at the expense of private property owners?

Good will? Respect? Decency? Profit motive is not the end-all-be-all of human behaviour. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216243226.0" user="saviourman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We had a guy sleep in the lobby of our apparent complex for a couple of days. It was in the middle of summer and nobody realized until a guy went down for his early shift. He confronted the man, the man appeared apologetic and went away. Later that night the guy checked downstairs and sure enough, the man was sleeping there again, except this time he was drunk. We had to call police to take him away.

&amp;gt; A week later our lobbies windows were broken in the night, now I can not prove it was the homeless man but he is the only one I can think of. Some homeless are addicts, and some are very unhygienic.

No one even noticed the guy was there? I find it difficult to see the issue. Sounds to me like you overreacted by calling the police.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
