<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="133919084.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27qcmk/cmv_homeless_spikes_are_just_plain_wrong_they/">
    <title>CMV: Homeless spikes are just plain wrong. They should never be installed.</title>
    <original_poster>8ackFr0mTh3D3AD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe homeless spikes are wrong.

http://www.channel4.com/news/londons-anti-homeless-spikes-criticised

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/homelessness-spikes-outside-london-flats-spark-outrage-on-twitter-9506390.html

http://www.theguardian.com/society/2014/jun/09/boris-johnson-calls-removal-anti-homeless-spikes

I think homeless spikes should be removed. I believe you will always have rough sleepers (although we could probably drastically reduce the amount in the UK) and as such should not introduce such measures.

I just don’t get the justification.

EDIT: Anybody who wants can sleep in my garden, or outside my house. If I didn't live with someone else who'd be worried about getting his stuff pinched I'd let anybody who asked sleep in my house, although I wouldn't let them have my room n I'd keep the door locked. There is very little to steal that I own.

I've never owned a car, never will, I just cannot justify it morally because of the environmental damage they cause. If I did own one I would let people sleep in it.

I do see a massive difference between putting spikes in what is a pubic place (regardless of who 'owns' it) and not letting homeless people sleep in your house though. I think it's moot.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27215415151.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>People don't have huge problems with homeless people sleeping in doorways. They'd prefer not to have them but if they're just sleeping there it's often not a big deal. 

However, they don't just sleep there. They also go to the bathroom there. Anyone who has opened a business with a front in an area where homeless sleep has had to deal with the smells and sight of urine and too often feces. It's a real problem.

If you don't like the spikes why not invite the homeless to sleep in your doorway? When you see homeless spikes put up a sign with your address and tell them they're welcome to sleep in your doorway.

It may seem heartless but it's easy to say it's okay for homeless to sleep *over there* much harder to welcome them to sleep in your area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215536807.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Public urination can be an issue, but unfortunately, I'm not sure that these spikes would do anything about that problem.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215544425.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>If people aren't sleeping there they are much less likely to urinate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215551715.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>OTOH, if people can't sleep there, then they might decide to urinate there anyway.

Maybe a person sleeping there would deter somebody else from such urination.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215574434.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>You have no experience with operating a business in an area with homeless do you? It's not as clearcut as you seem to think it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215580116.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that you can't be sure that people won't urinate just because you stop them from sleeping there.

Do you find this to be untrue?  That people only urinate where they sleep?

Because that does not track with my experiences at all, no.

And I can also imagine a person sleeping at a spot being a form of deterrence towards others urinating.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215595447.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that but it will limit it a great deal. The less homeless-friendly a place is the less homeless there will be. The less homeless there are the less public urination. 

It's unfortunate but it's where we are at today. We can't force people to get their act together and live inside.  So all we can do is give them the option to get their act together and live inside or try to minimize their affects on others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215602774.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's assuming it reduces the homeless problem.  And no, I don't think these strips are related to that option you gave at all.  

And I really don't see these spikes stopping much actual urination.  Especially if the problem with that isn't from the homeless.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215665949.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>They won't reduce the homeless problem, but they may move it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27215668347.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think moving it was a South Park episode.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216102830.0" user="Perite" delta="False">
    <text>There are different types of homeless people. The ones who are down on their luck usually try to keep as clean as possible and won't usually make too much mess. The ones with mental issues / raging alcoholism / severe drug problems tend to piss, shit and puke in doorways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27216213691.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, when it comes to piss, shit, and puke in doorways, it's not only homeless that do it here though.

It's people who do have a home, and money to go somewhere to get drunk, and yet can't manage the trip home without causing problems.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
