<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134214340.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27wog4/cmv_i_believe_a_sustainable_market_for_video/">
    <title>CMV: I Believe a Sustainable Market for Video Games Oriented Towards Women Exists, and that Feminism Would Be Better Served to Develop For It Than Merely Complain About It</title>
    <original_poster>OhCrapADinosaur</original_poster>
    <original_post>E3 took place the past couple of days, and of the various bits of news from the event, Ubisoft announced their Assassin's Creed title. I'm wholly indifferent to the Assassin's Creed games, but apparently this game features 4 person local multiplayer and only includes a slate of male characters. As a result of this news, some of my feminist former-friends posted articles to this effect: http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/11/5799386/no-female-characters-in-assassins-creed-unity-too-much-work

I'm not going to weigh in on the truth of Ubisoft's claims particularly, whether or not their claims were justified, or whether any of the views held by either side is right and just. The general consensus among the feminism crowd seemed to be along the lines that:

* 1. There are many sexist stereotypes prevalent in video games, possibly moreso in mainstream titles, and particularly noticed (by the feminists) are those stereotypes concerning women.
* 2. There is a large and substantial base of female gamers, many of whom would presumably enjoy games that break stereotypes and employ strong female lead characters
* 3. Many popular games today don't necessarily serve female gamers so well

I'm not going to suggest that feminists shouldn't complain (well, I might a little), but from my vantage point that's pretty much all I see get done. If you actually believe 1, 2, and 3 above, then there might be a GOLDEN MARKET OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU and you should invest your ranting energy into developing for this female gamer market (it's also overwhelmingly likely that this is, in fact, already being done and I'm just not particularly aware of it). Barriers to entry have probably never been lower to go develop for almost any platform you like, and indy games that hit it big have the opportunity to hit it REALLY big. You could make the video game equivalent of "Orange is the New Black" and have millions of loving, adoring fans who will cheer and talk about how you helped bring women into the video game mainstream. And hey, money!

Sadly, this attitude didn't much win over my feminist friends, who more or less told me to shut up and go fuck myself. So... yeah, I fail to see the problem with my thinking. Anybody want to help me out?
__________

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27218406020.0" user="Nebris" delta="False">
    <text>Do you realize how effective feminists have been simply by complaining?  It requires very little effort on their part, and its been getting the job done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218423429.0" user="aoigjreag" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree entirely. I don't think feminism has changed a single thing. I am seeing more and more games with "sexy" characters, fewer female protagonists, and games that do feature female protagonists flopping (Tomb Raider, Remember Me). Even Nintendo, which has always kept away from this stuff, has started sexualizing its characters. Look at Paultena's intro video, where the camera focuses on her ass and breasts. They are letting the heroine of Bayonetta wear Nintendo costumes. Fire Emblem used to be a fairly serious strategy game, now it is full of gross anime tropes and innuendos. Not to mention some of the characters in Hyrule Warriors. Games that objectify women like Dragon's Crown and Senran Kagura have been massive successes, despite all the protests from feminists and journalists.

Feminists were complaining about lack of representation in E3 this year. Well, they were doing the same exact thing last year, too. Nothing has changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218492924.0" user="BlackHumor" delta="False">
    <text>Look at the number of games that allow you to play as a woman that were released within the last five years. I can name five off the top of my head: Skyrim, Fallout New Vegas, the latest Pokemon, Mass Effect 3 (and 2), and Dragon Age 2.

Than look at the number of games that let you play as a woman 20-25 years ago. Most of these I had to look up: there's Super Metroid, there's Final Fantasy VI, and there's a few fighting games. And that was it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218510426.0" user="dcxcman" delta="False">
    <text>Lot's of games allow you to play as a woman. The argument here is that not nearly as many games have a female character as the only option compared to games with a male character. Metroid and Portal are about the only ones I can think of off the top of my head that have an exclusively female protagonist, and in the both cases it's not immediately obvious that you are playing as a woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218518940.0" user="BlackHumor" delta="False">
    <text>(To be fair to it, FF6 also had an exclusively female main character for both arcs. It just also had other characters.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219292479.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>Tomb Raider, Bayonetta, Catherine, and I think at least one of the Silent Hill games (though I haven't played them and honestly don't know). Resident Evil usually has a female protagonist along with a male protagonist with their own distinct story arcs (that is: you need to play as the female character and the male character to get the full story), and there are plenty of games where prominent/relevant NPCs are female.

The problem is that none of these games are the dudebro FPS games that get hyped to hell and back in mainstream media, and thus aren't all that visible unless you know to look for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218500143.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think feminism has changed a single thing.

I can tell you from personal experience that the videos and articles outlining sexist portrayals in video games are something discussed at great lengths between developers. There have been many a conversation about these issues, and these discussions do have effects how how the games are made and what kinds of characters and plots they have. This is happening much more in western games I think due in part to the language divide, but also due to cultural differences between western and eastern developers.

Your list of games that have sexist portrayals consists of almost entirely eastern games. You also state that the 2013 Tomb Raider (which is an example of a non-sexist portrayal of women) is a flop, but [my understanding is that that's not true at all.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomb_Raider_\(2013_video_game\)#Sales).

The feminist critiques might not be reaching Asian developers, but they are definitely having an impact on the thought process of developers over here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218719339.0" user="aoigjreag" delta="False">
    <text>"Discussion between developers" doesn't mean anything if the developers don't act on it. As a recent example, I remember when the developers of Shadow Warrior said [they were going to remove all the offensive sexist humor from the remake.](http://www.penny-arcade.com/report/article/shadow-warrior-reboot-keeps-setting-and-katana-ditches-sexism-racism-and-mp) Unfortunately, the ability for players to peep on naked girls taking baths was kept in the end. These developers can talk about inclusivity all they want, but they need to start showing it in their final product. 

[Also, despite millions of sales, yes, Tomb Raider was considered a flop.](http://www.digitalspy.com/gaming/news/a468632/tomb-raider-a-sales-flop-despite-shifting-34-million.html).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218811943.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "Discussion between developers" doesn't mean anything if the developers don't act on it. 

That's my point, they *do* act on it. It's precisely because of western developers awareness and discussion of these issues that it's better about gender dynamics overall. We have games like the Borderlands series which are fantastic at being inclusive. Or Bioshock Infinity, The Last of Us, Mass Effect, Portal, and many others which allow you to play as a woman or prominently feature women as major characters. We have more in terms of strong, interesting, or dynamic female characters in games as a result of these discussions happening. 

&amp;gt; Also, despite millions of sales, yes, Tomb Raider was considered a flop..

I think this is misleading. It was a flop financially because of the amount of money they sunk into it making it, not because the sales were poor in general, or poor relative to the rest of the series. It was critically acclaimed, topped charts, broke franchise records, and was second in sales only to Bioshock Infinity. Being a non-sexist portrayal of Croft didn't hurt the game at all. It's only failure was the executives overambitious goals for the game. The game showed that players were totally fine playing an interpretation of Lara Craft that wasn't completely over-sexualized. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
