<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134214340.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27wog4/cmv_i_believe_a_sustainable_market_for_video/">
    <title>CMV: I Believe a Sustainable Market for Video Games Oriented Towards Women Exists, and that Feminism Would Be Better Served to Develop For It Than Merely Complain About It</title>
    <original_poster>OhCrapADinosaur</original_poster>
    <original_post>E3 took place the past couple of days, and of the various bits of news from the event, Ubisoft announced their Assassin's Creed title. I'm wholly indifferent to the Assassin's Creed games, but apparently this game features 4 person local multiplayer and only includes a slate of male characters. As a result of this news, some of my feminist former-friends posted articles to this effect: http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/11/5799386/no-female-characters-in-assassins-creed-unity-too-much-work

I'm not going to weigh in on the truth of Ubisoft's claims particularly, whether or not their claims were justified, or whether any of the views held by either side is right and just. The general consensus among the feminism crowd seemed to be along the lines that:

* 1. There are many sexist stereotypes prevalent in video games, possibly moreso in mainstream titles, and particularly noticed (by the feminists) are those stereotypes concerning women.
* 2. There is a large and substantial base of female gamers, many of whom would presumably enjoy games that break stereotypes and employ strong female lead characters
* 3. Many popular games today don't necessarily serve female gamers so well

I'm not going to suggest that feminists shouldn't complain (well, I might a little), but from my vantage point that's pretty much all I see get done. If you actually believe 1, 2, and 3 above, then there might be a GOLDEN MARKET OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU and you should invest your ranting energy into developing for this female gamer market (it's also overwhelmingly likely that this is, in fact, already being done and I'm just not particularly aware of it). Barriers to entry have probably never been lower to go develop for almost any platform you like, and indy games that hit it big have the opportunity to hit it REALLY big. You could make the video game equivalent of "Orange is the New Black" and have millions of loving, adoring fans who will cheer and talk about how you helped bring women into the video game mainstream. And hey, money!

Sadly, this attitude didn't much win over my feminist friends, who more or less told me to shut up and go fuck myself. So... yeah, I fail to see the problem with my thinking. Anybody want to help me out?
__________

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27218401034.0" user="vokrama" delta="False">
    <text>Feminists don't just think that "women friendly games" ought to be some kind of market niche; they think that *all* games ought to be friendly to women and men alike. So I don't see how making a popular game with a strong female lead would help accomplish their goals. It's not like they'd be breaking new ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218647775.0" user="FormalPants" delta="False">
    <text>They could fund other feminist activities with the money while also creating something to help little girls enjoy videogames without feeling alienated.

Bitching's good too though.  Six of one, half dozen of the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219694849.0" user="vokrama" delta="False">
    <text>Little girls *can* enjoy video games without feeling alienated. They just can't enjoy all of them. Feminist groups have much more effective money raising activities than releasing video games.

Again, you're solving a problem that isn't there.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
