<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134214340.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27wog4/cmv_i_believe_a_sustainable_market_for_video/">
    <title>CMV: I Believe a Sustainable Market for Video Games Oriented Towards Women Exists, and that Feminism Would Be Better Served to Develop For It Than Merely Complain About It</title>
    <original_poster>OhCrapADinosaur</original_poster>
    <original_post>E3 took place the past couple of days, and of the various bits of news from the event, Ubisoft announced their Assassin's Creed title. I'm wholly indifferent to the Assassin's Creed games, but apparently this game features 4 person local multiplayer and only includes a slate of male characters. As a result of this news, some of my feminist former-friends posted articles to this effect: http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/11/5799386/no-female-characters-in-assassins-creed-unity-too-much-work

I'm not going to weigh in on the truth of Ubisoft's claims particularly, whether or not their claims were justified, or whether any of the views held by either side is right and just. The general consensus among the feminism crowd seemed to be along the lines that:

* 1. There are many sexist stereotypes prevalent in video games, possibly moreso in mainstream titles, and particularly noticed (by the feminists) are those stereotypes concerning women.
* 2. There is a large and substantial base of female gamers, many of whom would presumably enjoy games that break stereotypes and employ strong female lead characters
* 3. Many popular games today don't necessarily serve female gamers so well

I'm not going to suggest that feminists shouldn't complain (well, I might a little), but from my vantage point that's pretty much all I see get done. If you actually believe 1, 2, and 3 above, then there might be a GOLDEN MARKET OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU and you should invest your ranting energy into developing for this female gamer market (it's also overwhelmingly likely that this is, in fact, already being done and I'm just not particularly aware of it). Barriers to entry have probably never been lower to go develop for almost any platform you like, and indy games that hit it big have the opportunity to hit it REALLY big. You could make the video game equivalent of "Orange is the New Black" and have millions of loving, adoring fans who will cheer and talk about how you helped bring women into the video game mainstream. And hey, money!

Sadly, this attitude didn't much win over my feminist friends, who more or less told me to shut up and go fuck myself. So... yeah, I fail to see the problem with my thinking. Anybody want to help me out?
__________

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27218492083.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It rather sounds like you'd prefer women to go and make games about and for women, while men can continue to enjoy games about heroes. 

We grow up with the same stories as you do. We've noticed that we're invisible in these stories and we don't often get to take part. We want to play a hero, too, and to be represented. Female characters should simply be visible and have agency - in other words, be present, and be as cool as the guys.

It seems to be "common knowledge" that video games are driven by market forces, and the market is male. But just like in Hollywood, we've never actually been able to test that theory, because we've never had a chance to *try* creating games for a more balanced market. I think a lot of guys are doing quite a lot of pre-emptive whining because they're afraid that games are going to be "ruined" by some sort of equality mandate. But you don't even know that. They might get a lot better. The market might even get stronger. We should challenge the assumption that there are games that guys like and games that girls like, and that the current state of creative work is optimal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219171003.0" user="cfuse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It rather sounds like you'd prefer women to go and make games about and for women, while men can continue to enjoy games about heroes.

I cannot speak for OP, but I tend to believe that criticism (while it has its place) is vastly inferior to practical action (which in this case would be making 'better' games).

&amp;gt; We've noticed that we're invisible in these stories and we don't often get to take part. We want to play a hero, too, and to be represented. Female characters should simply be visible and have agency - in other words, be present, and be as cool as the guys.

1. I am not a hulking steroid addled hypermasculine man firing automatic weapons in all directions. The stereotypes for men as just as ridiculous as for women.

    [Dude, seriously. It's time to dial back on the butch.](http://i.imgur.com/iz36n0i.jpg)

    The narrative is typically as restricted and one dimensional as what feminists are complaining about: a thoroughly unrealistic standard.

    The reality is that avatars in gaming rarely represent *anyone*. It's like complaining that Sonic is male - Sonic is a *blue hedgehog*. Is a vagina and a hair bow really going to add or subtract significantly from that? Is some little girl's dreams *really* being crushed because Pacman is a man?

2. There are plenty of games that include female characters and female avatars. There are even games that do so without sucking. Why are these games *ignored* by the critics?

    Perhaps I'm not hanging out in the right places (likely), but where's the praise for the latest Tomb Raider for example?

    Criticism (IMO) has to include praise for those that get it right. There are games that get it right.

3. Is inclusion of a female avatar enough to argue inclusiveness? If it is, then I can list a huge number of games that do. If it's not - then what does inclusiveness look like (eg. what's the Bechdel test for games?)

&amp;gt; But just like in Hollywood, we've never actually been able to test that theory, because we've never had a chance to try creating games for a more balanced market.

In a word: bullshit.

Female devs have exactly the same kind of issues that male devs do. Can't develop a AAA title worth $200M? Guess what, neither can I. That doesn't stop you from downloading a copy of [Unity](http://unity3d.com/) and making whatever kind of game you like (Hell, dev with the [Unreal Engine](https://www.unrealengine.com/) if you've got the chops for it).

The point is, development has never been cheaper and easier than now, yet the complainers seem to keep expecting someone else to do it for them. I'm not outraged by the state of games - why should I be the one busting my ass for 18-24 months for no pay developing a game that might flop just to please *someone else's mores*?

I would say exactly the same thing to a feminist critic as I would to any other critic: if you don't like what you see, then get off your ass and at least have a go at fixing the problem as you see it. Talk is *cheap*, action not so much.

&amp;gt; We should challenge the assumption that there are games that guys like and games that girls like, and that the current state of creative work is optimal.

It's like when you go to the hardware store and see the pink hammer and wonder who thought that was a good idea. To me, boys and girls games is a somewhat toxic concept (at least in the absence of evidence of preferences^(1)).

The way I see it, games as an art are in the very early days. Apart from a few titles the narratives and design choices are pretty formulaic. The thing that increases the difficulty curve is that good gameplay and good art are often independent qualities. Mindless fun is still mindless fun - I'll happily play a game with *no story whatsoever* if it is fun. By the same token, my Steam library is littered with games I've either abandoned or never even played because they weren't enticing enough to keep my attention (regardless of how good they were as games or as art.

If we (because it's not like girl friendly game development should be restricted to feminists or females) want to develop better games then I think it comes back to using a gaming Bechdel test as a starting point. We can't just blindly dev games and just *hope* to hit on something that earns the seal of feminist approval (assuming that's the same thing as female approval, and market approval, which I think is a giant if).

---
1) This is another area that I will take the opportunity to scold feminist critics/gender researchers on. Making an application that tracks game usage by a preselected population is not difficult to do. That would be the kind of thing that could yield interesting insights into differences (if any) between male and female gamers. Hard data beats conjecture (no matter how intellectual) any day of the week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27219404321.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's like complaining that Sonic is male - Sonic is a blue hedgehog. Is a vagina and a hair bow really going to add or subtract significantly from that? Is some little girl's dreams really being crushed because Pacman is a man?

The problem is not the individual games but rather the market as a whole. These statements are simply strawmen.

&amp;gt; There are even games that do so without sucking. Why are these games ignored by the critics?

Not very many. Assassin's Creed: Liberation was one, Remember Me was another. Both got tons of praise. 

&amp;gt; Perhaps I'm not hanging out in the right places (likely), but where's the praise for the latest Tomb Raider for example?

http://www.forbes.com/sites/carolpinchefsky/2013/03/12/a-feminist-reviews-tomb-raiders-lara-croft/2/

&amp;gt; Is inclusion of a female avatar enough to argue inclusiveness? If it is, then I can list a huge number of games that do. If it's not - then what does inclusiveness look like (eg. what's the Bechdel test for games?)

It's not. Inclusiveness in games is very similar to inclusiveness in other media. Various female characters who are as varied as the male characters in their personalities, appearance, etc. The Bechdel test for video games.....is the Bechdel test....

&amp;gt; Female devs have exactly the same kind of issues that male devs do. Can't develop a AAA title worth $200M? Guess what, neither can I.

You should read about the hell developing the game Remember Me went through trying to find funding and a distributor for the game simply because the protagonist is a mixed race woman. How many companies were willing to fund and distribute the game if they rewrote the game to have a male protagonist instead. The gatekeepers of money for AAA games in general don't want female protagonists.

&amp;gt; The point is, development has never been cheaper and easier than now, yet the complainers seem to keep expecting someone else to do it for them.

As someone else in this thread stated, if I have a problem with how women are portrayed in media I'm not allowed to voice that problem and instead need to quit my job, learn a new skill, spend probably years developing a new game, and then if I don't have the money for marketing have it flop anyways regardless of how good it is, simply because the people who develop games as their career can't be bothered to not be sexist? Seriously?

Does this apply to everything? If you want to see political change then you shouldn't complain, you need to immediately drop your job and become a politician? If you want to see a change in a particular hardware component, you need to develop it yourself and have no right to complain? This is a ridiculous argument.

&amp;gt; To me, boys and girls games is a somewhat toxic concept

I agree completely on this one.

&amp;gt; Hard data beats conjecture (no matter how intellectual) any day of the week.

We do have data from surveys on what types of games people say they play separated by gender. And we find from those surveys that if it weren't for toxic communities and sexism that is faced by women playing online, we'd see roughly equal ratios of men and women playing the same types of games. Tons of women in those surveys state how they used to play games like call of duty or League of Legends (two highly male dominated communities) but stopped due to harassment or sexism in the online community. 

Don't knock the researchers claiming they don't have hard data unless you've actually looked at the data they do have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220449161.0" user="cfuse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The problem is not the individual games but rather the market as a whole.

Like I said, male representations are not really any better than female ones. If the only difference that feminists want is that it is a female space marine instead of a male one, then I really don't think they are setting the bar very high.

&amp;gt; Not very many.

Considering the amount of automatic rejection I keep seeing from feminists/females when it comes to making games, I'm not surprised. People (indies, not studios) make games for themselves. Don't like what you are seeing? Fix it.

&amp;gt; http://www.forbes.com/sites/carolpinchefsky/2013/03/12/a-feminist-reviews-tomb-raiders-lara-croft/2/

Yay.

&amp;gt; It's not. Inclusiveness in games is very similar to inclusiveness in other media. Various female characters who are as varied as the male characters in their personalities, appearance, etc. The Bechdel test for video games.....is the Bechdel test....

Well, then I guess the problem is that inclusiveness is very similar to other media.

I know I'm harping on about this, but if others (especially established power players in the business) aren't going to support you in creating more female friendly games, then you have to do it yourself.

What would you say to a female filmmaker if she was unhappy with the state of the industry? You'd tell her to go make a film that passes the Bechdel test (at the very least).

&amp;gt; You should read about the hell developing the game Remember Me went through trying to find funding and a distributor for the game simply because the protagonist is a mixed race woman. How many companies were willing to fund and distribute the game if they rewrote the game to have a male protagonist instead. The gatekeepers of money for AAA games in general don't want female protagonists.

I don't doubt that is the reality. If you know the 'gatekeepers' (who aren't really gatekeepers in this day and age of self publishing) aren't going to come to the party then you need to do an end run around them. This is doable, others have done it. What is unrealistic is expecting to go from where we are today to a market full of AAA titles that all pass the Bechdel test - change must be iterative and incremental. Somebody has to start somewhere.

&amp;gt; As someone else in this thread stated, if I have a problem with how women are portrayed in media I'm not allowed to voice that problem and instead need to quit my job, learn a new skill, spend probably years developing a new game, and then if I don't have the money for marketing have it flop anyways regardless of how good it is, simply because the people who develop games as their career can't be bothered to not be sexist? Seriously?

There's nothing wrong with criticism, and you have every right to criticise. I'm not here to silence you or anyone else, because regardless of what I think of the positions offered I support the right to express them.

However, there are two aspects I would like to address:

1. Nothing is stopping you from game dev other than you. Being a game dev is no different to any other high risk career - and if you're not cut out for it, I don't blame you for that. 

    The idea that *no* feminist/woman should be a dev and have direct investment in their ideas is silly. If you have faith in what you're saying then somebody has to action that at some point. It's no different to any other aspect of breaking barriers for women in feminism - women had to get out and do, they had to fight their way into universities, into jobs, to get the vote, etc. They didn't just sit around with idle criticism - they did what they needed to do. I don't see how this is any different.

2. There aren't the gatekeepers of old to please. Kickstarter for money. Steam Greenlight for platform sales. The limit here is that your game needs to be good - not fancy, not expensive, but good. You aren't competing with AAA titles, you are making indie experimental games. There's going to have to be plenty of failures to the few successes (just like normal indies experience). This is a venture with inherent risk - but *why can't you put your money where your mouth is?*

The dreaded patriarchy isn't keeping you down here, it's you keeping you down here. You have access to the same tools and knowledge that any other dev does, you have to raise funding just like any other dev does, you will probably have to live off ramen just like any dev does. Maybe you can't dev - but I find it hard to believe that you can contribute nothing of value to a project. Everyone has some useful skills.

&amp;gt; Does this apply to everything? If you want to see political change then you shouldn't complain, you need to immediately drop your job and become a politician? If you want to see a change in a particular hardware component, you need to develop it yourself and have no right to complain? This is a ridiculous argument.

If you want to see change then you have to do more than just complain. As I have said, criticism has its place.

If you think that solely complaining is going to get you the outcome you want, then do that. I don't believe that is the case, and I think that feminists and women need to be devs to reach that goal (because I *can't*. I'm not a feminist (for a variety of reasons, but I support the existence of and rights gained by feminism) and I'm not a woman. How much insight am I going to have into the issues? And even if I did manage to make a feminist friendly game I can guarantee that I would receive criticism for doing that and being male).

&amp;gt; Tons of women in those surveys state how they used to play games like call of duty or League of Legends (two highly male dominated communities) but stopped due to harassment or sexism in the online community.

This is true, but it is a separate issue to the idea of feminist friendly games. Stopping online sexism is like stopping trolling or other nastiness - virtually impossible. If I were a feminist game dev, I'd make a game about the experience of sexism as a woman for men/boys to play - games don't have to be happy or fun experiences (see Spec Ops: The Line, aka. PTSD the game), they have to be affecting experiences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220850792.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Like I said, male representations are not really any better than female ones. If the only difference that feminists want is that it is a female space marine instead of a male one, then I really don't think they are setting the bar very high.

Male representations in video games are miles better than female ones. Male characters get varied representation you have ugly male characters, you have male power fantasies, you have short, tall, in between. You have villains, you have heroes, you have sidekicks, characters that are fleshed out and characters that are on the sidelines. Male characters come in all shapes, sizes, backstories, etc. Female characters are almost universally just hot eye candy. You don't find Grizzled old space marine women and how they have dealt with the sexism of other space marines through their career, etc. It's not just wanting a female space marine instead of a male one, it's wanting female characters to be as widely variable as male characters. To not be relegated to being the eye candy, damsel, or male character with tits. 

&amp;gt;  People (indies, not studios) make games for themselves. Don't like what you are seeing? Fix it.

There's a huge barrier to entry for this though it's just not a feasible argument to say "don't like it? Quit your job, spend years learning a new skill, and then spend years making your own game hoping that the unlikely event will happen that someone will pick it up and distribute it for you so you can make enough money to survive. Because you don't have a right to criticize existing media if you can't do this". That's just a ridiculous argument. 

It's like saying that if I don't like the war in Afganistan I shouldn't protest or complain, I should become a politician who specializes in foreign affairs and single handedly end the war myself.

&amp;gt; Well, then I guess the problem is that inclusiveness is very similar to other media.

Yep. Inclusiveness in games is just as bad as it is in movies, tv, etc.

&amp;gt; I know I'm harping on about this, but if others (especially established power players in the business) aren't going to support you in creating more female friendly games, then you have to do it yourself.
What would you say to a female filmmaker if she was unhappy with the state of the industry? You'd tell her to go make a film that passes the Bechdel test (at the very least).

If she was already a filmmaker? Sure! If it's her career and that's what she does then that makes sense. However you're telling people who *are not game developers* who have entirely different careers, that they have no right to complain, and instead they should quit their current job, spend years learning how to make games, and then spend years making a game. It's an absurd statement.

&amp;gt; What is unrealistic is expecting to go from where we are today to a market full of AAA titles that all pass the Bechdel test - change must be iterative and incremental. Somebody has to start somewhere.

You're right about iterative and incremental, and the fastest increments of change we could see is if the large AAA companies start changing. It's unrealistic to expect it to happen overnight. But over the course of a few years with new people getting into the industry? Sure, that's something we can expect. We've seen games come out of the big companies before that are good, it's a matter of keeping those coming and getting people to recognize the sexism in the others.

&amp;gt; Nothing is stopping you from game dev other than you. Being a game dev is no different to any other high risk career - and if you're not cut out for it, I don't blame you for that.

yet, you are claiming that people who are not "cut out for" game dev should stop complaining about the industry unless they are willing to make a game. 

&amp;gt; The idea that no feminist/woman should be a dev and have direct investment in their ideas is silly

I agree, no where did I say that or anyone else in this thread. The point is that "you don't like it? Go make your own game!" is not a valid response to criticism of sexism in video games. I'd never stop a feminist from being a dev and having direct involvement in games. I'd highly encourage anyone who wants to, to do it. But it's not a feasible thing for tons of people. 

&amp;gt;  The limit here is that your game needs to be good - not fancy, not expensive, but good.

Agreed. And not everyone with a good idea can make a good game. That's the point. 

&amp;gt;  You have access to the same tools and knowledge that any other dev does, you have to raise funding just like any other dev does, you will probably have to live off ramen just like any dev does. Maybe you can't dev - but I find it hard to believe that you can contribute nothing of value to a project

Except you don't have the same skills and experience that *any other dev does*, perhaps they have a family and can't afford to live on ramen like that? Perhaps they have people that depend on them and they can't just quit their job and do that? Again, it's absurd to say that it's wrong to criticise or complain unless you're actively making a game. It's just a bad argument that ignores the existence of reality.

&amp;gt; And even if I did manage to make a feminist friendly game I can guarantee that I would receive criticism for doing that and being male).

If you did it right, then you wouldn't receive any criticism for being male while doing it. THe likelihood of you pulling it off by yourself is pretty low, but it wouldn't be difficult to ask people to help you, to have women and feminists help. And it would be awesome if you could do this, but by no means does it make sense to dismiss criticism and protests and using your wallet to fund things that are good versus not funding sexism simply because I don't have the time, funding, or ability to make a game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221795068.0" user="cfuse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Male representations in video games are miles better than female ones. Male characters get varied representation you have ugly male characters, you have male power fantasies, you have short, tall, in between. You have villains, you have heroes, you have sidekicks, characters that are fleshed out and characters that are on the sidelines. Male characters come in all shapes, sizes, backstories, etc. 

Show me the leading queer man of colour. There's plenty of inclusiveness issues here too.

I'm not saying "My problems are bigger than yours!" (although I've always had an issue with the "His glass has more in it than mine" school of feminist problem solving, simply because I think the problem is more complex than simply generating parity. The problem is bigger than that). I'm saying that failing to address the *entire* problem (white straight male viewpoints/narratives) is more important than putting in some girls like that's all it's going to take.

&amp;gt; Female characters are almost universally just hot eye candy. You don't find Grizzled old space marine women and how they have dealt with the sexism of other space marines through their career, etc. It's not just wanting a female space marine instead of a male one, it's wanting female characters to be as widely variable as male characters. To not be relegated to being the eye candy, damsel, or male character with tits.

And this is fair. I view this as a subset of fixing the problem (which you need not agree with).

It isn't enough to throw in women without addressing the roles of men in that interaction (as is the case (and the flaw in thought IMO) with so many feminist issues). Not dealing with the problem holistically is not going to work.

&amp;gt; There's a huge barrier to entry for this though 

No. I'm sick of seeing this falsehood repeated.

The tools are available (and either cheap or free), the knowledge to learn is available (again, cheap or free), your time is as available as you make it - if you refuse to make it available, that's you making a limit for yourself, not an external limit.

Distribution is pretty much free. You can do it yourself it nobody else will.

&amp;gt; it's just not a feasible argument to say "don't like it? Quit your job, spend years learning a new skill, and then spend years making your own game hoping that the unlikely event will happen that someone will pick it up and distribute it for you so you can make enough money to survive. Because you don't have a right to criticize existing media if you can't do this". That's just a ridiculous argument.

You always have the right to criticise. I hope it gets you what you want. I don't believe that criticism alone will (YMMV).

If the criticism is "Nobody's making the kind of games that need to be made" then you tell me why making that kind of game isn't a valid response to that?

You tell me why criticism is the only valid (or even the best) course of action?

&amp;gt; It's like saying that if I don't like the war in Afganistan I shouldn't protest or complain, I should become a politician who specializes in foreign affairs and single handedly end the war myself.

Again, I'm not telling you not to protest.

Why can't you become (more) politically active and work to end a war you don't agree with? Maybe your black and white thinking of *do nothing* vs. *end the war single handed* could be tempered with a bit of reality. Can you not write a letter to your senator, give their office a call? Can you not go to a peace protest? There *are* things you can do.

To be frank, I hear nothing but excuses from you about how it's all *impossible* for no other reason than you don't give enough of a shit to do something about it. That simply doesn't cut it with me. You have agency, that you choose not to exercise it is your own choice, not some universal constant that prevents your action.

Sure, criticism is an action, but it's often a weak one. There's a reason the phrase "Action speaks louder than words" exists.

&amp;gt; However you're telling people who are not game developers who have entirely different careers, that they have no right to complain, and instead they should quit their current job, spend years learning how to make games, and then spend years making a game.

A) That's not what I'm saying, and I'm getting tired of you making out that it is. By all means, criticise away.

B) I assume you have free time? Maybe you could spend some of that actually following up on what I've said about the current state of game development. It is something you could do (either by yourself, or with others) if you cared to.

I've seen a video of a transsexual woman that made a game maker game to teach her friend about her experience of everyday life (and I'm kicking myself that I can't find it). Game maker is pretty easy to use.

Look, I believe that action is just as (if not more) important as criticism. You don't have to agree with that.

&amp;gt; You're right about iterative and incremental, and the fastest increments of change we could see is if the large AAA companies start changing.

AAA is congruent with Hollywood, and we know where Hollywood stands on inclusiveness.

AAA is not going to take big risks, they are businesses first and artists second (just like Hollywood).

Where indies excel is in doing things that AAA won't - like inclusiveness.

If you think you can start at the top, good luck to you. I don't agree with that.

**I'm just going to stop quoting and responding at this point, the argument you seem to be making is that I am telling you to shut up and make a game, when the reality is that I am offering you an alternative to pure criticism. If you elect not to take that up, that's your choice and I can accept it.**

&amp;gt; If you did it right, then you wouldn't receive any criticism for being male while doing it.

I'd cop flack for cultural appropriation off the bat, and that's before we get to the pure hate that a man did it before a woman. It would be like if I was a white straight man making a game about the experience of being a black lesbian - I'd be *crucified* for that.

People are very good is hating those that they think are stepping out of their appropriate roles, and feminists are no different when it comes to that (even if they are operating under the flawed assumption that they are free from all bias).

If I did make a game that was female friendly to the point of being feminist friendly (which realistically can be male hostile) then I'd simply make up a reclusive female alter-ego so that I didn't have to deal with the bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
