<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36485070334.0" user="obert-wan-kenobert" delta="False">
    <text>Racism takes a lot of different forms. "I blame Asian women for my sex addiction and want to murder them to rid myself of temptation" is definitely one of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485114951.0" user="TruthOrFacts" delta="False">
    <text>First off, that explanation is a joke.  We don't have an issue in society where racists attacks are based off sexual attraction.  And the claims this attack was racist are based on kung flu lines of thinking, blaming asian people for covid etc, and that doesn't align with what occured.  So we have a narrative being built that is obviously false and politically motivated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485136886.0" user="obert-wan-kenobert" delta="False">
    <text>You’re saying people can’t be racist against a certain race if they’re also sexually attracted to that race?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485181006.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think the overall thought here is that we have to be very careful. We have to find facts. If a man goes into a Walmart and gets angry because they ran out of donuts, so he comes back and starts spraying and hits 10 people, and 8 were Native American, that doesn't mean it was a racially motivated crime. This crime is still in its infancy and we don't have all the information. For instance, I have yet to read any article that says he specifically blamed Asian women. I've only read where he specifically targeted spas and blamed a sex addiction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485764742.0" user="Fakename998" delta="False">
    <text>I will say that your analogy is not quite right, since if these Asian spas were known to be Asian-owned/employed then comparing them to a Walmart isn't quite analogous. It's like comparing a Applebee's restaurant to some local Chinese restaurant. You have an expectation of what kind of people you might find working at an established if it's ethnically-marketed. I have no argument for or against your other point. I am not personally aware of the exact explanation of the motive. By the way the police are handling it with the media, I don't necessarily trust the way they're portraying it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36486035613.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, I agree that my analogy wasn't crafted perfectly, but I'm glad you caught my drift. The problem I see with our media coverage is that there is often so much speculation in the beginning that it doesn't matter what the facts are in the end, because by that time the speculation has turned into the "true" story regardless of the facts that were found. Justice shouldn't be predicated on speculation and feelings, but on straight facts. What we do know is that he killed other human beings and he will be prosecuted. There are families that are grieving and deserve comfort and justice. These are facts. There is a movement to highlight anti-Asian crime and I'm all for that. It needs to be shown and confronted, but so many people have jumped on this story as if it is a race-motivated crime and we just don't know yet. Again we can speculate, and I can even agree that the guy probably has some Asian fetish, but still that's just speculation at this point and we don't do ourselves any favors muddying the waters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485191064.0" user="TruthOrFacts" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't what I said.  You know this attack isn't a "damn asians wrecking up our country I'll kill them to send a message" sort of thing.  This disturbed guys kink isn't a product of Trump rhetoric or white nationalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489211244.0" user="Moldy_Gecko" delta="False">
    <text>It'd be pretty masochistic to pay people you hate for a rub and tug.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485234274.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>He didn't explicitly blame Asian women for his sex addiction. It seems he was blaming sex workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485435642.0" user="im2wddrf" delta="False">
    <text>Is it possible perhaps that his idea of sex workers is fixated on Asians? Something along the lines of, "I would like to rid the world of temptation/sin. Who better embodies that than the Asian establishments I frequented?" He frequented those establishments *because* they were Asian (assuming that was his fetish). Therefore, whatever violence he would have committed would inevitably fall on Asians. Thus, it was racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485499645.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>Why is our analysis so rough over something as important to us as race? Does this really count as sophisticated systemic or psychological analysis? How is racism so murkily defined as to be only vaguely related? If this was a shooting motivated by incel type emotions, because he was attracted to Asian people does not make race the primary dimension.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485623097.0" user="im2wddrf" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with your general analysis, I think we need to go a level deeper. If he has a general affinity towards Asians and he happened upon these establishments, then perhaps it was not a racially motivated incident. If his primary conception of decadence and sin symbolized in Asian parlors (as opposed to other forms of decadence, such as online porn, strip clubs, etc.), and his fetishization of Asian women contributes to this very specific conception of sin, then an argument can be made that this was racially motivated. To say that his motivations were racially motivated *does not* mean that other motivations and factors were not in play.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36487116855.0" user="1917fuckordie" delta="False">
    <text>So he was such a misogynist he believed he needed to murder sex workers to remove the temptation of him "sinning", and just happened to have an asain fetish?

To me that sounds like he hates sex workers and women, and the asain part is secondary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489118203.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, the asian women were literally prostitutes. If you live in a city, at least 95% of the asian massage parlors in your area are brothels, it's just the easiest way to get cheap prostitutes. I know there are women who still do street walking, but I don't really see them much at all these days, and I'm out all night. The ones online are usually upscale, high price with it, and the cheap sites all got hit by the feds a couple years ago. Honestly, the legally safest and surprisingly cheapest way to get a prostitute is to go to an asian massage parlor. They get way, way too much business to be fetish only.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489197215.0" user="Moldy_Gecko" delta="False">
    <text>Racism means you hate them, which could be the case if he was a masochist.  But, for example, real racists, like the KKK wouldn't be caught dead in those places to begin with.  People just want to incorrectly throw around the word racism nowadays.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489109999.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So why did he seek out three Asian sex parlors, and intend to go to more in Florida, but couldn’t even be bothered to go to a single parlor that had employees of other races?  They are plentiful.  Lots of white people and other minorities choose sex work, and are trafficked in the u.s.  it isn’t hard to find non Asian sex workers.  But all three parlors he went to were predominantly Asian, and the ones he intended to shoot in Florida are believed to be Asian as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36823138113.0" user="RocketHopper" delta="False">
    <text>He was planning to go to Florida to shoot up porn studios, not Asian parlors, and Asian massage parlors are legal brothels that's why he was there</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
