<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36485599281.0" user="im2wddrf" delta="False">
    <text>Here is what I would say: 

A. The shooter may have a legal motive to not frame his crime as racially motivated. There is also a psychological motive for this perpetrator to convince himself that his actions were not racist, even though they were. In evaluating his whether this is racist, we should not weigh too heavily the perpetrator's own stated motives but look at the entirety of the evidence. The picture, as painted in this very moment, could support the theory that this was racially motivated, could also go the other way. I would also like to say that fetishization is not the same as "loving". Fetishization has to do with pleasure, and one can derive pleasure from the pain or dominance over others. If someone were to have a "rape fetish", that does not mean that they love rape, nor does it mean that they "love" any potential non-consenting victims (I am deliberately contrasting with partners who consent ahead of time to rape-play).

B. I think as details come out, it will further clarify whether the murder of the white victims support the theory of hate crime. For instance, it is entirely possible that in the commission of these crimes, the perpetrator saw that these white people were soliciting services from an industry he saw as inherently immoral; could be possible that he was angry, particularly with white people, who engaged in immoral behavior with Asians. Take for example this scenario: if a white man, having decided that the drug trade is so immoral as to require the murder of individuals participating in said trade, proceeds to go into a [known] predominantly black area of town (specifically because this individual conceptually ties blackness with drug trade), and then seeks and kills a black drug dealer and a white person in the middle of the drug deal, a case can still be made that racism motivated that rampage. 

C. I would argue that expressions of anti-China sentiment, though not indicative, does not prove his actions were not racist. In addition, expressions of anti-Asian prejudice may not distinguish between different cultures in the Asian continent (racists may not care about the differences between Korean, Japanese. Chinese, etc depending on how that prejudice is expressed).

D. There are different forms of racism that range from the ideological white nationalism รก la Klu Klux Klan, to a nascent general disdain/prejudice that is not verbally expressed but still emotionally felt. Confining our profile of racists to politically active white nationalists does not help us in evaluating whether this incident was racially motivated because racist behavior expresses itself in different ways. 

E. See D. "Usually come with manifestos" is not proof that this incident was not racist. In addition, I disagree that racist shootings come with manifestos. If, say, a predominantly African American gang were to venture into a predominantly Hispanic neighborhood and shoot bystanders, I would classify this as an intentionally racist shooting. Again, racial violence is highly contextual and we should be more mindful in the many profiles/contexts racist behaviors can manifest. 

F. The issue of meritocracy has nothing to do with this incident. To look at the literal murder of six asian victims and then recast the issue as one progressivism gone awry is terribly tone deaf and unproductive in understanding this specific, tragic incident. 

G. A strict criticism of China as a global power is not racism or xenophobia, but can become an expression of xenophobia depending on when such arguments are levied. For instance, if someone were offered American-made Chinese food and then that same person declines, citing their disdain for Chinese authoritarianism, then this could potentially be seen as racist since the actions of the government are tied to the culture-people. I follow many progressives who are outspoken about their criticism of China, though I am unsure what the Chinese government has anything to do with the killings of Atlanta.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
