<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36487386598.0" user="lavishlymediocre" delta="False">
    <text>That Newsweek op-ed is terrible. She writes "Asian Americans," but at best is referring to a small group of Chinese Americans. She also does not seem to actually understand what CRT is. Here is a piece written by an Asian American woman who was part of its conception: [Critical Race Theory is Not Anti-Asian](http://reappropriate.co/2021/03/mari-matsuda-critical-race-theory-is-not-anti-asian/). 

The only people who argue that "Asians are white-adjacent" are the ones who are trying to perpetuate the model minority myth that white conservatives have used for years to try to separate Asian Americans from other communities of color ([Not Your Wedge](https://www.advancingjustice-la.org/what-we-do/policy-and-research/educational-opportunity-and-empowerment/affirmative-action/not-your-wedge)).

It's my understanding that you're taking that op-ed to suggest that affirmative action and other similar policies are "the #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face." This is simply not true, as there are many more Asian American and Pacific Islander advocacy groups who support affirmative action policies ([Over 160 AAPI Groups File Brief in Support of Affirmative Action](https://www.advancingjustice-la.org/media-and-publications/press-releases/over-160-asian-american-and-pacific-islander-groups-file#.W1ulL9JKiUn), [Community orgs that supported ending California's ban on affirmative action - you'll see a lot of AAPI orgs on the list](https://voteyesonprop16.org/endorsements/endorsements-organizations/)).

If these shootings were not anti-Asian, then why drive 20-something miles to the next shooting location. Where there no other massage places, strip clubs, or adult entertainment stores between? If it was just motived by sex addiction, I think he could have doing more damage by going to places nearby instead of driving out of the way to places that also just so happen to have Asian employees.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
