<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36489153309.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You keep bringing up the fact that he killed a white woman and a whites man as evidence that it wasn’t racially motivated.  So why aren’t you arguing against this being an attack against women or sex workers, because one of the victims was a whites man and likely buyer?

You aren’t using your logic consistently, instead only where it conveniences you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489679743.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So why aren’t you arguing against this being an attack against women or sex workers, because one of the victims was a whites man and likely buyer?

Because the sexual dimension != the racial dimension. While racists, especially white supremacists, fetishize their own race, in particular the white ethnostate. We cannot say the same for incel types in regards to men. It's a hatred of women largely built on rejection. It's emotional, irrational, bleeding heart stuff. Makes sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489783132.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No your comment doesn’t make sense it doesn’t seem coherent or like it answers the question at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489800583.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>In what way? Racists fetishize their own race and see their measures as protective. Incels fetishize women and their pain to them. The only incoherency I see here is your treating of sex like race. There are certain ports that don't work. Think transgendered vs transracial. Sex and race is different. Fundamentally. That's why killing another man and likely buyer isn't a counterpoint to the incel rage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489812488.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Read my question so you address it.  You’re responding incoherently.  I didn’t mention incels.  You’re going on a tangent that isn’t related to my question.  

I’m not treating sex like race at all.  I asked a question about your flawed Logic.


Also, transgendered is not a word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489865364.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You’re responding incoherently. I didn’t mention incels.

Incel shit is the best explanation. That's the context of what you are commenting on. Look:

&amp;gt;So why aren’t you arguing against this being an attack against women or sex workers, because one of the victims was a whites man and likely buyer?

You asked why I am not arguing _against_ this being incel shit AKA against women or sex workers, because killing a white man and likely buyer is a counterpoint _in the same way_ to incel narrative as the white people are a counterpoint to the racist narrative. 

That's your claim. Right? Symmetrical comparison. 

The problem is your theory of mind is undifferentiated between race and sex. By making a symmetrical comparison, you are comparing apples and oranges. There's your incoherency.

And sure it is. Transgendered is a word. It doesn't have currency within the trans theorist camp because it's an adjective and not a noun. Haha they are incoherent, unfortunately, because they will turn around and describe the superstraight phenomenon as illegitimate because transness is a trait like being tall or with black hair, therefore superstraight not an orientation.

Anyways, you see the point, where transracial is not symmetrical to transgender? Sex and race are _different._ Therefore, it is illogical to compare them as symmetrical as you've done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489893813.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>They are comparable you just don’t want to answer the damn question.  Just like apples and oranges are comparable.  They’re both round, fruit, sugary, have calories, grow on trees, it goes on and on.  No two things you compare are exact or it isn’t a fucking comparison.  You cannot explain why a man who people acknowledge targeted sex workers, and who claims himself targeted sex workers, killed a man who was likely a buyer not a sex worker does not discredit him attacking sex workers, but you think that him killing two white people means he was not targeting Asians.  You don’t want to answer the question because you don’t want to admit logical fallacy.  But the two are fucking comparable.  I’m blocking you so I stop getting spammed with your incoherent comments and bs.  I’m done engaging and it is irritating to get notifications from you.

Transgendered is not a word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490361329.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are comparable you just don’t want to answer the damn question. Just like apples and oranges are comparable. They’re both round, fruit, sugary, have calories, grow on trees, it goes on and on. 

Right but you do understand the idiom, yes? Race and sex are comparable, but not as symmetries which deviation from reveals illogic. If one treats race differently than sex, and maintains that race and sex are different, there's no internal incoherency.

&amp;gt;No two things you compare are exact or it isn’t a fucking comparison. 

I'm not nitpicking. The dynamics and motivations between racism and inceldom are fundamentally different, to _at least_ the point where a symmetrical analysis doesn't autoprove illogic, as you seem to think. 

&amp;gt;You cannot explain why a man who people acknowledge targeted sex workers, and who claims himself targeted sex workers, killed a man who was likely a buyer not a sex worker does not discredit him attacking sex workers, but you think that him killing two white people means he was not targeting Asians. 

I did, but I'll put it another way. You're fixating on identity. You think hate works like this precise targeting of categories of people based on immutable characteristics for those characteristics alone. However, did you know incels also hate men? They hate the other men girls have sex with. Incels are not identitarians in the way racists are. My claim is you have an insufficient theory of mind for incels or sex-based killings. They are primarily poorly calibrated and incredibly libidinous individuals, who is spurned by rejection, who are addicted to what they can't have. Look up Elliot Rodger, king of the incels. He killed men and women. Okay? 

&amp;gt;You don’t want to answer the question because you don’t want to admit logical fallacy.

This is projection. You've committed a logical fallacy called _reification._ https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reification_(fallacy)#:~:text=Reification%20(also%20known%20as%20concretism,real%20event%20or%20physical%20entity. You are treating sex and race as independent of any theory of mind.

&amp;gt;Transgendered is not a word.

Yes, it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490243848.0" user="jjjjll3754" delta="False">
    <text>no, transgendered is not a word. if in the "trans theorist camp" they dont use it i dont understand why you think you know better &amp;amp; can speak for them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490515576.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>Here's something to consider. "Transgendered" isn't a word because it's an adjective and not a noun. Yet, in thinking about superstraight orientation, in a thread yesterday, I was told repeatedly that superstraight wasn't an orientation but a preference -- because trans was like 'tall' or 'black hair.' 

Could it be that this control of language is, actually, political? That, there's no actual principle underneath it all.

It would explain how it happens that sex is not gender, and sex is nature and gender is nurture, and yet sex is assigned and gender is real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490702149.0" user="jjjjll3754" delta="False">
    <text>why are you bringing up all of these strawmans thats not magically gonna make it a word, transgender isnt a seperate sex or gender thats why superstraight makes no sense, that doesnt make words magically exist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490901528.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>Quite literally, that is the real argumentation happening in the other thread. So within the trans community, you have transgender as a mere trait, which makes 'transgendered' a natural and intuitive descriptor. Oh yes, with a formal history of use. 

&amp;gt;transgender isnt a seperate sex or gender

Oh really? It's not a protected class? It's not a gender nor a sex?  There's no difference to be found in that trans, modifier, hmm?

What do you think of the difference between a simulation of reality and reality. It's my theory that trans theorists and their Progressive umbrella suffer from hyperreality. Do you find no distinction between, say, a trans vulva and a natural vulva?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36490923151.0" user="jjjjll3754" delta="False">
    <text>youre sitting here trying to instigate a gender and sex and superstraight argument when i didnt mention any of that. get some hobbies or something bro youre literally just getting offended over a word not existing in the dictionary and writing paragraphs about shit i never said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36491141836.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I didn't think you'd be coherent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36491200022.0" user="jjjjll3754" delta="False">
    <text>i truly dont care. im not having an argument with you about shit i never brought up bc you have nothing better to do. facts dont care about your feelings</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36491494093.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>transgendered is a word: fact #1</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
