<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36485377252.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>I mean even if the guy wasn't racist and never said a single thing about asians, doesn't it still say something about our culture that the sex workers he viewed as disposal and blamed for his problems *happened* to all be Asian women? Like if there was no obvious racial component here, like you're saying we should assume there isn't, well, isn't that a strange coincidence? Or maybe it isn't a coincidence, and actually, asian sex workers happen to be some of the most vulnerable people in our society, and the killer targeted those people specifically because of the way our society is. Maybe the guy wasn't explicitly motivated by race, but the outcome was still racist in effect, and, you know, maybe we should think about why that outcome happened the way it did. Instead of just defending a murderer for no reason</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485428305.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure how I am defending the murderer. I'm not trying to say he's not racist to say he's a good guy or to humanize him. Like oh, don't hurt his feelings! I'm saying to see this as primarily an anti-Asian event due to criticizing China is .. not solid reasoning. Yet, that's the conclusion that seems to be in effect. Trump said the virus came from China, ergo, white people want to kill Asians. 

Why are there Asian sex workers? Why did it happen to be Korean masseuses? Is there a system of White Supremacy which encourages society to be such a way to encourage Asians to get into sex work? I'm not sure. Asians do really well in our society! If there is anti-Asian sentiment, it's the antiracist folks saying formal discrimination against Asians are necessary because they are doing too well for themselves. What's more important, that Asians face actual discriminatory measures in education or jokes about China with a Y? Chyna?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
