<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36485133419.0" user="jendickers" delta="False">
    <text>The guy had a sex addiction and an Asian fetish. He killed those people to try to eliminate a temptation. This is racist fetishization that turned to murder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485181418.0" user="SuperStallionDriver" delta="False">
    <text>So at what point would you slice racism vs mental instability?

If I go kill my neighbor family because I think that they were secretly communing with the ghosts in my shed to give me nightmares for example... What if I had that belief because I had seen my neighbors (we will say they are hispanic) praying and lighting candles which in my mind is superstition/mysticism?

In my mind both cases are a case of mental derangement. The individual flavor of derangement is sort of unimportant in my mind.

Trying to ascribe rational reasons to irrational acts (racism is rational, if inaccurate and rediculous) doesn't impart any real understanding, just makes a more coherent narrative. Narratives make us feel good because we can say we understand what happened and take action. But some things are just irrational and unpredictable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485220285.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Did he have an Asian fetish?  I hadn't read that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485228501.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>"Asian fetish" is an anti-Asian sentiment on its face. Loving Asians is not an Asian fetish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485246268.0" user="edwardlleandre" delta="False">
    <text>You can fetishize something while also being racist. Look at slave owners who raped their slaves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485296010.0" user="zuluportero" delta="False">
    <text>You also can be attracted to a race more than others without it being a fetish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485342132.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>But if your rule is _any time_ someone is attracted to Asians it's Asian fetishizing, or that _at all times_ we must be critical or suspicious of attraction to Asians as such, it's anti-Asian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485462589.0" user="jendickers" delta="False">
    <text>No one said that was the case?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485536993.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>Right in this thread -- attraction to Asians is de facto Asian fetishizing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485560014.0" user="jendickers" delta="False">
    <text>No one said that. I did assert that driving out of your way to “eliminate the temptation”, that temptation being Asian women, means he had an fetish for Asian women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485805326.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>If you go on a killing spree towards those Asians it seems fair to suggest there's some wierd thoughts and fetishization involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485884385.0" user="1msera" delta="False">
    <text>This thread - that you made - is about a very specific incident. The only person broadening the scope to "any time" or "at all times" is you, as a deflection tactic. 

Obviously, *in this example that you chose to post about,* we're dealing with an individual who harbored a dehumanizing fetish and funneled that into a deadly hate crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485945534.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>If people are saying he had sex Asians, therefore fetishization -- there's your broad scope framework. Which is decidedly anti-Asian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485979653.0" user="1msera" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If people are saying he had sex Asians, therefore fetishization  

People aren't saying that. You're insisting on interpreting that because you're incapable of ceding ground in an argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36486068365.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>I already gave a delta. They sure are! That's exact form of the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489134256.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>He didn’t just have sex with Asians, he specifically only sought out Asians. He didn’t have sex with anyone of any other races even though other sex workers exist.  He sexualities them then murdered them for their race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485298373.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Killing asians is not loving asians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485336089.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>That's very true. But killing white people is not hating white people. Or did he hate white people too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485417462.0" user="littlebubulle" delta="False">
    <text>Let's take an non-racist killer killing random people. Or even people in a certain profession.

If race does not count in the killer's decision, then the number of asian victims would be around 1 out of 20 which is Altlanta's demographics as of 2010 census.

Here, out of the 8 currently identified victims, (there were four more victims that have not been identified yet), 6 were asian.

What are the odds that race wasn't taken into account here?

We can be 100% it was racially motivated. But when most of the victims are asian in a city where most people are not, we can infer that there is a higher then 50% probability that race was a factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485482472.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If race does not count in the killer's decision, then the number of asian victims would be around 1 out of 20 which is Altlanta's demographics as of 2010 census.

That doesn't follow. Nonracism is not achieving equitable outcomes reflecting population make up. By your logic, this is guy is about as pro-Black as they come. 

&amp;gt;What are the odds that race wasn't taken into account here?

The odds are probably near zero. If he is an incel type, humiliated by women .. if he keeps getting these physical intimate experiences, without emotional intimacy .. if this was an emotional killing and not planned out -- I'd say chances are he wasn't thinking about race.

&amp;gt;We can be 100% it was racially motivated. But when most of the victims are asian in a city where most people are not, we can infer that there is a higher then 50% probability that race was a factor.
 
Outcomes are not causation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485544382.0" user="ashdksndbfeo" delta="False">
    <text>About 2.5% of the people in the Atlanta metro area are Asian women. 75% of the people he murdered were Asian women. Those are some skewed statistics if the murders had nothing to do with race.

He shot up places that he knew were predominantly worked by Asian women. Atlanta is one of the sex trafficking capitals of the US. There’s so much prostitution. If the killings were about sex and had nothing to do with Asian women, why did he target Asian spas rather than prostitutes or strip clubs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489130946.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>He doesn’t love them.  He is literally sexualizing them to the point of dehumanizing them.  It’s why he doesn’t care if the women he is fucking and murdering are trafficked or not, even though that’s likely.  He’s using them to scape goat his own sexual desires.  How is that love?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489785402.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>No, the guy is clearly a dehumanizing bad guy. The fetishizing discourse in general is anti-Asian, racist, segregating stuff. Just from personal experience, witnessing it deployed against interracial couples who love each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489804502.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You again aren’t addressing what I’ve stated.  It’s weird. All of your comments have failed to address what you’re responding to to when you’ve replied to me this morning. It’s incoherent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489812059.0" user="MacV_writes" delta="False">
    <text>The incoherency is in you. You offered me an incoherent symmetry between race and sex. I described to you why. Because you cannot substantiate, you are self-describing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36485270304.0" user="jendickers" delta="False">
    <text>The guy said he was trying to “eliminate a temptation” and went hours out of his way to go to Asian massage parlors with the intent of murdering the employees there. You’re saying he wasn’t fetishizing those women? And yes, he killed two non-Asian people, I’m aware. Obviously I don’t know all the details but I’m willing to bet those people weren’t his intended targets when he planned this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36489136813.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>He had an asian fetish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36823162720.0" user="RocketHopper" delta="False">
    <text>There is no evidence he had an Asian fetish, stop pulling shit out of your ass</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
