<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1343602912.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m7y2n4/cmv_the_recent_atlantic_shootings_was_not_an/">
    <title>CMV: The recent Atlantic shootings was not an anti-Asian event.</title>
    <original_poster>MacV_writes</original_poster>
    <original_post>A white man shot six Asian women along with two others in Atlanta. The narrative that has been that this is directly caused by anti-Asian sentiment driven by racist white supremacists stoking bigotry against Asians. To solve this problem, America must truly commit to not being racist, to listen to those in the Asian community, and to teach young white men in particular the privilege they have as well as the deadly effects of toxic masculinity. 

However, there are details that do not fit the narrative. 

A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated. 

B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man. 

C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates. 

E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression. 

F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503 

G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia. 

It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital. It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system. People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis. Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China? Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36487443947.0" user="ChangeMyViewPiracy0" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A. The shooter said that this was not racially motivated.

"The robber/murderer said he wasn't financially motivated"

Hate crimes come with bigger sentences, why would he say it was racially motivated?

&amp;gt;B. The shooter killed a white woman and white man.

And killed 6 Asian women. It's like thinking black people are welfare queens, intimidating black people on the street, shouting the n-word and then saying "Muh black friend".

&amp;gt;C. While the shooter had shared a post critical of China https://twitter.com/yellokeith/status/1372202427584192513?s=09 it never rose beyond the national condemnation -- and the victims were Korean.

Do you think he pulled a gun, asked the women "What country do you come from?" and only kill if she comes from China? No, he targeted women with East Asian features.

&amp;gt;D. White nationalists in particular are well known for their love of Asian peoples and Asian culture, due to their valuation of ethnostates.

"White pride! Bring back the Nazis! Kung flu! Coronavirus!" I wonder who says this...

&amp;gt;E. Intentionally racist shootings usually come with racist manifestos, shamelessly racist worldviews, racist narratives about how white people are facing oppression.

Just because he never wrote a manifesto doesn't mean he's not racist. In any case, we may not have found his journals, diaries, etc. that contain more racist views.

&amp;gt;F. The #1 systemic discrimination Asian people face is from Progressives championing 'meritocracy is racist' and 'Asians are white-adjacent' inflammatory racial rhetoric, resulting in concrete discriminatory politics targeting Asian people specifically by their race. https://www.newsweek.com/asian-americans-emerging-strong-voice-against-critical-race-theory-opinion-1574503

Whataboutism. Also, you've been reading too much Twitter. Most progressives don't say anything of the sort.

&amp;gt;G. Criticism of China as a global, hegemonic, communist power is mainstream and not founded on race or xenophobia.

Because killing East Asian women is anti-CCP? Same way killing white women is anti-Putin?

&amp;gt;It is my view Progressivism is a system which converts Trauma into capital.

Is this about the shooting not being racist or about those evil progressives?

&amp;gt;It seems as though these current narratives are forcing an anti-Asian narrative as a politically motivated strategy to appeal to build on this system.

Please clarify what you mean.

&amp;gt;People like Trevor Noah believe killing six Asian people necessarily is a racist attack. But that strikes me as intentionally crude analysis.

No, but when it happens in a white-majority country it is damn likely to be one.

&amp;gt; Isn't it racist for us to project all Asians onto China?

No one is doing this.

&amp;gt;Aren't we racistly manipulating the narrative when we selectively emphasize race to push politics, especially when said politics advocates for formally discriminating against Asians as "white-adjacent?"

What are you even talking about? This doesn't happen.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
