<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134470458.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/28262i/cmv_i_believe_that_womans_nipples_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that woman's nipples should be censored despite men's not being so.</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of people that are pro-women being able to go topless in the streets. I've thought about why it bothers me and why I find it inappropriate. The big thing that bothers me is that women's nipples are sexualized, unlike men's, when it comes to the average person's view on sex.

I believe that a woman will never be able to go topless without causing a stir unless women's boobs, and more importantly, their nipples are no longer considered objects of sex*.

*I couldn't think of a better way to put this. I'm not objectifying women, I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27220932215.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Um, what role do women's nipples play in sex that is different from the role played by men's?

Shouldn't mouths be covered since they can be part of sex?  Or is it only intercourse, which means it's only the penis and vaginal area that should be covered?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220934463.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>Women's nipples are an object of sexual desire. They are a huge focal point during foreplay. I've been with many women and have rarely had mine played with and it doesn't seem very common to the average person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220952544.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>http://homepage.psy.utexas.edu/HomePage/Group/MestonLAB/Publications/Levin%20&amp;amp;%20Meston%202006.pdf

According to this study, manipulation of the nipples/breasts increases arousal in 82% of women and 52% of men.  

So, yes, while it is more common for women, they certainly play a role in sex for both genders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220955967.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>They both *can* and yes I get aroused with some nipple play, I don't see, at least in initial reading's though where it says that men commonly do this. It seems to ask how many men are aroused if it happens, but not whether it's common in their sex life. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220965000.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>No, there are not many studies about how often it's done.  But logically, if over half of men get off on it, how likely do you think it is that it doesn't happen frequently?  Certainly enough to refute your assertion that they don't play a role in sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220969914.0" user="keanex" delta="False">
    <text>As you can see in the study though, only 17% of men asked for it. I've had sex with 15 women, all of various intimacy levels, and have only had my nipples played with once or twice by my current girlfriend. I've asked a few of guys as well over the years and none of them have had any serious nipple play. Maybe something minor here or there, but nothing that was ever more than a quick brush or tease.

I know that's anecdotal, but I imagine you'd find similar results if you asked other guys.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27220974395.0" user="placebo-addict" delta="False">
    <text>To create an accurate analogy between men's and women's nipples and sexuality, you need to consider how many women consider men's nipples sexy, not how many men are aroused by nipple stimulation. For all you know, all women objectify all men's nipples in a sexual manner, but men can still take their shirts off whenever they want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221443839.0" user="greenceltic" delta="False">
    <text>I can't help but laugh at this conversation.  Are there really no women on reddit?  We're forced to speculate and debate the logic of whether women are turned on by nipples?  

If there's any women out there, it would help if you could chime in.  Are men's nipples sexy?  

If we really are all dudes, there has to be at least one person here who's near a woman.  Could someone just ask a woman who's near them if they think nipples are sexy?  Shouldn't be too awkward.  Tell them it's for science.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221457083.0" user="placebo-addict" delta="False">
    <text>I am a woman actually, and yes, in context, I find male nipples sexy. Not when someone is going about his business, but in bed, yes. I don't understand why female nipples should be taboo when male nipples are publicly acceptable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221597410.0" user="wallaceeffect" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a woman too, and no, I don't find them sexy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221796112.0" user="atfire" delta="False">
    <text>Nipples, no. Bare chests, absolutely. But only in a sexual context, not so much just walking down the street. So, exactly the same thing as the other way round.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221028354.0" user="princessbynature" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting.  I always thought nipples were for nursing babies, you know, cuz that's where milk comes put.  I recognize the enjoyment men get out of sucking on them or playing with them but seriously, nipples are nipples.  Your mom has them.  Why should women have to censor their own bodies because it might turn a man on?  Can men not control themselves?  I would like to think the vast majority of men are mature enough to hassle seeing a woman undressed without feeling the need to act on sexual urges. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27221604174.0" user="wallaceeffect" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it have to be about men? Why can't I decide what my nipples are for? For me, they are extremely sexual objects and a huge part of arousal and my sexual life. I'm not censoring my body because of what some man might think, I'm choosing to keep my private life private. I wouldn't walk around bottomless either, even if it were completely normalized. 

Of course, I don't see why other women should be prohibited from going topless if they want, but saying it's because "nipples are for nursing babies" is condescending. Nipples are for what their owners say they're for. If I say they're for sex (for me) it's not because a man told me so. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
