<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134470458.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/28262i/cmv_i_believe_that_womans_nipples_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that woman's nipples should be censored despite men's not being so.</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of people that are pro-women being able to go topless in the streets. I've thought about why it bothers me and why I find it inappropriate. The big thing that bothers me is that women's nipples are sexualized, unlike men's, when it comes to the average person's view on sex.

I believe that a woman will never be able to go topless without causing a stir unless women's boobs, and more importantly, their nipples are no longer considered objects of sex*.

*I couldn't think of a better way to put this. I'm not objectifying women, I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27222387822.0" user="HumpRAWR" delta="False">
    <text>I was watching a show that was like America's top model for tattoo artists. In this episode, some women wanted tattoos on their breats because they had gone through a medical surgery that removed their nipples(I think it involved cancer).

They showed these womens breasts with no censorship since it isn't a boob if it doesn't have a nipple. My gf and I laughed about it for a few minutes because we always joked about how people see boobs, and now theres this scene how ridiculous censorship involving tits is.

It's not even the nipple that gets censored. Think of all of the tv shows and movies where you can plainly see a woman's nipples and boobs through her shirt, but theres no censorship or R rating. Is it the colorization of the nipple us guys sexualize? Does anyone really think that?

I actually don't mind censoring boobs. Most of the content in "unrated" versions of things are just using people's immaturity and ignorance of what a woman is to sell more copies. Then again, I guess that form of advertisment wouldn't work if there were more non-sexually existent boobs everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
