<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134470458.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/28262i/cmv_i_believe_that_womans_nipples_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that woman's nipples should be censored despite men's not being so.</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of people that are pro-women being able to go topless in the streets. I've thought about why it bothers me and why I find it inappropriate. The big thing that bothers me is that women's nipples are sexualized, unlike men's, when it comes to the average person's view on sex.

I believe that a woman will never be able to go topless without causing a stir unless women's boobs, and more importantly, their nipples are no longer considered objects of sex*.

*I couldn't think of a better way to put this. I'm not objectifying women, I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27221004613.0" user="ratjea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

I know you didn't mean this literally, but I'm having a hilarious time imagining a penis behaving like a breast or vice versa.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
