<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134470458.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/28262i/cmv_i_believe_that_womans_nipples_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that woman's nipples should be censored despite men's not being so.</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of people that are pro-women being able to go topless in the streets. I've thought about why it bothers me and why I find it inappropriate. The big thing that bothers me is that women's nipples are sexualized, unlike men's, when it comes to the average person's view on sex.

I believe that a woman will never be able to go topless without causing a stir unless women's boobs, and more importantly, their nipples are no longer considered objects of sex*.

*I couldn't think of a better way to put this. I'm not objectifying women, I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27221183066.0" user="Ezada" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose the big question is, how do we make something no longer considered objects of sex? Simple, you let people see them, in public, and let the population get used to it. Ankles used to be sexualized too, a long time ago. Now if you were to say "Cover your ankles, that is offensive!" people would laugh at you.

It will take time, and the right sort of promoting to get people to realize that boobs are just inflated versions of mens chests, but I think with the right mind people would realize its just a boob. All women have them, and there really isn't anything that sensational about them. Course, I have my own pair so I get to see them every day.

Oversexualization of body parts is how (some) oppression begins. "Womens nipples are sexualized, they need to be covered, I find it offensive!!" Look at women in the middle east, they are forced to be covered from head to toe because of oversexualization (well and religion).

Now this can also lead to the argument of other body parts that are considered sexual, and why don't we just go nude? In some cultures it is normal to be topless/nude all the time, because the human body is just that, the human body. You might find it offensive, but what if the person who wants to be topless is not offended? At what point do we draw the line at political correctness and nudity? What if I found a mans wrists attractive, or if all women banned together and wrists were suddenly the new nipple, would we force men to cover them so that we wouldn't get wet in public? 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
