<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134470458.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/28262i/cmv_i_believe_that_womans_nipples_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that woman's nipples should be censored despite men's not being so.</title>
    <original_poster>keanex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of people that are pro-women being able to go topless in the streets. I've thought about why it bothers me and why I find it inappropriate. The big thing that bothers me is that women's nipples are sexualized, unlike men's, when it comes to the average person's view on sex.

I believe that a woman will never be able to go topless without causing a stir unless women's boobs, and more importantly, their nipples are no longer considered objects of sex*.

*I couldn't think of a better way to put this. I'm not objectifying women, I'm stating that the body part in question plays a role during sex, like a man's penis.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27221151276.0" user="electricmink" delta="False">
    <text>Men's nipples get sucked on and nibbled during sex as well (and it is delightful!) so I'm not buying it - you might as well be arguing that women's nipples need to remain covered because they are deeply instinctually ingrained in us as a food source, and seeing them all the time will make people hungry and overeat....

See, context matters.  If I see a woman bare-breasted on the street going about her daily business, that isn't a sexual situation, it's not arousing, it's just....a woman going about her business.  If I found her attractive, sure, I might look, but really no more so than were she more covered - I'm not immune to physical beauty!  But unless she and I have some kind of emotional connection, we're in a setting where we can play (or soon will be), and she is giving me the smokey, "come-hither" look (you know the one!) or is otherwise expressing some serious, unmistakable interest...well, her nudity may be something I find beautiful, but it isn't "sexy".

But then, I've been around an awful lot of naked people in my day, just doing everyday people things.  Nudity is not inherently sexual to me because I've encountered so very much of it.  And I'm betting that's what will happen after a few short years of women going about in public topless - we'll all just get over it, already.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
