<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36521294691.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Fascist states generally come about  via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution.  They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist  regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter.  Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there  is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist  ones.

Which fascist regime was actually elected? The Nazis never got the popular vote in an election with more than 1 party. Also the Russian Revolution(s) were itself pretty tame:

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/February\_Revolution](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/February_Revolution)

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/October\_Revolution](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/October_Revolution)

With the February Revolution being the bloodier. Though paling in comparison to the millions of Russians dying in WWI. The subsequent civil war increased that death toll by hundreds of thousands but that is as much to blame on the reactionaries as on the socialists. Who haven't been any less blood thirsty:

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White\_Terror\_(Russia)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Terror_(Russia))

While the Nazi sure had their fair share of political violence prior to their power grab. And Weimar Germany wasn't really all that stable to begin with. With basically the left, right and the upper class agitating against the republic. 

&amp;gt;Secondly, Fascist regimes are more  compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and  specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those  societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain.  Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow  the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of  communism.

Which is pretty damning for capitalist can conservative systems... But  yes when push comes to shove conservatives will happily demolish the pillars of society if the pillars of their power are promised to remain untouched. Though often that's also only as long as they are needed, before they get disposed off. 

&amp;gt;Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm  least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you  take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms  of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their  people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like  'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but  it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is  more fertile when it comes to fascism.

Not really. Under normal circumstances that bullshit doesn't fly and fascists regularly have to employ leftist rhetoric because that's actually popular while the whole strong leader bs usually doesn't interest people. I mean they tell you about "us vs them", but in reality, most people will not be part of "us", so if they actually rolled out their program that would be massively unfavorable.

&amp;gt;This is a more long term argument. I  don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count.  That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than  anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening.

It's not just whom they kill but why. I mean people shouldn't be all to sorry for tzars and kings, they probably got what they deserved. Whereas if your entire raison d'être rests upon conspiracy theories that you need to kill people for, that's fucked up. That being said, the so called "communists" where also often just plain authoritarian and as such not just disposed of political enemies but also "friends" and internal opposition and whatnot. Though again not really a feature of the ideology rather a feature of authoritarian rule, the kings and tzars most likely did the same. 

&amp;gt;My  main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become  a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post  communism.

Most of these countries didn't start off as democracies. Russia didn't, the third world countries didn't. Often enough those revolutions were part of a liberation and independence movement which the "democratic" nations often suppressed in favor of actual fascists who keep the power structure and allow for further economic exploitation of labor and resources.

Not to mention that authoritarian regimes often have a much harder time getting to a democratic system. I mean it took France 5 iterations of a republic to get away from the Monarchy, Germany needed 2 revolutions and 2 world wars to ditch authoritarianism plus some cultural revolution in the late 60s. Many "democratized" war zones fall back to "old habits". Democracy needs practice and at least in theory communism would offer more democracy not less, which is why those currently in power never were quite favorable of it and rather preferred keeping their authoritarian system or transforming it a little but not too much.

&amp;gt;Communism pulls down  the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything  likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate  a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of  those pillars but they are still there at the end.

Explain. I mean the backbone of autocracy is supposed to be dismantled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521377139.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>You can win elections without winning the popular vote. For example, the liberals control the minority government in Canada right now and didn't win the popular vote. Hitler did gain his power democratically initially. 

Some of your other points I already gave deltas for and some I disagree with. 

France needed 5 republics, sure. But, it's probable they would have ended up with a constitutional monarchy anyway. Germany was a democracy by the standard of the day from 1890 and was a representative democracy after world war 1. 

The backbone of autocracy is the method where by most democracies became so. Via, compromises with that backbone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521599743.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can win elections without winning the popular vote. For example, the liberals control the minority government in Canada right now and didn't win the popular vote. Hitler did gain his power democratically initially.

Nope. He got the majority of votes (37%) in June 1932, but not the government because the rest formed a coalition that had more votes. That coalition broke apart and so there were new elections in November of 1932 where they dropped to 33%. Still no government. Then that coalition fell apart as well and so the president appointed Hitler chancellor in January (afaik) without any election. And within the span of 1 1/2 month, Hitler used that power to blame a fire in the parliament on the communists in order to ban the entire party (16.9% in the November election) and to terrorize the communist and social democratic parties prior to the upcoming election in March of 1933. Which he won with 43.9% which was still not enough to form the government. So he had to form a coalition with another fascist party (more traditional still fascist) and then use coercion and shenanigans to officially declare the state of emergency which allowed him to pass legislation without consent from the parliament. (Restricted for 4 years, renewed every 4 years.). The election in March is already considered no longer fair as parties were already be banned and the Nazis were already terrorizing their opponents and even with those circumstances they still didn't won the popular vote.

&amp;gt;France needed 5 republics, sure. But,  it's probable they would have ended up with a constitutional monarchy  anyway. Germany was a democracy by the standard of the day from 1890 and  was a representative democracy after world war 1.

France treid a constitutional monarchy, but the aristocracy tried to get the king out of France to get the neighbors to declare war on France to restore the monarchy, that's why they lost their heads. And then more people lost their heads but that's a different story. But still it's not that they didn't try it. And yes Germany was a constitutional monarchy, but there was still A LOT of power with the king/emperor. It's not like modern constitutional democracies, where the monarch is mostly representative with no actual political power.

&amp;gt;The backbone of autocracy is the method where by most democracies became so. Via, compromises with that backbone.

No, not really most democracies came into existence when that backbone got cracks and couldn't defend itself anymore against demands from the people. When they were stable enough to do so they more often than not crushed those demands rather than compromise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521614437.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Is the president allowed to appoint him as chancellor at that point? 

If so, that's democratically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521649316.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;appoint him as chancellor at that point?  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;If so, that's democratically.

Democratically means that it has the mandate of the people (demos = the people craties = rule) and it clearly didn't have that mandate. When there is no government the president could appoint a government and parliament could chose not to support that, which is what happened (hence the new election). Though using that interim period in order to ban opposing parties and let your thugs take up "police duties" is far from what a provisional government is allowed or tasked to do...

Edit: Don't confuse "legal" with "democratic". Just because something isn't technically illegal doesn't mean it's democratic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521697308.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say he achieved total power democratically. I meant he achieved the position from which he was able to grab that power democratically. 

It's absolutely untrue that all democracies reflect the strict mandate of the people. They can have rules where individuals get much more power than the election result of that party. 

They also do not have to reflect the will of the people. If that was the case situations like the democratic party losing elections where they won the popular vote wouldn't happen. 

You are engaging in ridiculous semantics at this point. In the Weimar republic, was it within their system for the president to appoint Hitler as chancellor in that situation? If the answer is yes and then Hitler exploited that situation to his own ends... that still means he got there democratically. I have no idea why you are even arguing this as you OBVIOUSLY know what I mean. Move on to something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36522963591.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>One person appointing another to high office without the will of the people is LITERALLY undemocratic, I've no idea how you don't understand this. The other commenter is clearly more knowledgeable about this subject than you and their analysis is better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36524221740.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>The Governor General just appointed Justin Trudeau the prime minister last year without the will of the people. He got less share of the popular vote than the second place party. I guess Canada isn’t a democracy. 

All the machinations and frequent change of chancellors was part of their system of government. Hitler was only in the position to become chancellor because his party won the most seats in the preceding election. That’s what I meant by him gaining the position democratically. He did it within the system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36527837507.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that sounds pretty undemocratic to me in both cases. Undemocratic things can happen in otherwise democratic systems of government, and systems of government that claim to be democratic sometimes aren't. Case I point: Democratic peoples republic of Korea and Democratic people's republic of the Congo. Doesn't change the fact that that Hitler seized power undemocratically.

Edit: it actually seems to be you who is engaging in ridiculous semantics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528108632.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, I’ll amend it. 

Hitler like leaders in many many other countries that we colloquially know as democracies but which I have now been informed are not actually democracies was appointed chancellor partially or mostly because his party won the most votes in the previous election. Henceforth, any situation where a president, queen, Governor General or any other such figure in a parliamentary system appoints someone as a prime minister or Taoiseach or chancellor will not be referred to as ‘democratic’ because that is an INSANE thing to say and it’s not semantics at all to argue with that. 

Thanks, man. I’m enlightened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528215003.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>How so? Appointments that go against the will of the people are undemocratic. Even appointments that happen to align with the will of the people are undemocratic. No one gets to vote on appointments and it basically comes down to one person doing the appointing. I don't see how that fits the definition of democratic. Legal, sure, in many governments. But not democratic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528533496.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>There is a process that leads to that appointment that is part of the parliamentary system. Usually, it means that the party holds a majority or leads a coalition or a minority govt. This is a standard in parliamentary democracies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528947925.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't change my point in the slightest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529063474.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, your point seems to be that parliamentary democracies aren’t democratic. Seems irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529091482.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that one single person making an appointment, especially one of this importance, does not reflect the will of the people and as such that action isn't democratic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529157144.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>And thus parliamentary democracies aren’t democracies. Good to know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529366330.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>And the national socialist party wasn't actually socialist. A government can claim to be democratic while in reality taking shortcuts that end up being undemocratic. The other commenter made a compelling case for how Hitler was able to take power undemocratically within a government that called itself a democracy, I'm not sure what you're failing to grasp here. He got his opponents kicked out of parliament and still wasn't able to get a majority of the votes, indicating that his appointment was not a result of the will of the people but the will of one single man. 

In the U.S. for example, the electoral college makes votes from certain states worth less or more than votes from other states. That is undemocratic, despite the US calling itself a representational democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36530077712.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>By your definition, there literally isn’t a democracy in existence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36531038890.0" user="frolf_grisbee" delta="False">
    <text>I mean yeah. Many countries aspire to democracy and enact policies that attempt to respond to the will of their citizens. But true democracy has never really been logistically feasible until recently, so we've approximated and compromised with representational democracy. I don't know how you can see candidates elected to office despite losing the popular vote and call that democratic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36524459860.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest you should probably define what you mean by "democracy" because the way you use it seems to be pretty incompatible with how it's usually defined.

Democracy, literally means "rule of the people". In the most idealistic forms that that is the of "self-governing". Meaning the members of a group come together and decide by themselves, for themselves how the group should move forward. So each member has equal power to participate, petition a proposal, discuss that proposal, voice concerns about that, amend it and so on. Ideally you could also have that consent based, so every person has a veto right as well.

But usually people opt for a more restrictive version where instead of giving everybody a veto right (which could lead to gridlock if there are really really incompatible positions and no intent to consider the other position) they just aim for "broad support", that is a majority or a qualifying majority. So idk 50+% or even a 2/3 majority for major changes to the constitution or whatnot where a regular majority is just not enough. So not everybody has to agree but everybody has to be asked and a majority has to respond in favor of a proposal.

An even more restrictive version is the representative democracy where you have that democratic process but by proxy of representatives. Meaning people vote for delegates and those delegates than go through the motion of what an actual democracy would look like (what happens in parliaments). Where you can again distinguish between imperative mandates and the non-imperative mandate. Where in the case of the imperative mandate the representative is just that, a representative, he/she is bound to the will of the people who sent him has to put forward their points and can be retracted if the people whom he represent aren't satisfied with him. On the other hand a non-imperative mandate basically elects a person to an office, where after election they are free to make their own decisions not being dependent on the consent of the people.  

Now that non-imperative mandate is certainly more democratic than a government based on heritage, as the source for it's power comes from the people. Everybody has the active and passive voting right and can participate in that. So often enough people already group that in the "democracy" camp, but it's far away from being "peak democracy", it usually comes with restrictive adjectives and you could argue whether it really is a democracy or whether it's just a democratic process (elections), which legitimize a temporary aristocracy. Though as it's currently the most common form of democracy people usually also just call it democracy. But it's always important to remember that there's still quite some room for improvement. 

Keeping all that in mind Hitler neither got into office with a democratic mandate, nor through a democratic process, nor did he actively behave very democratically while in office. 

People for a long time apparently refused to use the word "revolution" in that context because the left has a favorable view on revolutions and didn't wanted to grant the Nazis that honor while other historians found the lack of struggle with the system lacking, in that they didn't really "fight the man" but more or less got the power handed over. Though while certain steps in that process had been legal there is no lack of illegal activities and terrorism by the Nazis during their quest for power. So that nowadays people call it a "totalitarian revolution". 

Also in terms of legality, it's complicated. As a matter of fact the democracy of the Weimar Republic had it rather rough from the start but even before Hitler was appointed the democracy already had suffered some major blows.

I mean the troubles start in WWI, where after 1916 the military high command basically took dictatorial control over Germany. After they had realized that they've lost the war they tried to put the blame on someone else. So they confirmed with the allied demand for a republic rather than a monarchy, in order to blame the military loss on the republic rather than themselves. So when the U.S. ordered a military capitulation they acted all offended and ordered to proceed the fighting and to commit suicide mission to do harm against the allies without any chance of actually winning, just damage for damages sake. That let to riots, mutiny, revolts and the socalled German revolution of 1918/19. In the following meetings of the workers and soldiers councils (soviet republic like in Russia before Lenin took the power), a majority was in favor of a parliamentary democracy. Which pissed off the socialist/communists left which was in favor of giving more power to the workers/soldiers councils. Which let to a split in the socialist movement. 

Going forward the former socialists SPD formed a coalition with several center right parties. Further revolts by the communists were brutally put down with the help of the former military dictatorship (as well as proto fascist paramilitaries of which there existed quite a few... lots of unemployed soldiers after WWI) which were all too keen on killing communists despite hating the social democrats the republic and democracies in general and rather planning to return to a monarchy. 

So the left hated the republic because it gutted the revolution and murdered it's most prominent figures, which then proceeded to grow closer to Russia and undermine the republic in pursuit of another shot at a revolution. While the military dictatorship enjoyed their "deep state" existence where through their defense of the republic they retained more or less an independent status that was never truly in favor of the republic. All while pushing propaganda that they would have won the war if it weren't for those treacherous social democrats ("backstabbing myth"). So whenever a left revolt happened they would crush it, whereas right wing revolts like Hitler's first putsch resulted in 1 year luxury prison for fucking HIGH TREASON also his co-conspirator was the de facto leader of the military high command who got out of that scot free despite being a major figure in that coup. 

Basically governments changed once or twice a year despite 4 year voting cycles. And the first blow happened when Paul von Hindenburg the nominal dictator of the military high command got elected president. Basically in the first round a president needed to get 50% while in the 2nd round he only needed a plurality (more than the rest) which resulted in 2 candidates being picked rather than the 7 or more in first round. Where the anti-democrats picked Paul von Hindenburg and the democrats went for the conservative Marx because they feared that conservatives would not vote for a social democrat, the communists picked Thälmann. And so Hindenburg won with 48% in Marx with 45% and Thälmann with 6%. In other words the communists really hated the social democrats for their betrayal and the conservatives weren't in favor of a democracy either. 

And from 1930s onwards the democracy was in it's last breaths. Because while the president had the formal task to pick a government that was more or less a formal procedure in the sense that the parliament tells the president whom they pick and he confirms them. However from 1930s onwards the president basically appointed minority governments and used undefined emergency legislation to basically rule with executive orders rather than consent of the parliament. Which the SPD tolerated because they thought conservative anti-democrats were still better than Nazis or communists. However which set the precendents for what was to come. So any following government basically followed that pattern with von Papen basically ignoring the  parliament altogether staffing his cabinet completely with unelected "experts" his former nobility buddies. However that was so unpopular that he had to resign because the elites now faced backlash from basically everyone (communists, democrats, nazis). So von Schleicher took over who wanted a state of emergency to deal with the Nazi problem, though Hindenburg refused and so he stepped down and appointed Hitler to rule. And the rest was already described in another post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36524590124.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Part II

&amp;gt;It's absolutely untrue that all democracies reflect the strict mandate of the people. They can have rules where individuals get much more power than the election result of that party.

As said that is the minimal definition of a democracy, if that is not a given then it's simply wrong to call it a democracy. Maybe it's a democratic election process but if a minority support leads to a majority of power it's not even a democratic process.

&amp;gt;They also do not have to reflect the will of the people. If that was the case situations like the democratic party losing elections where they won the popular vote wouldn't happen.

Yes, that actually makes the claim of the U.S. to be a democracy pretty dubious and for example the newspaper "The Economist" already ranks it as "flawed democracy" [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democracy\_Index](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democracy_Index).

Now you can argue that the election of the electorates is a democratic process and of congress is a democratic process so at some level it has some democratic mandate. But yeah it exemplifies pretty good why  representational democracies are restrictive democracies that do not actually fully embrace the ideal of self-governance and the representation of the will of the people.

&amp;gt;You are engaging in ridiculous semantics at this point. In the Weimar republic, was it within their system for the president to appoint Hitler as chancellor in that situation? If the answer is yes and then Hitler exploited that situation to his own ends... that still means he got there democratically. I have no idea why you are even arguing this as you OBVIOUSLY know what I mean. Move on to something else.

Again democratically does mean on a mandate of the people or at the very least a majority confirmation. Neither of which was the case. It does not mean legal. I mean under Hitler's system it was legal for him to make rules without the parliament despite not officially revoking the constitution, does that constitute a democracy just because it wasn't illegal under it's own made up laws?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36524762902.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>If the concept here that the Weimar Republic like most democracies had a system where power didn’t exactly correlate to the exact will of the people, then that’s fine. 

I honestly don’t really care. My original point is that he got to a point where he could seize power within the existing power structure. 

That power structure was usually labelled a democracy. If the Weimar Republic was not actually a democracy, then that’s fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36526428820.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If the concept here that the Weimar  Republic like most democracies had a system where power didn’t exactly  correlate to the exact will of the people, then that’s fine.

If your idea is that there is a slight misrepresentation of voters to parties which happen in many representative democracies. Then no, that is an actual problem but that was not the major problem of the Weimar Republic. 

Apart from the position of the president which was modeled after the monarchy and which had undefined emergency powers which were used pretty extensively, early on and kinda messed with the separation of power (no mix between the legislative, executive and judiciary branch). The Weimar Republic was from it's structure actually a quite progressive democracy for it's time but even in general. It had a constitution, lots of parties and even small parties with 60,000 votes could get into parliament. It had elements of direct democracies so that the public could petition laws, it was a federal system with both  representatives from the different federal states as well as a general assembly all of which were directly voted on. 

The biggest problem was as explained in the other long post (the one not labeled part II), that there were quite some people who were simply against that system on principles. 

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weimar\_political\_parties](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weimar_political_parties)

The communists felt it was a betrayal of the revolution to not pursue a direct worker council based system in favor of one that gets the old elites on board. While the old elites basically tried everything to revert the social progress to the time before the republic. So in weird coincidence the communists weren't wrong, in that cooperating with the old elites and always picking the lesser of two evils got them Hitler. That being said a full on revolution likely would have resulted in a civil war given the constellations and it's unclear how that would have turned out. 

Still you had a somewhat biased judiciary system where Hitler got a minimum luxury prison sentence for high treason after attempting a coup, because higher ups have intervened so that the case wasn't brought to a high court but was judged on the local level where a jury almost overruled the judge to get him off the charges entirely. Though that was likely not for Hitler but to safe the other more powerful von Ludendorff. 

You had a military that was disloyal to the government and more in favor of a conservative revolution. You had a restriction on the military in terms of size, which let to the problem that every party had it's own paramilitary wing that was often multiple times the size of the regular army. So political violence was rather common. You also had a "schwarze Reichswehr" which was basically the army that wasn't supposed to exist. So a much bigger army of irregular fighter, training in Russia that went around the protocol of how big the army was allowed to be. Which was largely tolerated by the government because not doing so would be kind of treason so due to the nature of the business that army was NOT under the control of the parliament and the republic. 

On top of all that you had external and internal struggles that led to governments with rather short shelf lives (1-2 years often shorter) and from 1925 onwards you had a president who was actively antidemocratic and who basically from 1930s onwards enabled governments without majority support of the parliament (or the people). 

So they basically used all kinds of legal and illegal shenanigans to undermine the very basic of democracy. With the social democrats often playing along because the alternatives were even worse. I mean that's the inherent "problem" with democracy if people don't want democracy they could also vote to end it. But that vote already happened in 1925 by electing an antidemocrat president. Hitler was just the last straw that broke the camels back. And even that vote for the antidemocratic president wasn't a popular vote but just a plurality vote which literally was 48% to 45%. So a pretty tied race... 

So it's not so much that he seized power by democratic means, through the democracy or with shenanigans in a democracy, it was rather that the military power structure didn't intent to stop him despite using illegal means because deep down they themselves were in favor of a more authoritarian system. 

They used some barely legal shenanigans but most of it had to do with a lack of resistance or rather support of conservatives circumventing and undermining the democratic system.

&amp;gt;That power structure was usually labelled a democracy. If the Weimar Republic was not actually a democracy, then that’s fine.

It used to be for some time, but especially going towards it end it pretty much undermined the democratic elements of that system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36526518064.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>His party still got by far the most votes of any party in both elections prior to him being named Chancellor. In other words, it would have been very unlikely that he would have been in the position to become chancellor and then leverage that into total power, if he didn't have that underlying credibility.

That is the entire point. Alot of people voted for him. Therefore he was in a position to use the system as it was to grab total power.

You are making this whole thing into an argument I'm not even remotely interested in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528419285.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>You don't seem to realize what a chancellor is. The chancellor is basically the head of the government and as such he's not directly elected but merely the leader faction or the factions (usually the biggest) that either got a parliamentary majority OR of a minority that is tolerated by enough other factions to form get them over the 50%. Without a majority of votes/seats in parliament the title of "government" means next to nothing. 

That's the democratic process you/your party or a coalition of parties get enough votes to pass the bar of 50% so that you can make legislatures with that majority or you form a minority government in which case you constantly rely on other parties voting for your proposals despite not being part of the government. 

And Hitler never passed that bar in a fair election. And from 1930 onwards that process had already been turned ad absurdum by the fact that basically each new government essentially ruled not by a majority in parliament but by the president pushing through their legislation via executive orders and emergency decrees completely bypassing the democratic process altogether. Which was pretty much skewed in favor of far right upper class conservatives as they held the military power and the office of the president. However they weren't necessarily the most popular in fact they basically made politics against the working class, how they used to do when they were still the nobility. So in an attempt to gain popularity some of them brought the Nazis into the mainstream and gave that bunch of criminals some credibility, lifted the ban on their paramilitary groups and let them agitate and terrorize without consequences.

Prior to 1930 and the decline of democracy, Hitler's party was basically non-existent. After 1923 it was literally banned because of the coup, his thugs were disbanded as terrorists and afterwards they saw little to no success. They had a 2% in 1928. It was just after the conservative made them viable that they gained traction to the point where the conservatives couldn't militarily contain them without losing face because the Nazis basically presented the conservative agenda on steroids. However again neither of them had much of a popular support or the ability to make laws following the democratic process. 

They relied on executive orders and emergency legislation that wouldn't have lasted a supervision by the supreme court. However that never happened because before the checks and balances could stop it those actions had already destroyed the system. I mean seriously some have this weird idea of a "boiling the frog narrative" where Hitler apparently did secretly do shit over years or some Star Wars level narrative where "democracy dies with thunderous applause" or stuff like that but that's not actually how it went down. 

Hitler was appointed chancellor on January the 30th 1933. On the 1st of February the parliament was dissolved because there was no stable coalition to govern, so new elections were scheduled on March the 5th. On the 5th of February the president passed a decree that was already planned for by the previous conservative presidential cabinet (ruling not by parliament but by presidential support) that basically restricted freedom of the press and the right to assemble. To make conditions pretty much impossible for other parties to engage in a political campaign. You know apart from the government (that at that point had no democratic mandate as there wasn't even a parliament left).

On night from 27th to 28th of February 1933 there was a fire at the Reichstag. The very same day February 28th he crafted an emergency decree banning the communists, imprisoning political enemies, restricting freedom of speech and freedom of the press, house raids, suspension of post and transmission secrets and so one. Basically a version of the Patriot Act on steroid, just that the Patriot Act took a month while that took hours. And within hours they knew who the perpetrators were... Even with the most rose colored glasses you know that this is bullshit. And it again passed not by parliamentary support or even tolerance but by executive order of the president (not Hitler but Hindenburg). And mind you all of that happened 5 FUCKING DAYS BEFORE THE ELECTION on March the 5th. For real think of what that election was like when 5 days before the election basically all civil liberties are restricted 

The communists were still on the ballots and scored 12.3% despite being banned and imprisoned in concentration camps (you know 1930s Guantanamo). Hitler than basically pretended that their seat in parliament don't count because they weren't present (for obvious reasons), which inflated his share of the seats or worse that those not present would have supported his proposition to rule entirely without parliament. To which he found "agreement" with armed SA men present at the vote. There are memorial stones in Berlin for the 100 who symbolically didn't support that, but at that point it was more or less to fulfill the form, it had already seized to be a democracy prior to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528516790.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>How did his coup result in his party getting most votes in the two elections prior to him being named chancellor? 

I know what that it is. Its the equivalent to a prime minister.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528673469.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>He got the most votes of a single party. However he was far from getting a majority of the votes and the trend was downwards. The NSDAP had a boost from the global economic crisis and their continued conspiracy theories that had already been propagated and not refuted by conservatives. However that was about to drop, whereas the KPD had increasing voter shares. Also if the socialist parties KPD and SPD wouldn't have hated each other as much as they did they would have gotten similar or better results as the Nazis. 

But anyway that didn't really matter because at that point it was no longer about voters or shares of the parliament, the chancellors that Hindenburg appointed prior to Hitler were either from the centrist party (\~10%) or had no party affiliation at all. So essentially the military elites appointed whomever they liked and didn't even intend to ask the parliament for consent. As said the cabinet von Papen didn't even utilize delegates as ministers but went for nobility that had never seen an election in the first place.

The numbers mattered in terms of military strength. Because the Nazi party was basically a covert military with ranks from private to generals and so they were a factor in the power distribution. The SPD and the parties in favor of the republic also had some strong paramilitary forces but they counted on the democratic process rather than extrajudicial means to obtain power and the Antifa which actually did engage militantly with the Nazis was too small and also again too focused on shaming the social democrats. 

The power of the Nazis really didn't come from the democratic process at best that was kind of a show of force in terms of numbers but their power was rather in their paramilitary organization and the fact that conservatives basically handed them the government on a silver platter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528719447.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Is it probable that the people who were in control and thought they could control hitler would have chose him if he didn’t lead the party that got a high share of the vote? 

Yes or no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36530772819.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>As said, as a matter of fact the president DID appoint chancellors right before Hitler which neither had the popular support nor were even close to being the biggest party (Zentrum) or unaffiliated. Some had a minimal amount of support in terms of being not directly rejected by parliament but especially the latter ones simply didn't care.

 The only reason why Hitler was rejected for so long was not because he was a fascist and authoritarian, many of those former military leaders were, he was rather rejected because he had only been a private in WWI, a commoner, he wasn't one of them. So he got some conservatives who tried to convince the higher ups to give him a chance and ride that wave of some level of populism, compared to what those aristocrats were used to. Also they probably weren't to unhappy about the Nazis doing the dirty work for them of oppressing political adversaries without being directly associated with those crimes.

So it certainly helped that he had some popular support, but it was not that they cared about the democratic process. In fact Hitler much like Lenin basically went for some Vanguard party approach where he actively tried to decrease membership in the SA or to rank it so that his inner circle consists of a small number of dedicated fascists and DOES NOT rely on popular support. 

The thing is in a real democracy, what the people give the people can take away. The government isn't yours you're just giving temporary permission and that permission can be revoked. So neither the military leaders nor Hitler were all to keen on getting power through the democratic process as that comes with responsibilities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36531350225.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Some popular support is understating it. He had the most popular support of anyone in the preceding two elections.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36532613594.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not understating it, he once achieved 37% in the aftermath of the global economic crisis and the abysmal crisis management of the government who had the plan to intensify the crisis in order to compel the allies to drop some of the restriction which made things even worse than they needed to be. But things were already getting better economically and the support of the NSDAP dropped to 33% respectively. Meaning 63% or respectively 67% of the population did not support Hitler.

Seriously again for a democracy you need a majority not just "some support". With some support and the rest tolerating your power grab you can attempt a coup, but that has nothing to do with democracy, democratic mandates or a democratic process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36532795366.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a country where 33% of the vote is a very strong minority govt (the one right now in fact). Canada is considered a democracy. 

37% of the vote in a multi party state is a strong showing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36535742645.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>The thing you seem to miss or ignore is that you compare a democratic system to a dictatorship. Yes if you have a multiparty system that can lead to a spreading of the votes which means that it's unlikely that one party achieves a majority on their own. Which makes 30+ a good result and makes the party an aspirant on forming a government. That being said you still require 50% to actually make laws and govern. Meaning you either have to form a coalition or you need other parties to at least tolerate you otherwise your 30+% aren't going to cut it as you've 70-% that are still against you. 

However that is fundamentally different from arguing that 30% of the votes are sufficient to rule a country with powers that you'd only have if you'd have gathered a majority behind you (whether as formal, informal or tolerating coalition). 

So if it's a minority government that relies on the rest of the parliament to either come together on an case by case basis or as a coalition, that's still somewhat democratic or at least resembles some populism. Whereas if scoring a plurality makes you the de facto ruler, that claim for a "democracy" becomes a lot more dubious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36535901969.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I never said that 30% was sufficient. My point was hitler got into a position where he could seize power because of elections. If they got 5% of the vote he wouldn’t have gotten to be chancellor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36538311980.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>As said von Papen was chancellor despite being a nobody, for the sole reason that he was an aristocrat with a military background and friends with a guy whom Hindenburg had been friends with. These guys didn't give a shit about democracy and democratic mandates or how many percent they got in an election. These  guys propped up the Nazis in the first place by basically offering them the conservative platform and making them a viable option, which they hadn't been prior to the decline of democracy.

And they would have also given a 5% or even lower rated party or person the power exemplified by the fact that they very much did that. It wasn't about what was legal or democratic but what they could get away with and pretty likely numbers played a role in that, but democracy was not their battlefield they still thought in terms of aristocratic intrigues and military power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36539484285.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Was hitler an aristocrat with a noble background?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36539619725.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Not that I know of. And also his military rank was private first class (gefreiter), literally the first non-recruit rank. Which is why hindenburgs circle went through several others to undermine democracy and circumvent the parliament before they took a shot with Hitler after some of their buddies had recommended him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36539625693.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>And do you think their buddies would have recommended some Austrian nobody if his party wasn’t as powerful? 

You know this. I know this. It’s just fun watching you dance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36539937088.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Dude with all due respect, but you made the claim that he got his power through a democratic process and based on voting results, which he clearly didn't. If your point is just that he had some support in the population, ... well obviously. But that also applies for pretty much all dictators otherwise they'd be dead pretty soon.

And Hitler gave up the Austrian citizenship and became a German citizen in 1932 otherwise he wouldn't have been able to run for president, which he also attempted in 1925 but failed.

And it's also the other way around without powerful people protecting him he wouldn't have gotten to being powerful in the first place. I mean his party was banned in 1923, his paramilitaries were banned numerous times. Without conservatives lifting the sanctions time and time again, pardoning him for HIGH TREASON and shit like that there wouldn't have been a Hitler. There might have been still a fascist dictatorship because that's where the conservatives were steering towards anyway, but a different one.

So I don't know what you dance is about cause you're clearly in the wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36540133144.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>It obviously was based on voting results! There is absolutely no way he would have been in position to become chancellor without the clout that being the biggest party gave him. 

Your continued effort to downplay that is amusing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36541030964.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>It was based on popular support, it was not based on voting results. So yes and no... I mean if he wanted to he would have given him the chancellorship in July of 1932 when Hitler had 37% and not in January when they dropped to 33%. Also apparently for the election in 1932 the conservatives lifted the ban on the SA in exchange for their tolerance of a right wing government. Which failed anyway but the resulting terror caused hundreds of deaths and thousands of people to be injured in street fight between nazis, communists and social democrats.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
