<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36519331221.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>

First, both fascist and communist movements tend to arise in response to the failure of the liberal democratic state to adequately redress the economic failures of capitalism.  When an economic crisis occurs, the liberal state has a tendency to resolve the crisis in favor of capitalists and with an imposition of economic austerity on the rest of the population.  For example, this is what happened in Germany in the 1930’s and it is what contributed to the scapegoating of German Jews.  For the fascist, liberal democracy comes to be seen as a form of compromise with out-groups that should be excluded from the democratic process entirely.  Thus, it is a misconception that fascists take power democratically; their first step is to exclude certain groups from the definition of the democratic group, and then to proceed with a democratic process in which no actual alternatives exist for the people to choose from. 

By contrast, the attitude towards democracy among communists is far less consistent.  Some communist parties participate heavily in electoral politics and use democracy to legitimize regime rule; other communist parties justify seizing power for the good of the proletariat.  In any case, both movements gain traction when people’s economic needs are not being met, as they both provide an alternative to the “tough medicine” of economic austerity that is prescribed by liberals.

For your second point, I would agree that fascists generally tend to preserve institutions by seizing them rather than dismantling them.  However, I would not characterize this as any better because the effect is still horrendous.  The seizure of institutions involves the brutal exclusion of every group outside the fascist’s definition of the nation.  The preservation of the institutions themselves seems like a poor consolation when so many people have been harmed.  I would also point out that communist regimes have proven capable of replacing the functions of some institutions and even participating in global capitalist economics.  As mentioned above in regards to democracy, communist regimes vary greatly in how they treat existing institutions and how much they end up restricting the political agency of the people.

The real reason why fascism is much worse than communism is because fascism is vehemently anti-intellectual.  Communist ideology starts with a theoretical engagement with Marx and subsequent theorists, and as a result it is subject to rational critique and revisions to political strategy.  This is why you see communist regimes vary so much in terms of their commitments and the outcomes they produce.  Just look at how much China has changed since its initial revolution, and how much good it has done for its people alongside all of the harm it has done.  This is not to say that China is perfect or that communism was the best it could have done, but just to point out that communism did not lead to China’s complete destruction, and moreover that there is room for China to improve without abandoning communist ideological commitments precisely because those commitments are intellectually flexible. 

On the other hand, there is no core theory underlying fascism; just a pure appeal to the violent exclusionary impulses of the people.  Fascism is an exploitation of people’s feelings: the feeling that one is powerless over one’s destiny; the feeling of belonging to an in-group; the feeling that out-groups are getting preferential treatment at the expense of your in-group; the feeling of vicarious absolute power that has been invested in a single authority figure; and so on.  Fascism gains momentum through its appeal to violence, and it cannot maintain momentum without continued violence – first against internal enemies, then against external enemies.  Fasicsm is inherently self-destructive and can literally only end in tragedy.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519570361.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I know both come out of crises, but I think communism requires deeper crises... which is why I think fascism is more likely. 

In terms of seizing institutions, I meant more long term in that they are still around if and when democracy can take hold again. 

This is the a very optimistic view of china. Don't you think with their embrace of a market economy, chinese corporations and nationalism, that they have almost become a fascist state themselves?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519950905.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>

I brought up China to illustrate the point that communism has a large degree of flexibility because it is rooted in an intellectual discipline.  The fact that China was able to open up its economy shows that it is not dogmatically committed to abstract principles, and it is capable of making rational and pragmatic decisions to secure a desired outcome.  Fascists on the other hand derive power from an appeal to feelings, particularly violent feelings.  Fascists are willing to sacrifice everything for the abstract glory of the nation-state; and in fact, their idealization of power can *only* express itself through sacrificial violence.  If fascists let go of violence, then the power of their appeal is effectively neutered; there must always be another target to pursue. 

This is also what makes fascism distinct from nationalism.  This difference is subtle, because fascism is really just nationalism taken to an absurd extreme.  China has some fascistic tendencies that stem from its commitment to nationalism, most notably its genocide of the Uyghur population.  But Chinese nationalism as a whole does not resemble fascism because it does not appear to be an absolutely absurd and self-destructive commitment to national purity.  My hope is that China will realize that its “re-education” of the Uyghurs is costing them more than it benefits them and they will eventually back off.  If they fail to do so, I think this would be crossing a line from nationalism into fascism.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
