<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36518981555.0" user="generic1001" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end

What are these "pillars" you speak of?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36518991860.0" user="WhiteWolf3117" delta="False">
    <text>And in what way does fascism leave anything behind?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519039184.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>One example is the ‘dual state’ in nazi Germany. They kept the original bureaucracy in large part. The original one survived.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519029200.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Religion, political parties, bureaucracy, corporations, nobility. 

Not all of them survived every fascist regime but usually most do in some form.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519110929.0" user="generic1001" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, but even if we agree on these "pillars", I don't understand. Those survived communism about as much as they survived Nazism. Maybe two or three of those "survived" Nazi Germany. You're aware Hitler outlawed other political parties, persecuted religious minorities and tried to enforce a nazified state religion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519189153.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Tried is the operative word there. If hitler had to ‘try’ to do something like that, it shows that a fascist state is more normative than a communist one. Stalin would have just did it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521101652.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Hitler also "just did it", tried just refers to the fact that he didn't succeed in rolling out that plan, while Stalin was more effective in replacing Jesus with images of himself. That doesn't mean that he had faced resistance for that or would have cared about resistance. On the contrary the church positions itself against Stalin while this:

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reichskonkordat](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reichskonkordat)

used to be a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521279433.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you are really arguing against me. I meant Stalin was more effective. Also, an example of nazi germany co opting an institution instead of destroying is exactly what I was talking about when I said that fascism tended to subvert institutions than destroy them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521368142.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Not surprising, Stalin studied in the Orthodox Spiritual Seminary in Tiflis, so he knew what religious symbolism was about and how he could subvert that. 

Also while fascists usually present themselves as less revolutionary, that doesn't mean that they are less destructive. I mean Hitler basically replaced each and every institution with a Nazi version, every club was either part of the Nazi party or banned. Which in turn pretty much undermines all those institutions because you're not able to be free in them as they serve the main purpose of keeping people under control rather than what they are actually supposed to be. 

Also most often those very institutions that the Nazis didn't touch were those which were authoritarian to begin with. I mean the Nazis weren't against social hierarchies they just wanted to be on top. Though democracy is usually incompatible with such social hierarchies and getting rid of them is more complicated than establishing them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521401874.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>He didn't replace every institution. For example, alot of the german bureaucracy was largely untouched. 

Also, nazism placing themself at the top of a social hierarchy is exactly what I'm talking about. That's just repeating my argument. 

Democracies usually arise with the existing social hierarchy making compromises.  They usually don;t arise with those hierarchies being fully purged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521513602.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Also, nazism placing themself at the  top of a social hierarchy is exactly what I'm talking about. That's just  repeating my argument.

Look it up, for pretty much every organization there was a Nazi equivalent with military ranks under the command of the party. By 1933 they basically had a shadow government mirroring any position in the actual government which was one of the reasons why the conservatives let them rule, because they feared they couldn't fight the fascists, the communists and the republicans at the same time and so they basically joined the fascists. 

&amp;gt;Democracies usually arise with the  existing social hierarchy making compromises.  They usually don;t arise  with those hierarchies being fully purged.

They often don't have the power to fully purge social hierarchies and often enough revolutions come out of the middle class, so they have themselves some interest in at least keeping some of the social hierarchies (those that profited them). So idk you get great talks about liberty while owning slaves or the "liberté, egalité, fraternité" while making sure that the working class "knows it's place". So in that way progress is often delayed. Not to mention that often enough the richer, upper class is often more educated both in terms of having access to classical education and having had practical experience in how things work. So that way they often manage to stick around. Though while in technical issues that might be the case in terms of politics there's often no real difference between a career politician and a revolutionary and history rarely makes one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521519459.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I have no idea how this contradicts what I'm saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521685211.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>The idea that Hitler kept institutions that were good before and built upon afterwards. Those are rather rare and the stuff that was kept was rather radically reinterpreted both by Hitler and afterwards. 

So idk Hitler had a parliament, but practically it was "the worlds largest choir", because apart from singing patriotic songs the power of parliament was non existent. They might have pro-forma extended his emergency powers but it's not that they would have lived to tell the story if they didn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521707397.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say anything about good and I didn't claim that he kept institutions in the same power as they held before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36523508043.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>You made this claim:

&amp;gt;Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end.

They were often there by name only, which seriously demolishes and harms even the very concept of those ideas, because their conceptual ideas are tainted by their execution and the fact that Nazis can use them as "euphemism" for destabilizing the system. 

Also you seem to be under the false assumption that self-governance and democracy are hard concepts. They are easy. In fact they are so easy that they basically are what you'd probably default to if nothing else would be left. I mean how much easier could it get than having no leaders, institutions and hierarchies and just debating with each other in an open forum? 

Seriously you don't need to tell people that they have an equal right to participate in the decision making process, that's what they assume to begin with if you had no laws and power structures enforcing something else. If you end up stuck somewhere with 10 people that have never seen each other would you rather discuss on eye level or accept one of you declaring themselves king/president/prime minister/chancellor or whatnot by their own power? You'd probably either tell him to shut up or ignore that loony. 

The only exception is if someone has a plan and people agree that it's a good plan that could work, then they might give that person permission to follow through with that plan and consent them coordinating that. Which would go from an anarchistic society to a representative democracy. But it probably needs either quite some time or coercion before people would accept rituals and institutions that are not either directly democratic or at least rooted in the general public giving their consent to that. 

Though sure if you're used to drive your bike under supervision and with additional wheels and someone takes that away from you without notifying you, that's pretty scary and you might want to rebound to that previous state, but more often than not you'll figure it out eventually. Despite them pretending to be leaders aren't really any special to the average person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521070789.0" user="yogabagabagaba" delta="False">
    <text>No they didn’t survive communism. In the Soviet Union religion was oppressed severely, political parties were banned, nobility were stripped of their property and businesses and often killed, same with corporations and bureaucracy was changed from incentivising people to be competent to incentivising the best liars and schemers who would please the higher ups to survive. So yeah most of civil society is destroyed under communism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521085277.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>How are those a good thing? I mean the nobility surviving the military dictatorship that ruled Germany during WWI and then backstabbing the republic in an attempt on a reactionary conservative revolution, that would be as equally fascist as the fascists have been, just more focused on the upper class. 

And while religions technically should be antifascist, they often enough endorsed them because they were more focused on conservatism than actually caring about the morality that they preach. 

And how is for example plutocrats taking over the remainder of the USSR and using that money to corrupt the system a "pillar of society". And even if you consider it that way what's the detriment of pulling that pillar down? 

I mean you pretend as if those things are good. While most of them aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521294305.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>Avenues to democracy. 

Democracies tend to come about via compromises of pillars of society. The most common path was constitutional monarchy... which requires a nobility.

It's much harder to get to democracy by just removing all those things as the vacuum is usually filled with other forms of autocracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521455380.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>You might want to read up on that one. Actually a whole lot of democracies are the direct or indirect result of revolutions and turmoil. For example the American Revolution, the French Revolution, the shock waves that those events sent through Europe and which encouraged various revolutions in the 1840s which were often violently put down. And which basically let to the next wave of democracies and revolutions happen at the end of WWI where the existing power structures were so destructed that there was room for more free alternatives and less options to suppress it. 

I mean there is a reason why Marx and many of their peers argued for revolutions and why Lenin did everything he could to destabilize his country, because with the existing power structure of the nobility nothing would have changed. Although when Lenin destabilized Russia, there had already been a revolution and he was largely running in open doors.

And the next wave happened after WWII for the same reason. The imperial nations where no longer able to sustain their colonial rule and so you had lots of countries going democratic or declaring their independence. 

The route over a constitutional democracy is actually only open since democracies have become the norm. I mean the French tried that one and the king or rather his nobility betrayed them. Same for the Russians in 1905 or the Germans in 1918. Basically if you give the authoritarian regime the small finger of still being around, they'll try their best to turn back time and reclaim the system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
