<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36519542038.0" user="Wintores" delta="False">
    <text>Thats not rly correct considering communism and most communist regimes don’t line up</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
