<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1349693156.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mbklwk/cmv_fascism_is_generally_a_more_clear_and_present/">
    <title>CMV: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger than communism but communism is generally worse in practice.</title>
    <original_poster>jmomcc</original_poster>
    <original_post>These are two ideas but they connect, so I decided to put them in one post with two parts. 'In practice' are key words here. I'm not interested in communism as an ideology beyond acknowledging that I prefer it to fascism. When I say communist, I mean countries and regimes that aspired to communism and saw themselves as communist. I acknowledge that no country ever actually achieved communism as Marx envisioned. 

**Part 1: Fascism is generally a more clear and present danger.**

I base this on the following observations: 

Fascist states generally come about via elections and/or military coup rather than full scale revolution. They, therefore tend to come about in MORE peaceful times than communist regimes because more widespread disruption is required for the latter. Nazi germany, for example compared to the soviet union. Therefore, there is a wider 'sweet spot' for fascist regimes taking hold than communist ones. 

Secondly, Fascist regimes are more compatible with a typical capitalist society than communism and specifically more compatible with the powerful people in those societies. Think corporations in nazi germany and the church in spain. Therefore, the people with the most to lose are more likely to follow the carrot of fascism, especially if they are scared of the stick of communism. 

Thirdly, and honestly the one I'm least sure of, fascism is a more appealing idea to most people if you take away the word fascism and its connotations. People think in terms of 'us and them' and the 'other'. People are receptive to ideas of their people being a special people and having a special destiny. They like 'strong' leaders. I'm not saying that everyone is down with genocide but it usually doesn't start with genocide. In other words, the soil is more fertile when it comes to fascism. 

**Part 2: Communism is worse than fascism in practice** 

This is a more long term argument. I don't think communism is worse because they have a larger kill count. That's mostly a result of just how long those regimes survived than anything. I think they are both equally bad when actually happening. 

My main reason why communism is worse, is that it is much easier to become a democratic country again post fascism than it is to become one post communism. 

Communism pulls down the pillars of society and then fails to replace them with anything likewise. Then if communism fails, those pillars arent there to recreate a democratic society. Fascism tends to subvert and repress some of those pillars but they are still there at the end. 

I'm very interested in the replies. These are views I've held for a long time but never articulated so clearly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36519176465.0" user="Nobody_Expects_That" delta="False">
    <text>This post addresses some topics that are important to define properly. Firstly: what is communism, and which nations are communist? Communism is an ideology that has a lot of variations, both Marxist and otherwise. The ideology has the goal of: 1. Collectively owning the means of production. 2. Removing class 3. Removing money (though this is in some versions replaced by other systems) 4. Abolishing the state (sometimes replaced by having a very small, very democratic state)

You mentioned yourself that historical communist nations aren’t perfect, so why does this need to be said? Because the historical communists knew they didn’t fulfil these requirements. They believed in a communist utopia, but the society was not communist itself - the idea was that the society they created would transition to communism. There are a lot of theories of how to reach the communist utopia, some democratic, some undemocratic. Communism isn’t inherently revolutionary, but many Marxists are, and revolutions, communist or not, often end in dictatorship. What you’re criticising here isn’t communism, it’s regimes that failed to achieve the communist dream. 

A lot of your criticism doesn’t touch upon why the ideology itself is bad, just why the regimes that tried to achieve them are bad, and to a degree their sub-ideologies. There are communists who don’t believe in violent revolutions and only want to act through democratic reform and there are communists who, after a revolution would only change society a tiny bit at a time. This is why modern communists often argue that nobody has tried “real communism”, meaning whatever new idea they just came up with for achieving their utopia.  (though as a side note - some communists have been democratically elected and turned out to be assholes anyways, but that’s just how South American politics tend to work).

TL;DR If you want to critics Stalin and other historical communists be my guest, but don’t criticise an entire ideology based on how poorly they tried to carry it out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36519395171.0" user="jmomcc" delta="False">
    <text>I defined what I meant by it in my post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521087822.0" user="yogabagabagaba" delta="False">
    <text>Ahh yes Communism the thing that has never succeeded but is still the solution to everything because it’s never been tried. 

Those weren’t real communists holding the communist manifesto! That was a real socialist country even though it had socialist in its name.

Just one more try pleeeeease. Just oooone more pile of dead bodies please then communism will work we promise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36521161759.0" user="Nobody_Expects_That" delta="False">
    <text>I mean they were socialist by definition. No denying that - the means of production were owned collectively by the working class instead of by capitalists. It’s just that they kinda forgot about the whole democracy thing. Unless you’re referring to countries like Angola and Nazi Germany, which by definition weren’t socialist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528458838.0" user="pigeonshual" delta="False">
    <text>Hard to say even that the means of production were collectively owned by the working class -- in China, for example, the farm cooperatives (which were initially successful and popular among the peasants) were soon de facto taken over by party bureaucrats and commissars who took all actual control away from the peasants. That's more or less how it went in Russia too, IIRC. Unless you accept the party assertion that it's the legitimate representative of the working class because they say so, it's hard to even call those countries socialist. More like lite social democracy without the democracy and with purges.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528499974.0" user="Nobody_Expects_That" delta="False">
    <text>You’re absolutely right. They might have been socialist in principle, but in practice it was just an excuse to oppress the people. Even that is still better than fascism though, where the entire point is to oppress the population.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
