<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36527965957.0" user="Significant_Data2123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange


Id argue that this is actually an excellent idea. Circumstances aside, if you are no longer able to care for an animal it seems to me that its better for that animal to go back to where it came from than it is for the animal to left to fend for itself on the streets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528926331.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't sure that you even could return a pet to a pet store......that gives me chills. That should at least come with a ban on purchasing further pets at the very least from that store. I agree thay they should have some way to safely surrender the pet, but wow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528977283.0" user="Significant_Data2123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That should at least come with a ban on purchasing further pets at the very least from that store

Well first, that would accomplish nothing. If they wanted a pet they would find one. Second, circumstances change. Not being able to properly care for an animal can be overcome by finding a new job, a new source of help, etc. Barring them is shortsighted without context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529059278.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Or let them continue to easily buy more with no intervention or consequence. Nobody would make that argument about adopting children repeatedly after returning them because they can always just resort to human trafficking if they want one badly enough. Not saying it is even their fault, but we still don't give a pass when you failed your responsibility for whatever reason. 
If there are never any consequences, the cultural views on the matter won't change. Enforce the law when that person goes out to "find one," which I agree wouldn't be easy until they ran out of pet shops to buy from and got illegal with their shopping.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
