<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36527910535.0" user="HorrorDisk8" delta="False">
    <text>PetSmart and other pet stores actually have a policy of contracting the adoptions to a local humane society. The humane society is in charge of those adoptions and their rules then supervise the adoption. 

For example, both of my cats were adopted from a PetSmart contracted humane society, and I had to submit paperwork proving that my apartment complex allowed the animals and I had paid a pet deposit. I also had to take a short questionnaire about the circumstances of returning an animal designed to weed out people who are not good candidates. Their policy is entirely separate from any PetSmart returns.

The enclosures and cages they have them in are very similar to the facilities at the humane societies and doesn't really reflect anything differently than "maximizing space, minimizing cost." Running humane societies efficiently and effectively with the little money they have result in setups like that.

Advertising animals this way helps humane societies keep animals off of kill lists and encourages adoptions. This is anecdotal, but I would not have started thinking about adopting a cat if I didn't see the cats up for adoption as I walked to to the fish care isle. One of my cats was days from being euthanized because he was an unwanted runt, and I'm grateful to PetSmart's program for letting me save his life.

Edit: apparently OP is explicitly referencing for-profit puppy milling shops, which I cannot and will not ever argue in favor of. The above statement applies only to adoption and rescue based operations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528982515.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Key word "adopt," not purchase. You adopted them from a shelter who was advertising them at a pet accessory store. That has little to nothing to do with pet stores other than that it confuses children. 

*That last bit was a joke.

I'm referring to for-profit overhead stores in malls and the like that only have puppies in cuby holes on the wall and are never forthcoming about where the animals came from. The best I got from one retail worker I asked was "from an ethical breeder in Wisconsin" and couldn't get the name out of her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529032550.0" user="HorrorDisk8" delta="False">
    <text>That's actually real puppy milling you experienced. That's how most dogs put through puppy mills are sold. I absolutely do not disagree with you there and I don't think you'll find anyone on CMV in favor of puppy mills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529090428.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, I suddenly saw the store while milling about (pun intended), and after I got over the sadness I got heated and went in to question them. 
I totally support the petco partnerships and such, they tend to help shelters quite a bit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
