<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36527948548.0" user="emein" delta="False">
    <text>Why not go after wet markets instead of pet shops.  People have e been buying pets since before money was a thing.  Maybe regulate the business.  Sure terrible things happen but thats why there's a government to regulate things.  Simply stamping out the business will drive it underground.  Then living conditions for the animals will be left up to people avoiding the law.  Cancle culture is a cancer on society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528971453.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Legislation = cancel culture 

Kids these days</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
