<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36530497605.0" user="Disastrous_Video7542" delta="False">
    <text>I think your forgetting a major pet, fish

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\#1   I just can't understand a humane reason for putting \~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

this just isn't a thing with most fish, especially popular fish which get snatched in a couple of weeks before the tank size influences them, and the exceptions to the rule usually need to be custom ordered.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\#2  What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Compared to puppies, fish are much cheaper for pet stores to keep long term and so this again, just is not a thing.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think your last points are perfectly valid

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Most of the points you bring up are solely in relation to cats and dogs, which isn't the only animals pet stores sell, and there are other pets like fish, snails, etc that are fine in pet stores.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
