<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36528126654.0" user="atxlrj" delta="False">
    <text>Pet stores and shelters are actually both products of the same issue: irresponsible breeding practices. 

Encouraging everyone to adopt from shelter does not disrupt the practices that lead to overflowing shelter populations. If everyone adopted pets from shelters, buying into the “adopt don’t shop” mantra, the decline of ethical breeders would accelerate even further, leaving only unethical breeders to plug the demand gap. What we really need to encourage is for people to properly shop for ethical breeders, to get a pet with good health and a good temperament and receive support on preparation and training. These pets are less likely to end up in a shelter and an ethical breeder would never sell to a pet store.

Another interesting point is that shelters have the same physical conditions you are describing  as pet stores (cramped conditions, pets in cages/boxes etc.). On the shelter point, contrary to popular belief, “no-kill” shelters also harm animals by only accepting pets they consider most adoptable, not maintaining full enrollment, etc., leaving municipal shelters will unmaintainable populations of undesirable pets (see unethical breeders) that they inevitably have to euthanize.

The answer should not be for everyone to patronize shelters for pets but to eliminate the need for shelters and cutting off the pet store’s supply by cracking down on backyard breeders and puppy mills. Ethical breeders will be able to fill the demand gap and will ensure that pets maintain the health and temperamental traits and qualities they have been bred for and are known for. We have to get away from the idea that purchasing pets is bad and adopting pets is good - while adopting pets is noble (I have two pets adopted from shelter), it will not solve the problems of overpopulation or poor breeding that lead to the avoidable deaths of animals and the destruction of breed qualities that literally make a pet a pet. Only elevation of ethical breeding practices can do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528770478.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>I worked in shelters for 3 years, and the conditions are atrocious I agree. However, the shelters are not profiting from the issue, only trying to support and are rarely caught knowingly working with breeders. Pet stores don't seem regulated enough to ensure they source ethically and vet their breeders. I would blame the pet stores far more than shelters for encouraging milling. I agree that milling and unethical breeding is the source of all of these issues, but I guess I just think that shutting down pet stores would be a easy mitigating factor. And possibly bring unethical breeders into the light as they scramble to ramp up to meet demand.  I guess my real concern is the legality of it all, because milling is illegal but profiting off quickly selling puppies isn't as long as you have a storefront.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
