<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36529957300.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>I have never heard of pet shops sedating their pets.  That seems like a costly, complex, and dangerous way to do business and customers who want a low energy pet and get it only to find it hyper when not sedated will not be happy with your business.

Do you have any evidence that any pet shops do this as a normal practice and not just some one off horrible store owner who got tired of a dog barking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36628899636.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Open top platforms with plexy glass sidings that animals could easily escape if they were not drowsy most of the time.  Many of the dogs I witnessed could have easily jumped out of their habitats, but they didn't even seem to have full energy when people came in and interacted with them. They seemed to want to interact, but seemed....well...sedated. the pet shop was in Arapahoe County, CO</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36629108017.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>so because you saw the animals were not energetic you assume they should be, you assume the store owner is keeping them drugged up during business hours?  that is quite a leap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36630913886.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Yep, sure did. Saw it once and assumed it was true all the time....seriously dude? I've been in there daily and know much more about their practices. Go there once and talk to staff then come back with your omniscient wisdom about pet store operations in a place I would bet you don't live in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36630980726.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>You were the one making unsubstantiated claims that they were sedating their pets.  I asked how you know this and you basically said their pets look low energy so you assumed they were being sedated.  That is far from evidence to support such a bold claim.

You say I should talk to them, maybe you should talk to them if you are there daily.  

On second though, why are you visiting a pet store daily that you believe is abusing their pets?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36657337522.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Did you read any of the comments on this post before showing off your ignorance. I have already stated that I visit regularly in order to speak to the workers. I have already shared several of their answers to my questions. And no, they will not give a straight answer about sedation and its not that expensive to lightly sedate.  Unless I'm in court I can speculate to the ends of the earth about shit I've witnessed.

Go be needlessly argumentative and pedantic on a post that you bother to read through fully.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36657364408.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>I did read it, and I was just confirming that you had no actual evidence.  I am not saying you can’t speculate they do sedate their animals, you have every right to do that and I have every right to doubt your evidence-less claims.

Maybe they have lights and music on at night which keeps the animals awake so they are tired during the day.  Who knows?  Maybe the just underfeed them during the day so they are low energy?  

I would say you need to calm down but you would probably twist that and say you have every right to rant and I have no legal authority to force you to be calm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37384718030.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>That's the weirdest thing I've ever heard. Damn right you have no "legal right" to tell anyone to calm down. No one was hype. I think you probably need to calm down about obsessing over speculation. Why you mad, though?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
