<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1351274931.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mciier/cmv_pet_stores_should_not_be_legally_permissible/">
    <title>CMV: Pet stores should not be legally permissible</title>
    <original_poster>theArchivesAreAshes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just can't understand a humane reason for putting ~25 animals in small glass boxes/cages for weeks on end, sometimes sedated. What do they do with the puppies that don't sell? How is it any different than puppy milling? 
Until the populations in animal shelters approache more manageable levels, I don't understand why retail stores where you pick out living things like shoes would be permissible.  

The sale of cats and dogs specifically disturbs me, especially when they are in tanks like gerbils. They are offered for sale in the same context as products you can return or exchange, which seems to lead many patrons to do just that. What is the mindset here? 

I can only imagine that patrons of those stores and either looking for a specific breed or are warey of shelters for some reason. That's why I'm asking, because I can't come up with a good reason. I would need to be shown how they can provide more good than harm for animals to change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36527968145.0" user="CoyotePatronus" delta="False">
    <text>I think you mean, pet stores that sell pets instead of hosting adoptable pets should not be legally permissible.

After all, plenty of pet stores out there don't sell animals at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36528914860.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>I would call those pet accessory stores, but that's just semantics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36529332362.0" user="LeMegachonk" delta="False">
    <text>Well, they provide great locations for rescues to find homes for their charges.  I have 3 cats, and all of them were adopted from 2 PetSmart stores' cat rescue partners.  You can adopt a cat and leave with all the accessories you'll need all in one place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36628879548.0" user="theArchivesAreAshes" delta="False">
    <text>Again, not a pet store. You are adopting through a shelter technically</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36530540859.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>In that case I don't think my city has a single pet store, but that certainly would be news to the couple hundred people who work in them.

What you're describing is already the case in many places, though pet stores where I live still sell fish, reptiles, amphibians, and rodents, they all have enclosures probably much nicer than what they're going to post-purchase. Some of them have dogs and cats in rooms that you can see but its all done through adoption orgs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
