<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="137563770.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/29wgvu/cmv_police_should_not_be_able_to_grab_a_us/">
    <title>CMV: Police should not be able to grab a US citizen and throw them in jail until AFTER they have been proven guilty.</title>
    <original_poster>donit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe in this day and age, where it is much more difficult to hide one's identity or run from the law, and would be ruinous to do so, it is unnecessary and highly unfair and disrespectful for police to still be grabbing US citizens and holding them in jail when they are only accused of a crime. 

Right now, a grand jury only considers the accuser's side of the story, and so this creates a hair-trigger situation where if anyone makes a convincing accusation against you, the police will come out to your house and grab you and drag you off to jail, and there is nothing you can say or do about it.  And then several weeks or months later, you show up in court wearing shackles, guilty until proven innocent. 

I believe taking away a US citizen's hard-won freedom should be considered a big deal and should require a fair trial where a court listens to both sides of the story and gives the citizen a chance to defend themselves from the accusation. 

 The only exceptions I would make would be with a serial killer or any type of active combatant, or someone who already has a history of moving around and changing their identity, or in the cases of obvious guilt where it wouldn't matter what the person had to say anyway.

 
Example:  Kim Dotcom, a citizen of New Zealand was advised by his attorneys that his website was in compliance with US laws, and genuinely believed he would prevail against any type of indictment or lawsuit.  Yet US prosecutors were able to snatch him up like a wild animal and put him in a cage, and freeze all his assets. That's how the system works right now, everything is based on the accuser's one-sided testimony to the grand jury.  

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27252026057.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're forgetting about bail... Sometimes bail is set really high, other times it's extremely low based on the person and crime in question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252037693.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>But bail is also a function of their wealth, connections or credit score.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252047013.0" user="notdomoduro" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say it was a perfect system, just something that was completely neglected in the original post.  You can't talk about this issue without having a discussion about bail, especially if you admit that some people accused of some crimes should be held before being proven guilty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252065262.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>No, that is combining unrelated things.  People post bail because they have the credit and connections, or because the judge set it low enough for their credit and connections.  That has nothing to do with whether or not their are guilty, or whether or not their freedom should be respected, or whether they are a danger to society. Bail is completely financial. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252068090.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That has nothing to do with whether or not their are guilty, or whether or not their freedom should be respected, or whether their possible guilt makes them a danger to society.

All of those are considered when the judge sets the bail.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252082832.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you're determining someone's freedom without considering both sides of the argument.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252096500.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>The judge absolutely considers both sides of the argument.  This is why bail is set by a judge, not the police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252128442.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>It is impossible for a judge to hear both sides of the argument if the defendant isn't given a chance to mount a defense and fully make their case.  

If you're already sitting in jail, there's not much you can do.  Can you imagine someone filing a lawsuit against you, and then locking you in a cage and saying go ahead and defend yourself?  That's what they are doing to criminal defendents and you don't see anything wrong with that??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252135553.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>Go down to your local courthouse and watch an arraignment hearing, where bail is set.  The situation you're describing does not exist in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252469797.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>It is exactly what I am describing.  A person's freedom is determined by a one-sided presentation to the grand jury, and then a mostly one-sided arraignment.  They aren't given a chance to even build a case until the trial, and even then it's still not fair because they can't do any of the legwork to build their case. 

I got interested in this phenomenon when I saw what happened to Kim Dotcom. He was advised by his lawyers that his website was in compliance of the laws of the US and he genuinely believed he would prevail against any type of indictment or lawsuit.  But the US prosecutor just had him snatched up like an animal, and froze his money too.  Everything is based on the one-sided testimony to the grand jury, and then the subsequent arraignment, but none of that involves a fair trial and opportunity to gather evidence and present your case. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252492986.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Kim Dotcom was arrested by police in New Zealand. And placed in a New Zealand prison. Yes it was in response to US charges but that gets into much more complicated international laws involving treaties and extradition rules. He is still in NZ last I heard. And a hell of lot more people signed off on that sort of action than just one US prosecutor. Relying on bad legal advice sucks and can get you into trouble but ignorance of the law is never a defense. If he truly believed he would prevail, then he should voluntarily travel to the US to face trial. I mean, I would never advise him to do that, if I were his attorney, but he may never get his money back unless he does so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
