<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="137563770.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/29wgvu/cmv_police_should_not_be_able_to_grab_a_us/">
    <title>CMV: Police should not be able to grab a US citizen and throw them in jail until AFTER they have been proven guilty.</title>
    <original_poster>donit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe in this day and age, where it is much more difficult to hide one's identity or run from the law, and would be ruinous to do so, it is unnecessary and highly unfair and disrespectful for police to still be grabbing US citizens and holding them in jail when they are only accused of a crime. 

Right now, a grand jury only considers the accuser's side of the story, and so this creates a hair-trigger situation where if anyone makes a convincing accusation against you, the police will come out to your house and grab you and drag you off to jail, and there is nothing you can say or do about it.  And then several weeks or months later, you show up in court wearing shackles, guilty until proven innocent. 

I believe taking away a US citizen's hard-won freedom should be considered a big deal and should require a fair trial where a court listens to both sides of the story and gives the citizen a chance to defend themselves from the accusation. 

 The only exceptions I would make would be with a serial killer or any type of active combatant, or someone who already has a history of moving around and changing their identity, or in the cases of obvious guilt where it wouldn't matter what the person had to say anyway.

 
Example:  Kim Dotcom, a citizen of New Zealand was advised by his attorneys that his website was in compliance with US laws, and genuinely believed he would prevail against any type of indictment or lawsuit.  Yet US prosecutors were able to snatch him up like a wild animal and put him in a cage, and freeze all his assets. That's how the system works right now, everything is based on the accuser's one-sided testimony to the grand jury.  

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27252058589.0" user="kolobian" delta="False">
    <text>Not everyone who has been arrested has to stay in jail until trial. You can get bailed out while you are waiting for trail. The amount of bail depends on you, the alleged crime, etc., and when you show up for trial you can get the amount back (minus a fee a fee if you used a bondsmen). If you pose no flight risk, you can also be allowed out on on your own recognizance, with no attached bail.

However, some people absolutely are a flight risk, so they either have high bail or are confined (and no, it's not that hard to run or hide from the police. It happens all the time). If they've been accused of a horrific crime, it's good to keep them there to prevent further crimes, as well as to protect them. If someone is accused of doing a heinous crime that outrages the community, not keeping them in custody might be a threat to their own life. That's why those accused of heinous crimes typically wear bullet proof vests and are transported during weird hours of the night.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252087250.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>That is all true, but you are basically saying a person -might- have their freedom respected if they have the wealth and connections to swing bail, or if the judge feels like setting it low, based on only hearing one side of the story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252107394.0" user="kolobian" delta="False">
    <text>Not really, you can get low bail even with a court appointed attorney.  It's true that if you have more money that you can often hire a better attorney, but it doesn't mean that a poor person won't have their freedom respected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252165222.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;or if the judge feels like setting it low, based on only hearing one side of the story.

Do you know what an arraignment hearing is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252241461.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>What I mean is the prosecution is free to gather as much evidence as they need to support their side and build their case, but the defendent is sitting in a cage.  He can't go around and take photographs, talk to people, or make any phone calls for that matter other than to his lawyer, and he can't research his case online because all of that has been taken away from him.

Sounds pretty one-sided to me.  Locking a US citizen in a cage should only happen after they are proven guilty.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252370939.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>A, that has nothing to do with an arraignment. B, that evidence must be turned over prior to trial and be enough to get a judge to approve the arrest warrant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252428052.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>I think people are too caught up in the terminology and finer details to realize what is actually going on.  

Disrespecting a person by snatching them up like an animal and throwing them into in jail before giving them a chance to defend themselves is an assault on their personal space, an assault on their person, and an assault on their rights.  Basically, when someone is accused, all their citizenship rights disappear and they are just treated as a wild animal and thrown into a cage.

I think a US citizen should retain their rights up until the end of a fair trial because that's the only time the definition of their status legally changed.  That's the point where the no longer own their right to freedom.  And I think caging someone before their trial makes it no longer a fair trial.

Would you agree?  ...or which part would you agree or disagree with and why? 
  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252448150.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Their rights do not disappear and you are assuming that the police and judges are all evil and just out there looking to get everybody. It's simply not the case. They're people too. In the US system, generally, there are different standards of proof that are required at different stages of the process. An arrest requires probable cause, a conviction requires proof beyond a reasonable doubt. Probable cause is easier to meet than reasonable doubt but it's not easy either. Prior to an arrest, the judge sits in the position of the defendant in many ways. His job is to be check against overzealous police action. In order for a valid warrant to be issued, the judge has to be convinced that a crime has been committed and there is probable cause that the suspect in question was responsible for it. If the state doesn't have the evidence to show both of those things, the judge will not sign the warrant. If the judge is wrong and too lenient on the side of the prosecution, the arrest will likely be overturned by a higher court and the case may be ruined along with it. Judges hate being overruled.  
  
This notion of rights being suspended is ridiculous. US citizens still retain their right to counsel, to not testify against themselves, to a speedy trial and to 4th amendment protections against searches and seizures. The reason grand juries are successful is because investigators and prosecutors know the minimum amount of evidence it takes to get an indictment from years of experience and don't waste their time or the grand jury's time with long shots.   
  
Oh and since I'm an attorney practicing in the US and you clearly are not, I do realize what's going on much more than you. So let's pump the brakes on the accusations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252657443.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, there are some checks that help prevent abuse, but then on the other hand we have some corrupt prosecutors who only care about winning because that's the only thing they are scored on. Nobody should ever profit from hurting people by getting a promotion, but unfortunately, that's the corrupt system we have.  A prosecutor would hurt his career if he dropped some cases based on his conscience, or helped the defense if he found out something in their favor or thought of something that was in their favor.  That concerns me a great deal.   I appreciate your weighing in on these things, but it still seems like a person loses a significant portion of their rights just from being accused.  You answer is the judge is a good guy and might not let the system hurt the wrong people.  But the system should automatically protect a person's rights, and we have gotten far, far away from that by automatically putting people in jail first, and then maybe letting some of them out.  I think the ease at which people are thrown in jail makes a mockery of their citizenship.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252887095.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you have your ideas based on movies and media reports and I have my actual experience working in this world. Yes, it sucks to be accused of a crime, but rights are maintained throughout. That's why warrants are required except for specific circumstances. That's why there is an arraignment quickly after arrest. The fact is, police are really good at their job. They don't make very many arrests of the wrong person. You don't have the right to never be arrested or accused of a crime you did not commit. Your example involving a New Zealand citizen accused of breaking US law while abroad is an interesting case for a lot of reasons but not for the ones you want to focus on.   
  
You presumably posted here because you felt like this view was questionable. I and many others have tried to illustrate that your opinion is based on incomplete and false information and we have attempted to clarify things for you. Yet you stubbornly refuse to give in and continue to throw out bromides based on information that nobody would consider authoritative. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27253691275.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>I have listened to all the points given, and appreciate the effort, but they all seem to focus on trusting the system to not be abusive, which doesn't address the design flaws I have pointed out.  I could cherry-pick some cases to show examples, but I know that can be done with any theory, so I think it's better to focus in the design.  

Another design flaw with law enforcement that I learned from the Dotcom case is that law enforcement only cares about catching people breaking the law.  That's not law enforcement, that's law punishment.  Law enforcement would be enforcing the law, ie causing people to comply with the law with whatever means necessary.  But that's not what they do.  For the most part, they don't put any effort into deterring crime, preventing laws from being broken, or protecting people.  

Someone like Kim Dotcom would never receive a call or letter from law enforcement saying "Hey, what you're doing is illegal, you'd better knock it off." That's because it's not about compliance or enforcement of the law, it's only about inflicting punishment. Their only job is to sneak up on him and try to capture, fine and imprison him. 

So, it's like we've created this giant T-Rex that only wants to capture, fine and imprison people.  It's only job is to hurt people.  But by creating a vicious agency that only goes around trying to bite people, guess what, we're putting ourselves in danger of getting bitten also.  You might think, well, just obey the law.   But that would be like lining all the hallways of your house with razor-sharp, hair-trigger bear traps, and saying to yourself "I'll just tiptoe around them carefully."  When you surround yourself with dangerous vectors, you're only putting yourself in danger.  I don't that that was the intent of the American people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27253768277.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>But your expressed understanding of the system is flawed. It does not work how you've described it as working and you refuse to acknowledge that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27253818984.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Someone like Kim Dotcom would never receive a call or letter from law enforcement saying "Hey, what you're doing is illegal, you'd better knock it off."

Furthermore, this cannot ever be how you think law enforcement should work. Everyone gets a free crime, then a letter in the mail, then punishment really becomes an issue. This is the grown-up world. A fuck up is a fuck up. People are obligated to know and follow US law while physically being in or operating in the borders of the US. Some laws are very technical and applicable to select endeavors but most are common sense. Don't hurt other people. Don't take things that aren't yours to take. Pay your taxes. Don't do it unless you're sure the person is 18. Furthermore, you seem stuck on this notion of unlimited time for the prosecution to mount evidence. The future defendant has the same amount of time if he or she is worried about being caught. Again, an arrest means that the defendant has been proven to have committed a crime, just to a lower burden of evidentiary proof than is required for a conviction. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27253991376.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>I get the sense you're going with "that's the way it is, so it must be right" and then filling in details and appropriate justification to match that belief.

Kim Dotcom got ripped off by a corrupt system.  There was no law stating that "all Megaupload sites will be prosecuted".  His argument was his site was similar in design to Youtube where people upload their own files.  So, if the government wanted to narrow the law and try to establish Megaupload as illegal, they needed to work that out in court.  No effort was made to work it out the legality.  The Justice Department acted in bad faith, because they don't care about legality, compliance, or law enforcement.  They only attack, and this was a perfect example of how they are willing to bend the laws by stretching their interpretation in order to carry out an attack. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27254348896.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>For one, the book is not yet closed on that case so its premature to make any meaningful conclusions at this point. He may very well be correct and the justice department may lose. Or there may be a lot more to the story that simply has not been made public. I know that I don't know so I wait and see. 
  
I never said that the current system is prefect by any means. No system can be. But your stated description of the system of pre conviction confinement was simply incorrect and leading you to an odd conclusion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27256341664.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>I think we already have a meaningful conclusion.  Dotcom received preconviction confinement as a result of people following the normal procedures, which tells me the procedures are flawed.

You say that it's rare for that to happen because judges usually don't treat people this badly.  But I think it shouldn't be set up to where you have to hope for the best.  That's like leaving a bad clause or hole in a contract, trusting people wouldn't be that stupid or that cruel.  But as I've learned as a businessman, if you leave a hole, you're agreeing for it to happen.

I read about stories of abuses all the time, especially with plea-bargaining, which might require a whole new thread.   Being held pre conviction is unfair both because it makes it much harder to build a defense and because it changes the dynamic, and sometimes the outcome of the case.  When prosecutor asks someone who has been held prisoner if they would like to plead guilty so they can go home early and have their life back, how are they going to give an objective answer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27256389131.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Well we have rules against people shooting other people and those aren't followed all the time either. Any human system is prone to human error. You still have the right to access evidence and build a case if you are confined. In the criminal world, you will have an attorney provided that will do that sort of thing on your behalf. Or you hire your own attorney. Most of the time, people are able to make bail, if it's even set. You do not have the right against preconviction confinement. You have a right to have that confinement be reasonable and as a result of a warrant. There are hundreds of people who are in prison without being convicted. They have either chosen not to post bail or circumstances around their situation have resulted in no bail being offered. Again, all of those determinations are appealable and many times are successfully.   
  
&amp;gt;When prosecutor asks someone who has been held prisoner if they would like to plead guilty so they can go home early and have their life back, how are they going to give an objective answer?  
  
They can make the determination after listening to the guidance of their own attorney. You're 100% right that most people are not equipped to fully evaluate that choice. That's why in the US, criminal defendants have the right to counsel even if they can't afford to pay. 
  
The truth is, the police are good at their jobs. They arrest the right person far more often than the wrong person. Of course it's never going to be perfect, which is why the 4th Amendment is so powerful as is the adversarial judicial process. Defendants are given the opportunity to be heard and face their accusers. Most of the time, they are not confined during trial. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27272406777.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for this discussion.  I realize you don't think people are wrongfully arrested significant amount of times, and therefore don't think of it as a problem, but I suspect it is, and so I think my next step is to see if I can gather up a list of victims.

Three examples just popped up in a [new thread yesterday:]
(http://redd.it/2awgul)  

Edit-find on page:  "ODDG" (and the one below it), and "RPG"

Maybe you think those are rare, but I think it shouldn't be that easy to violate a U.S. citizen's personal space and manhandle them as if they were livestock. 

You either treat people with respect for their citizenship and their personal space, or you don't.  A farmer corrals his livestock because he wants to.  He has authority because he owns the cattle and he owns their personal space.  

But a U.S. citizen owns their own personal space.  So, the conditions for revoking the personal space citizenship of a US citizen should be very significant and not just based on what somebody said as it appears to have happened in these three examples.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27276252102.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Are people wrongfully arrested? Of course. But not every wrongful arrest is born out of malice. Police are capable of making honest mistakes. That's another reason why we have an adversarial justice system. There are also civil actions available to citizens to compensate them for truly egregious police misconduct. Maybe I'm understating the problem, but you are massively overstating it. The thread you linked to contains no details surrounding the arrest of OP. Plus, you'd only be getting one side of the story.  
  
US citizens are free from unreasonable searches and seizures. Police can lie I suppose but no system is going to eliminate human failings. You mentioned in the thread that you feel it is appropriate to 'send a letter telling a person they are breaking the law and to knock it off'. That is simply not a realistic solution. If someone is harming me by committing a crime, I want that crime stopped and the person punished. Not, we decided we'd chance he'd do the right thing and waited 4-6 weeks before his case popped up again on our system and we realized he didn't actually stop despite our super-nice letter.  
  
&amp;gt;should be very significant  
  
It is. Long term prison sentences following criminal convictions require the highest burden of proof in the judicial system. The VAST majority of arrested people are home within 48 hours of their arrest. We already recognize the difference between the arresting officer's story and the trial process. Other arrests are the result of months, sometimes years of investigation and the case is incredibly strong against a particular defendant. That still requires a judge signing a warrant. A judge elected by the public that has to keep that in mind when he agrees to let a constituent be arrested and prosecuted. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252368856.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>No. Bail is not set by the grand jury and very few state crimes require a grand jury finding at all. A grand jury can award an indictment, that leads to an arrest. Bond is set by the judge after hearing from both sides. And it takes into account the defendants assets.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
