<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="137563770.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/29wgvu/cmv_police_should_not_be_able_to_grab_a_us/">
    <title>CMV: Police should not be able to grab a US citizen and throw them in jail until AFTER they have been proven guilty.</title>
    <original_poster>donit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe in this day and age, where it is much more difficult to hide one's identity or run from the law, and would be ruinous to do so, it is unnecessary and highly unfair and disrespectful for police to still be grabbing US citizens and holding them in jail when they are only accused of a crime. 

Right now, a grand jury only considers the accuser's side of the story, and so this creates a hair-trigger situation where if anyone makes a convincing accusation against you, the police will come out to your house and grab you and drag you off to jail, and there is nothing you can say or do about it.  And then several weeks or months later, you show up in court wearing shackles, guilty until proven innocent. 

I believe taking away a US citizen's hard-won freedom should be considered a big deal and should require a fair trial where a court listens to both sides of the story and gives the citizen a chance to defend themselves from the accusation. 

 The only exceptions I would make would be with a serial killer or any type of active combatant, or someone who already has a history of moving around and changing their identity, or in the cases of obvious guilt where it wouldn't matter what the person had to say anyway.

 
Example:  Kim Dotcom, a citizen of New Zealand was advised by his attorneys that his website was in compliance with US laws, and genuinely believed he would prevail against any type of indictment or lawsuit.  Yet US prosecutors were able to snatch him up like a wild animal and put him in a cage, and freeze all his assets. That's how the system works right now, everything is based on the accuser's one-sided testimony to the grand jury.  

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27252256928.0" user="SloppyPrecision" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think we need to change your view on this because your view is totally consistent with laws and rules in the U.S., you are simply misunderstanding how the system works.  

When one is arrested for a crime, there is a legal presumption that the person will be released on their own recognizance (meaning they are released on their promise to appear at future court dates).  In situations where a person is held on bail, or even held as non-bailable, there must be an additional justification, proven to a judge, for these enhanced release conditions. These additional justifications vary by state but, for example, could require a showing that the person has previously failed to appear in court, or there is greater than probable cause that the person committed the crime (one such standard is "proof evident and presumption great").

Basically, what you wrote in your post is, in fact, the law.  Certainly the laws are not always followed and the system is subject to being abused by the prosecution but, generally, what you think it should be is what it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252284525.0" user="omgpieftw" delta="False">
    <text>Actually because the U.S has been in a state of emergency since 9/11 all these conditions you're talking about can be suspended if the person in question is suspected of associating with 'terrorists' or 'affiliated terrorist groups'. 

So really I could be arrested and detained indefinitely without trial for the crime of being suspected of being associated with 'terrorist groups'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252373988.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Without trial does not mean without access to the courts and the scotus decisions have been one sided in favor of defendants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252284917.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the system is even close to what it should be.  Kim Dotcom was advised by his attorneys that his website was in compliance with US laws. Yet the prosecutors were able to snatch him up like a wild animal and put him in a cage, and freeze all his assets.  He was a citizen of New Zealand who believed he would prevail against any type of indictment or lawsuit, and they still snatched him up like an animal.  

I know another guy who was late on his child support payments and the police snatched him up and put him in jail.   No proof required as to whether he owed the money (lost his job) or whether he actually had the means to pay the money.  That's my point, you should have to prove it first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252376813.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>You admitted your friend was breaking the law. The proof would be the missed payments. You pay child support to the court which then turns it over to the custodial parent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252443856.0" user="donit" delta="False">
    <text>The law says that a portion of his income goes to the ex wife.  But missing a payment isn't proof of that because the guy might have lost his job, and not owed the payment.  Such can only be determined with a hearing. 

This happens over and over across the country because when the guy loses his job, he has to hire a lawyer and have another hearing to determine the new level of child support.  This takes time and money, but the ex can have him arrested in the meantime right when he starts missing payments after losing his job.  And what is he supposed to use for money to hire a lawyer to get the payments reduced? And how is he supposed to continue making payments at the old rate, up until the court date?  It's a sad catch-22 and happens over and over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27252488911.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure that in every jurisdiction, child support is owed even if the party responsible loses their job. Or, if there is a rule allowing for suspension of payment, I'm pretty sure the person needs to take steps to inform the court and the custodial parent in order to prevent this kind of trouble. And believe me, no court is that efficient that one missed payment will lead to an arrest. And the custodial parent doesn't make arrest decisions. People in that situation represent themselves all the time and he has every right to do so, but he needs to be on the ball.   
  
The argument you'll hear though is: the child doesn't stop having needs just because you lost your job. If he qualifies for unemployment benefits, he should get those and make child support payments out of that while he looks for new work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
