<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696142357.0" user="musiclover1998" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s less about looks and more about how you make women feel. Maybe the energy you give off doesn’t match what they’re looking for. If you’re a kind person, but a girl isn’t attracted to you, she isn’t going to want a relationship. 

Also, a lot of younger girls tend to be really shallow, as you get older I feel like your view on women will change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696273406.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Yay, so I can get women when they are old and used up? That makes me soooo happy :/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696293272.0" user="Responsible_Phase890" delta="False">
    <text>Dude.. this stamentement right here is the problem.  If you want to stop being an Incel then get this shit thinking out of your mind. This indicates that you don't really value women</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696335440.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Oh cmon, you want me to date old people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696354960.0" user="Responsible_Phase890" delta="False">
    <text>Don't be obtuse.  Your stamentement shows that you don't seem to care about women as people,  just a status symbol.  But if you actually tried to get to know women as people, instead of an object you are being deprived of, you might change your view</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696407438.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>I can name so many horrible things about dating an older women. Here’s a few: 

They die faster. They are far less fertile. They are more likely to already have kids / have gone through a divorce. They are *very* unlikely to be virgin or even only had sex with one or two guys. 

That’s just a few.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696467275.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How do you square comments like this with your claim to not even really care about sex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696485784.0" user="Responsible_Phase890" delta="False">
    <text>No one is telling you to date a 50 year old, first of all.
 the idea is to be patient because as you get older, you will be around more mature women

Second of all, calling a woman used and worn out is dehumanizing language which speaks to how you think about women in general. She doesn't lose value evey time she has sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696528369.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>How can you love someone if you’ve opened your legs to like 60 guys? She wouldn’t be able to love me, she would think about all those other guys. I’m not a cuck, I only want a pure virgin who’s brain hasn’t been filled with thoughts of other males.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696575301.0" user="Responsible_Phase890" delta="False">
    <text>You sound like you are trolling at this point. If you honestly cannot see how irrational you are, there is nothing that can be done. You  do not have realistic expectations about women so you will always be disappointed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696923716.0" user="HappyRainbowSparkle" delta="False">
    <text>Then get a blow up doll, let's be real you don't want a woman you want somewhere to put your dick</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696302444.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>Are you sure it's all women who are shallow?  Because it sounds more like you're shallow and projecting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696332136.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't want them when they are mature, you sure as hell don't deserve them when they are in their prime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696475263.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>Oh please. A 17 yr old not interested in a 30 year old is not bad.  Would you say the same to a 17 year old girl about a 30 year old man..... I sure as hell hope not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696507873.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>The problem here is what his "interest" actually is.  Older women are "used up" - this shows that he thinks women are to be used for sex, they are a commodity being withheld from them rather than people to have relationships with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696663774.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>I missed his statement to that effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696532615.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that anyone is saying that he should be dating 30-year-olds now, it's that his response to saying, "Well, as the women around you mature it's going to get easier" is going, "And fuck old, ugly bitches? No thanks!"

ETA: This despite, you know, complaining about women being shallow and insisting he doesn't even really care about sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696335511.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Weren't you the one complaining that women are shallow and only care about looks? What do you think *this* comment is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696387189.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I’ll remove the ugly. Actually, milfs are pretty hot. Not all older women are ugly. However, I still don’t want an old woman’s okay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696407424.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>1) That's still shallow, so this is still very hypocritical of you.

2) When the user you responded to said "as you get older," how old do you think they actually mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696433275.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>25 to 30?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696440264.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's not *old*, and that you think it is a sign of an inability to see past your own circumstances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696466190.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of teenager wouldnt want to date another teenager, unless we are talking about milfs or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696476492.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>We're not talking about that, we're talking about you bemoaning not being able to date a teenager as being confined to having to date old, ugly women later, when what you mean by that is a woman who is fucking *twenty-five*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696554407.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of teens don't want to date at all.  They are more focused on school, sports, hobbies, their future.  You probably care a lot more about dating and sex than many of your peers, judging from this post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696517379.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>25 year old women are usually closer in experience/looks/maturity to high school/college age girls than actual old women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696376108.0" user="musiclover1998" delta="False">
    <text>You can get women that are equally as attractive as you are. If you have a problem with that, make yourself more attractive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697216507.0" user="plumsftw" delta="False">
    <text>There are a lot of rightfully defensive replies to your comment here so I think maybe I can make an attempt at reasoning here.  It sounds like from your comments that your "pool" of candidate women at your school is virtually zero. Maybe you will find a girlfriend in your teens, maybe you won't. If you don't, it's not the end of the world. Your world and beliefs will likely transform to a great degree when and if you go to college. Your possibilities open up, you'll grow up and meet different people with values you likely didn't encounter in college. There are bound to be girls who you will eventually find whose interests match up with your own.  No doubt when you are a few years older, but not OLD, you will find someone your age whom you may connect with.

But I think the issue here is the high value you place on virginity. Fair enough, you want your first relationship to be special, with someone who will also view the experience as precious, hence the value on it being her first time as well. But what about afterwards? What if that first relationship doesn't work out? Do you think YOUR value as a partner suddenly goes down because you're no longer a virgin? Or are you projecting a double standard on women that doesn't apply to you? 

Women who "have experience" in their 20s aren't necessarily serial one-night-standers. Both women and men have probabilistically had more relationships at that point in their life. It's not so much their minds have been "filled with thoughts of other males" or "opening her legs to 60 guys", it's more likely the average woman you meet may have had like 3-5 relationships at that point (and there is obviously going to be a wide range). And get this, these women will probably be BETTER partners than an inexperienced teenage girl, not just sexually but emotionally and mentally as well.

I am not attempting to be judgemental, just suggesting that you should consider that you might not be a virgin once you find the relationship that means the most to you, and that doesn't lower your value as a partner. And to apply that thinking to women as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697270156.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. I guess it just makes me sad and insecure thinking about my hypothetical gf being with anyone else. Arent I all that should matter to them? And how do I know they don’t miss the other person? And if I get a gf, it’s not I will have dated anyone before her, so I wish it could be the same. I don’t think people who have fucked are worth less, I just want a pure, virgin angel</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697684586.0" user="plumsftw" delta="False">
    <text>If that's what you want then there are definitely girls who share that mentality (your point about potentially being a fit for religious girls stands, for example). I'll argue that it is possible for someone to have been with someone and still devote all of their attention to the person they're currently with. Obviously that person would need to be really secure with their relationship; it's not impossible. 

A caveat is that pure virgin angels still have no fucking clue what they actually want in a partner, less because of the lack of sexual experience but because if they've literally never been with someone than how can they know? After your first relationship you may find that it's preferable to be with someone who does know what they want. The plus side is that then you can be the best person they've had, and they actually have experience to back up that judgement :)

To deviate from the above points, are there extracurriculars or volunteering you can do in your community to meet other girls? Even just making some friends would be a step in the right direction. I mean that could give you what you want and it could also introduce you to other perspectives.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
