<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696136244.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>Well I disagree with you and even with what I am about to say. But this isn't abkjt being correct it's about changing your mind about your statement. 


Women also care about money.  Otherwise why do so many ugly men worth a lot of money have Women all over them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696211732.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>That isn’t a good thing. I wouldn’t want a women who wants me for my money cause then she wouldn’t actually love me. Like I said, I care about more than just sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696341823.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Like I said, I care about more than just sex. 

We know now that this is you lying to us:

&amp;gt;Yay, so I can get women when they are old, ugly, and used up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696350914.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>How are you people so insane that you insist I’m shallow for wanting to date old women? Like would they literally be pedophiles</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696400345.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>You said that in response to someone telling you that women (like all people) become less judgemental as they mature.  That's not a good thing for you, because you only want them young, because all you care about is sex.  You can't afford to wait because then the sex you could be having won't be as good.  

Therefore, all you actually care about is sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696421497.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I’m so horrible for wanting teenage love, aren’t I?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696478048.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, yes!  If what you want is not sex, but a real relationship, then you would be willing to wait for it.  You are more focused on losing your virginity while you are still a teen.  An actual relationship with a woman is not what you want, nor is it even something you would be capable of at this point since you don't understand or respect women at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698293938.0" user="aceytahphuu" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes, you labeling older women as "used up" was clearly just you being worried about pedophilia, how silly of us to interpret it any other way!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696344691.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn't your statement.  Your statement stated very clearly "women are shallow abd only care about looks"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696597082.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Fair is fair. Men who use women as their bank account are a thing, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696694622.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>That is true.

My point being women aren't "only" worried about looks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697036705.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>That sentence would sound better if you included both sexes.

Every single thing you say about women are human emotions and views. They are not special to women. Men have the same types of issues.

Remember my point about human beings. Put yourself in the other person's shoes and use your human skill of empathy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697126287.0" user="SpeakerClassic4418" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, but this topic is specifically about women.  I'm adult who understands that a statement is just that, a singular statement and not all encompassing worrying about everyone's perceived issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698116838.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I intended that reply for someone else, so sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
