<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696392845.0" user="dreamofdandelions" delta="False">
    <text>First off: I hear your frustrations, and appreciate the thought and energy you’ve put into spelling them out in a detailed and considered way.

With regards to so many women going for assholes/abusive guys - hindsight is 20/20. Sometimes girls go for guys who are dicks because they find them attractive, but most of the time, relationships start new and shiny and fun. And the abusive people - the real ones - are very, very good at hiding it. It might look obvious that someone is abusive from the outside, but abuse is SO complicated, it’s not just about someone being an asshole, it’s about them fundamentally stripping you of your self-worth and making you feel like that’s all you deserve, and doing it so expertly that you don’t realise what’s happening. It’s a lot harder to spot red flags when you’re in the early stages of being excited about someone, even if you’re good at spotting them in other people’s relationships. And with regards to relationships that are garbage but not abusive: the way you talk about an old relationship is inflected with wisdom about how it turned out. It’s quite rare to hear people talk fondly of a past relationship, especially while it’s still fresh. And talking about all the nice things in your relationship is just boring, so you don’t hear the normal/chill bits! So of course it sounds like women are only dating assholes, but the reality is: people are dating people, and dating is hard! For everyone!

Also, you’re so young, SO young - relationships are complicated and hard and decisions that are no-brainers down the line can be much tougher for a teenage girl who’s never dated before. I’m 25 - so not even that old, I hope! - and the social hierarchies that dominated high school mean absolutely nothing to me or any of my friends now: priorities change, people mature. Don’t make the mistake of basing your understanding of women and relationships on your situation and peers right now. Teenage relationships are going to be drama-filled and look like trainwrecks because many teenagers don’t know how to make good relationship decisions yet. It’s not hypocrisy, it’s a learning curve! 

And on that note: I promise, people are having way less sex than you think they’re having. WAY LESS. Even if they’re bragging about how much sex they’re having. Most of the people I slept with at university were virgins. It’s not at all abnormal to make it to adulthood a virgin, and there’s no shame in it!

The other thing is, I get that you’re scared of being called a “creep” for expressing interest in people. In pop culture, that’s what happens when a man who isn’t the romantic lead in the show expresses interest. In high school, it’s what happens if you’re not popular because high school is garbage. Real life isn’t like that, provided you’re not actually a creep. Sure, sometimes people get their wires crossed, but most of the time, if you’re fine, women are too. Just be friendly, be considerate, form meaningful friendships with women you DON’T want to sleep with because women are great, and I promise this will all feel a lot more manageable in a few years’ time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
