<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696270406.0" user="OwsaBowsa" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, I think it’s great you’re trying to appeal to others in your efforts to improve your life and change your attitude. You’ve gotta start somewhere!

The absolute biggest aspect worth pointing out is that you’re a teenager. You know who, on average, doesn’t have their life figured out?  Teenagers. Most adults don’t have their lives figured out either, but they tend to have a lot more access to therapy, medication, and circumstances of their choosing rather than the happenstance of living at home under a guardian’s watchful eye.

Have you traveled outside of your hometown? Around the world? What do your social circles look like? These kinds of things greatly impact your outlook on life, how others treat you, and how you’ll think of others. I’ve lived in several states, traveled to a handful of different countries, and had numerous casual and romantic relationships (most of which came AFTER college). My experiences are my own, but they’re across a broader spectrum of what life has to offer. As a result I have a better understanding of myself, what I look for in the people I surround myself with, and more compassion for others, whether I’ve met them or not. From what I’ve seen, people in my life who never left their immediate surroundings since birth are more close minded, more religious (in an extremist way), more bigoted, and just generally unpleasant towards others.

Think of it like a scientific experiment. If you test something 10 times, that’s not a great sample size and your data is severely flawed. Test something 1,000 or one million times and chances are your hypothesis is going to be a lot more sound. So it goes with life experiences and making assumptions about other people. One of your “problems with the world” is that women won’t date you. Have the met the world? There’s billions of people out there. They come from other cultures, speak other languages, and may very well still have similar interests to you! But you’re 17. You haven’t met them yet. That doesn’t mean you should judge half the population of Earth so harshly. Never mind the irony of complaining about women as a whole being so picky and yet you ALSO seem to be rather picky in your own limited exposure to the rest of the population.

There’s a lot more I could respond to (and I’m happy to if you have other questions/comments), but for now I’ll just say that even at your age, your life hasn’t quite gotten off the ground yet. Don’t hold other people to your standards or expectations because they have their own lives their dealing with. In time, as you ping pong around life, you’ll meet all sorts of great people and eventually you’ll connect with some on a whole other amazing level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696727769.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>You’re right. But I really want teenage love, everything sucks and gets harder when you’re older, so this is the ideal time. And I’ll never have that. I’ll never be happy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696797776.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry for being all up and down this thread, but you're really sticking to me as a misguided guy who needs this talk. 

Honestly? The worst relationship a lot of people have is high school, teenaged love. When I say you in these next sentences, I'm talking about anyone engaging in a relationship, not "you," /u/ITSINCElTIME. You don't know how to be in a relationship. You don't know how to communicate with women. You don't know how to manage conflict. Like any skill, it needs practice.

 I'm 24 in grad school, not that much older than you. And believe me when I say my current relationship is much better than the one I had in college, which itself was infinitely better than the one I had in high school. I'm more experienced, understand what is healthy and unhealthy in both my actions and my partner's. And it's the happiest I've been with someone, even when I thought that my high school girlfriend would be my future wife.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696820982.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36707708197.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/OwsaBowsa – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20OwsaBowsa&amp;amp;message=OwsaBowsa%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/-/guwc8ae/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696866289.0" user="OwsaBowsa" delta="False">
    <text>What you want isn’t necessarily what others want, and to expect anything different is a fool’s errand. And who says things get harder when you’re older? People around you who are exactly the same age? I make my own money. I can drive a car anywhere I want. I can book a flight to anywhere in the world. Every decision I make is entirely my own and it’s great!

Never claiming you’ll have a relationship, or love, or happiness definitely points to something bigger going on. Reaching out to Reddit in the first place is an indicator that you want more out of your life. It’s probably best you talk to family (if you have it) and ideally a professional who can help you really work through things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697050367.0" user="pensivegargoyle" delta="False">
    <text>That's so wrong. Starting and maintaining relationships is never easy but the hardest time to do that of all is when you're young. You haven't had the experience to be sure what you want and you haven't developed the skills to communicate well. You learn that by doing</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
