<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696331211.0" user="Melodic_Echidna" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women

Look, I'm glad you're here and seemingly want to change your view. That's a great first step. But you also just said you think women are shallow hypocrites who only care about appearance. Women are individuals. Imagine for a second how it would feel if you were a woman and quite regularly (this sub alone gets several of these posts a week) saw men willing to make incredibly broad and negative assumptions about you as a person based on only your gender, something you have absolutely no control over. 

Additionally, incel forums not infrequently engage in violent rhetoric and make matyrs of men who committed or attempted to commit mass violence on women. And I get that a lot of the incels who come to this forum asking for these views to to be changed don't *want* to be bitter but they do often hang out in places where this rhetoric is prevalent. This isn't the behavior of somebody who is kind and respectful of women. Even if you can hide those views  IRL (and I think that's far harder than many self-identified incels think it is) you are really only pretending to be kind and respectful while being unkind and disrespectful where you can be anonymous.  

&amp;gt;Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

About 55% of teenagers have sex by their 18th birthday with slightly more males being sexually active at some point than females ([https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs\_press\_releases/2017/201706\_NSFG.htm](https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs_press_releases/2017/201706_NSFG.htm)) , so yes there are plenty of 18-year-old virgins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696377359.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, women constantly call all men misogynistic rapists and harassers. And second, I don’t go on incel forums, and when people worship Elliot Rodger or whatever it’s completely ironic usually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696409133.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>You are literally a misogynist though, so at least that much is an accurate perception.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696433783.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You should reflect on your tendency to interpret everything women do and say in the worst possible light ("they all constantly call men misogynistic but also only date misogynists"), but do the opposite with men ("when incels say they worship Elliot Rodger it's ironic").</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696478181.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, women constantly call all men misogynistic rapists and harassers.

This isn't my experience.  In my expanded social circle there was a fake rape accusation. I'd say the mix of women who believed it was 60/40, with men closer to 50/50. When women were given the whole story in private they were much more likely to sympathize with victim of the accuser.

I think you're greatly exaggerating here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696594021.0" user="Melodic_Echidna" delta="False">
    <text>While I've seen misandrists posts here my impression has been they happen far less often then incel posts or posts otherwise demonizing women. 

Worshipping a mass murderer ironically or doing it genuinely is not, I think, a particularly meaningful difference. In the first case you are treating it as an in-joke and in the second case you are treating it as something laudable and neither of those are the right response. 

Whether you frequent what you consider to be incel forums or not, you've managed to pick up their philosophies and vocabulary and incorporated it into your own, so you might want to consider whether the places you're exposed to that are really healthy places to be spending time on the internet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696585145.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine for a second how it would feel if you were a woman and quite regularly saw men willing to make incredibly broad and negative assumptions about you as a person based on only your gender

Oh, yeah, because women *never* make broad negative assumptions about men based upon nothing but there gender.  Men would *never* know how that might feel.  /s

For God's sake, we're all seen as rapists so women are afraid to be out at night.  Haven't you read the internet?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
