<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696153074.0" user="PivotPsycho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if I even talk to them at all. 

Right, this is kinda a prerequisite. People in general don't date people just because those people tell folks on the internet they're not abusive. 

For the rest it seems like you have a confirmation bias that can be resolved resolving the quote above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696251925.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Talking is a two sided thing. They don’t want to talk to me, because women see anyone who isn’t chad or a clown as subhuman. I don’t even know where to start with them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696293314.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, man, that's not it. They don't talk to you because you don't actually seem to be making an effort to talk to them or even, like, view them as human.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696321951.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>They would see me as a creep and laugh at me if I even tried.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696329720.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How. Do. You. Know? You don't even talk to them, so you don't know anything about them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696343066.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Strange how people are like “oh but women can sense that you are toxic and resent them” but I can’t recognize when girls are judging me? They even laugh at me sometimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696420623.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So can women tell you're an incel or not? You've claimed both now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696427075.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>When did I say girls can tell I’m an incel? If you think I said that I didn’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696445541.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So what are they laughing at you about then?

Like, you see what I'm saying right? Girls have no idea you're toxic, but they do know that there's something about you worth making fun of? Despite you never actually talking to them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696473270.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, because I’m quiet, have nerdy interests, and not very attractive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696498586.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>And if you continue to harbor these thoughts about how horrible women are, it’ll be reflected in your attitude and girls won’t want to interact with someone that acts like they hate women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696532088.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, buddy. I’m a good actor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696590829.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>You're a 17 year old kid who can't even pretend on a text based forum that you're even slightly interested in having your mind changed. I'd love to actually have a conversation with you and try to help you, because I feel bad. But you're not giving any showing that you actually want your mind changed about how trash you think women are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696645925.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, just try not to act like women are telepaths. And even if you still think they are, I have the ability to shield my brain from their attacks. Then we can continue a conversation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696680435.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, women aren't telepaths. And if they are, you can shield your brain. Congratulations.

However, people are surprisingly good at reading body language and nonverbal cues. Almost 90% of communication is nonverbal. Let's assume even if you are a good actor, you're not Tom Cruise or Daniel Day Lewis. There will be cracks or tells in how you really feel. 

If you despise women as much as you say here, then that will come through. I'd never want to spend any more time than necessary around someone who is giving me the vibe that they actively dislike me. 

And that's got nothing to do with what you're saying about you and women, and how unhealthy that stuff is. I'm just saying above that girls can probably tell more than you think that you don't like them. They accordingly will try to avoid you, setting you up for a self-fulfilling cycle that YOU need to break out of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696598715.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, you're not. It took you like 10 minutes to reveal in the comments that you actually only care about sex despite claiming not to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696624489.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>You’re projecting</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696634568.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Am I? Then how do you square your statements in the OP with claims to not want to have to wait to date 25-year-olds because they're old, used-up, and ugly? Why the emphasis on virginity? You're being a hypocrite, and I think you know that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696505936.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It rather seems you're drawing the worst possible conclusions based on zero evidence. You can't really know what anyone thinks of you unless you talk to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696545880.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, how do you suggest a start a conversation with a femoid. What are they gonna talk about, tiktok? Makeup or something? I forgot to mention that in my post, most women have the most boring interests, I could never date a girl who doesn’t like what I do or isn’t willing to try out my interests.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696560587.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you view women as sub-human "femoids" who can't possibly like anything other than TikTok or makeup, it is not surprising that you find yourself unable to talk to them.

What are you actually hoping to get out of this CMV post, exactly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696635167.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Yesterday me and my girl talked for probably 45 minutes about what kind of toppings each of the Avengers would most likely order on their burger.

You're applying all these negative values to women, who you call "femoids", that you obviously have no actual idea about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696660600.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>The Avengers is normie tier shit I have no interest in. Do girls like anime or anything?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696732648.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so you have lots of issues here. Who cares what other people like? If you don't like the Avengers, that's fine. I enjoy the films as popcorn flicks, but I don't love them either. She does, so I talked about it with her. You aren't going to find someone who's likes and values are a mirror. And honestly, that's fine. But saying girls only like TikTok and makeup is wrong and unhealthy. And calling stuff "normie tier shit" is unnecessarily adversarial, and contributes to what I'm telling you is putting people off.

There are plenty of girls who watch anime. I know in high school especially it's tough to talk about that stuff and find girls in your school who are open about it. In college, I met tons of girls that would be completely happy spending a Friday night with people close to them watching a few different animes. Look on reddit at anime subreddits. See if they have any discord links or chats. Go on them, and don't ask people if they're male or female. Just talk to everyone the same, and you'll be surprised to learn how many girls like the same things you do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696779785.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I think there are some girls who like anime at my school. But I’m like weird and they are pretty and wear cool clothes and I don’t think they would ever want to talk to me. And like I don’t have any friends and it would be so weird and creepy to just go and talk to them for no reason. I just wish I was someone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696868662.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Man, it's alright. I'm not going to tell you that you're perfect just the way you are, because we both know telling anyone that is bullshit. But that doesn't mean you shouldn't try to always better yourself. Liking anime and "nerdy" things is fine. My most played game on Steam is Smite, a MOBA that isn't even League. I could tell you more about European history than you'd ever want to know. But I still make time to go to the gym to stay healthy, I look up guides online on what clothes look good together, stay groomed and clean. While still maintaining my identity. Are there small things you can do to improve your outward look?

Before you get a girlfriend, you need to be secure in yourself. And it doesn't sound like you are. That's why I'm suggesting going on subreddits and their discords and just talking normally. Don't go on about "femoids" or what not, just talk about the anime you're watching. Talk about it with other people. You play any multiplayer video games? See if there are groups dedicated to that, and people that want to play with others. Friends don't have to be to in your town or neighborhood to be great friends.

And a little hint. The thing that women really are into? Confidence. If you're secure in yourself, without being arrogant, girls will be attracted to that. Someone who is just so secure in themselves is something both sexes are into.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696647564.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>If you have nothing to talk with women about, why do you want to be dating one?  

You are constantly showing us that you are completely lying when you say you have no interest in sex, and what's worse is that you are totally projecting your own obsession with sex onto women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696680439.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I want a girlfriend who has the same interests as me, won’t think I’m a pussy for crying, will cuddle with me and show me lots of physical affection (not sex), and isn’t going to cheat on me or leave me (which is more likely if she’s not a virgin). You can’t make whatever accusations you want, but I know in my heart I’m not lying to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696725908.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>The problem then is that you want women to *generally* be like what you want *specifically.  That's not exactly a fair attitude towards women, is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696749369.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>FWIW, I believe that you don't see what you're doing here as "lying," you just have enormous cognitive dissonance about this and can't see how what you claim to want from women is contradicted by how you actually talk about them.

The best possible thing for you, at this point, would be to get professional counseling, and to try to work on yourself before you even think about getting into a relationship. Like you say women can't tell you're toxic -- okay, maybe not, you don't talk to them anyway. Are you telling me you'll be able to get into a long-term relationship and just totally hide that part of yourself from that person? I highly doubt it.

Stay off of red-pill and incel spaces too. This isn't entirely your fault, because these places actively try to radicalize young, lonely men exactly you, and you've essentially been brainwashed, but you have to make the effort to extract yourself from those spaces and that way of thinking now. Stop thinking of women as "femoids." They're human beings. They want all the same things you do, and are as individually variable as any man is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696852605.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I wouldn’t need to think this way if a girl loved me, right? 

I wish I could stop thinking this way. But it’s hard. Pretty much impossible. I have a therapist but I couldn’t tell her about this. I mean, she’s a female herself</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696875996.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You need to tell your therapist about this. It is a huge issue for you that is actively damaging everything about your life. She's a trained professional who wants to help you, she's not going to just be like, "get the fuck out of here."

You just said it yourself -- you don't think you can change your thinking on your own. 

And also: things are *not* going to magically change if "a girl loves you." You're going to get into one relationship and suddenly all the misogyny, all the "women are just shallow femoids"  stuff, all the hatred and resentment you've built up for an entire gender is just magically going to disappear? That's not how this works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697113859.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t know if she could help me. I’ve had therapists a lot of my life, and I’m not very confident in them. 

I’m just thinking that if the cause of all my misogyny is being rejected and hated by women, maybe love could fix it. Or maybe I could even get a anti feminist gf. Rare but it would be nice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697123000.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Your therapist *can* help you, and is much more likely to do so than just magically finding love will. You're just making excuses now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697175862.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>True. I talk to her on Tuesday. Hopefully I’m brave enough to bring it up and she doesn’t report me for thoughtcrimes because I don’t like women. Canada sucks lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697538611.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm Canadian and there is no possibility of you being reported by your therapist for "thoughtcrimes."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697575300.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, I’ve heard of people getting arrested for hate speech</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697584110.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Hate speech is a very specific thing and it doesn't encompass telling your therapist that you have issues with women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697597819.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Good. I was mostly joking around tho</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697645061.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You should get out of the habit of even joking about these things. You're not a victim here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698250225.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Being lonely and unloved doesn’t make me a victim? Okay</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698340651.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't, no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698382914.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Lol okay, depression and being suicidal is basically nothing! My life is perfect!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701519477.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Forgive me if I'm not exactly overflowing with sympathy given some of the things you've said here. I suffer from depression and suicidal thoughts too. Hell, I didn't bring this up because I didn't think it was relevant to the point I was making, but I didn't lose my virginity until I was 25. I know how difficult some of what you're going through can be, but it also doesn't excuse the spiral of hate and misogyny you've gone down, and extracting yourself from that is, like I said, ultimately your responsibility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701536672.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>I’d love women if they behaved correctly or were willing to date me. I’m not much of a misogynist really.

Anyway, tell me again how my life if perfect and I’ve never suffered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701607566.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say that. This self-pity is doing you no favours. But I'm not about to go, "aw it's okay" to someone who, in the same breath as complaining about how much they suffer and protesting that they're not a misogynist, says women only deserve love if they "behave correctly" or are willing to date you

Women are human beings who deserve respect and deserve to be treated like human beings regardless of how they act or regardless of whether they date you. Your fundamental problem is you don't see them that way right now, you see them as, fundamentally, obstacles to your happiness. Nothing is going to change for you until you shift that attitude, and being all "woe is me" here isn't going to help that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701672471.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>In real life, I’m very kind to girls and I treat them with respect. A lot of people think that girls can somehow sense my resentment, but even if they could I treat them the same as guys and do nice things for them all the time. Obviously women are human beings and I feel bad if they suffer, I’m not a monster. Did you consider that I might be a human being worthy of respect?

I’m going to try to change things for myself. Maybe if I’m in better shape I’ll feel less insecure and more confident in myself. Maybe if I try to make friends with them my mindset will change. I expect it to fail, because girls can be horribly cruel and they suck sometimes, but maybe not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701743529.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that you are kind to girls and treat them with respect, in part because *by your own admission you don't interact with them*. And you can claim you see them as human beings all you want, your OP, and many of your comments in this thread, suggest otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701783228.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>You can do nice things for people without having a conversation, which is what I meant when I say I don’t talk to them. I mean, I exchange words with girls, obviously, but that’s not what it means to have a talk with someone lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701799814.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever nice things you think you do don't erase the, frankly, disgustingly sexist and misogynist views you've expressed in this thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36701818230.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Dang I said I was willing to fix it. All you want to do is condemn me for being a big bad misogynist instead of wanting me to actually fix myself. I’ll talk to my therapist about this stuff like people said, I’ll maybe try to talk to girls in just a friendly manner, like people said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36702031202.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You said you'd fix it but then made a "joke" about being reported for "thoughtcrime." What I want is for you to take this seriously.

You also don't get a pass for the shitty things you say just because you go, "okay, I'll work on it." Take responsibility for yourself, quit blaming others here and quit wallowing in self-pity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36702201712.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>God, you’re just like the cancel culture types. If you found out my real identity, would you try to get me fired 30 years for now for my thoughtcrimes? I am working on it, there’s literally nothing else to be done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36702268052.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>See, this is exactly what I mean. You're taking harsh but fair criticism of how you've presented yourself here and finding a way to make yourself the victim of "cancel culture." Your misogynistic views are not some noble thing you're clinging to that other people are trying to get you accused of "thoughtcrime" for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36702555940.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, alright. But criticism of women is misogyny?

Listen, I can’t change overnight.

Although, I was on a call with a girl on discord right now and she called me handsome lol. So maybe they aren’t all evil. Or maybe she could sense the misogyny leaving my body?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36703615103.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Alright, alright. But criticism of women is misogyny?

It is very, very generous to call what you've said in this thread "criticism." Calling women "femoids," saying women have no value after they've had sex, calling *twenty-five-year-olds* ugly, used-up, and old, and so on and so forth.... none of that deserves to be referred to with the same word you'd use for a critique of some film you didn't like. You are a misogynist.

&amp;gt;Although, I was on a call with a girl on discord right now and she called me handsome lol. So maybe they aren’t all evil. Or maybe she could sense the misogyny leaving my body?

Just read back over what you wrote there. You're willing to grant that maybe women aren't "all evil" if and when they validate you and make you feel better about yourself. Stop making your willingness to respect or see women as human contingent on their giving you what you think you want from them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36703810989.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>All of that is very exaggerated. I never said women have no value after they have had sex, just that I would prefer a virgin partner and it makes me insecure it they aren’t. I meant that if I dated a women who’s 30, she would very likely be a non-virgin, have had tons of sex or kids, and that she would be less fertile. 25 was just a example on the younger side and it’s not like I thought about it much. it’s my personal preference to date younger girls. Also, the femoids thing is ironic, it’s a joke. I often call guys I don’t like “moids” because it sounds ridiculous. 

That second thing was just proving that maybe it’s not as bad as I though. I was happy a girl thought I was handsome, and you had to make it some evil thing. Anyway, I’m working on all this stuff, and her saying I didn’t look horrible is making me think that maybe I can escape this toxic mentality and that it’s not as bad as I thought. Maybe I can get a girlfriend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36704608432.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also, the femoids thing is ironic, it’s a joke. 

This is the last thing I'll say: don't use this excuse. You know it's not a joke. Don't hide behind "I'm just being ironic." It's very clear what you actually think about women, all of your attempts to downplay it after-the-fact notwithstanding.

It's good you're starting to feel more optimistic, but a girl calling you handsome is not going to fix what's fundamentally broken about your world view and the way you think about women. That's only going to come with serious self-work and, hopefully, the maturity that's going to naturally come with age.

ETA: The final word I'll give you is: forget your last sentence. Getting a girlfriend is not going to be the magic pill you think it is to change your thinking. Work on escaping the toxic mentality *first*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36704808954.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, thanks. Sorry for being a dumbass lol

I’ll really try to be better</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36711803455.0" user="schwenomorph" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by "behave correctly"? It sounds like you want women to be less than human subservient objects instead of their own individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36763738923.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Saying that there are certain standards people should be held to isn’t wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696896636.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well, I wouldn’t need to think this way if a girl loved me, right?

You'd still think this way. You'd get jealous over perceived actions, and think they're maybe going to cheat on you or leave you due to tiny things you overthink. 

A girl's love is never going to fix a single problem you have. It'll feel amazing when you find a girl who loves you, believe me. You'll feel great. But that love only enhances your life, it doesn't fix anything. 

And you can absolutely talk to a therapist about this. The way you're feeling isn't unique. And you're young. You're the perfect age to feel this way, and therapists are *really* good at their jobs. Odds are you aren't the first to talk to her about this stuff, and won't be the last. And maybe it'll help you to hear the perspectives of a woman on this stuff? You admit you don't talk to girls a lot, here's one you can talk to without that pressure of wondering if you could be in a relationship with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696565057.0" user="thinkingpains" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think there are no women who are quiet, have nerdy interests, and aren't very attractive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696566501.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Either that, or the women you're condemning are human beings who have to learn how to navigate the pitfalls of human relationships--just like you.

Girls eat and drink; they pee, shit, and fart--just like you.

Girls are not all the same. Some girls really do make snap judgements about people they haven't even spoken to--just like you.

But--that's only *some.* Not all. 

It sounds like you've "othered" women. It means you've stopped thinking of them as "like me" and are now thinking of them as "not like me." No wonder you can't figure out how to talk to them.

There are, probably, out the 4 billion women and girls on the planet, at least a few whom you might actually like and develop a relationship with--if you stop treating them as something other than human.

About the only thing the redpill says that has an inkling of reality in it is that intimate relationships are a numbers game. 

That means you do have to make a *social* effort to find a partner. The more social you are, the more chances that you'll meet some you like, who likes you, too.

Girls have their own unique preferences and unless you make an effort to find out what they are, you'll never know whether you're missing out on a potential romantic partner.

But don't forget, girls are human, too. They have agency, just like you. They get to decide if they like you or not, or if they want a relationship with you. 

And you get to decide, too, just like them.

My last advice is to lose the redpill terminology and mindset. It's a pretty demeaning way to view fellow humans, and that just isn't attractive at all. To anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696620348.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Your point about 4 billion women does make sense... until you consider most of those women are in China, India, Russia, ect. Like, there’s only so many girls that I have access to. Also, I don’t use the red pill terms on front of girls, accept my one friend online, and it usually is in jokes so she wouldn’t take it seriously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697018635.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that you're saying it to other people, it's that *you've* internalized the redpill message, and it affects how *you* view other people.

Even if you don't say the words out loud, we humans are *very* sophisticated at reading emotions. 

You have internalized a negative view of women, and you don't have to say a word for it to be written all over your body.

Also, my point about 4 billion women is that even if a good number of them are elsewhere, the population around *you* is bigger than it would have been even 30 years ago, never mind 200.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697046977.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t know, do you think I start like, tensing up or scowling around girls or something? I just can’t imagine it’s that obvious.

Most of the girls in my school aren’t options I think. And I don’t know where else to meet gitls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697112369.0" user="mischiffmaker" delta="False">
    <text>No, you need to do some serious reflecting on your own attitude. 

You think all women, the 4 billion women you don't even know, are rejecting you. That comes across.

Body language is a subtle thing. People will react negatively to it and sometimes not even know *why* they're uncomfortable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696490163.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They don't talk to you because you don't actually seem to be making an effort to talk to them

Of course he's not.  That would be creepy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696508873.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it creepy to try to talk to somebody?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696634516.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>You got me.  But haven't you read the internet?  If a woman wants to talk to you, she'll talk to you.  But women never want to be approached by men at any time for any reason because that's creepy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696646816.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, that's a straw man of that position. Women don't want to be randomly approached by strangers. We're talking about a kid in high school talking to other kids in high school whom he has, presumably, at least seen around a bunch.

Like there are all sorts of contexts in which introducing yourself to someone, whether the opposite sex or not, is appropriate and fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696654757.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>yeah... I dunno man.  Doubt it's worth the risk.  Once one chick in your high school labels you as creepy, you're pretty much done for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696660278.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, you're wrong, and in any case high school ends and then real life actually starts. You seem young, probably at least as young as OP, so it's not surprising you think this, but that's not how life works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696311787.0" user="PivotPsycho" delta="False">
    <text>If that's your approach they indeed won't. I can't fix that mentality for ya here mate. 

At the end of the day though, most women are mostly like most men. They are not some alien creature you can speak distantly from, or some higher life form.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696336401.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Yet if you look around at 30 year olds, you will find a ton of married people who are neither chads nor clowns. Why do you think that is? Could your idea be wrong here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696389106.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696502381.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Can poor people not get married?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696570871.0" user="thinkingpains" delta="False">
    <text>Poor people never get married, in your world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696666010.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't know how it is possible to be so ignorant. 

People are trying to help you. But if you insist on just closing your eyes and ears, I don't know what to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696504379.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; at 30 year olds, you will find a ton of married people who are neither chads nor clowns. Why do you think that is?

Because women start to value guys who are safe, have good earnings potential and will be a good provider for her and her children at that age.  They're no longer actually looking for a guy who excites them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696674044.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're no longer actually looking for a guy who excites them.

Do you think that they are just lying to all of their friends and family when they speak about their spouses? What of the men I know who make less money than their wives?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696814545.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>There's obviously exceptions, so you might find a few, but we're talking general trends here.

&amp;gt; Do you think that they are just lying to all of their friends and family when they speak about their spouses?
 
If they're saying that they're excited by their spouse, yes.  If they're saying that they're really "comfortable" with their spouse and that he's a "good man" and a "good father" and "takes care of us", then no, they're not lying.  They're explaining why they're with him.

&amp;gt; What of the men I know who make less money than their wives?

Could be a lot of things.  One of the few exceptions; a miscalculation of his future earnings potential; settling for what she could get (better to have a man contribution $40,000 than contributing nothing).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696913809.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's obviously exceptions, so you might find a few, but we're talking general trends here.

I don't know a *single* couple who'd follow the pattern you describe among my friends. These are exceptions, they are norm.

&amp;gt; If they're saying that they're excited by their spouse, yes. 

You are unbelievable. What can I do if you just tell me that everything I've ever heard from people I trust are just lies, despite their stated claims being 100% consistent with their actions? These people are just fucking harpies because you say so?

See, misogyny straight from your posts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696942963.0" user="AskWhyKnot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What can I do if you just tell me that everything I've ever heard from people I trust are just lies,

Wait a minute, are you a dude or a chick?  If you're a dude and talking to your friend's wives, then, yes, they are 100% lying to you just like they're lying to their spouse.  If you're a chick and your girlfriends are telling you their spouse excites them, I dunno.  Maybe they're lying to themselves, maybe they don't want you to know they settled, maybe they're an exception.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
