<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36698686126.0" user="thethoughtexperiment" delta="False">
    <text>1. From your post, it seems like you have taken on a lot of the incel talking points as facts.

Going to incel sites for insights about dating is a bit like asking people who are unemployed for advice on how to get a job.

If you're spending time reading incel subs and chatting with incels, seriously ask yourself if those are the people you want to become. And if not, consider staying as far away from those sites as possible. A lot of guys find that their lives get *much* better after getting off such sites.

Check out: [r/menslib](https://redditcommentsearch.com/r/menslib), [r/bropill](https://redditcommentsearch.com/r/bropill), [r/HumansBeingBros](https://redditcommentsearch.com/r/HumansBeingBros), [https://www.reddit.com/r/IncelExit/top/?t=all](https://www.reddit.com/r/IncelExit/top/?t=all)

... for more positive communities, with more positive and inclusive views of masculinity.

Be careful what you are feeding your brain.

It's like that Chinese proverb says:

“You cannot prevent the birds of sadness from passing over your head, but you can prevent their making a nest in your hair.”

Rather than reading stuff about how you can build a better nest for your sadness, ***replace them*** with sites that are built around positive things.

2) More broadly, in terms of building a functional understanding of relationships, this brief (and funny) article is also helpful.

It's been read by over 25 million people, and is the best article I've ever seen for helping people who struggle with relationships change the way they think about them, and start to see positive changes to their lives as a result:

[https://www.cracked.com/blog/6-harsh-truths-that-will-make-you-better-person/](https://www.cracked.com/blog/6-harsh-truths-that-will-make-you-better-person/)

3) Consider that the reason most guys are able to date successfully is because they have typically practiced their IRL social skills and continue to keep using and developing them. Usually, this is done through having *at least* a moderate amount of regular social interactions weekly, making friends, paying attention to and accurately understanding people's responses to their behavior, learning to listen effectively to others, and learning from the feedback of how other people react to their behaviors to hone their communication skills.

Friendships are the "easy" mode of relationships. If someone can't effectively make friends IRL, then there is a very good chance that they are going to struggle *a lot* in forming closer relationships that require more advanced interpersonal skills.

Not having IRL friends can also make a person *very* lonely, and overly focused on romantic relationships that they aren't actually ready for.

So, if you struggle with social skills / making friends in real life, consider that it makes *perfect sense* that you're going to run into problems trying to have romantic relationships.

But also, keep in mind that *no one* is born with fully developed social skills. They must be learned. That is why if you grow up in one culture, you may have trouble adapting to social life in another culture - because you have to change the way you behave in order to operate effectively in a different social environment.

For most people, it takes spending *a significant amount* of interacting with other people in real life, and paying a lot of attention to learn how to operate reasonably well in social situations.

Some people just haven't yet put in the time and effort to learn them yet.

For some useful info on social skill development, check out:

[https://www.cracked.com/blog/15-things-socially-awkward-people-need-to-know/](https://www.cracked.com/blog/15-things-socially-awkward-people-need-to-know/)

Important to also note here that basic social skills are not the "success code" for dating anyone on earth - rather, they are a key ingredient that is usually necessary (but not sufficient on its own) for being able to function reasonably well in a social situation (friendships, relationships, among coworkers, etc.).

***They are the floor that more advanced social interactions are built on.***

It takes time and practice for everyone to learn, and the reason the vast majority of people invest the time and practice into developing their social skills is because it's worth it.

So, if you haven't made new friends in a while / don't have a good IRL friend group yet, put even thinking about romantic relationships out of your mind for now. Making new friends can help you refresh your social skills, help build your self confidence, and give you the practice to establish those more basic skills you need.

Reaching out to make **new** friends is also a great way to learn about what qualities the people who click with you tend to have. And once you know what those qualities are, you can start to have a better idea for who you might be a good match with for a relationship.

This [large study](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6743509/) of hundreds of thousands of people's actual online dating behavior across 4 countries finds that individuals tend to gravitate toward partners who are similar to them. This tendency to match with similar partners is shown in the realms of appearance, income, education, personality, relationship preference, religious preferences, height, and essentially all attributes they investigated. So, to match with someone, your best bet is to look for someone who is similar to you in personality, attractiveness, education, height, income, religious preference, education, etc. Having an accurate sense of your own qualities, and being able to accurately detect those of others is extremely helpful for finding matches.

4)  A person's thinking style can have a **massive** impact on their happiness, self-esteem, and ability to form relationships.

Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (a type of therapy that helps people change their thinking style) has been shown to have a significant positive effect on a person's self esteem. \[[source](https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797611417725)\] It's also extremely effective for social anxiety. \[[source](https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2015/10/what-is-social-anxiety/411556/)\] And, it has been found to help lonely people, because they often have a counter productive thinking style that gets in the way of their happiness and ability to form relationships. Namely, researchers have found that:

"programs that focused on maladaptive social cognition through cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) appeared somewhat successful in reducing loneliness ([Young, 1982](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3865701/#R171)). The cornerstone of this intervention was to teach lonely individuals to identify automatic negative thoughts and regard them as hypotheses to be tested rather than facts." \[[source](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3865701/)\]

Therapy has been life changing (and sometimes even life saving) for *millions* of people.

Tl;DR: Some of the work involves changing what you are feeding your brain, including what you're telling yourself so that you can establish a healthy sense of self-esteem. From there, there are ways to improve someone's chances of social success - per the links above, it involves spending more time on IRL social activities (practice, practice, practice - social activities weekly), making new friends to practice your social skills, being the kind of person who creates value for others, and learning who you are a match with. Therapy can also be a game changer. Seriously, having a therapist is like having a coach who helps you build the skills you need to succeed at life.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
