<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1378810771.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/mswp77/cmv_im_a_bit_of_an_incel_who_thinks_women_are/">
    <title>CMV: I’m a bit of an incel who thinks women are shallow and only care about looks.</title>
    <original_poster>ITSINCElTIME</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I saw that there was a post about an incel that hit pretty big, so if you guys are willing to actually talk to us, I think that’s cool. I read that post, and I came out hating that guy. He seemed like a dick, only caring about sex and treating women like objects, while I actually really want to have a loving and caring relationship with a girl. I value cuddling more than sex, to put it plainly. In fact, I don’t really care about sex that much, unless my hypothetical gf wants it herself. 

Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me. Something that really bothers me is that women take for granted so many things. So many women find it normal to have multiple guys perusing them, and complain when they don’t perfectly match their standards. Of course, I don’t blame them for that at all, after all, I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage, so there’s nothing wrong with women rejecting a guy. However, I just hate how they are so rude and label guys as creeps for just having genuine feelings. If a girl confessed her feelings to me, even if I didn’t give a shit about her, I would really appreciate it and be incredibly flattered. 

Something I also hate is the hypocrisy of women. And there’s a lot of it. One of the greatest is how they condemn misogyny and abuse, yet always go after men who are abusive and sexist. Every fucking time, like clockwork. So many damn women have a story of their abusive ex boyfriend, which I don’t blame them for, but if they are so willing to date guys like that, why am I single? Why are assholes so successful, when literally all I’ve ever wanted is to love and cherish a girl? So many girls say how much they hate things that guys do, such as ignoring them or acting unfaithfully... so why don’t you just date me? I’ve always been kind and respectful to everyone my whole life, including women, and it goes unnoticed completely. I don’t expect to be rewarded for kindness, but it just hurts when people who are rude and disrespectful are rewarded more. Either women actually do like abusive and misogynistic men and are lying, are willing to excuse those traits if the man is attractive, or are just really bad at detecting red flags. All seem likely and none are very nice. 

Also, it bothers me that so many women are not virgins. Like, I’m 17, and I’ll be 18 relatively soon. Are there any virgin girls my age left? I know sex your first time supposedly sucks, but I want my first time to also be her first time, and for us both to be teenagers. I’ve fantasized about that a lot. Probably won’t happen though.

Also, I’ll get some arguments out of the way here:
-Why a women want to date you if you are a incel??
Ive never told anyone about my thoughts in real life. Just on this anonymous throwaway account on reddit. And no, they can’t sniff my inceldom. I’m very kind to women irl, if I even talk to them at all.
-Why don’t you just take a shower and go to the gym?
I have good hygiene and while I’m not in perfect shape, I’ve started going to the gym with a friend. Surprisingly enough, we aren’t all neckbeard caricatures.

I could probably say more, but that’s most of it. If I think of more I’ll add it later. Can you guys change my mind? I realize that women can’t read my mind to tell I’m an incel, but maybe they would like me more if I wasn’t. Just maybe. Don’t want to be a white Knight or anything.

EDIT: Forgot to mention this: Most girls are boring. I could never date a girl who doesn’t share my interests, or isn’t at the very least willing to try out the things I like. I mean, what do most girls like nowadays? Tiktok? Painting there fingernails? Idk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36696273775.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think maybe that this:

&amp;gt;Anyway, one of my biggest problems with the world, obviously, is that women won’t date me.

Might be due to attitudes like this:

&amp;gt;I’ll be the first to admit that most modern women are fucking garbage</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696279611.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Women aren’t psychic. They have no idea I think that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696309686.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>You would be surprised how deeply held resentment can come out through your interactions, even if you don't intend it.  Women tend to be more socially adept so they can often pick up on your thinly veiled contempt or your sense of entitlement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696385742.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>I guarantee you aren’t as good at hiding it as you think you are</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697208189.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Another case of the psychic women. I need to start wearing a tinfoil hat or something to protect me from your mind penetrating abilities</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697356338.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>It has nothing to do with psychic abilities and everything to do with the fact that people in general are terrible at disguising contempt. I highly doubt that as a 17 year old with no training who’s admitted not great at social interactions with women you’ve got it mastered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697384002.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>Alright. Then how do I stop showing it? Or even better, get rid of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697483465.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>Stop viewing women as a monolith. People have unique personalities some women suck, some men suck, some women are great, some men are great. Talk to women like they’re just people not potential girlfriends or idiots who only like Tiktok and nail polish. Having boobs really doesn’t actually dictate ones personality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697523112.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Having boobs doesn’t dictate someone’s personality

Except for the hormones and different brain structure they have.

That aside, I don’t view them as a monolith. There are good ones, I know that. I want to talk to them so bad but it’s scary and I know I’m not good at it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36697616295.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>Brain structures are trends it’s not like men all have the same brain structure and women all have the same but different structure. Everyone has a different brain structure with certain patterns that are common to men or women. 

&amp;gt; I want to talk to them so bad but it’s scary and I know I’m not good at it.

So maybe the first step is to not blame women for you not being good at something? It’s okay to not be good at it, it takes practice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698262323.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not okay to be bad, because they will think you’re a weirdo or creep if you mess up. Or even worse, you’ll get called a sexual harasser. I’ve hears of autistic guys getting arrested just because they were bad at talking to girls. As someone on the spectrum that scares me a bit even if I’m not *that* bad at social interaction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698262723.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not okay to be bad, because they will think you’re a weirdo or creep if you mess up. Or even worse, you’ll get called a sexual harasser. I’ve hears of autistic guys getting arrested just because they were bad at talking to girls. As someone on the spectrum that scares me a bit even if I’m not *that* bad at social interaction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698264058.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not okay to be bad, because they will think you’re a weirdo or creep if you mess up. Or even worse, you’ll get called a sexual harasser. I’ve hears of autistic guys getting arrested just because they were bad at talking to girls. As someone on the spectrum that scares me a bit even if I’m not *that* bad at social interaction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36698264523.0" user="ITSINCElTIME" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not okay to be bad, because they will think you’re a weirdo or creep if you mess up. Or even worse, you’ll get called a sexual harasser. I’ve hears of autistic guys getting arrested just because they were bad at talking to girls. As someone on the spectrum that scares me a bit even if I’m not *that* bad at social interaction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36709391949.0" user="Glittering_knave" delta="False">
    <text>1. Assume that everyone is a decent person until they show you otherwise. Stop forcing women to earn the right to be treated as a human being.
2. Not being sexually attracted to you is not personality flaw that shows that women are bad people.
3. Don't treat men and women differently, at  least upon initial meeting.  Get to know women as people not just sex objects. 
4. Figure out things that you want to share with friends, and talk to women about that.  If D&amp;amp;D is really important to you, find people that like D&amp;amp;D.  If you are finding it hard to talk to woman, it's may be because you are talking to the wrong women.  How are you picking the ones that you approach?  Having a common interest will really, really, help.
5. Learn about consent. People that get arrested and called creeps cross a tonne of boundaries.  If someone asks you to stop something, you need to stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36696523099.0" user="Tellsyouajoke" delta="False">
    <text>Your responses here show you’re probably not good at hiding that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36709310468.0" user="Glittering_knave" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, yes they do.  Women can't read your mind, but they sure as heck can judge your actions.  I you think that modern women are fucking garbage, I am going to go out on a limb and say that you treat women worse than you think you do.  If you demand that all females earn your respect before you treat them like human beings, they are going to avoid you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
