<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1404281738.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/n82mq2/cmv_in_order_to_better_achieve_success_in_future/">
    <title>CMV: In order to better achieve success in future elections, Democrats need to immediately adopt a hyperaggressive, anti-Republican fearmongering everyman stance, even if this comes at the cost of integrity.</title>
    <original_poster>KingTyranitar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Repeatedly, Democrats have been notorious for trying to high road or extend olive branches to Republicans in vain when they could be passing meaningful legislation instead. McConnell recently said that the Republican Party's goal at the moment is 100% curtailing any Democratic legislation.

It has been noted often that even conservative voters generally want conceptually liberal policies (stimulus checks, a stronger police force...all things that involve a stronger government) and shun programs and legislation that would directly benefit them. Why? Because they're presented as **liberal**.

The Republicans have shown that they aren't above breaking their own logic (appointing RBG) and that they are willing to resort to fascist tactics to try to illegally subvert democracy.

And the worst part? It's **working.** The majority of Republicans believe that the 2020 Election was illegitimate despite there being no evidence. Voter suppression is being successfully locked in all over the country, and their conservative constituents cheer them on, even when they directly oppose their own interests (voting against the stimulus). Why? It's all about branding.

We need to recognize that the majority of America simply isn't as intellectually sophisticated as we like, and we need to capitalize on it. Donald Trump rose to the very top of the Republican Party by crude, straightforward rhetoric, and its time for the Democrats to do the same.


Democrats need to start saying it *exactly* like it is. It is clear that people find direct linguistics refreshing, and this is what I believed hurt Hillary in 2016. Ideally, every high ranking Democratic politician should be at the very least as hostile as AOC.

They need to start calling Republicans out on their shit and keep bringing it up, over and over again until it *sticks*, because voters have the memory of a goldfish. Dems should be screaming from the rooftops that Ted Cruz is a spineless loser who is a bootlicker for the man who insulted his wife, and they should only address him as "Cancun Cruz" henceforth. 
They need to come up with logic on how Republicans have 'communist behavior' - **even if it isn't true** - and constantly stick them with it, differentiating socialism from communism. Call them bear-hugging commies and point to their various dealings with Russia. Propagate that they are essentially Russian sleeper agents wanting to destroy America with communism and their lies on the 2020 Election is "Phase 1". See what I'm doing here? I'm literally just rambling about made up cultist shit but I know that it will spiral out of control and appeal to conservative voters.

Note every single Republican who voted against certifying the election and immediately paint them as Russian communists. You see how the right uses China as a scapegoat? We need to be doing that with Russia, but like times ten. Paint Putin as a puppetteer of sorts and do it *constantly*, *over and over again until it sticks*.
See how Kevin McCarthy is dragging his feet on denouncing Gaetz? Immediately jump to the conclusion that McCarthy is in kahoots with Gaetz and that there is a pedophile ring within the GOP. The Republicans have done the same to the Democrats. Bring to light Trump's accusations of child sexual assault and link that to Gaetz and McCarthy. Hell, make shit up if you have to, but nail down the image that the Republicans are pedophiles.

This can go on and on. We can hammer down that every single Trump voter is anti-democratic. We can start making fun of Trump's weight, we can call him a fat, old man constantly on the brink of a heart attack because hes busy stuffing Big Macs and Diet Cokes into his mouth. We can nail Ron Johnson as a communist sleeper agent for his dealings with Russia. We can nail Ron DeSantis as an authoritarian Nazi for sending a SWAT team to that whistle-blower. Call him a racist and make up shit for that if you have to. Say that he'll never truly be Trump and that he's a sad, pathetic Shadow who will never reach Trump's level.

If we want to go far enough we can even feminize Lindsay Graham, note that he's single and has a girls name. 

Say that the GOP hates the police and make up rationale for it. Make it stick. Claim that they're infiltrating police unions and trying to demonize police officers. Publicly disavow ACAB and Defund the police and paint the police themselves as victims who have been infiltrated by Republican Threat Actors.
Of course none of this is true. In fact, it's slander. **That's the point.** Republicans have been doing this for *years* and its done nothing but cause extreme success for themselves. To be honest, so have the Democrats at a lesser level. It's time to step it up. We need stronger, younger personalities with cults of personality. For example, The Rock is clearly trying to setup a run for office, give the dude a few years in political experience to give him the qualifications.
 People like shows of strongmanship, aggressiveness, and character assassination. It's time to give the people what they want.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36851043636.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>They haven’t already? The majority of Democrats believe that Russians changed votes in the 2016 election. A majority of liberal/very liberal individuals believe that thousands of unarmed black people are killed by the police and that you have a 50 percent chance of ending up in the hospital if you get covid. Misinformation goes both ways.

https://today.yougov.com/topics/politics/articles-reports/2018/03/09/russias-impact-election-seen-through-partisan-eyes

https://www.skeptic.com/research-center/reports/Research-Report-CUPES-007.pdf

https://www.brookings.edu/research/how-misinformation-is-distorting-covid-policies-and-behaviors/

Also - where’s your evidence of voter suppression? Was it shown in the voter turnout in 2020?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
