<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1404281738.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/n82mq2/cmv_in_order_to_better_achieve_success_in_future/">
    <title>CMV: In order to better achieve success in future elections, Democrats need to immediately adopt a hyperaggressive, anti-Republican fearmongering everyman stance, even if this comes at the cost of integrity.</title>
    <original_poster>KingTyranitar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Repeatedly, Democrats have been notorious for trying to high road or extend olive branches to Republicans in vain when they could be passing meaningful legislation instead. McConnell recently said that the Republican Party's goal at the moment is 100% curtailing any Democratic legislation.

It has been noted often that even conservative voters generally want conceptually liberal policies (stimulus checks, a stronger police force...all things that involve a stronger government) and shun programs and legislation that would directly benefit them. Why? Because they're presented as **liberal**.

The Republicans have shown that they aren't above breaking their own logic (appointing RBG) and that they are willing to resort to fascist tactics to try to illegally subvert democracy.

And the worst part? It's **working.** The majority of Republicans believe that the 2020 Election was illegitimate despite there being no evidence. Voter suppression is being successfully locked in all over the country, and their conservative constituents cheer them on, even when they directly oppose their own interests (voting against the stimulus). Why? It's all about branding.

We need to recognize that the majority of America simply isn't as intellectually sophisticated as we like, and we need to capitalize on it. Donald Trump rose to the very top of the Republican Party by crude, straightforward rhetoric, and its time for the Democrats to do the same.


Democrats need to start saying it *exactly* like it is. It is clear that people find direct linguistics refreshing, and this is what I believed hurt Hillary in 2016. Ideally, every high ranking Democratic politician should be at the very least as hostile as AOC.

They need to start calling Republicans out on their shit and keep bringing it up, over and over again until it *sticks*, because voters have the memory of a goldfish. Dems should be screaming from the rooftops that Ted Cruz is a spineless loser who is a bootlicker for the man who insulted his wife, and they should only address him as "Cancun Cruz" henceforth. 
They need to come up with logic on how Republicans have 'communist behavior' - **even if it isn't true** - and constantly stick them with it, differentiating socialism from communism. Call them bear-hugging commies and point to their various dealings with Russia. Propagate that they are essentially Russian sleeper agents wanting to destroy America with communism and their lies on the 2020 Election is "Phase 1". See what I'm doing here? I'm literally just rambling about made up cultist shit but I know that it will spiral out of control and appeal to conservative voters.

Note every single Republican who voted against certifying the election and immediately paint them as Russian communists. You see how the right uses China as a scapegoat? We need to be doing that with Russia, but like times ten. Paint Putin as a puppetteer of sorts and do it *constantly*, *over and over again until it sticks*.
See how Kevin McCarthy is dragging his feet on denouncing Gaetz? Immediately jump to the conclusion that McCarthy is in kahoots with Gaetz and that there is a pedophile ring within the GOP. The Republicans have done the same to the Democrats. Bring to light Trump's accusations of child sexual assault and link that to Gaetz and McCarthy. Hell, make shit up if you have to, but nail down the image that the Republicans are pedophiles.

This can go on and on. We can hammer down that every single Trump voter is anti-democratic. We can start making fun of Trump's weight, we can call him a fat, old man constantly on the brink of a heart attack because hes busy stuffing Big Macs and Diet Cokes into his mouth. We can nail Ron Johnson as a communist sleeper agent for his dealings with Russia. We can nail Ron DeSantis as an authoritarian Nazi for sending a SWAT team to that whistle-blower. Call him a racist and make up shit for that if you have to. Say that he'll never truly be Trump and that he's a sad, pathetic Shadow who will never reach Trump's level.

If we want to go far enough we can even feminize Lindsay Graham, note that he's single and has a girls name. 

Say that the GOP hates the police and make up rationale for it. Make it stick. Claim that they're infiltrating police unions and trying to demonize police officers. Publicly disavow ACAB and Defund the police and paint the police themselves as victims who have been infiltrated by Republican Threat Actors.
Of course none of this is true. In fact, it's slander. **That's the point.** Republicans have been doing this for *years* and its done nothing but cause extreme success for themselves. To be honest, so have the Democrats at a lesser level. It's time to step it up. We need stronger, younger personalities with cults of personality. For example, The Rock is clearly trying to setup a run for office, give the dude a few years in political experience to give him the qualifications.
 People like shows of strongmanship, aggressiveness, and character assassination. It's time to give the people what they want.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36851121218.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Repeatedly, Democrats have been notorious for trying to high road or extend olive branches to Republicans in vain

Uh...when?  Exactly?  Near as I can tell, this is a point proffered by the hard left to criticize Democrats who don't do hard left things, but I'm not aware of this outreach that's occurred.  I do know that multiple compromise bills from Republicans have essentially been ignored from the outset of the Biden presidency.

&amp;gt;when they could be passing meaningful legislation instead. 

I mean...they can't.  They don't have the votes.  For all the complaining about the filibuster, nothing's been filibustered because Democrats have struggled to get 50 votes, much less 60.

So in sum: they're not passing legislation because they didn't win enough seats.  This is a dead end alley.

&amp;gt;The majority of Republicans believe that the 2020 Election was illegitimate despite there being no evidence.

What might've made change this?  Certainly the Republican party has a lot of the blame, but the media has also thoroughly lost the trust of much of the public.  Technocratic experts - the kind who said COVID lockdowns were absolutely necessary unless you were a BLM protester - have lost credibility as well.

They believe as they do because trust itself has been cleaved in this country.  They believe a falsehood primarily because they have lost all trust in those who would tell them it's a lie.

&amp;gt;We need to recognize that the majority of America simply isn't as intellectually sophisticated as we like,

Setting aside the reeking condescension...that's what a person says to justify knowingly, willfully lying.  You're saying Democrats should lie.  Not that they already don't but...why would you encourage them to do so?

Building trust by lying is certainly a novel strategy.

&amp;gt;They need to start calling Republicans out on their shit and keep bringing it up,

...were they not?

&amp;gt;because voters have the memory of a goldfish.

Has it occurred to you that if this kind of contempt for voters is common among Democrats, it might actually be *detected?*

&amp;gt;they should only address him as "Cancun Cruz" henceforth.

That totally kept Donald Drumpf out of office.

&amp;gt;They need to come up with logic on how Republicans have 'communist behavior' - even if it isn't true - and constantly stick them with it, differentiating socialism from communism. Call them bear-hugging commies and point to their various dealings with Russia. Propagate that they are essentially Russian sleeper agents wanting to destroy America with communism and their lies on the 2020 Election is "Phase 1". See what I'm doing here? I'm literally just rambling about made up cultist shit but I know that it will spiral out of control and appeal to conservative voters.

Yeah...that just sounds like really clumsy and pathetic lying.

&amp;gt;See how Kevin McCarthy is dragging his feet on denouncing Gaetz? Immediately jump to the conclusion that McCarthy is in kahoots with Gaetz and that there is a pedophile ring within the GOP.

Has it occurred to you that, if this would work, Democrats would already be trying it?  Maybe they know something you don't.

&amp;gt;We can start making fun of Trump's weight, we can call him a fat, old man constantly on the brink of a heart attack because hes busy stuffing Big Macs and Diet Cokes into his mouth

Yeah...you already did that.

&amp;gt;Call him a racist and make up shit for that if you have to. 

Again with the open, shameless lying.

&amp;gt;If we want to go far enough we can even feminize Lindsay Graham, note that he's single and has a girls name.

Gotta love it when an artist finds a way to make a symphony of sexism and homophobia.  Behold the progressive!

&amp;gt;Say that the GOP hates the police and make up rationale for it. Make it stick. 

You can't make it stick.

&amp;gt;Publicly disavow ACAB and Defund the police and paint the police themselves as victims who have been infiltrated by Republican Threat Actors.

Or we could just blame leprechauns and unicorns.

===================================

All told, your advice for the Democratic Party is astoundingly bad.  It's dishonest, bigoted and holds voters in hateful contempt.  More importantly, it's strategically nonsensical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36851168974.0" user="KingTyranitar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All told, your advice for the Democratic Party is astoundingly bad. It's dishonest, bigoted and holds voters in hateful contempt. More importantly, it's strategically nonsensical.

That's the point. Voters clearly are receptive to such ridiculous rhetoric. The vast majority of Republicans believe that the 2020 election was stolen despite Trump-appointed judges and a conservative Supreme Court unanimously shunning their cases and the head of the country's cybersecurity saying that this was the most secure election in U.S. history. 
A minority genuinely believes that there is a ring of satanic pedophiles within the Democratic party. A small minority, but one large enough to have Donald Trump dogwhistle it a few times and have a few QAnon politicians get to office.

Millions genuinely believe that climate change isn't real, that BLM is a Marxist terrorist organization engaging in fraud, that racism ended the day Obama was elected President, that Biden is being controlled by Kamala Harris. If trying to be logical will not work, I don't see why being deliberately illogical with the goal of stoking fear won't, especially considering that worse case scenario, you're back at square 1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36851209141.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>So...none of that actually explained anything.  It was just a rant.

1) You're assuming you've actually tried to be logical.  From a certain point of view, your failure to convince would be proof that you hadn't.

2) You're assuming any of the cockamamie lies you've thought up would stick, and they wouldn't.

3) By openly embracing deliberate deception, you conclusively prove that you are not the lesser of two evils.  If the mean voter has, if not your expansive intelligence, at least a strong animal instinct for honesty...they might detect this and judge you as untrustworthy as the lying suggests you are.  That would be counterproductive for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36851398335.0" user="Lack_of_godmode" delta="False">
    <text>This whole thing reads like a grift to me. I believe that a certain portion of the population holds genuine contempt for Republicans but I refuse to believe someone could really come to the conclusion that the best way to win an election is to deliberately lie and make fun of at minimum like 25% of the population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36851223715.0" user="ZorgZeFrenchGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn’t the only thing you’d be doing is justifying that second conservative argument?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
