<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36874006686.0" user="IamB_E_A_N" delta="False">
    <text>Attraction is about more than just size.

As a few others have pointed out, it's about confidence first and foremost. If you're feeling inferior, chances are you'll come across as inferior when talking to women, and who wants to have sex with someone sub-par?

Secondly, despite what women may tell you, many still crave hot bods, especially those not looking for steady relationships but for fulfilling sex. If you buff up, i.e. change your nutrition and hit the gym or regularly train with weights, you're going to be much more attractive to women in around six months.

So I think yes, average men can have a very good chance for sex with women if they put in some effort.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
