<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36871997102.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Im 5"11. My eyes aren't even and I don't keep my hair very neat. My teeth are crooked. I've been told I have nice smile dimples by some. At best I'm like a little bit above average. Seriously compared to what's out there I'm an 8 at fucking BEST more like a 6 or a 7. I have had over 30 sexual partners. 

Your "averageness" doesn't matter. What matters is hygeine, and projection. I don't keep my hair very neat but the rest of me I do. Most nights I met women who became attracted to me I had dressed up a little. I also meet women in places where I project confidence and fun, namely karaoke bars. Practice has made me a decent singer. I have fun with it and I share that with everyone around me. If I feel like I did well I put the mic down with a huge genuine smile on my face. I can confidently say like half the women Ive slept with would have hardly noticed me had they not heard me sing. My averageness would have gone unnoticed had I never learned to sing. 

So focus on hygiene and finding a place or activity where you truly come alive as a genuinely fun and confident person. Find something you enjoy and are good at that is simple fun. You will meet people who come to the same places and like the same things. You will make friends and people (girls) will like you. Depending on exactly where you are and what you are doing you can make friends, pursue meaningful relationships or casual sex 🤷‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
