<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36873604848.0" user="Archi_balding" delta="False">
    <text>The vast amjority of people tend to find a partner at some point in their life so no, average men pretty much have really good chances to have sex with women. Some people have more chances than other but the average chance is still really high.

Then little piece of advice : thinking this low of yourself will only lay two things : first you'll be visibly uncomfortable around people which is a turn off. Then you'll get in a "why bother trying" mindset which will abolutely reduce your chances with women because... you'll just meet less people overall. 

If 1 person in 500 (really really pessimistic take) will be attracted to you then the goal is to meet 1000 people. And you won't be doing that by sulking in your corner. Get to know people and don't see them as pieces of meat and you should have no problem finding someone. No secret for that, go out, practice a social hobby, dating apps...

Finally you need to understand that penis size... doesn't matter except for extreme cases. When someone is close enough to have a good guess about it chances are that the situation is already terminally headed toward sex except if its an urologist (and you probably shouldn't try to hit on your urologist). No ammount of small PP will derail the direction of that kind of situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
