<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36871747846.0" user="ThirteenOnline" delta="False">
    <text>Okay first, the average man has an average chance with the average heterosexual woman.

Second, the vagina has a limited depth, at some point the size doesn't matter. It really is about how you use it. If you're good at basketball it doesn't matter if you're playing in your drive way with an old ball or in a state of the art gym. If you're good at the game you're good at the game. And that comes with experience, asking your partners what they like, learning what you like, learning how to communicate your wants and needs and executing.

Third, if a girl wanted to have sex with you, you like her, you're interested in her, you get home and she gets naked. And she had on a push up bra and her breasts are smaller than you thought. Or she has a scar. Or she has a unique birthmark. Would you cancel having sex with her? Probably not, because you aren't having sex with a vagina, you're having sex with a person. And you like that person not just their parts. If someone decides they want to have sex with you, it's you not your penis they are having sex with. So if you are attentive, loving, communicative, and are willing to do more than just vaginal penetration like you can go very far.

Four, if you look at porn MANY of those guys are average looking, or skinny, or fat. There's porn with ugly guys, obese guys, micropenis guys, trans men with vaginas, old guys, like every type of guy imaginable. This should tell you that it's not random luck, there is someone out there willing to have sex with any type of guy. You just need to find those specific people that are pickign up what you're putting down. There are women that hate big penises. There are women that like older guys, fat guys, shlubby guys. And I mean beautiful sexy hot women. But you have to be willing to put yourself out there.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
