<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36871718378.0" user="CrimsonAvenger35" delta="False">
    <text>At 19 and a virgin, you shouldn't have views about sex or relationships that need changing. You need to spend some time learning to be comfortable with yourself, and then try dating without the intention being purely to have sex. But most importantly STOP COMPARING YOURSELF TO OTHER PEOPLE. I'm assuming that aside from most of your other posts, that the reason for your insecurity is from watching porn. You have weirdly unreal expectations of what a sexual relationship is, when you should be focused on just the relationship part. You shouldn't be worrying if you'll ever have sex, you should be worrying about how you would keep your partner happy aside from sex</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871947738.0" user="fitness35754745" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for your comment. I 100 percent dont want to start dating if all I want is sex. It's just that I hear this people do these fun things and I compare and feel inferior. Do you have any advice on not comparing yourself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36872792556.0" user="MardocAgain" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP, but what I would tell you is that worrying about things you can’t control is a recipe for endless anxiety. You can’t change other people, you can’t change your height, you can’t change your penis size. If you Fee inferior in you looks you can change your fitness level or how you dress. You can look to others for inspiration on body types to strive for or fashion styles,  but the end comparison should be what you are against what you expect of yourself.

Your post reeks of the insecurity and I’d be very confident guessing that comes through in your social interactions. When you leave to feel happy with yourself and your life then others will want to be a part of that whether it’s friends or relationships. I promise you the metrics you are using are not barriers to romance. Women do not evaluate men the same way most men do women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36875982998.0" user="CrimsonAvenger35" delta="False">
    <text>I said before to get comfortable with yourself before anything else. What that means is up to you. Maybe you need to just accept things about yourself as the way they are. Maybe you need to make changes to the things you can change until you're happy with yourself. Both of those things can be right or wrong in practice though, so I would say to make sure that whatever you do, you do it for yourself. Once you're happy with the person that you are, you can start to think about the kind of partner that would complement you.

In terms of not comparing yourself to others, I would first say to stop watching porn. Once you start having sex, I think you might find most porn almost laughably inaccurate. It's like wanting to be a hit man, and using John Wick as a reference point. 

Secondly, definitely don't take the experiences of others as things you're missing out on. I would say that for someone in your situation, talking to others about their sexual exploits is harmful to you because you don't have a frame of mind for a healthy sexual relationship with a partner.

As you try to work on being your best version of you, confidence will come in time. When you're happy with yourself, you will feel and exude confidence. In the meantime, don't be afraid to date, just try not to have high expectations of it working out or of having sex. Very few people stay with their first partner, the reason is that being in the relationship teaches you about yourself and what you want. Often you can make that work with your partner, but sometimes relationships are just stepping stones to finding the right person. I'm sure if you go in with that mentality, losing your virginity and dating will just feel like a progression of learning, instead of the endgoal</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
