<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1408003409.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/naaedt/cmv_average_men_do_not_have_a_good_chance_of/">
    <title>CMV: Average men do not have a good chance of having sex with women.</title>
    <original_poster>fitness35754745</original_poster>
    <original_post>My lady friends husband has had a threesome before and they are looking into being able to do it again.

This guy is 6 foot 3.

For me I'm only average sized. 5 foot 9 which an average penis of 5.5 inches length and 4.8 inches girth. My looks are also average only too I would say. However I would say my personality is good towards friends, I've managed to get my lady friend to open up to me about talking about her sexual experiences so I must be doing something right. (No flirting just friends talking, I'm lucky to have a friend like her)

I'm super insecure about this and this has kept me from sleeping. I'm not exsactly worried about having threesomes or often sex, I just feel quite inferior for not.

Do average guys really have a chance with this type of thing? I cant help but feel this guys height (and possible above average penis size) is making women consider sleeping with him more. Do I have atleast a good chance? I believe I dont and that I'm at a very big disadvantage. 

I know from fair studies that the preferred penis size is bigger than average and I'm sure the preferred height for a man is above average too. I'm more worried about penis size because well, it can change the plessure the women recieves no matter good or bad.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36871675707.0" user="roodonog22" delta="False">
    <text>Its literally all about confidence. Nobody actually cares about height or anything like that, if you're confident in your personality and looks, women will be much more attracted to that.

Edit: 

To your point that average men do not have a chance with women; that is not true, average men are very popular with women IF the man is confident.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871710591.0" user="Dingo_Jiu_Jitsu" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with this. I feel this guy has watched too much porn and has filled his head with expectations. 
If you can make a girl laugh and smile your half way there already. Confidence is key and having unrealistic expectations and assumptions will only weaken you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871763317.0" user="fitness35754745" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe that's what has been happening. I think what's screwing my head even more is I've heard the preference is a little bit above average. I dont mind based in looks, no one will see my penis unless we are already in bed. It's just that I've got no idea how much of an actual difference in plays in the plessure department?

Edit: I know r/femaledaitingstrategy is a super sexist subreddit but alot of the women their mention how if the penis isnt above average they dont want anything to do with them. That's also messing me up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871775047.0" user="roodonog22" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't matter as long as you communicate with your partner about preferences. Making sure that both of you are enjoying it and size doesn't always equal pleasure. Its not about the size of the boat but the motion of the ocean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871811656.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>Men taking what's said on r/femaledatingstrategy to heart is almost as dumb as women taking what's said on r/theredpill to heart.

All women are different, all women have different preferences and biology.  My wife is far more sensitive down there, and i have to go slowly and gently, or it ruins it for her, even with my average sized peen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871821220.0" user="fitness35754745" delta="False">
    <text>Hahahaha thank you. And thanks for telling me your experience those always help. Yeah that subreddit is full of women I wouldnt want anyway</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871817626.0" user="Dingo_Jiu_Jitsu" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't think the girl will care about any of this. You need to clear your mind of things "you've heard" and start to see world through your own eyes. To be honest knowone cares about your penis as much as you do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871827332.0" user="serketboard" delta="False">
    <text>Keep in mind that subs like that represent a small fraction of the population - a group of likeminded people concentrated in one spot can make anything or opinion look incredibly prevalent when it’s not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36871889274.0" user="Eng_Queen" delta="False">
    <text>Lesbians have more orgasms than bisexual women who have more orgasms than straight women. I don’t think penis size has much to do with women’s pleasure...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36880671800.0" user="selvorix" delta="False">
    <text>When you are in a long-term relationship, you might be having sex multiple times a week, once a week, or only once or twice a month. But you're going to be living with that person and associated with that person for every moment of your life. Which one will make a bigger difference to a woman then... your penis size being 0.003 inches less than average? Or how well you can comfort each other emotionally, manage finances, keep a clean house, get along with each other's families, etc?

P.S. how you use the dick and your physicality in general is far more important than the size. The most well-endowed sexual partner I ever had was also one of the most disappointing. On the other hand you can give a woman very good pleasure without using the dick whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36872255803.0" user="agaminon22" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nobody actually cares about height or anything like that

I don't think this is really true. I definitely know and have seen girls that will simply reject a dude because he's too short. It happens more in dating sites, but it's a thing. Saying that no one cares ignores the fact that plenty of people are shallow like that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883764083.0" user="roodonog22" delta="False">
    <text>The average woman does not care about height. We're talking about averages here. Some women definitely do have a preference but overall, its not realistic to assume that every single woman cares about height.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883801903.0" user="agaminon22" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know about the average woman over all, that's probably true in general. The average woman on tinder does, though, at least according to their own studies.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
