<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884436515.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I think the only potential way a double-standards post could be useful is if the SPECIFIC view is "X and Y are meaningfully the same thing" and entirely focused on that part of it rather than on the standards people hold for each.

Or, if that's too strict, it might be good to have a rule that a person can't post from a neutral perspective?  These trojan horse posts are almost exclusively someone having to feign neutrality, because that's the only way to attack hypocrisy without being inconsistent yourself.  And how many useful, good-faith posts are from a view of neutrality anyway?

&amp;gt; You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that.

It would be really great to somehow codify this overall, though honestly I have absolutely no clue how to do that more than it's already done.  But the issue with double standards posts is that they're almost exclusively focused on what the poster thinks (or wants to think) other people believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887782606.0" user="Criminal_of_Thought" delta="False">
    <text>By rule D, it's already against the rules for an OP to have a neutral stance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888715746.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>"Having a neutral stance" isn't the same thing as "voicing a stance from a feigned position of neutrality."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889303650.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>In regards to rule enforcement, how would those not be the same?  Could you give an example that would fall into one but not the other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36898457468.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>"Vanilla yogurt tastes neither particularly good nor particularly bad."  That's a neutral stance.

"If we accept transgender people, we should accept transracial people." That's lobbed from a feigned neutral perspective, because the poster is acting like they're equally ok with accepting both as accepting neither, and they almost certainly don't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
