<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36886525234.0" user="zfreakazoidz" delta="False">
    <text>I know my one topic wasn't deleted because "You were not willing to to change your view". Which doesn't make much sense. If its my view and I don't see any good arguments, why would I change it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888001737.0" user="Criminal_of_Thought" delta="False">
    <text>If there's only one comment and the argument the commenter provided wasn't good enough, then sure, that's fine.

But if a large number of comments all pose arguments (which may or may not be similar among themselves) and *none* of them are good enough, how is an outside person supposed to know that the view presented by the poster has a very high barrier that those comments aren't overcoming, as opposed to the poster just deflecting all arguments given against them because they don't actually want their view changed? If you're part of the first camp, perhaps the reasons why the parts of the view that those commenters are addressing aren't being changed could be put in the opening post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36911687245.0" user="Rufus_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ... But if a large number of comments all pose arguments (which may or may not be similar among themselves) and none of them are good enough ...

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Criticism_of_the_theory_of_relativity#A_Hundred_Authors_Against_Einstein

The admins seem to get things mostly right, but it's less about the number of arguments, and more about the nature of the discussion.  For example, people who keep "moving the goalposts" or trying to change the topic instead of engaging with the substance of the arguments are likely hit with Rule B violations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36911689493.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**Criticism_of_the_theory_of_relativity** 
 
 [A Hundred Authors Against Einstein](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Criticism_of_the_theory_of_relativity#A_Hundred_Authors_Against_Einstein) 
 
 &amp;gt;A collection of various criticisms can be found in the book Hundert Autoren gegen Einstein (A Hundred Authors Against Einstein), published in 1931. It contains very short texts from 28 authors, and excerpts from the publications of another 19 authors. The rest consists of a list that also includes people who only for some time were opposed to relativity. Besides philosophic objections (mostly based on Kantianism), also some alleged elementary failures of the theory were included; however, as some commented, those failures were due to the authors' misunderstanding of relativity.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | Credit: kittens_from_space)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36894877406.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Even in the absence of an argument that changes an OP's view, we can look at other things, like whether they responded to all of the arguments or ignored ones they didn't have good rebuttals to, whether they ask questions and try to understand commenters'' viewpoints rather than doubling down, whether they got hostile when someone challenges their view, etc. I've seen plenty of posts with no deltas that still had plenty of good conversation (and posts with deltas that were still in violation of Rule B for the above reasons).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
