<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36887390733.0" user="earthican-earthican" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve been wondering, is there a sub like r/changemyview but where it’s okay if I’m already *trying* to change my own view, but I need help from others to get all the way there?

I’m talking about things like:
- I buy things on Amazon even though I know it’s bad for everyone, including myself. I would like to bring an end to this madness, but I need help. I’ve thought about posting on here, “CMV: it’s okay to buy stuff from Amazon,” so that my Reddit peeps can help by shredding my complacency and showing me all the ways Amazon shopping is harmful / all the reasons to stop. But I would be violating the rules because I already think it’s bad to shop on Amazon (yet my behavior does not line up with my supposed view, so part of me still needs to be convinced)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887524376.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure if this is exactly what you're looking for, but take a look at r/GetMotivatedBuddies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36893772752.0" user="earthican-earthican" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, thank you, I will check it out!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888775292.0" user="Natural-Arugula" delta="False">
    <text>"Cmv: Amazon is bad, but it's ok if I keep shopping there."

Idk, you seem to think it's not Ok, yet you do keep shopping there.

The comments would be interrogating your reasons for why you continue to shop there. So maybe you can do that on your own?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36893827767.0" user="earthican-earthican" delta="False">
    <text>I see, yes, that would be a way of phrasing it that could work without violating sub rules. Thanks! The reason I want to hear from other people on this topic (instead of just myself) is that other people know specific things about Amazon, Jeff Bezos, etc that I don’t know. Also, other people know of alternatives that I don’t know about.

But yeah, there’s also some personal work I need to do to reveal (to myself) why I continue to shop there. So thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347352766.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>With a little bit of reflection, I think that you could create a CMV on this subject.  There are lots of cases where I feel that I am forced to be inconsistent in regards to my beliefs and my actions.  Here's an example of something I could post that I think is analogous to your situation.  I'm doing something that is contrary to my ethics and I believe I do so rationally.  I would be open to learning a different way to think about this that opens up new options to me.  I don't think the mods would remove this, but I'd welcome their input.  :)

&amp;gt;CMV:  "It is justified for me to be an AT&amp;amp;T customer despite my strongly held belief they are evil, harmful, and commit illegal acts."

&amp;gt;I think that AT&amp;amp;T is a horrible company.  Some of their leaders should be in prison.  The company has a whole has all kinds of shady practices.

&amp;gt;AT&amp;amp;T illegally conspires with the US government to spy on me.  AT&amp;amp;T has historically sponsored and supported all kinds of legislation that has harmed the internet and kept prices artificially high and speed artificially slow.  AT&amp;amp;T has accepted government money for years to expand broadband access and provide service to the underserved without actually making any meaningful progress on this goal - they simply pocket the money.  AT&amp;amp;T's customer service is arguably awful.  It's difficult to reach a person and even when you do they don't typically resolve any issue.

&amp;gt;But, here I am, an AT&amp;amp;T customer.  I work from home and must have reliable, high-speed internet to do my job.  I'm also a PC gamer as one of my few forms of entertainment which also need decent internet.

&amp;gt;Having explored my options, AT&amp;amp;T is the most reliable and highest speed in my area.  Because of regulatory capture, market consolidation, and legalized monopolies, the "competitors" suffer from the same faults.  I don't have an ethical, rational alternative so I use AT&amp;amp;T.  I also can't just boycott all of the existing providers to make an opening for a new player.

edit:  /u/herrsatan  --  I just posted above to a couple month old topic...  would you spend a minute to review and just state if this would be an allowed CMV?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37349674058.0" user="earthican-earthican" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for this! This is how I feel about Amazon, and about the fact that I rely so heavily on what they have to offer (product mix, customer reviews, delivery and return service) even though I know Amazon is an actively negative company in many of the same kinds of ways you’ve described. I appreciate you taking time to post this response!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
