<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884451060.0" user="Meii345" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really get what a trojan horse is, can someone give me a concrete exemple please? :3 Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885011007.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, here's one common one: 

"If someone can be transgender, they can be transracial, too". 

OP almost never *actually* believes that people should be allowed to be transracial... they are just disguising "trans isn't real" posts in a CMV they hope looks like it's about something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885383530.0" user="jmorfeus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;OP almost never actually believes that people should be allowed to be transracial...

But that's not what you wrote they're saying, is it? 

You wrote 
"IF someone can be transgender, THEN they can be transracial". 

Not "People should be allowed to be transracial"

It's two different statements.

It's perfectly viable for someone to hold this view, no? It doesn't say anything about what they think about being transgender. They're arguing the implication.

They more than likely don't believe people should be allowed to be transgender, but you're trying to change their view on that IF they are, they should also be allowed to be transracial. So it's about finding a difference in the two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885744643.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>It's technically possible to actually want to argue this view of "if a, then b"... but almost no one does that. The vast majority have a long post history of being transphobic and almost none of any interest in supposed "transraciality". Nor do their comments or post actually make much attempt to address it. 

If someone wants to appeal and make that argument, or is sufficiently clear in their OP and responses to comments, we'll consider it.

Basically, we're looking way more carefully at people who are making "if A, then B... but really, not A" arguments. 

This logically devolves to "not A" (B is irrelevant if A is false in that construct), but worded as though someone cares about the "if", when they don't act like that's the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889656730.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's technically possible to actually want to argue this view of "if a, then b"... but almost no one does that. 

I disagree; I see it all the time.

The argument is that there is a double standard in society and that both are treated differently and I indeed see this topic come up often and I usually see OP argue the dual standard.

I have always interpreted such topics not as that the view is that OP has any particular affinity with transrqacial individuals or views to their behalf but merely that there is a double standard in how it's treated.

&amp;gt; The vast majority have a long post history of being transphobic and almost none of any interest in supposed "transraciality". Nor do their comments or post actually make much attempt to address it.

And I see nothing wrong with that in regards to this view. The view is not that transracialsim should be accepted but that there is a double standard and the nonacceptance of transracialism is used to point out this double standard.

&amp;gt; Basically, we're looking way more carefully at people who are making "if A, then B... but really, not A" arguments.

I find this concerning. To be completely frank reading this it sounds as though you lack the most basic understanding of elementary logical syllogisms.

"if A, then B" in no way implies that A is true—reading it as such is an absolutely basic logical fallacy.

&amp;gt; This logically devolves to "not A" (B is irrelevant if A is false in that construct), but worded as though someone cares about the "if", when they don't act like that's the case.

Can you give a concrete example? because every time I've seen this common topic that I remember, it was always a few against the double standard in society.

Now, of course, removing such topics because OP is clearly not interested in having a view expanded/changed and is only interested in preaching that a double standard exists is fine and a completely different matter—but the way I see it almost all of these topics claim to hold a view that there is a double standard, and hold that view, and that OP's history is anti transgender changes absolutely nothing about that these CMVs hardly ever claim to be in support of transrqacial rights, merely that they hold the view that there is a dual standard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36890726006.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The view is not that transracialsim should be accepted but that there is a double standard

You might think that, and in theory it could be correct, but in practice they end up not really talking about the validity of the *analogy* between the two sides, but rather about the invalidity of one or the other or both sides. 

OP almost never tries to genuinely argue why these are similar or dissimilar, which would be necessary to understand whether a "double standard" exists (because different things naturally have different standards).

Or if they do, it's almost always done in a "gotcha" sense of trying to use reductio ad absurdum to invalidate the transgender side. E.g. a less obvious form of "See, you consider concept of transracial people to be absurd so you can't really believe in transgendered people...". Which is basically the exact *opposite* of a "double standard".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886215767.0" user="cuteman" delta="False">
    <text>If the entire experience is based on what people they themselves believe then how can you prove that they don't believe in being transracial?

There are numerous examples where people seem to shift into a different race and it becomes there identity.

While it may be for argument sake the reason it's not just thrown out is because it does make some sense and there are examples, even if it seems the person isn't arguing in good faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886272840.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; can you prove that they don't believe in being transracial?

Irrelevant to OPs that aren't claiming to be transracial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885022335.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>In Greek mythology, the Trojan horse was supposed to be a gift from the Greeks to the city of Troy, but it was actually full of soldiers who killed everybody. The way we're using it is for a topic that's pretending to be about one thing but is really about another. One example from the past week was gun control and cars. OP said "If we regulate guns, we should also regulate cars". But what they actually wanted was to get people to argue against car regulation so they could then apply those arguments to guns. Basically like "hey, see how dumb this argument is for cars, so we shouldn't regulate guns." We called it a Trojan Horse because OP's are being dishonest about the point of their post and are going to try to push the conversation in a different direction than their post would suggest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885031300.0" user="KinoranaUPSB" delta="False">
    <text>Hypothetical example: "If transgender people are valid, transracial people are too". The post isn't really about transracial people, and they don't believe in transracialism, OP is just taking jabs at transgenderism by showing how their logic can implicate ridiculous things, implying that transgenderism is equally ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
