<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884505267.0" user="msneurorad" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand the reasoning for the rule, but would like to point out that such comparisons can be a useful way if investigating a topic and peeling back layers of complexity, especially if that topic is not as familiar as the comparison being drawn. I guess so long as a poster just comes out and says "gun control laws are nonsensical" and as a way of justifying that view draws comparisons to vehicle restrictions and such that would be fine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885817195.0" user="Xiver1972" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but would like to point out that such comparisons can be a useful way if investigating a topic and peeling back layers of complexity

Those lines of reasonings can be used in the comment section, but they don't belong as a misleading CMV.  If someone is against gun control, then they should say they are against gun control not that they are against vehicle control.  They can use comparison and contrast to argue their point in the comments, without making a confusing and misleading topic.

Say what you mean and mean what you say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887598238.0" user="msneurorad" delta="False">
    <text>Rules for CMV generally require the OP to lay out their view and arguments/facts/points why they believe that way. If a primary reason you hold a certain view is because you see a strong parallel with some other issue that is more familiar to us, I think that should be fair to include as supporting reasons for the view.

On the other hand, I think the kids are saying make the title and CMV about the actual view, not about the parallel so that you can circle back later and say "yeah and what about..." which seems entirely logical of course.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
