<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36883034230.0" user="Frank91405" delta="False">
    <text>Has there been a recent example of this? I don’t remember seeing one like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883134837.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>There was one recently about how taxes on rich people was anti-Semitic that really seemed to be a way to attack the concept of disparate outcomes in general. But then that poster had a lot of questionable stuff in their history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883219114.0" user="adjsdjlia" delta="False">
    <text>Take a look at any conservative leaning political post and it's a solid chance that this is going to occur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883295496.0" user="zuluportero" delta="False">
    <text>"We should accept transracial people"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883717907.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>I saw one that said that all sports cars should be banned and used a lot of rhetoric similar to gun control, how speed kills, HP restrictions, government registries, special permits, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883830195.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>Yep. Last week I think?

It was super transparent and the OP had posted a ton in a bunch of gun subreddits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883843569.0" user="CoffeeAndCannabis310" delta="False">
    <text>It's been my experience that the posters of that content tend to fall in a relative homogenous ideology</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883847611.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely a pattern...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889291968.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>I thought I recognized your username.  You had that evidence against that poster who did numerous trojan horses (like the Israeli Palistine one and the death penalty; always started the posts by "reminding us of the rules of CMV").  You must have a knack for spotting trojan horses ;p</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891184783.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah, u/speedyjohn tipped us off to that via modmail, was super helpful!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891188996.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, in retrospect I should’ve just left it to you guys and not commented. Got a little carried away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891203385.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>I have been that guy before :) It's hard sometimes, and like u/Poo-et said earlier R3 can interact bad with posts that are actually in bad faith. It's still better not to feed the trolls, but I absolutely understand the impulse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891237943.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>Plus now /u/RedditExplorer89 knows who I am and they seem cool.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891242725.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that's a win for sure! You're e-famous now :)

Edit: as a side note, both you and u/RedditExplorer89 have the "helpful user" tag in my RES.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36893281059.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>That's cool to know :D</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36893269283.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Lol and I got some good drama to read out of it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884699884.0" user="lovelyyecats" delta="False">
    <text>Any post that talks about oppression against men or false rape allegations or child support is usually just a trojan horse for "I hate feminism."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
