<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884816682.0" user="Irishfury86" delta="False">
    <text>Can we for the love of God put a moratorium on CMVs about transgenderism?  It's the exact same post every single day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884998224.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>It's honestly not that difficult to ignore them. If other people want to keep arguing them, that's fine. Except on Fresh Topic Friday, of course.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886075286.0" user="gusgalarnyk" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is they're breeding grounds for hateful rhetoric if good people don't keep up the debate. If the person with the objectively right take or well researched argument gets tired of posting every single day to a group of people who systematically repeat the system, you end up with the chance that more posts are filled with sympathizers or even proponents of the absurd. I think this is one of the reasons these bad circles and communities can form and thrive, because everyone feels like they've answered the same obvious question 1-6 times already this year. That weariness leaves openings for misbehaviors and trolls, we need systematic rules against that poor behavior, hence the request for specific bans or larger refresh windows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886267368.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Not really what we observe actually happening. Top comments are typically all the best arguments against the OP, and we remove Rule 1 violations and non sequiturs pretty quickly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886311782.0" user="gusgalarnyk" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying the almost daily transgender questions are all well purposed and reasoned and each of their top comments are the best possible response with rock solid arguments and the OP is consistently impressed? Cause I can't imagine that's the actual case. They may be decent comments, but I'd wager the best discussion happened 200 posts ago on the subject matter. It'd be better if we had the ability to sticky the best versions of certain conversations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886345525.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm saying that there's minimal harm for the relatively short period of time before the mods remove the post for violating Rule B (if, indeed, OP doesn't change their view, which actually does happen more often than you'd think). 

Because you've got 1 OP pushing a view, usually incoherently, and dozens arguing against them, typically cogently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886365699.0" user="gusgalarnyk" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I see. Thanks for clarifying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885500807.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>We had a post about this recently.  We aren't going to ban them, but we are going to more strictly enforce our "no duplicate topics within 24 hours" rule.  So, basically, that means we're going to allow one a day on any given aspect of the topic.

If you see a duplicate, report it .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886609689.0" user="Henderson-McHastur" delta="False">
    <text>For the people whose duplicates are removed, will there be any feature to direct them to the post they were duplicating? It might ease some people’s concerns, since posters who were interested in a certain view being changed would still be able to participate, or at least have access to the arguments for and against their position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887104715.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Yes - we link them to the similar post in the removal message.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887106950.0" user="Henderson-McHastur" delta="False">
    <text>Pog mods</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887498467.0" user="bradfordmaster" delta="False">
    <text>Personally, I'd vote to see it go down to once a week. It's honestly pretty rare that I see anything other than a recycled gender or race issue post make it to my overall front page from this sub anymore....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36890094181.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>I would not mind friday being three or four days per week myself.

- transgender
- white individuals and dreadlocks
- body positivity movement
- virtuous paedophiles

Too much of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36890130032.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Taking off my mod hat for a minute, I _personally_ agree with you.  I'd like to see fewer posts on those subjects.

Putting the had back on, I have to try and strike a balance.  Some people want to see fewer posts on those topics, and others feel that any restrictions - even FTF - are over moderation.  The balance we've tried to strike is one day a week where those post are (effectively) banned, and on all other days we limit it to a single post on each aspect of the topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347182693.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>Would you consider making this a once-a-week rule?  Daily has no real impact on the trolls whose primary intent is to keep the toxic message in front of everyone every single day.  At once a week there is still an opening for real questions, but enough delay to dissuade the short-attention-span trolls.  It also gives everyone else a respite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347361616.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>We are discussing making it longer, but I doubt we’d ever go to one a week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347435506.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>What is the concern with 1 week?  If there is a concern that it will cut back on the posts, that shouldn't be the concern since that is the desired outcome.  The troll posts are like weeds...  they choke out the good posts.  You might see a temporary decline in total posts, but you'd probably also see some growth of better posts a short time later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347450727.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>One per week makes it effectively impossible for someone with one of these views to come here to have it changed.  CMV exists so that people who have views like this have a place to come, discuss them, and hopefully begin to see the other side.

Yes, troll posts choke out the good ones in the garden, but you can't scorch the earth to kill the weeds - do that and nothing can grow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347581574.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One per week makes it effectively impossible for someone with one of these views to come here to have it changed.

How so?  One week is a drop in the bucket.  

If nobody posts at the 1-week point then it's a pretty clear statement that the vast majority of the posts on the subject were just troll posts and the community is better off.

If there is legitimately that much interest in the topic and it's not just trolls then somebody is going to post on it.  If anyone posts at the 1-week point then the topic is there for everyone to participate and have their views changed.  

It's a win-win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347596735.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's a win-win.

We may have to agree to disagree here.  I see the person who truly could have had their view changed not being able to post as a major lose for that person and for the goal of this community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347636546.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>I think the part I'm missing is not understanding how the cmv person is not being able to post.  They can be part of that conversation every single week.

Is your concern that once a week a troll will come in and steal the topic and that is how the cmv person doesn't get to participate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347649320.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Its the same reason we don't do megathreads for any subject - CMVs are highly personal to the OP.  It is about OP explaining _their_ view and people crafting arguments to try and change that specific view.  Megathreads are by their very nature impersonal and less effective at our mission.

My concern is that this individual won't post at all, and their view will remain unchallenged.  That is the exact thing that CMV exists to try and stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347767771.0" user="blatsnorf" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for explaining.  Has there ever been any consideration and/or testing of only allowing certain topics on certain days of the week?  For instance, there could be 1000+ threads about LGBT topics created, but only on Mondays?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37347833747.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>We've discussed it as a possibility, yes.  We are trying the 24 hour rule first to see if it helps before we do anything more restrictive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886902233.0" user="atropax" delta="False">
    <text>Just so you know, 'transgenderism' isn't a word used by trans people. The majority of people who use it are those trying to portray being trans as an insidious ideology, when it is simply a state of being - trans people don't have a homogenous ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888148007.0" user="Irishfury86" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The majority of people who use it are those trying to portray being trans as an insidious ideology

That's the most ridiculous, nonsensical, and unsubstantiated thing I have read in weeks.   Just so you know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889134261.0" user="atropax" delta="False">
    <text>If it doesn't have negative connotations then why is it not used by trans people themselves? Why do I only see it used by people who are arguing against trans rights, and people who haven't done that much research/don't care much either way? 

The suffix -ism is used to make transness seem like an ideology, and therefore when they argue against it they can have the veneer of just having a political debate rather than arguing against the existence of people and their right to exist and express themselves.

I'm not saying this is what you were trying to do, I'm just saying that this is how the word is used. Now that you know, you can decide whether you want to continue to use the word.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Compare this resource from a health service ("trangenderism" is at the bottom)

[https://www.albertahealthservices.ca/assets/info/pf/div/if-pf-div-terms-and-phrases-to-avoid.pdf](https://www.albertahealthservices.ca/assets/info/pf/div/if-pf-div-terms-and-phrases-to-avoid.pdf)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

to these uses from anti-trans actors:

[http://religiousinstitute.org/denom\_statements/transgenderism-transsexuality-gender-identity/](http://religiousinstitute.org/denom_statements/transgenderism-transsexuality-gender-identity/)

[https://www.pinknews.co.uk/2021/01/27/womens-human-rights-campaign-gender-recognition-act-inquiry-trans-transphobia/](https://www.pinknews.co.uk/2021/01/27/womens-human-rights-campaign-gender-recognition-act-inquiry-trans-transphobia/)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Seriously, try and find a couple of instances where "transgenderism" is used by trans people or trans rights activists in a serious way. It's virtually impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
