<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36883382289.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>What are we going to do about the obvious Russian trolls that make strawman arguments with the goal of irritating people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883937921.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>If you have clear evidence of their state-employed Russian-ness I'd go ahead and message the admins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885507967.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's going to be hard to come by. Best evidence that I have is that when I simply call them out for being Russian trolls they immediately stop responding to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885548615.0" user="Quakespeare" delta="False">
    <text>I would also ignore you if you called me a Russian troll.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885616254.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm then maybe I've figured out the secret sauce to getting annoying people to leave me alone on Reddit with their outrageous strawman arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885833437.0" user="MegaBlastoise23" delta="False">
    <text>i mean, I highly doubt they are engaging you. It sounds like you are engaging them and their posts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886191015.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>I cited an example in response to someone else here. [You can see what I mean here](https://www.reddit.com/r/PoliticalDiscussion/comments/n5mhlb/what_should_european_countries_do_about/gx3e5sh?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) (look at who replied, I didn't engage)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887451984.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Not that I agree with that user's point but I don't see how that's a Russian troll or even just an "annoying" person. They just made a comment challenging yours, just like you made a comment challenging someone else's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891351084.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>Except it didn't challenge mine because it rephrased my claim as if I was only calling out Europeans and not Asians or Africans. 

It's the intentional use of 'you' in phrases like this:

&amp;gt; Why exactly do you only complain about this when it's people of European descent making these assertions?

I never mentioned Europeans, and ironically enough I was thinking about Peruvians when I said it. But I left my comment completely neutral in terms of nationality. But this is what they do. This wasn't my claim, but they twist it so that now you have to try and dig yourself out of their rhetorical hole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887394373.0" user="classicmirthmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Spoken like a true Russian troll</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889894383.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I think, it's pretty universal that if you start throwing personal insults at people, they will stop responding to you regardless of the discussion that preceded the insults. I would (or at least point the rule 7 violation). Have you tried a bit more polite approach to find out if they indeed are Russians and/or trolling?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891375321.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>I've engaged with several and seen where it goes. I don't think calling someone a Russian troll is an insult, either. It's a legitimate profession, apparently. Sometimes I even offer them advice to improve their performance. 

I'm at the point where I can immediately smell when these conversations are being derailed by these types, and I just don't engage any more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36891823329.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I've been personally called a Chinese shill and a Russian troll just by defending an opinion that these sides may have or not even that. Sometimes just not being 100% anti-Chinese or anti-Russian can get you that label. 

I don't know you personally and maybe you are more careful with such labels, but my personal experience is that people throw these labels pretty liberally at the point when their arguments get shot down. 

There are a few cases that I have had a strong feeling that the arguments proposed by someone have indeed been manufactured at the GRU trollfarm, but compared to the number of times I've seen people being called Russian trolls these are a small minority. 

&amp;gt;I'm at the point where I can immediately smell when these conversations are being derailed by these types, and I just don't engage any more.

My feeling is that far more often it's just normal trolls or even people who just can't admit being wrong and thus rather move goal posts or something similar than actual paid trolls. I'm not saying the actual Russian (or Macedonians or whatever) trolls don't exist, but I'm just saying that they are much less common than just normal people not willing to admit they are wrong. Calling them Russian trolls won't make them admit they are wrong, but can make them see you as an unpolite person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884374030.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>We have had a slight uptick in Rule B violating troll posts in the last couple days. We're catching them as we see them - sometimes it takes a while to remove them because a) it takes a little while to see the OP is not engaging in a meaningful way and b) there's a limit on the availability of mods with the time to review entire posts, especially at certain times of day. Best thing to do is report them and not engage - posts with multiple reports rise to the top of the priority list.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885035889.0" user="AWFUL_COCK" delta="False">
    <text>Very curious about this--can you show me an example?

I don't mean this in a challenging way. I've long thought that the CMV subreddit (as well as the AITA subreddit) is filled to the brim with lazy psy-ops.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885576789.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>Given how lame Reddit's search functions are for my comment history it would be a royal PITA to dig up a proper example, and I'll readily admit I've seen more of them outside of CMV than inside. But they're there. 

Typically it's on the post that espouses some conservative view. [Here I was](https://www.reddit.com/r/PoliticalDiscussion/comments/n5mhlb/what_should_european_countries_do_about/gx3e5sh?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) (not on CMV, just the most recent example) simply commenting how the most xenophobic people are those that haven't even interacted with people from a foreign culture. The next reply pulls a wild strawman and makes it seem that I'm unfairly only attacking white people, despite never mentioning race once in my original comment.

Users like these typically have relatively recent accounts, tend to only try to trigger, and most of their karma is from a successful article post or two while everything else is negative in comments. The successful post is how you hide your shittiness at a glance. It's textbook Russian troll. 

Called him out instantly and would you look at that, runs away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886136661.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>Calling people "Russian trolls" when they disagree with you is not exactly productive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886208105.0" user="steelerfaninperu" delta="False">
    <text>Did you look at my example? It's not about someone "disagreeing" with me. 

I love it when people disagree. That's why I love this sub. What I don't love is people making strawman arguments to make it seem like I was being unfair or misleading with what I said. 

It's the guy that does the "but what about" and then adds on "so see you're actually the \_\_\_\_ one here"

Instead of having an actual discussion with opposing viewpoints, you're now sitting there trying to dig yourself out of this person's imaginary hole and the whole time you're getting more and more irritated. This is what these Russian troll ops do. They typically use conservative talking points because they know Reddit, on average, leans liberal. So it's logically going to be more effective. 

None of these interactions I've had started with me engaging them, and none of them addressed any of the points I actually made in my original post. It's just someone looking to rile people up.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
