<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36885018921.0" user="Legendary_lamp_" delta="False">
    <text>What would be an example of this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885104456.0" user="veryreasonable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What would be an example of this?

Okay: 

"If student debt should be forgiven, then clearly *all* outstanding debts should be forgiven as debt contracts no longer mean anything, CMV" 

...would be a Trojan Horse if OP doesn't actually believe that debts should be forgiven, but really just wants to crowd source arguments that student debt shouldn't be forgiven, either.  

Basically, a CMV post that is framed as though OP thinks one way, when in reality they actually *already* think the exact opposite way.  

It doesn't work in this sub because top-level comments are supposed to challenge OP's view.  However, if OP's view is the exact opposite of what they claim it is in the initial post, then their post is essentially asking people to take time out of their day challenging a few that perhaps nobody actually even holds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885366604.0" user="Khal-Frodo" delta="False">
    <text>I saw one a before the COVID ban was lifted that advocated making condoms mandatory for all sexual interactions. Most of the comments were pointing out that this was a thinly-veiled allegory for masking, which was very obvious by the arguments in the OP.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
