<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884580638.0" user="GeraldTibbons" delta="False">
    <text>Why so many fucking rules?  Let the upvotes decide :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884725532.0" user="Orwellian1" delta="False">
    <text>That is the vast majority of reddit. If you want shallow hive-mind, you have plenty of places to find that. Strictly moderated subs are for those who want more than a popularity contest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885056854.0" user="nowlistenhereboy" delta="False">
    <text>We wouldn't need rules if people didn't incessantly try to game the system in dishonest ways and make intentionally misleading statements/claims/arguments. The average user isn't paying enough attention to the posts they upvote or downvote to tell the difference between a genuine post and one that is a troll or otherwise intentionally deceptive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885074568.0" user="fishling" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't work, ever, in specialized subs. People do not upvote rationally or consistently, and they do not upvote in ways that align to the rules.

If a focused sub wants to survive, it requires moderation.

In fact, you're proof that this wouldn't work, because you're admitting that you wouldn't care about following any community rules when you are deciding to upvote or downvote something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885278958.0" user="no_fluffies_please" delta="False">
    <text>To add on to your point: there is no feedback mechanism so that users can tell if they're upvoting incorrectly and why. With comments/posts, you can tell people "hey that's not in the spirit of the sub". The a large chunk of users upvote and never comment.

So theoretically, let's say you had a sub about discussing dogs without rules. Because they don't know about the rules, a group of people from r/all can come in and upvote image posts or worse, cat pics. Additionally, people from other social media platforms will confuse the meaning of an upvote with the meaning of a "like".

You get this problem where you're constantly trying to fight the eternal september effect, because vote-only redditors *never* need to learn the rules and conventions of the sub. The best subs have mechanisms to combat this, either with heavy moderation (deleting posts/comments is like a "hard" downvote) or something like a delta where you need to explain *why* you upvoted something and you can get feedback on that explanation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885106001.0" user="AWFUL_COCK" delta="False">
    <text>Without rules, this sub (and every other sub, as well) would be a 24/7 debate about whether Trans people and feminists are bad. Fuck that. Even though they are a minority, the trolls will always take over because they simply have more time and obsession than normal people do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885230883.0" user="veryreasonable" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're missing the point here.  The fundamental idea of this sub is that people can present and explain a viewpoint, and replies in the comments will challenge that viewpoint, and the original poster is at least somewhat open to having their view changed.

A "Trojan Horse" in this context is a post that does not actually express OP's real viewpoint.  Accordingly, their real viewpoint, which is never stated, can't actually be challenged by the comment replies. Which defeats the whole purpose of the sub.

I believe subs like /r/unpopularopinion are the "better" places to post that sort of thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
