<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36884443892.0" user="StunningEstates" delta="False">
    <text>Could someone Eli5? People are posting views they don’t hold so that others can defeat them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884789456.0" user="CountVine" delta="False">
    <text>If I understand it correctly, the situation is as follows: a person thinks that A is unreasonable, to demonstrate that they create a CMV about a different topic B, which they attempt to defend in a way similar to that used by proponents of A.

Somebody in this comment section gave an example of a post on regulations for race cars being used as an attack on gun control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885081763.0" user="StunningEstates" delta="False">
    <text>Ahhhhhh, thank you! Sneaky, haha!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885158928.0" user="veryreasonable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People are posting views they don’t hold so that others can defeat them?

Yeah.  To make up an example on the spot...

"If prisons and police should be abolished, then we might as well abolish *all* courts, laws, and regulations, CMV"

Is a Trojan Horse if OP doesn't actually believe that prisons or police should be abolished (let alone anything else).  

It's inviting top all top level commenters to waste their time trying to challenge a view that they'll never change, because they don't even hold it.  Basically, a Trojan Horse is a post that breaks Submission Rule B, while also being at its core a roundabout bad-faith attempt to prove a different point entirely.  

(In the above example, what OP should actually have posted, if they were following the rules, might be something like "I think rules and laws are important, and so I don't believe prison or police abolition are good ideas, CMV."  That would have been honest, and reflected their actual viewpoint, and invited replies to challenge that view.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
