<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36883451142.0" user="BrutusJunior" delta="False">
    <text>Just want to clarify the 'trojan horse'.

Around once a week, I see CMVs that are titled: 'If people can change their gender, then they should be allowed to change their race'. Would this qualify as 'trojan horse' CMV?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883605571.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>It depends. 

In some cases, it could be a legitimate CMV. The OP could see the two as equivalent and truly believe that if one is allowed, the other is equally viable. That would be fine. 

In others, the OP doesn’t really believe transracialism is a thing and is using it as a red herring to _really_ talk about how transgenderism is unreasonable. They don’t relive believe that they are equally reasonable, but rather just want to talk about the former. That is what we are concerned about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884526115.0" user="infrikinfix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In others, the OP doesn’t really believe transracialism is a thing and is using it as a red herring to really talk about how transgenderism is unreasonable.

That's not how if statements work though. 

You can have any manner of opinion about transracialism and transgenerism and sincerely hold the view that transracialism exists IF transgenderism exists.

It is actually quite interesting when there are seemingly contradictory views popularly held by people at once, and it can be worthwhile to figure out whether or not they are really contradictory views. 

Now it may be that most people who ask that question have a particular view on the matters, but why should that mean a question about the logic of the relationship between two popular viewpoints is not worthwhile to explore?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884555150.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, which is why I stared the response with "It depends."

Sometimes what you are saying is the view being presented and we'll let that play out.  Sometimes, however, it is clear that they are bringing up trans-racialism with no intent to actually talk about that, but rather to try and subvert the idea  of transgenderism.  If you want to talk about transgenderism that is fine, but then talk about that directly; don't couch it in a subject you don't really believe to try and make some kind of point.

I can't give much guidance beyond that because each case has to be evaluated individually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886551115.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sometimes, however, it is clear that they are bringing up trans-racialism with no intent to actually talk about that, but rather to try and subvert the idea of transgenderism. If you want to talk about transgenderism that is fine, but then talk about that directly; don't couch it in a subject you don't really believe to try and make some kind of point.

The example brought up above was not a discussion of transracialism, it was a discussion of the contradiction between how many people treat transracialism and transgenderism.  

In essence, it was the view that "if X then Y".  Talking about X or about Y or about both or about the relationship between the two should be allowed.  It is not bait-and-switching between saying X and then really talking about Y, it's bringing up the relationship between X and Y, which involves both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884581450.0" user="philosophical_lens" delta="False">
    <text>Logically there are several conditions under which the claim "if A then B" can be true (see truth table below and [click here for source](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Material_conditional)). It is logically consistent and sound to believe both A and B are false but "if A then B" is true.

A | B | If A then B
---|---|----
True | True | True
True | False | False
False | True | True
False | False | True</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884665398.0" user="fubo" delta="False">
    <text>Logical equivalence isn't all that matters, though. In this specific case, other things that matter include rhetorical dishonesty, misleading emphasis, and the use of "Just Asking Questions" as a form of deliberate harassment or exclusion.

(If every time you came to the sub, you saw a new collection of CMVs proposing that you are an insane fraud, how welcome would *you* feel?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885221761.0" user="You_Yew_Ewe" delta="False">
    <text>So this response would seem to indicate this is really an issue of questioning transgenderism in general no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885264087.0" user="fubo" delta="False">
    <text>No, it seems to indicate narrowly and specifically that truth-tables and explanations of elementary logic are a distraction from the issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885294190.0" user="You_Yew_Ewe" delta="False">
    <text>Logic is an important part of how we reason (maybe not for everyone, but for some people), and reason is an important part of how views are changed.


That aside, you brought this into it
&amp;gt;If every time you came to the sub, you saw a new collection of CMVs proposing that you are an insane fraud, how welcome would you feel?

So why not just make a rule banning disussions that would make transgender people feel excluded in general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885306898.0" user="fubo" delta="False">
    <text>Logic is very important, but bringing up elementary logic in this discussion is a distraction, since the issue here is one that has to do with *dishonesty and misuse of the forum*, not illogic.

It's like if someone asked you if your house has two toilets and you said "There is one toilet and one toilet, and one plus one is two (1 + 1 = 2), maybe not to you but to most people." A person wouldn't say that unless they were trying to be an asshole.

There are other kinds of "bad arguments" besides *illogical* ones. There are, for instance, arguments based on false premises; there are arguments based on prejudice (i.e. ignorance pretending to be knowledge). There are also *spammy* arguments; if someone posts the same thing seventeen times over, it doesn't matter how logical it is; they're misusing the forum. There are also *malicious posts*, where someone posts not to learn more, but to cause harm to others, or to insult them, or to build consensus for wrongdoing against someone.

Since problems with logic are not the issue, bringing it up is a distraction, and implying that others do not care about logic is an insult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885475155.0" user="You_Yew_Ewe" delta="False">
    <text>I did not mean that to be insulting, but some people explicitly do not care about logic in principle. I was allowing that maybe you do not but pointing out many that use this forum do and they shouldn't be dismissed. Anyone is free not to engage with their arguments if their presentation is not interesting to you (You may not have noticed but I did a ninja edit depersonalizing the staetment realizing that might be interpreted as an attempt to insult). 

This actually brings up something relevant to the discussion, when people are worked up about or very emotionally invested in something they are, I think, all too quick to accuse people of being insincere who contradict their view.  I really think you should look out for that. you've already gone there with me.

Yes, truth tables may not be convincing, but I think the poster abovr may have been sincerely confused why you  don't seem to accept the usefulness of discussing conditional statements regardless of what's in people's hearts.

If you don't like questions that might make trans people excluded---and you made a statement that would definitely lead me to believe that's what this is about---you should maybe make that an explicit rule instead of trying to winnow the discussion down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885667781.0" user="philosophical_lens" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, truth tables may not be convincing, but I think the poster abovr may have been sincerely confused why you don't seem to accept the usefulness of discussing conditional statements regardless of what's in people's hearts.

Yes, I am the poster in question, and this is exactly my confusion. I was replying to [the comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/gxzjo77/) by /u/Ansuz07 which seemed to suggest that you cannot make posts about conditionals such as "If A then B" unless you actually believe B, which is a very confused (and IMO misguided) requirement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885709293.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't _quite_ what I meant, so if it came across that way I apologize.

It is permissible to post something like "If A then B" if your goal is to try and highlight inconsistencies between two similar position and try to understand why those consistencies do/don't make sense.    What we are trying to stop is people who post about B but _really_ are looking to make a point about A.

A good example that was brought up earlier was around an old post where someone was talking about wanting more regulations around cars.  As the conversation developed, it was clear that they were _really_ trying to make a point about gun control, and suggested more car regulations as a way of pointing out that gun control regulations were bad.  They didn't _really_ believe in more car regulations - they were using that to try and make a point about guns.

That is what we are trying to stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885839078.0" user="philosophical_lens" delta="False">
    <text>OK, thanks for clarifying, this makes a lot more sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885841066.0" user="You_Yew_Ewe" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, that's not about conditionals then, that's just about ole' switcheroos.

Thanks for clarifying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885519445.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm really sorry that you see those hurtful things on a regular basis.

This is a topic that has prompted a ton of discussion, both internal and external. It's a little bit of an [Eternal September](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_September) issue, where the regulars are sick to death of seeing these anti-trans threads, but the people posting them are posting them for the first time. And they do lead to people being educated and changing their minds. So how do we balance the potential good of giving people opportunities to overcome their biases and misconceptions against the potential harm of giving people with no intention of changing their views chances to soapbox? 

Right now where we're at is leaving them up and watching them as closely as we can for Rule B violations, enforcing the 24-hour duplicate topic rule, and having Fresh Topic Friday as a holiday from that and all other frequently repeated topics. It seems like the chance of education is outweighing the chance for soapboxing right now. And it's good to see in a lot of those threads that allies/cis people are taking some of the burden of emotional labor off of trans people. But yeah, it's not a perfect solution, and I'm sorry that this can be yet another place to be reminded that your identity is a political football.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885521510.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Eternal_September](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_September)** 
 
 &amp;gt;Eternal September or the September that never ended is Usenet slang for a period beginning in September 1993, the month that Internet service provider America Online (AOL) began offering Usenet access to its many users, overwhelming the existing culture for online forums. Before then, Usenet was largely restricted to colleges, universities, and other research institutions. Every September, many incoming students would acquire access to Usenet for the first time, taking time to become accustomed to Usenet's standards of conduct and "netiquette".
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | Credit: kittens_from_space)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887942823.0" user="PunDefeated" delta="False">
    <text>I’m mostly joking about this, but I am tired of transgender related questions here. So… Trans Tuesday mega thread? Put a list of all the previous transgender related CMVs in the sidebar and ask folks to read them before posting any additional ones?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36890257271.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Lol Trans Tuesday :)

Yeah, it's really hard to get people to read stuff. It probably doesn't help that reddit's search function for old posts is kinda janky. It would be cool to have the auto-mod comment with links to the top five related posts by keyword, but that would probably be a gigantic pain in the ass to code.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885821781.0" user="MegaBlastoise23" delta="False">
    <text>First I want to say I'm extremely sorry that these posts emotionally harm you in that way.

But second, these debates happen are a good for convincing those people. Hell people make posts all the time about how God isn't real and christians rightly feel offended at it as they and their conversations with God, and sometimes their life's purpose, is being called into question. Any "conversation" they've had with God is just insanity or them muttering to themselves. That their entire support structure is based on a lie. 

Debates can be hurtful. Sometimes that's how it goes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885854771.0" user="fubo" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be responding to someone else's comment, seeing as I didn't say the things you're responding to.

(Elsewhere in the thread, I used "CMV: Religion X is evil!" as an example of a waste-of-time post that generally comes down to venting hostility rather than expressing curiosity.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885996573.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you legitimately believe a religion is evil, it’s a good idea to make that known and welcome evidence to the contrary. There are, after all, good things and evil things, so what’s wrong with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889450082.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; (If every time you came to the sub, you saw a new collection of CMVs proposing that you are an insane fraud, how welcome would you feel?)

You mean "if every time I came; I saw a collection of CMVs that propose that a group I belong to is"—and that happens all the time and I don't really care.

CMV should not base its policies to avoid individuals getting hurt; views on here are negative of groups very often, and without that it can barely exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888779154.0" user="DallasTruther" delta="False">
    <text>Logically consistent? 

If it's a rectangle, it's a square.

If it's a square, it's a rectangle.

Compare those.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884603102.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>This is such an odd statement. I understand what you’re saying (sort of), but then how does one who believes both things to be equally INVALID get their view changed? 
Am I phrasing this correctly? I’m not sure I am. I’m trying to say that if someone finds the concept of transgender-ism invalid specifically because any other similar -ism with any factor other than gender is only ever viewed as invalid, how do they make a post on this sub to be convinced otherwise without having that post removed? 

Because the example you used is (to me; correct me if I’m wrong here) one of the exact things this sub would be useful for, as an enormous number of people honestly cannot understand why transgenderism is seen as valid when trans[anything else] is not. It’s basically the most common point of contention with the acceptance of trans identities (since  identifying, however sincerely, as another race, age, height, species, etc is universally rejected by the medical community and society at large).

So if the CMV was “transgenderism is a mental disorder because every other variant of trans[blank]ism is qualified that way. CMV” it would be okay? Because it shows the OP does NOT believe in both equally? It’s only if they are pretending both are valid while not believing that to be true that you would remove the post?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36884674099.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>To clarify, double standard posts (although we don't think they make terribly good posts) are still allowed. "If X is allowed, Y should also be allowed because argument ad absurdum" is still perfectly valid logic. What you're no longer allowed to do is that "Y should be allowed" while attempting to use the same rhetoric style you perceive as being used by the people that argue for X.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885997995.0" user="DunklerReiter" delta="False">
    <text>I think in many cases a trojan CMV is a post in which someone argues in favor for something they are disagreeing with but in a way that should show how absurd these views are and therefore, convince people to be against this issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886396357.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that's correct. But responders are forced by rules 1 and 3 (which are necessary in their own right) to engage with the view as it presented and not the subtext. That's why it's problematic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36888570086.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>To be transphobic one could just say "CMV: Just like you can't change race, you can't change gender" in which case they would be stating their belief.
"CMV: Because you CAN change gender, you can change race" when you really believe transgender people are invalid is Trojan horse, but it isn't a Trojan horse if you think you can change race.

It is also a Trojan horse if one is a large wooden horse with soldiers inside it sent as a gift to the city of Troy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36928124026.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>the most common one is parents should be forced to donate organs and blood to their children, as a way to arguet against abortion, when the person was against abortion in the first place, and enforced blood/organ donation  and is just trying to show pro life people as hypocrites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889506104.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>But this is not at all what you responded to.

The original phrasing was:

&amp;gt; 'If people can change their gender, then they should be allowed to change their race'.

Not:

&amp;gt; I believe people should be able to change their race, because they are able to change their gender

These two are _very_ different and the way your logic here works implies that the former phrasing should _always_ be allowed, whereas the latter should only be allowed if OP actually does believe that individuals should be able to change their race.

The former is an if/then logical statement and the latter is not. You can _clearly_ see in this thread and the responses that many of the criticisms immediately draw to truth tables and logical principes showing that most unerstand the difference well and consider it fundamental.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889658459.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>That's a very good point. In the latter case OP would smuggle in the equivalence of the cases and not let that to be challenged because they know that that's the weakest link in their argument, not the "Y should be allowed" part, while in the former case, people could try to present arguments why the logic from making X and Y equivalent does not work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885003997.0" user="AWFUL_COCK" delta="False">
    <text>I think the right way to phrase it would be: "CMV: X-ism is invalid for the same reasons that Y-ism is invalid."

There, you're not hiding your beliefs about either X or Y and you have properly centered the discussion around X rather than Y.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885832316.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's what I thought. I guess the general idea here is that people are making CMV posts that look genuine but are intended to show the responders the flaws in their logic (or make them question/explain why they believe X is valid but Y is not, as would be the case in the transgender/transracial question) but are not in essence sincere attempts to have the OP's views changed, and that is what's being targeted. 

I genuinely love this sub, and have learned a ton of interesting things just by reading various posts, so I don't even care if the questions are insincere given the value of the discussions that arise from them, but I can see how it must be an absolute ball ache to mod so whatever they feel they need to do is probably valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885433528.0" user="CovidLivesMatter" delta="False">
    <text>It's an If/Then logical statement.  The challenge is to divorce the two views, not to validate/invalidate either.

So like "CMV: If you justify abortion with "the right to body autonomy" then I can justify not getting the vaccine with my right to "body autonomy" 

In a proper CMV post, the meat of the view would be explaining why OP thinks these two statements are tied together and your response should explain why they're different.  The validity of wanting the vaccine or supporting abortion are superficial.

Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885768953.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>All right. Yes. That makes more sense to me. Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36885500459.0" user="sonofaresiii" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but then how does one who believes both things to be equally INVALID get their view changed?

If I'm reading you right, if someone believes both are invalid, then they do not sincerely hold the belief that both should be valid-- which is the hypothetical you proposed.

"People should not be allowed to do X OR Y" would be the sincerely held belief if they believe both to be invalid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886415893.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I'm reading you right, if someone believes both are invalid, then they do not sincerely hold the belief that both should be valid-- which is the hypothetical you proposed.

But that wasn't the hypothetical that was proposed.  

The hypothetical was "if X then Y", which is very different from "both X and Y are true".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886744382.0" user="sonofaresiii" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; one who believes both things to be equally INVALID

That is the sincerely held belief in the hypothetical proposed.

&amp;gt; The hypothetical was "if X then Y"

That is the hypothetical CMV proposed. The CMV does not reflect the sincerely held belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887169119.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The CMV does not reflect the sincerely held belief.

What?  How?  

The CMV proposed, and the sincerely held belief, is that "if X then Y".  How do two identical things somehow contradict?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887428004.0" user="sonofaresiii" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how to explain to you that two different things are not identical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887036968.0" user="jazaniac" delta="False">
    <text>because "invalid" ranges from "I don't understand it" to "I want to kill these people and am hiding that behind bad-faith questions". You really shouldn't allow the latter kinds of posts to proliferate anywhere. If you just want understanding you would have something more specific to ask about either topic and wouldn't be making the comparison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889712679.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>Are we really going to pretend that even a fraction of the people posting Trojan horse posts on CMV are harbouring murderous intent? Because I do not believe that for a second and think it’s ridiculous hyperbole. CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36892184494.0" user="jazaniac" delta="False">
    <text>Fascism is an inherently murderous ideology. Furthering it through crypto-propaganda is an action of murderous intent, however far down the line it takes for that to happen. Also you'd be surprised at the number of people on the internet who transparently advocate for the killing of undesirables, and imagine for every one of those there's a larger number of people who believe it but won't say it outright.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36898231298.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>If you say so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886313588.0" user="medeagoestothebes" delta="False">
    <text>I think i get it,  though could you clarify if I'm wrong, because this was tricky to unpack.  

Say the OP believes transgenderism is absurd because it is, to them equivalent to transracialism, which they also view as absurd. They believe that they are equally reasonable,  or rather,  equally unreasonable.

By phrasing their view this way,  they've focused discussion on the hypothetical equivalence of transracialism and transgenderism, but not the legitimacy of transgenderism,  which is the important thing to actually changing the OPs view. To change the stated view of OP, from a logical perspective,  one would need to prove that race and gender are not similar in their mutability (probably not the right word,  but i can't think of the right one) and/or legitimacy, while to change the OPs actual unstated view,  one would need to prove the legitimacy of trans individuals.  You're essentially banning a form of intentional miscommunication of views.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886405060.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Note that rule 1 requires commenters to disagree with OP's stated view, and rule 3 requires commenters to never accuse OP of being dishonest about their view. These rules both exist for good reasons in their own right, but interact terribly with this kind of post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886595134.0" user="lakotajames" delta="False">
    <text>If I were to convince the poster that there isn't an equivalence, that would be changing thier view, though, right? I understand where you're coming from, in that you want to argue against the unstated view, but the poster isn't being dishonest or hiding their view in this scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36890228110.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that the posters of those views will often not accept pointing out the bad equivalence as a changed view. From the OP: "These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886376267.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In others, the OP doesn’t really believe transracialism is a thing and is using it as a red herring to really talk about how transgenderism is unreasonable. They don’t relive believe that they are equally reasonable, but rather just want to talk about the former. That is what we are concerned about.

In the OP, the concern was "a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely".  

This doesn't fit that concern.  Transgenderism, transracialism, woke ideology, the inconsistency within woke ideology between how they treat transgenderism and how they treat transracialism, and the inconsistencies that abound in woke ideology are all tightly coupled ideas.  They are not "something else entirely".  

If someone says "If people can change their gender, then they should be allowed to change their race", they are not referring to transgenderism, transracialism, woke ideology, or logical inconsistencies in a "veiled" manner.  They are referring to them directly.  And it's not clear (just from that title) that they're attacking any of the above, except for logical inconsistencies.  

Banning discussions that are a veiled attack on something else entirely seems reasonable.  Preventing discussions from straying into very closely related topics is quite different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36886414463.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear, discussions about transracialism and potential parallels between that and trans issues is fine. What's not fine is stating that you believe transracialism is fine when really your dispute is with the entire concept of trans-anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36887115080.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>The hypothetical we're discussing is "transgenderism implies transracialism".  

It is not a statement that transracialism is fine.  It is not a statement that transracialism is not fine.  

It's a position which is compatible with being against trans anything.  But it's also compatible with pro trans anything, or with not knowing whether you're for or against these things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36921922128.0" user="6data" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're focusing on the wrong thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37013998984.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>It's not clear how I am supposedly focusing on the "wrong thing" for two reasons.  First, it's not clear what you think I'm focusing on that is in your opinion the wrong thing to focus on, and second, it's not clear what you think I should be focusing on instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37019353840.0" user="6data" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe [this reply](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/gy0srfx/) will help you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37020510838.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>That reply doesn't address what I'm talking about.  

I stated my case in [this post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/gy1722z/) above.  The reply you reference doesn't address that at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37024808490.0" user="6data" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't need to, that's my point. You're focused on the wrong things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37025202860.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're focused on the wrong things.

You've already refused to explain what you're talking about here.  So long as you continue not to explain what you mean, there is no point in attempting to reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37030525210.0" user="6data" delta="False">
    <text>It's like you have blinders on. It's not about the subjects you wish to discuss, it's about striving to discuss genuine views and genuine attempts to have those views changed. 

You're focused on an imaginary argument with imaginary people. No one's arguing for or against your [largely transphobic] views, they're establishing that this view is ***genuinely*** held and that you ***genuinely*** wish to have it changed. For example, if you want to argue that the death penalty is the same as abortion, go for it. If you want to start a disingenuous discussion about the death penalty in order to "trap" one side into acknowledging some metaphorical parallel, your post will be removed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37032523066.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No one's arguing for or against your [largely transphobic] views

And this, right here, is the problem.  

I don't have any transphobic views.  And I haven't expressed the views I do have on trans people in this thread.  

But this didn't stop you from leaping to the conclusion that, somehow, I must have "transphobic views".  

And it appears that the mods are doing this too.  That's worrying.  

&amp;gt; You're focused on an imaginary argument with imaginary people.

No, I'm focusing on how the mods said they would respond to an argument that frequently shows up on cmv.  This is a real argument with real people that shows up so frequently that many people are tired of it.  

&amp;gt; For example, if you want to argue that the death penalty is the same as abortion, go for it. If you want to start a disingenuous discussion about the death penalty in order to "trap" one side into acknowledging some metaphorical parallel, your post will be removed.

And how would you tell which one of these is the case?  

If we follow what the mods have said on the trans case, they would leap to the conclusion that it's "disingenuous" no matter what, and ban it accordingly.  

If we follow the way you've approached it, you'd leap the the conclusion that it was "disingenuous" based on no evidence.  

Based on your approach or the mods' approach, there is no difference between the two.  That's the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033317986.0" user="6data" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And this, right here, is the problem.

No it's not, it has nothing to do with anything. Your views are your views, the conversation isn't about that. 

&amp;gt;I don't have any transphobic views. 

Yes, and they happen to be transphobic. Irrelevant, and transphobic. 

&amp;gt;But this didn't stop you from leaping to the conclusion that, somehow, I must have "transphobic views".

You do. It's in the language you use and the way you speak about the subject and the people. This isn't a conclusion I'm "jumping" to, it's just a fact. Sorta like how racists say things like "13/52" and use other tells in their language. 

&amp;gt;And it appears that the mods are doing this too. That's worrying.

No. They're not. They've very clearly said they're not. Acknowledging your transphobia has almost nothing to do with whether your post would be removed. 

&amp;gt;No, I'm focusing on how the mods said they would respond to an argument that frequently shows up on cmv. This is a real argument with real people that shows up so frequently that many people are tired of it.

Yes. And if it's a ***real*** argument with ***real*** concerns (and follows all the other rules), it's almost certainly not an issue. 

&amp;gt;And how would you tell which one of these is the case?

They've very clearly stated that it's a judgement call. Why are you asking me to repeat the things already stated in this thread? Since you seem incredibly hung up on your transphobia, I linked an entirely unrelated example ***and*** gave you an entirely unrelated analogy. 

&amp;gt;If we follow what the mods have said on the trans case, they would leap to the conclusion that it's "disingenuous" no matter what, and ban it accordingly.

Disingenuous =! Transphobic

You can have shitty views, but they must actually be yours. Not some philosophical trap. 

&amp;gt;If we follow the way you've approached it, you'd leap the the conclusion that it was "disingenuous" based on no evidence.

Do you not know the difference between *"disingenuous"* and *"transphobic"*? You can be (and are) ***genuinely*** transphobic, that doesn't mean you're posting in bad faith. 

&amp;gt;Based on your approach or the mods' approach, there is no difference between the two. That's the problem.

There very much is. You're having an argument that literally does not exist. If you can continue this discussion without your ultra-focus on the transphobia, I'm more than happy to continue this discussion. Otherwise 
#**you continue to focus on the wrong things** 

and this conversation is going nowhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039763461.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, and they happen to be transphobic. Irrelevant, and transphobic.

And this is, as I pointed out last time, the problem.  

You are claiming that I have "transphobic views".  But I have *never* had transphobic views, much less expressed them here.  

So how did you get this idea?  It's not clear, and you won't say.  

But you think that, somehow, you leaping to an incorrect conclusion about views I don't hold and haven't expressed, somehow, magically, means that I can't discuss a contradiction in someone else's views by bringing up a logical implication.  Why?  It makes no sense.  

Also, if you attempt to accuse me of being transphobic again, I will report the rule-breaking insult to the mods.  

&amp;gt; Do you not know the difference between "disingenuous" and "transphobic"? You can be (and are) genuinely transphobic, that doesn't mean you're posting in bad faith.

This is evading the point.  You are accusing me of being "disingenuous" because you have leapt to the false conclusion that I am "transphobic".  There is no other reason for you to accuse me of being "disingenuous", nor for the mods to make the same claim in the hypotheticals they responded to.  

And when I point this out, you claim that I am "focusing on the wrong things".  

&amp;gt; It's in the language you use and the way you speak about the subject and the people.

Bullshit.  I have not disparaged trans people, and you know it.  

But it is precisely this bullshit that I think it would be revealing to discuss.  

You are trying to somehow read things into the way I speak, without saying why or how.  I can't see any logic to how either you or the mods have responded, but if we dig into the details here, I might finally discover what you're really trying to say.  

&amp;gt; If you can continue this discussion without your ultra-focus on the transphobia, I'm more than happy to continue this discussion.

But I don't have an "ultra-focus on the transphobia".  My objection translated perfectly to the other example you gave, and I'm perfectly happy to discuss that.  

To the extent that I'm focusing on the issue of transphobia, I'm only doing that in response to how you and the mods have acted.  The mods heard a hypothetical about trans people, presumably because it comes up frequently in cmv.  They then reacted illogically to it, and after having the bad logic pointed out to them, still persisted in the illogic of their position.  When you came along, you took much the same position, and now you're accusing me of "transphobia" based on my pointing out the bad logic.  

That is a bizarre reaction.  

I would like to know why the bizarre reactions have occurred, but if it is too emotional a topic for you, I would be happy to discuss the same logic in a different setting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36889438849.0" user="Shirley_Schmidthoe" delta="False">
    <text>This response seems problematic to me. Because OP never claimed in such a case to believe that anything is "a thing" merely that if one is accepted, so should the other.

The OP can very much  believe that both are wrong, but that if one is accepted, then so should the other.

I for instance believe that marriage is outdated as a legal idea and that governments should withdraw themselves from the concept entirely, but I also believe that _if_ governments allow one type of marriage, they should allow _all_ types—notwithstanding that I believe that they really should allow _no_ types of it.

I believe that if I make a CMV about this and say "If governments allow opposite sex marriage, they should also allow same sex", that this ia truly a view I hold, even if I believethat they should not allow marriage at all.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
