<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="142721845.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2cz0vp/cmv_a_line_from_a_recent_movie_that_people_love/">
    <title>CMV: A line from a recent movie that people love is actually terrible. ~~~Guardians of the Galaxy SPOILERS~~~ Don't count on particpants to use tags!</title>
    <original_poster>thefonztm</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here's a less serious topic for a CMV.

The line is: [SPOILERS: You have been warned](#s "We are Groot.")

I hate that line. In fact, I cringed when I heard it.

[SPOILERS](#s "Groot expresses itself through limit dialogue, why break this? I am groot would have been and equally moving response. The meaning is never in the words with groot. It's the expressions, the tone, the pacing. Why throw all that out for: *OMG! He only says 'I am Groot' but this is so intense he's learned/used a new word!*")

[SPOILERS](#s "Alternatively, why not silence? Maybe a look to Rocket? Some things are beyond words. Giving your life for your friends would easily fall in this category.")

So, I'll be open minded. Why is this a good line?

^(Also, the line was *miserably* obvious. I saw it coming so far away I think I was still watching the trailer.)

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27305065342.0" user="w41twh4t" delta="False">
    <text>I guessed the line before opening the topic. The point of the change was to illustrate the move from Groot's standard position toward the team. It's like if you say please or thank you in another language but on a more dramatic level. To repeat the line would illustrate individuality both on a literal linguistic level and the symbolic level of speaking his language instead of their language.

In dramatic terms it is a reverse of expectation and in a small way a character arc to illustrate change.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
