<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="142721845.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2cz0vp/cmv_a_line_from_a_recent_movie_that_people_love/">
    <title>CMV: A line from a recent movie that people love is actually terrible. ~~~Guardians of the Galaxy SPOILERS~~~ Don't count on particpants to use tags!</title>
    <original_poster>thefonztm</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here's a less serious topic for a CMV.

The line is: [SPOILERS: You have been warned](#s "We are Groot.")

I hate that line. In fact, I cringed when I heard it.

[SPOILERS](#s "Groot expresses itself through limit dialogue, why break this? I am groot would have been and equally moving response. The meaning is never in the words with groot. It's the expressions, the tone, the pacing. Why throw all that out for: *OMG! He only says 'I am Groot' but this is so intense he's learned/used a new word!*")

[SPOILERS](#s "Alternatively, why not silence? Maybe a look to Rocket? Some things are beyond words. Giving your life for your friends would easily fall in this category.")

So, I'll be open minded. Why is this a good line?

^(Also, the line was *miserably* obvious. I saw it coming so far away I think I was still watching the trailer.)

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27304627367.0" user="MonkeyButlers" delta="False">
    <text>While I generally agree that Groot should only say "I am Groot," that line would have been tonally wrong for the moment.  Before the movie I read up on Groot (I actually enjoy reading about comics more than reading the comics themselves) and understand that Groot is actually something of a genius and that while his vocabulary is limited to "I am Groot" he uses that vocabulary to express the full range of ideas for which other species use thousands of words.  

The problem is, that doesn't really come across in the film and it would be difficult to explain it without it being a piece of clunky exposition.  Instead, the only scene in which this idea is conveyed is played for laughs, the audience thinks that Rocket responding to Groot in different ways is actually Rocket just responding to his own thoughts and not that Groot is actually saying the things to which Rocket responds.  And that is fine, it totally fits the tone of the film, which is mostly an action-comedy.  The "we are Groot" line, on the other hand, isn't supposed to be funny and "I am Groot" in its place would have diminished the emotional impact of the scene and of Groot's sacrifice.  So, while in a world in which the audience of Guardians of the Galaxy is completely aware of the characters before they watch the film Groot should have said "I am Groot," that is not the world we live in and "We are Groot" is an acceptable alternative which helped the film connect to it's intended audience, people who have no idea who any of the characters are before the film starts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27304638154.0" user="thefonztm" delta="False">
    <text>Depending on how Vin delievered "I am Groot" I don't think it would have taken away from the scene.

For instance, take this scene from *The Iron Giant*.

http://youtu.be/3UkZOZIO63I?t=40s

With similar tone and supporting music I feel Vin could have pulled it off. If you didn't know, Vin also did the voice in the iron giant.

Even if it did come of funnily, there are such things as sad laughter.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
