<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010371367.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders

no, it really shouldn't be.

Company founders have values.  Shareholders should understand that, and can decide which companies to invest in based on that.

Investment should be a free market, too.  You shouldn't force your values upon publicly traded companies.  Investors have a choice.

https://www.nytimes.com/roomfordebate/2015/04/16/what-are-corporations-obligations-to-shareholders/corporations-dont-have-to-maximize-profits</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010378880.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Investment should be a free market, too.

Yeah definitely, I'm not arguing about this from a legal perspective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010402066.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>If company management is transparent about corporate values to investors, why would should they feel morally obligated to abandon those principles to make more money for their shareholders?

Isn't transparency and lack of personal conflict of interests enough?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
