<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010205754.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers.

Replacing workers is expensive and is time consuming, it can be cheaper to give a small semi-automatic wage increase that helps retain current employees than finding a new employee.

To replace my current job my employeer would likely have to pay recruiter fees which start at 5k (based on the salary). Then theres the lost work if a gap in my leaving and the new employee onboarding and signing bonuses are pretty standard (another ~5k)

If they know a 5k yearly bonus is likely to keep me it's cheaper than replacing me (starting at 10k)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010222934.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; retain current employees than finding a new employee

Notice, I did not argue against raising wages to help retain workers, I argued against raising wages solely for the moral reason of helping the workers financially if you are able to maintain the workers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010243909.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>These are basically the same thing, my employeer gives me additional benefits that help me, in turn that helps me stay with them. Generally happy employees are better employees, being known to help your employees helps a company recruit and attract better candidates. Theres a reason that there are places people compete to work at.

If you want the best employees you should be helping your employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010454684.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>What if I told you that they only say that it's to benefit workers, so the workers feel appreciated?

The same way that gun lobby groups frame  gun ownership as "freedom" and "rights" when it's really about selling expensive toys to satiate a manufactured fear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010465002.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What if I told you that they only say that it's to benefit workers, so the workers feel appreciated?

That's fine, just a white lie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010519473.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.  It's a white lie. no employers are actually paying employees more for purely altruistic motives.

It could something more straight forward like "pay employees more do they don't leave" and It can also be something for philosophical like "happy workers are productive workers." Or "providing performance incentives motivates workers" or "making employees feel valued gives employees a sense of ownership/pride in their work"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010532635.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;no employers are actually paying employees more for purely altruistic motives

Which should be the case</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010780149.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so it sounds like you are not contesting that. If you agree no employers actually do that, then why are you creating this whole discussion about it? 

My guess is you didn’t realize/think about the fact that employees don’t do it solely for altruistic reasons, and so if you aren’t going to contest that is true, then you should probably award a delta to whoever first brought that up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010811957.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about how people are expecting it to be otherwise, it's actually not the case all the time, but if it is what's happening than it should be that way...
However I'm talking about how people expect it to be different, like the fact that companies should pay more if they are getting more than enough profits which is wrong.. The whole reason I posted this was because I saw a post about a job offer where the pay was kind of low and people were scoffing/criticizing at it in the comments but really they shouldn't.. If that's what the company needs to offer to hire enough workers they shouldn't be expected to pay more than that amount</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010981262.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like it goes back to my point about how you can assign yourself whatever purpose you want, but others aren't obligated to recognize and respect it, let alone enshrine it as a moral duty.

The people who expect it to be different aren't confused about the company's self-interest calculus. They're just approaching the question with different starting values. Pointing out why a company acts the way it does doesn't really do anything to address their objections.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010681567.0" user="shouldco" delta="False">
    <text>If you hold out until people are literary about to quit then you will loose a lot of talent. Once I have started interviewing for jobs I have basically already quit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010696106.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't mean to hold out till last moment at all.. Just when you think it's time to raise wages because someone has been there long enough to "deserve it" I guess or inflation</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
