<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010902465.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Your view is obviously pretty reactionary, as opposed to an impartial assessment of reality, which is a poor way to start.

You've chosen to frame the situation only in terms of hard lined, negative restrictions instead of addressing the shifting variables at play in a positive and proactive manner.

And the whole "morality" angle is a red herring. Regardless of what moral structure you claim to believe it doesn't actually change the answers terribly much. You will still need to step off the pedestal of moral superiority at some point and deal with practical actions and their repercussions, none of which are significantly changed by claims of morality.

Trough out the thread so far you have, from your very first reply, already started walking your original view back further and further and provided clarifications that don't line up with the hard lined, negative and restrictive view that you originally wrote.

Wouldn't it be more accurate to say something along the lines of:

Employee pay should be determined by and is effected by a lot of factors including but not limited to:

1. Company profits
2. competitive recruitment and retention
3. employee morale
4. public opinion
5. industry standards
6. investor pay outs
7. government regulation

Because that's actually true and unarguable enough that it's literally taught that way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010942813.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>First of all number 7 shouldn't exist and number 4 is what I'm trying to change 1 and 6 are basically the point. Second the other 3 are basically what I Mena by enough workers as well as them being higher quality. I don't think I've moved the goal posts. I did edit the post to emphasize something many people didn't know I had already taken into account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011238542.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First of all number 7 shouldn't exist 

Ok? It does though. And it always has and always will exist in some form. So we're going to have to deal with it as a factor

All of these things are interconnected and have an effect on each other. That's why they should all be considered when deciding employee pay

You can't have profits and investor payouts without positive/neutral public opinion, adequate recruitment and good employee morale. If you treat your employees well and collaborate with the rest of your industry to maintain adequate standards than there will be less public insistence to increase regulations. They all effect one another.

It doesn't make sense to approach these relationships with a restrictive rule like you've proposed, when you can more accurately describe them this way. And again, this is how these things are *actually taught* and actually thought about in the real world. 

&amp;gt; I don't think I've moved the goal posts.

I haven't said that you did... What I did say is that you've walked your original view back further and further and provided clarifications that don't line up with the hard lined, negative and restrictive view that you originally wrote. Because you started your view as a negative, reactionary restriction instead of a flexible and more accurate description you have had to modify your view to fit into realistic situations proposed by people responding to you. If you go through and catalog all of the clarifications and caveats you've creatd/admitted to so far you are basically half way to what I'm saying anyway. So why say it the way you have?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
