<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010406562.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders

I think you might be misinformed about what causes a company's stock to rise for its shareholders. Companies that operate at high profit margins don't have a higher value than companies that operate at low profit margins. A company's value is much more about how big the company is than its profit margin. For example, Amazon operated at a loss for years while its stock price soared. Amazon didn't have a "moral duty" to maximize profits for its shareholders (for multiple reasons, but most obviously) because maximizing profit wouldn't have helped Amazon's shareholders at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010424878.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>No I understand that concept but for example... 

&amp;gt;Amazon operated at a loss for years while its stock price soared

That was also for profits in the form of capital appreciation due to growth and expansion of the company which is still valid</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010431254.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;capital appreciation due to growth and expansion of the company which is still valid

So how does paying low wages help a company expand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010445384.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>More profits means more capital to build new facilities, to make more profit to raise more capital and so on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010461353.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>Why would you use cash reserves from profit to build new facilities? That's not a good business model and not at all similar to what Amazon did. Amazon didn't even have profits. They expanded using investment capital to acquire other companies and build new facilities. Profit wasn't relevant in the slightest. In fact, if Amazon had insisted on being "profitable," they would have expanded much more slowly to the detriment of shareholders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010471276.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>They are trying to increase market share, non the less, this increases expected profits for the future</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010508947.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>What good would profits in the future do? And if they increased their market share exponentially without turning a profit, why do you think profits are so important for shareholders? 

If a company has a wide profit margin, that means it's not spending money very well. If the company's goal is to increase their market share/stock value, they should be reinvesting their revenue back into the company. There are a lot of ways to do that. Acquiring competitors is one, but a very common and very valid strategy for increasing market share is to develop/acquire talent. In fact, in competitive fields, companies go to great lengths to steal the best employees from each other for high wages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010527311.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What good would profits in the future do?

Lol, in the future maybe 2032  you will become a multi millionaire doesn't that make you happy? Plus capital appreciation ofcourse 

&amp;gt;In fact, in competitive fields, companies go to great lengths to steal the best employees from each other for high wages

Best way to naturally raise prices of wages, I support that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010542636.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Lol, in the future maybe 2032 you will become a multi millionaire doesn't that make you happy?

I meant, what good do profits do for shareholders? Obviously profits can be distributed to the CEO and upper management of the company, just like they can be distributed to anyone in the company. But what exactly does a large profit margin do for shareholders (except signify that the company isn't expanding as much as it could be)? 

&amp;gt;Best way to naturally raise prices of wages, I support that

Then you support companies raising wages voluntarily. Do you think that there's some other "way" that companies raise wages voluntarily?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010565040.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;
I meant, what good do profits do for shareholders? Obviously profits can be distributed to the CEO and upper management of the company, just like they can be distributed to anyone in the company. But what exactly does a large profit margin do for shareholders (except signify that the company isn't expanding as much as it could be)? 


It's a company choice, expansion or divideds 


&amp;gt;Then you support companies raising wages voluntarily. Do you think that there's some other "way" that companies raise wages voluntarily?

Nope, that's them raising wages due to competitive behavior, if they don't raise wages in that case they lose workers
I'm talking volantarily, if you read the post it says that would be the company doing it solely for the benefit of the worker not because they have to compete</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010588071.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;solely for the benefit of the worker

It's impossible to do something solely for the benefit of a worker. A worker produces value for the company, so if you raise wages/improve your workforce then of course you'll improve the company. 

&amp;gt;It's a company choice, expansion or divideds 

Sure, but you seem to be under the impression that dividends are the only way to benefit shareholders. Your whole argument is that you can't *possibly* be doing the best thing for your shareholders if you choose expansion instead of dividends. I'm saying you can. 

Also, some companies are employee-owned. In those companies, wages and dividends are the same thing. So voluntarily raising wages is the same thing as producing dividends for shareholders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010618310.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A worker produces value for the company, so if you raise wages/improve your workforce then of course you'll improve the company. 

Up to a certain point, afterwards it's like refusing to pay lower than a specific amount for your electric bill.. That point may be $12,and if so it would mean raising wages from $10 to $12 would help the company but raising from $12 to $15 would decrease profits.. In that case the wage shouldn't be raised even if it's to provide a so called "living wage" for example 

&amp;gt;Sure, but you seem to be under the impression that dividends are the only way to benefit shareholders. Your whole argument is that you can't possibly be doing the best thing for your shareholders if you choose expansion instead of dividends.

I guess I meant either 

&amp;gt;
Also, some companies are employee-owned. In those companies, wages and dividends are the same thing. So voluntarily raising wages is the same thing as producing dividends for shareholders.

Well yeah I'm not addressing those companies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010679245.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That point may be $12,and if so it would mean raising wages from $10 to $12 would help the company but raising from $12 to $15 would decrease profits

What if raising wages from $12 to $15 causes the profit margin to fall, but gives the company the edge over the competition which results in increased expansion/market share? 

None of what I'm talking about is a hypothetical. That's why I chose Amazon as an example. There are almost zero companies that have done better for their shareholders than Amazon. Amazon has created value for their shareholders by acquiring/expanding, not by operating at a profit. Amazon has also voluntarily raised wages. I'm extremely amused that out of all the legitimate things you could have criticized Amazon for, you're trying to criticize them for...not being good enough to their shareholders. Like, I'm not sure how else to tell you that reality simply doesn't line up with your opinion. Are you aware that Amazon stock has gone up by over 1200% in the last ten years? Why exactly do you think that Amazon hasn't made good choices for its shareholders? 

Further, Amazon's biggest threat right now is low quality control. How do you think Amazon should address that? By paying people starvation wages and hoping that they magically perform their jobs perfectly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010726890.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;not being good enough to their shareholders.

What??? I didn't criticize them for that, what??? They deserve credit for that!


&amp;gt;What if raising wages from $12 to $15 causes the profit margin to fall, but gives the company the edge over the competition which results in increased expansion/market share? 

It can't, it's like paying extra for an electric bill, at some point you'll get the maximum quality work for a certain wage where raising wages doesn't increase quality because the job is just too simple and not complicated. $10 might cause a small pool of applicants to choose from while $12 might cause it to quadruple.. If you only need 10% of the applicants anyways having a $15 wage might only make it so you need 0.2% of the applicants.. You already have a large enough pool to choose from at $12.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010776432.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What??? I didn't criticize them for that, what??? They deserve credit for that!

You disagree with all of their decisions. Do you think Amazon would have done better for their shareholders if they had followed your ideas? If so, you're criticizing them for that. 

&amp;gt;$10 might cause a small pool of applicants to choose from while $12 might cause it to quadruple.. If you only need 10% of the applicants anyways having a $15 wage might only make it so you need 0.2% of the applicants..

It's not just about having a large pool to choose from. It's also about reducing turnover and developing the talent you have. 

Let's say you run your business at $12 and I run mine at $15. You enjoy a slightly higher short term profit margin. But your workers keep leaving and you waste a lot of time and money training new ones. The applicants you have are qualified, but most people at your company have only been with you for six months on average. My employees are experts at their jobs because they've been with the company for years. Eventually I acquire your company. 

If that sounds far fetched, just change the name of your company to whole foods (or any of a hundred other companies) and the name of mine to Amazon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010839301.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You disagree with all of their decisions

I don't think I did man, different investors want different thinas, security, high risk/high reward, stable dividends and capital appreciation is definetely one of them

&amp;gt;It's not just about having a large pool to choose from. It's also about reducing turnover and developing the talent you have. 

Notice, a job that has a 10% acceptance rate for applicants probably won't have that much of a problem with turn over rate, especially if wages are raised with experience(for the sole of keeping workers thus helping the company) 

&amp;gt;If that sounds far fetched,

Not gonna lie I didn't get that last part I apologize</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010875174.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think I did man

The title of your post is something Amazon has done multiple times. 

&amp;gt;Notice, a job that has a 10% acceptance rate for applicants probably won't have that much of a problem with turn over rate

A job with higher wages will have even less of a problem. A job that accepts whoever walks in the door won't have "that much" of a problem with quality control, but they'll still get put out of business by a company that has better employees. A job that has safety violations won't have "that much" of a problem with employees dying but they'll still get shut down. I'm not sure what "that much" of a problem is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010911918.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The title of your post is something Amazon has done multiple times. 

&amp;gt;

No, They were pressured by politicians 

&amp;gt;A job with higher wages will have even less of a problem

At some point it becomes a non problem 

&amp;gt;but they'll still get put out of business by a company that has better employees

the market price for low skilled  labor in a given locality is the usually similar.. Whatever is enough to incentivize enough workers to join the workforce usually or a bit higher for "harder jobs" maybe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010947942.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No, They were pressured by politicians 

This is a weird take. Politicians are tripping over each other to offer Amazon the biggest tax incentives, not "pressuring" them. Also, are you saying that Amazon stock would have risen more than 1200% if they had paid their employees even less? That's the same thing as criticizing Amazon. And of course, Amazon is advertising constantly for new hires. That doesn't exactly sound like a company that got pressured to raise wages for no reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010993409.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;This is a weird take. Politicians are tripping over each other to offer Amazon the biggest tax incentives, not "pressuring" them.

It was Bernie sanders and ro Khanna, this is a fact not up for debate.. Yes other politicians did other things but that doesn't change that they were pressured 

&amp;gt;. Also, are you saying that Amazon stock would have risen more than 1200% if they had paid their employees even less?

Again it's a balancing game, companies need to raise wages for their own sake but up to a certain point it just becomes like refusing to pay less than a certain amount for your electric bill.. Keywords(up to a certain point), and my whole post is about how people shouldn't expect companies to go over that point solely for the sake of workers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011093991.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;my whole post is about how people shouldn't expect companies to go over that point solely for the sake of workers

Was there something you wanted to have your view changed on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011121866.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't really expecting it to change... I saw a post about a job offering and people were ridiculing the pay. I was like if that's the amount they need to offer to hire what they needed than they shouldn't be blamed for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011148620.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, okay. This sub isn't really a place for just soapboxing. The idea is that you should be open to changing your view, hence the name of the sub. 

If people were ridiculing the pay offered for a job, what is that to you? Either the pay is competitive and the people are unreasonable, or the pay is not competitive and the company is unreasonable. There's no reason to assume that it's one or the other without context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011175092.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;open to changing your view,

I'm open to it, just didn't expect it to happen 

&amp;gt;what is that to you?

just that they were expecting they company for some reason to care about the workers when they shouldn't be expected to unless it's in their own self interest.. But other than that nothing they have the right to say whatever</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011226457.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;they shouldn't be expected to unless it's in their own self interest..

Caring about workers is always in the employer's self interest. 

&amp;gt;But other than that nothing they have the right to say whatever

Everyone has the right to say whatever they want to. If a company is begging for a front end web developer to come work for $9/hr, of course they'll get made fun of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011710198.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>You can expect a thing in a descriptive sense or in a normative sense, and the two are often different. I think you and the people you're talking about are having two tangentially related conversations past each other. They're making a moral judgment that a company ought to have different values. You're arguing that it would be a poor self-interest calculus under their current values.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
