<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010325425.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>I can think of a few situations where it makes business sense:

1. Companies that are either partially or entirely employee-owned may decide to increase wages instead of expanding, increasing share price, or dividend payouts.  It distributes the excess revenue differently than those other options and the employee-owners may prefer that as a way to more immediately put money in their pockets than other options.

2.  Increasing wages decreases turnover.  There is a cost associated with onboarding new employees.  Even when a company already pays above the market average, there will still be employees that end up leaving over one frustration or another.  In some cases, an employee may pursue a career shift that takes them to an unrelated field that pays more.  By increasing wages, this reduces the desire for these employees to leave and in the end reduces the overhead cost of onboarding new employees.

3.  Sometimes there isn't a market to expand into.  Growing the company wider would be a poor decision because there are not additional customers to bring in.  However, the existing clientele might be willing to pay more.  So, a business expansion comes in the form of raising prices rather than selling more product.  From a marketing standpoint, this increase in price might be easier to swallow if it is justified by an increase in wages, even if the total increase in revenue outpaces the increase in payroll.  For example, some businesses will charge their clients based on man-hours.  The actual pay the employees receive is only a percentage of what is charged to the client, and if that percentage is kept consistent, an increase in pay means and an even greater increase of the bill to the client.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
