<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010641397.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've posed this in a very challenging way, because most of the reasons to arbitrarily increase wages come with a business reason - hiring better workers, retaining workers etc.  I don't disagree that there is a moral drive for boards of directors/managers of a company to maximise profits of their shareholders. However there are a few further issues:

Companies and businesses form part of society. They are subject to the same costs and benefits as other stakeholders in that society - they enjoy the use of public services, but have to abide by the law etc.

As a part of society they are also bound by the morals of that society. In some cases this is enshrined in the law, and others it is not. But  a company cannot survive if it outrages the morals of the society in which it exists: it relies on that society existing and that society engaging to consume its product or service. 

Taking an extreme example - let's say a company gets an extra 1% profit every time it kills a child. It would be immoral for the board of directors to authorise a child killing strategy. Even if this could be kept secret, and there would be no consequences  the competing morality of not killing children overwhelms the morality of continuing to secure a profit. 

If you accept that then the increasing wages is a matter of degree - it is immoral for a company to not pay workers anything - right?  That is to say even if it wasn't illegal it would be immoral to use slave labour. So how much pay is moral? Is it always exactly what the market decides? No - not if that causes people harm. We can debate about how low a wage is harmful and whether that is below the minimum wage in the US or UK etc, but there must be a line between slavery and fair pay that is immoral but not nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010687550.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Taking an extreme example - let's say a company gets an extra 1% profit every time it kills a child. It would be immoral for the board of directors to authorise a child killing strategy. Even if this could be kept secret, and there would be no consequences the competing morality of not killing children overwhelms the morality of continuing to secure a profit. 

I'm talking about maximizimg profits without agression


&amp;gt;If you accept that then the increasing wages is a matter of degree - it is immoral for a company to not pay workers anything - right?

It's not immoral to offer zero pay, you just won't get any workers, but if someone volantarily agrees to work for nothing than no It's not immoral 

&amp;gt;So how much pay is moral?

There is no specific amount, whatever amount allows you to hire enough workers is the right amount</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010763020.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>You are arbitrarily adding in aggression post-fact. Why? If a company only has a singular moral drive then it MUST do ANYTHING to maximise a profit. Why not aggression? That is surely a tacit acceptance that companies have some other moral responsibility than profit. And if they should not do harm in that way, why should they do harm by paying exploitative wages. 

Also slavery exists.

It was the most financially viable way for a company to make profit when it was available as an option. And it was legal.  By your standard, a company MUST take on slaves if possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010783967.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are arbitrarily adding in aggression post-fact. Why?

One sort of assumes people already understand that concept 

I'm talking about passively doing what's in your own interest, so polluting the environment is agression as well

&amp;gt;And if they should not do harm in that way, why should they do harm by paying exploitative wages. 

It's not harm since you can accept or refuse the offer, you aren't coerced (if you say maybe some people are coerced because they need the money my response is that's not the fault of the company)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010894559.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One sort of assumes people already understand that concept

That companies have a moral obligation not to cause harm? But that contradicts what you said - that they only have a singular moral obligation - to profit. And you haven't explained why they shouldn't actively do harm, you've just said that I should understand that they shouldn't.

And it is harm. The company is at fault if people come to harm because they pay an exploitative wage. They are acting immorally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010969329.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But that contradicts what you said - that they only have a singular moral obligation - to profit.

I didn't post to state the obvious however 

&amp;gt;And it is harm. The company is at fault if people come to harm because they pay an exploitative wage.

Wages are prices set by supply and demand. Nothing to do with exploitation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010999520.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>"the obvious" directly contradicts your viewpoint. And you haven't addressed how you can reconcile that  contradiction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011028514.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"the obvious" directly contradicts your viewpoint.

You've got to be kidding me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011044323.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>Companies have a moral obligation to make profits. Immoral acts can make more profits. Companies should not do immoral acts. Companies therefore have a moral obligation beyond making a profit. Why does that not extend to voluntarily paying a fair wage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011058561.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Because I can offer you whatever I want and if you accept it no matter how horrible a deal that is than I'm not to blame</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011168568.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>I am destitute. You offer me a straw bed in a hovel and meagre gruel twice a day to work in a mine for 18 hours a day. I have no education or other skills. You are not acting imorrally?

I need to take a loan to pay for my child's healthcare. You offer to let me pay it back by working 12 hour shifts doing security at a nightclub you own without additional pay. That is indentured servitude and is both immoral and illegal.

I am an immigrant living with my sick mother in London. I have no access to transport, and my mother relies on me to take care of her daily needs. You offer me a job at minimum wage. This is insufficient to pay for rent and food but I have no option to accept the job. In order to get the job I have to a day long trial interview where I work without pay. I choose to do this, because I have little choice. Is this immoral? Working interviewss have recently been made illegal. Are they immoral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011232171.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>



&amp;gt;I am destitute. You offer me a straw bed in a hovel and meagre gruel twice a day to work in a mine for 18 hours a day. I have no education or other skills. You are not acting imorrally?

You're ignoring business competition that lets that virtually impossible to happen without the business going bankrupt 

&amp;gt;I am an immigrant living with my sick mother in London. I have no access to transport, and my mother relies on me to take care of her daily needs. You offer me a job at minimum wage. This is insufficient to pay for rent and food but I have no option to accept the job. In order to get the job I have to a day long trial interview where I work without pay. I choose to do this, because I have little choice. Is this immoral? Working interviewss have recently been made illegal. Are they immoral?

Why is it the businesses job to make sure your needs are met if your productivity doesn't justify the pay?



Charity and NGOs are important also</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011306527.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>You missed the point on the second one: is an unpaid interview that requires a day of work moral if it is a choice of the interviewee?

Also business competition doesn't stop that shit. What about the near slaves working on construction in Qatar for the world Cup? Or countless other examples of desperate people working for just above subsistence.

Legislation is what prevents indentured servitude, businesses benefit from it.

I think I've demonstrated that there are circumstances where businesses should not exploit the opportunity to pay less than a fair wage. That it is morally wrong for them to do so, regardless of business reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011408709.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You missed the point on the second one: is an unpaid interview that requires a day of work moral if it is a choice of the interviewee?

Yeah, if you accept it and it isn't forced upon you 

&amp;gt;Also business competition doesn't stop that shit.

It does, worked in a state where minimum wage was $7.25 and was being paid $15 for a low skilled job

&amp;gt;What about the near slaves working on construction in Qatar for the world Cup?

I would need to look into that but my guess is because they don't get citizenship and therefore have a hard time finding regular jobs, so it would be government's fault in that case
I really need to look into it though but you gotta remember the world is fucked up more in countries with less economic freedom so not surprised even though it's a rich country 

&amp;gt;Legislation is what prevents indentured servitude,

Increased productivity in the economy is what guarantees is followed by comoetetion
Government can declare anything a right but if you don't have the infrastructure to support it it's useless, ink on paper and government is too dumb to understand it

&amp;gt;I think I've demonstrated that there are circumstances where businesses should not exploit the opportunity to pay less than a fair wage

One situation where I agree with you, it's called monopsonies, there I think careful government intervention might be needed and only on localities not federally or at the state level either but other than that as a general rule no. (monopsonies are rare also so usually even localities shouldn't interfere)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
