<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010184119.0" user="dontwannabearedditor" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but youre coming from the assumption that it's a good thing that a company's duty is to generate profit for shareholders. It's not, it's fucked up. So that's why it's good to raise wages lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010233685.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>That's the sole purpose of starting a business, it's to get as much return as possible on your investment and it's what incentivizes people to start a business in the first place, so their entitled that the company they own does the best that can to maximize profits</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010283830.0" user="dontwannabearedditor" delta="False">
    <text>You must be a miserable person if you think this is the only thing that could possibly motivate someone to start a business. 
Many people do it to turn a hobby into a job. Or because their life situation (ie. many children or young siblings, disability, travelling, time consuming hobbies) requires more flexible hours than a wage job could ever provide. Others start businesses because they want to change the world by introducing innovative products they feel could benefit others. Some start businesses because they enjoy the lifestyle associated with those businesses (like they like the idea of owning a book store, or a water tram, or whatever). 


Most people have a life, feelings, and motivations that extend beyond financial profit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010286340.0" user="ProLifePanda" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's the sole purpose of starting a business, it's to get as much return as possible on your investment

That is normally the MAIN goal, but is hardly ever the only goal. Some employers WANT their employees to also be happy, or provide a valuable service to the community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010291457.0" user="YourViewisBadFaith" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's the sole purpose of starting a business

Wow, we should really abolish this terrible system then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010300250.0" user="abcd123np" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize there is a cost of turnover and a cost of replacing employees who aren’t happy? Wage is just one factor. If I raise someone’s salary who has been doing the job for 5 years because it’ll make them happy and they stay I avoid incurring the cost of hiring someone new, training them, having slower pace of work as they learn, incur costs of mistakes and errors etc. Yes, the goal is to maximize profit but that doesn’t necessarily mean minimize wages. 

I’ve raised peoples wages constantly for taking on more work (cheaper to bump someone up $20k than it is to hire a whole new person), going above and beyond on their targets and the profit they generate for the company. (Sales person A needs to generate $500k profit. They generate $2m of course I’m paying them extra because the $1.5m disappears if they leave and my next person might only deliver the $500k or maybe $1m only) 

Maximizing profits doesn’t mean minimizing wages per se. they’re only one factor in the equation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010333404.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;. If I raise someone’s salary who has been doing the job for 5 years because it’ll make them happy and they stay I avoid incurring the cost of hiring someone new, training them, having slower pace of work as they learn, incur costs of mistakes and errors etc.

Yes I understand that, it's why I edited the post.. Raise wages if you need to, not solely because of the supposed moral reason of wanting to help workers financially</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010392791.0" user="abcd123np" delta="False">
    <text>They do kinda go hand in hand….. financially supporting them up front allows me to retain them. People prefer to work for a boss that will have their backs. 
If my employees get to the point of having to demand a higher wage or quit, I’ve failed. The majority of people who receive counter offers to stay leave within 6 months anyways. They got to the point of no return and they were/are unhappy enough to quit on me. That’s a failure on my part as a CEO. 

So, while the wage rising isn’t out of some “moral” reason as you put it, but rather my intention to retain them the two are interconnected. We will offer wage increases for things such as inflation, merit increases, overachieving on financial targets, we’ve even given people more leave or paid extra because of their medical needs. Again, I didn’t do this because it’s the “moral” thing to do, I did it because I know it will make my employee happier and therefore she won’t leave. But you can see how the two intertwine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010341624.0" user="illogictc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it's to get as much return as possible on your investment

Source on seeking absolute maximum profit always? If this were true you wouldn't have companies that use "we still do this or that by hand" as a selling point when automation exists for it. They wouldn't pay dividends. They would always use the cheapest grades of materials instead of like DeWalt and other handtool makers who use glass fiber reinforced nylon for tool clamshells, or companies speccing stainless steel fasteners when regular steel might be okay to get away with. They wouldn't donate t charities, they wouldn't host company picnics, they wouldn't pay hardly shit into your 401(k) matching.

The point of offering higher wages is to attract and retain more and better talent. High turnover can be detrimental to companies as they get stuck in a cycle of constantly paying for training costs, constantly having a lot of staff who cannot reasonably be expected to put out at the expected rate because they're still under their hiring probationary period, and as their more local labor pool is exhausted as people leave for better pay they can have a harder time filling positions. If you can't fill positions to get the job done then you can't make money. Thus it is long-term beneficial to a company from a profit standpoint to compete on wages instead of paying bottom dollar always. To this end they're willing to do things like pay night shift differentials, having your factory run 24 hours a day even if the labor cost is slightly higher for half of it is long-term beneficial as you are maximizing the use of your investment on millions of dollars of equipment instead of leaving it idle and open the door to putting out up to twice as much product (meaning twice as many sales, a whole lot more $$$).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010361590.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what you're talking about in the first paragraph, what?
They'll do whatever is needed to increase profits

&amp;gt;They wouldn't donate t charities

They shouldn't! 

&amp;gt;they wouldn't pay hardly shit into your 401(k) matching.

They should only do that if they need to, to become more competitive and incentivize more people to agree to work for them so they never have a labor shortage(especially quality labor)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011722072.0" user="illogictc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They'll do whatever is needed to increase profits

Again, source? I listed a bunch of stuff that actively eats into profits yet *companies still do it.* perhaps you're cherry-picking some singular example as representative of "companies" as a whole but that's not the way the real world works. They throw money at things all the time, and skip out on potential other profits like for example by not automating when automation exists already for the process. In my industry, literally almost everything that happens besides pulling raw material off the shelves and loading finished product into a trailer already has automation available. There are whole machining centers that do all the fabrication automatically in addition to doing the material cuts and just spit out ready-to-use pieces that there exists automation for taking those pieces and assembling them automatically, I'm talking zero human intervention required. This stuff exists, it's an obvious boost to throughput and overall quality, but we don't do it. We don't even Bill ourselves like Rolls Royce going "look guys it's all hand-assembled so it deserves top dollar!" we don't even compete on the high end of the market, we're low to mid grade. Every few years machine makers introduce new equipment with quicker cycle times and all that too which can drastically increase throughput too, but we're clinging to our 20-year-old machines that go half as fast even though they've paid for themselves about 15 years ago. So again I ask, where is your source that every company will always maximize profit always? Even infamous "maximize profits" Amazon is offering a minimum of $15/hr for all positions, even in places where the minimum wage does not specify anything anywhere close.

There's a point to increasing wages to be "livable" and for the good of employees. It's competing. If they don't, what if the guys across town do? Well there goes all the labor to the other shop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011886409.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They throw money at things all the time, and skip out on potential other profits like for example by not automating when automation exists already for the process. In my industry, literally almost everything that happens besides pulling raw material off the shelves and loading finished product into a trailer already has automation available. There are whole machining centers that do all the fabrication automatically in addition to doing the material cuts and just spit out ready-to-use pieces that there exists automation for taking those pieces and assembling them automatically, I'm talking zero human intervention required. This stuff exists, it's an obvious boost to throughput and overall quality, but we don't do it.

Okay it just wouldn't make sense for them not to due it, I mean I don't know though you tell me, are they planning to. In the future? Are there any obstacles? Is it not worth the amount of money that will be saved? So many factors, but they should be doing what will save them the most money, I worked at a fulfillment warehouse and I was about a month or two from having my job automated and I could see them placing the infrastructure for the new machinery and all that, but in your situation I simply don't know what factors were affecting their decisions. Maybe investors are collecting profits rather than reinvesting which is a valid choice 

&amp;gt;So again I ask, where is your source that every company will always maximize profit always?

I'm saying it's immoral not do so for the sake of workers, not that it happens
.. Btw it could just be the case that in your situation investors are collecting profits rather than reinvesting so that's a possibility ofcourse 

&amp;gt;Even infamous "maximize profits" Amazon is offering a minimum of $15/hr for all positions, even in places where the minimum wage does not specify anything anywhere close.

Yeah I was getting paid the same for a low skilled job, and minimum wage was 7.25...I guess competetion works huh
Also, Amazon was pressured to raise from $13 to $15 due to political pressure by Bernie sanders and ro Khanna 

&amp;gt;There's a point to increasing wages to be "livable" and for the good of employees. It's competing. If they don't, what if the guys across town do? Well there goes all the labor to the other shop.

Exactly but my point is what if it only increases it up to a point that isn't "livable".. My whole point is that society shouldn't expect it to raise any more than it needs to regardless of worker needs.. Honestly this last paragraph is my which you're reading right now is my central point and most important</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37017084590.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>Let's expand on that last paragraph since it's the most central part. At the moment you've told us that you believe a business exists to generate profit but you haven't really given us any insight into why you think it's immoral to expect anything else. There's really no other context where a person or group can simply point to their self-assigned purpose and all consideration for how they treat others disappears.

You're talking about what society should or shouldn't expect as if society isn't allowed to have its own goals and purpose that aren't always the same as those of a business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010338748.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>USSR would be proud of that answer! Carry forward comrade!

No but seriously there is 2 lawn management companies. One employs 300 people to cut grass with scissors. The other employs 10 to cut grass with a lawn mower. One prioritizes giving people work even if its extremely inefficient. One prioritizes profit and is thus far more efficient.

Incentivizing profit forces the system to do things efficiently. Which in turn creates way more products. Which in turn improves the quality of life for everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010363323.0" user="dontwannabearedditor" delta="False">
    <text>you think thats a diss but i am literally enrolled in the polish socialist party.... lol


your metaphor is reductive and misses the point. the argument isnt about providing people with work, but instead about paying them fairly for the work they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010682437.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Ahh well that makes perfect sense then.

Alright Mr Polish Socialist member. Ironic considering how much Poland suffered from imposed communism. But I am genuinely curious about your answer on this question.

I live in Ukraine and I was born in USSR. So not that far from you actually. I think we would both agree that the economic system in USSR failed miserably. We probably wouldn't agree on why though. Otherwise you wouldn't be a socialist party member. 

How can socialism properly incentivize SYSTEMS (not people) to behave in an efficient manner? The way capitalism accomplishes this is by using peoples greed. Greedy people are good if they act in a way that benefits the larger society. By privatizing companies you allow that same greed to direct the policies of the companies. Which in turn forces the entire economy to innovate/optimize every single facet. This just doesn't happen in communism. Hence the reason why Poland, Ukraine and Russia had horrific economies compared with the west.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010776002.0" user="dontwannabearedditor" delta="False">
    <text>i literally did not ask to debate with you 😭</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
