<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010270780.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders

I disagree. Maximizing profit for it's shareholders is a financial responsibility, but not a moral duty. The *moral* duty of every company is to provide the highest quality goods/services to society while providing for its employees. There is zero *moral* duty to the shareholders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010308794.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The moral duty of every company is to provide the highest quality goods/services to society

Wrong, that is only the means by which they can achieve highest returns on investment 

&amp;gt;while providing for its employees.

That shouldn't be a priority, labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010332943.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Wrong, that is only the means by which they can achieve highest returns on investment

Wrong. Making money is *NEVER* a moral act unless you believe personal wealth has a higher value than human life and societal well being, which would essentially make you a sociopath. You used the word *moral,* which completely changes how you ought to look at a business. Most businesses are amoral or immoral entities. They are not seeking to do what is right or just. Wanting to make money is an amoral act. Exploitative practices are immoral. Using your goods and services to provide the most benefit to society is the only morally justifiable goal of a business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010530845.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is a very odd view of capitalism. 

A person who manages a company is entrusted to take the money of investors/shareholders and work in good faith to promote the success of the company and maximise the benefits to the shareholders. 

It would be immoral for a board of directors to take the money from shareholders (lets say a pension fund for disable veterans) and then to pay all the employees three times the market rate for their labour without a good business reason (lets say, in this case, the initial salary is above a living wage, and the new salaries are massively in excess of that). Particularly if it ended up that the company lost money, had no profit, the share price fell and the investment (which, remember, was going to pay the pensions of disabled veterans, and was made from their contributions from their salaries for which they worked honestly) became worthless. 

Many people live in capitalist societies where there is a moral incentive for people who manage companies to maximise profits.  It doesn't matter who the shareholder is - the board of directors have a moral responsibility to them.  You could argue that there is a competing moral value to not exploit workers, and that this should supersede any other moral drive, but it is not immoral or amoral for a board of directors to direct a company to make a profit - under capitalism.

This is why moral decisions should not be entrusted to corporations or businesses. Baseline rules for ethical treatment of workers must be enforced from a societal or governmental level, even in the most bare-faced capitalist society. 

NB I'm not saying this is good - I think this system drives economic inequality and suffering, but this is through a failure to properly regard the competing moral aims of corporations, and the blatant benefits of using the moral aim of maximising benefit for shareholders to justify horrendously immoral acts - pharma companies, here's looking at you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010659640.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this is a very odd view of capitalism.

It's not a view of capitalism. It's a moral position. 

&amp;gt;A person who manages a company is entrusted to take the money of investors/shareholders and work in good faith to promote the success of the company and maximise the benefits to the shareholders.

No. Investors see a company and put money into it in the *hopes* that they make more money out of it. Just like how I go up to a Blackjack table in the *hopes* that I get a blackjack. It's a gamble, and gambling is amoral. If the investors have expectations that a company will act solely to make them more money, then that is on them, not the company. Companies have *zero* moral responsibility to investors. It's their company and they can run it how they want. The investors can either trust that they will run it in a way that pays dividends or not. The only exception to this would be if there is a signed contract between a company representative and a specific investor that a specific amount of money would be used for a specific thing. But, last I checked, when I buy stocks there is no such contract. 

&amp;gt;It would be immoral for a board of directors to take the money from shareholders

Actually, no. It's perfectly moral for a board of directors to do literally anything they want with the money. They could blow it all on doughnuts and be well within their moral right to do so. The reason they *don't* do that is because then nobody would invest in them ever again. This has nothing to do with moral obligations, only a mutual understanding that both parties want to make more money.

&amp;gt;Many people live in capitalist societies where there is a moral incentive for people who manage companies to maximise profits.

No, not a single place on earth has a compelling moral argument to maximize profits. The only justification for maximizing profits is a financial one, and that is amoral. 

&amp;gt;This is why moral decisions should not be entrusted to corporations or businesses.

I agree that moral decisions should not be entrusted to businesses, but not for the reason you mentioned. People who start businesses are successful because they happen to care about making money. There is not a moral obligation involved, there is only an amoral desire for money. 

&amp;gt;but this is through a failure to properly regard the competing moral aims of corporations,

Here you are conflating financial goals with morality. A corporation has no moral principals. They only want money, and that is, as I said, either amoral or immoral. 

Now, can you morally justify valuing money for shareholders over human well-being and societal benefit? If you can't than it is impossible to declare that corporations have a moral obligation to make money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010826444.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, you are wrong. 

A board of directors cannot do anything they want with investors money. The investor has invested in the hope of making a profit, but this is on the shared belief that the people receiving the investment will honestly try to make a profit. Otherwise it is theft. Or fraud and theft - see any one of many fraudulent investment schemes, or accounting crimes. The people who took other peoples' money and did not honestly try to make a profit acted immorally. (As an aside - also illegally, and people are frequently punished for financial crimes

While both fraud and theft are legal concept, they are also moral concepts. 

And the people who are on the board of directors do have contracts to work earnestly for the company. And when you buy shares you definitely do enter into a legal agreement with the company. You gain rights - like the right to attend shareholders meetings, to review accounts etc. 

In the  UK this is based on the Companies act 2006, which describes in detail the duties of a board of directors, and rights of shareholders. 

P.S. If you didn't know this you probably shouldn't be buying stocks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011590336.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sorry, you are wrong.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; A board of directors cannot do anything they want with investors money.

Legally speaking. Not morally. The two are not related. None of this is relevant. 

&amp;gt;but this is on the shared belief

Yup. Shared belief. Not moral obligation. Your argument fails right here. 

&amp;gt;And the people who are on the board of directors do have contracts to work earnestly for the company.

Which is not what I stated the exception would be, so this is also irrelevant. 

&amp;gt; And when you buy shares you definitely do enter into a legal agreement with the company.

Again, not the one I stated, so not relevant. 

Now, you have *legally* justified companies maximizing profits. Do you have any moral arguments to provide? Because you said *morally* not legally. Nothing the law says is at all relevant in a moral argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011794314.0" user="drawing_goblin" delta="False">
    <text>Trust is a fundamental aspect of a collaborative society. Breaking trust is fundamentally damaging to society and therefore morally wrong, and should not be done unless there is an overriding moral reason. 

So when you buy shares you are commissioning the people who run a company to work in earnest for you. If they fail to do this they are acting immorally by breaking the trust that you placed in them. The board of directors are the people who act on behalf of the company, and therefore their immoral actions are the immoral actions of the company. 


If you and I make an agreement which involves a shared set of expectations and bilateral remuneration of one form or another, then each has a moral responsibility to fulfil those responsibilities. If you therefore allow a person to invest in your company you have created a situation where you have a moral obligation.

Also people have a right to possessions. Depriving someone of possessions under false pretenses is morally wrong (legally fraud or theft). So a company has the moral responsibility to fulfil its agreements with its shareholders or investors to the best of its ability or it will be acting immorally, as they deprived me of money for their shares under the establish share agreements. 

So companies have a moral responsibility to society to uphold their agreements to work earnestly for the success of their companies and have a moral responsibility to their individual shareholders and investors.

Honestly: do I really need to define why fraud and theft are morally wrong in the absence of mitigating circumstances? Christ.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
