<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010229770.0" user="AManHasAJob" delta="False">
    <text>Motivated and productive employees are what create profits for shareholders.  Companies don't magically conjur profits out of thin air.  Paying a competitive salary is the best way to attract and maintain talented employees.  That includes voluntary regular wage increases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010239997.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Remember I said anything above the wage where you can recruit more than enough quality workers is unjustified. I already took what you said into account</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010272618.0" user="AManHasAJob" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but that wage amount is going to change.  If a company doesn't take an active role in monitoring industry trends and understanding what they need to pay employees, they aren't going to be able to recruit and hire talented employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010283394.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it should change but only when it needs to, not randomly "for the sake of the workers".. But only when the company thinks they need to do it to hire more quality workers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010351562.0" user="AManHasAJob" delta="False">
    <text>Companies don't generally "randomly" raise wages anyway.  Generally, it's always in response to something.  It may be done to reward exceptional performance on a particularly difficult project or a yearly increase to (help) keep up with inflation, but never just out of the blue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011206066.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>This is a bit like saying "all beef burgers should be cooked". Are there large numbers of corporations that are paying their workers higher wages just for the sake of it, after concluding that they'd be able to make more money if they paid their workers less? Where are these corporations? It feels like you are arguing against a cloud.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011354526.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Two things

1- we don't know for sure, many companies can be paying $15 when they could be just as productive with $13 maybe not the majority but probably many companies do this 

2-im basically arguing against people's expectations of what companies should be prioritizing, a worker should know full well that a company shouldn't be expected to pay them more than what is enough to convince them (and enough other people) to work there..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011606069.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but probably many companies do this
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

Why do you believe this? Just a hunch?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37012009903.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but probably many companies do this

is this based on anything?

like your whole cmv seems to be based on the fact that companies pay more than they need to out of the kindness of their hearts. but this seems unintuitive and you havent shown that to be the case</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37012032809.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;like your whole cmv seems to be based on the fact that companies pay more than they need to out of the kindness of their hearts

More on the fact that society expects them to do so and society needs to learn that it would be immoral if they did what society wants them to do which is to pay more than they need to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37012050318.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>i dont think society expects companies to do this on their own.

thats why higher wages are generally targeted through higher minimum wages right? we cant expect companies to help their workers and pay them more because, obviously.

so we ask the government to make them do it

ive never heard anyone seriously say "walmart should pay their workers $20 an hour because that would be really nice of them"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
