<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37011151288.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty.

You assert this as if it's some sort of self-evident point when it absolutely is not. If you believe this, then it logically follows that companies should not voluntarily decline to use child labor or slaves. And it logically follows that companies should push for laws that would allow them to use child labor and slaves. After all, their moral duty is to maximizing profit, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011419635.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;child labor or slaves.

My post assumes non aggression and not having consent for taking someone's labor but still taking their labor is aggression</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011734834.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>So then you agree that there are other moral duties that sometimes supersedes a company's moral duty to maximize profit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011748428.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>When it comes to regular business routine no, that doesn't mean they can go out killing people, but my post assumes the obvious</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011815423.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>How does it assume that? You say a business has a moral obligation to maximize profits. On that basis, they used slavery until it was outlawed. It used child labor until it was outlawed. You say now that was an "obvious" bad thing, but at the time clearly not enough people believed it was "obvious" or else it never would have happened. What's to say an increased minimum wage won't be "obvious" to everyone 50 years from now?

You, therefore, make it clear that there are "obvious" instances in which businesses have moral imperatives that supersede their need to maximize profit. Why is "paying your workers a living wage" not an "obvious" instance? Seems pretty obvious to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011900318.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What's to say an increased minimum wage won't be "obvious" to everyone 50 years from now?

Good point, morality is always changing, but honestly I think it's all about consent.. It makes the most sense... 

&amp;gt;"paying your workers a living wage" not an "obvious" instance? Seems pretty obvious to me

Because they can consent to the wages if they don't like it they don't have to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011919559.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>So there should be no minimum wage then? If companies want to pay 5 cents per hour then people can either take the job or not, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37011962088.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, there shouldn't be one... But businesses will still be forced to pay wages based on supply and demand... It's really not up to them either way, if they offer 5cents an hour they will go out of business</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37012043337.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But businesses will still be forced to pay wages based on supply and demand... It's really not up to them either way, if they offer 5cents an hour they will go out of business

Maybe you should do some reading on why the minimum wage was instituted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37012051216.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the advice</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
