<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1432874783.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/np3h9b/cmv_companies_should_not_volantarily_raise_wages/">
    <title>Cmv: Companies should not volantarily raise wages</title>
    <original_poster>omar1759</original_poster>
    <original_post>A company (specifically one that has many investors such as publicly traded companies, but also private ones) that is already able to recruit AND KEEP more than enough quality workers at a given wage should never decide to volantarily(meaning without being forced by market conditions that cause labor prices to go up naturally) raise wages solely on the basis of helping workers. This is because generally speaking a company's moral duty should be to maximize profit for it's shareholders and basically labor is an expense just like utilities and companies are supposed to minimize expenses to achieve this duty. 
This btw does not include small businesses where the only investor is the one owner of the business rather than a group of investors. 
In that case the owner would be free to raise wages as he wishes however unintelligent that may be. I still it is not a smart decision to raise wages significantly above the market rate in this situation if you are looking at the overall good. A small business with more profits can expand the business and hire more workers.
However in this post I am still trying to focus on businesses with many investors and how it is morally unacceptable for the board of directors or CEOs to decide to raise wages more than necessary to hire enough quality workers.

Edit: I just want to emphasize I'm talking about raisiwages when the current wages already help recruit more than enough high quality workers, because people are responding saying that paying workers enough helps them be more productive.. I already took that into account.. If you need 50 high quality workers and you can get them at $12 you should not raise wages to $15 if it won't make much of a difference in quality and if your only objective is to help workers financially or "provide a living wage"</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37010360242.0" user="babycam" delta="False">
    <text>So through all of these you are trying to make a point that doesn't exist. No company raises wages because of morals they may say its to be fair or we care about our workers but their are a large verity of influences on workers and generally you are trying to do the bare minimum to pay them more. But if your playing the game overall it works out better. 

Look at the guy who made everyone's wages the same from janitor to CEO he played the "moral and nice card" and is doing great sometimes doing what is bad for investors short term is need for long term gains.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010374942.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>Gosh that guy was horrible.. I mean obviously you're going to lose all your higher qualified employees who deserve more, I think that's what happened.. Also a very immoral thing to do 

&amp;gt;is need for long term gains.

Doubt that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010679581.0" user="babycam" delta="False">
    <text>Dude look at gravity payments at the start of pandemic a news report said 98% of his employees were willing to take a paycut.  He said he did it for a moral reason but loyalties hard to buy he came out ahead.

And from your view reinvestment is bad because it doesn't maximize profits for the investors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37010736231.0" user="omar1759" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Dude look at gravity payments at the start of pandemic a news report said 98% of his employees were willing to take a paycut. He said he did it for a moral reason but loyalties hard to buy he came out ahead.

Well you never know what would have happened if he had cut wages.. Maybe it would have been better, it didn't happen 

&amp;gt;And from your view reinvestment is bad because it doesn't maximize profits for the investors.

No, capital appreciation is one way to reward investors</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37013284848.0" user="babycam" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry for late Reply.
Did he not cut wages? https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/08/12/employees-pay-cuts-productivity/

But if your talking about someone else cutting the wage of employees down to some level I would hope people don't stand for that but brining others up is reasonable and good PR stunt.

Capital appreciation only rewards in the sense that it should increase future productivity but if you build a new factory and the company crashes then Where was the gain? So short term risk and less profit for long term gain.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
