<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37035034948.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>I think that for any particular individual, it's entirely possible for there to be a bad music genre. 

There are genres where I genuinely have never heard a song where I didn't think it would better if it either didn't exist or was in another genre. And some genres were I think most of the songs would be worse if they were in any other genre. 

Could there hypothetically be a superlative/execrable artist that manages to transcend the limitations of the genre? Sure... but if I never encounter one, they might as well not exist for me. 

If what you mean is that there is not any *universally* bad music genre, generally that's true, as tastes vary. I would only say that there may be some genres analogous to hate speech or child porn which are objectively evil because they harm innocent people simply by existing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
