<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143643292.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dirvg/cmv_of_all_the_people_with_a_claim_on_the_iron/">
    <title>CMV: Of all the people with a claim on the Iron Throne, Stannis Baratheon would make the best king.</title>
    <original_poster>ytpies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can't really talk about this without avoiding spoilers, but I'll try and spoiler tag things that haven't happened in the show yet, so the discussion isn't restricted to book readers only.

Let's have a look at Stannis' competition:

- Dany

A young girl with little experience ruling, the Westerosi equivalent of nukes, and a tenuous grip on sanity. She's female, her father went power crazy and started killing people, she can't control her dragons, and her army is made up of slaves. It should come as no surprise that the nobles of Westeros won't exactly welcome her with open arms, forcing her to stage an invasion just to get close to ruling. Not to mention she's infertile, so when she dies there will be yet more drama over who succeeds her. Unstable would be the best way to describe both her rule, and Dany herself.

- 
[Spoiler](/s "Aegon.")

[spoiler](/s "Having been raised to rule, and claiming to be the son of Rhaegar, who was much more popular and much less insane than this father, he would have a much easier time of convincing various Lords to his side. However, there's a good chance that he isn't who he claims he is, and his army is made up of sellswords, only a fraction of which actually made it to Westeros. Plus he hangs around with a Greyscale victim who might inadvertently infect him.")

- Tommen

A puppet ruler. controlled by his mother. Although getting him onto the Iron Throne would be no problem, since he already has it, keeping him on it is another thing entirely. If Cersei doesn't singlehandedly destroy the dynasty, the yes men she put on the Small Council will. Confidence in him is very low, since the tale of Tommen's parentage has also been spread far and wide, and though many people don't believe it, everyone knows it.

- Myrcella

Free from her mother's influence, and rightful queen under Dornish law, Myrcella would make a much stronger ruler than Tommen. However, her claim is under Dornish law only, so for her to be recognised by the rest of the realm Tommen would have to die. She's strong-willed, but I doubt that she would go along with killing her own brother. [Spoiler](/s "It is doubtful that even Dorne would support her fully, since they are also likely to back Aegon."). There is also the whole incest thing to contend with.

- Jon Snow

If R+L=J is true, then Jon would also have a claim on the throne. He would be backed by the North, due to his Stark blood, and has [Spoiler](/s "experience as a leader from being Lord Commander of the Night's Watch."). However, since he is a part of the Night's Watch, his oaths would forbid him from ruling.  Even if he were to escape his vows somehow, and if R+L=J turns out to be true, he would still be a bastard. His claim would be very weak. [Spoiler](/s "He also might be dead.")

There are very few other real contenders for the throne. Gendry would have to find proof of his parentage, would still have a very weak claim, and would probably be just as bad a ruler as Robert. Rickon could become King in the North, but he's a child and believed dead. People seem to think that Sansa will become queen with Littlefinger backing her, but that involves trusting Littlefinger. Almost all of the various "x is a secret Targ" theories are stupid.

Compare those with Stannis the Mannis. He is an experienced leader, commander, and king. He rewards people based on merit rather than birth, and hates brown-nosers. He prefers to act based on honor, but will not let it bind him when the stakes are higher. He leaps to defend the realm from the Others rather than continuing to squabble over the throne. He actually is the rightful king of Westeros. He has Melisandre, who can do legit magic, and a good chunk of the realm already recognises him as king, so he doesn't have to climb over a mountain of corpses to get to the throne.

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27313801011.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>I don't want to spoil this entire post and it's impossible to discuss this with show only knowledge, so please stop reading if you want to avoid book spoilers

Firstly, succession is irrelevant. If someone wins the throne, no one is going to care about their right to it. The one with the biggest army can keep the throne no matter what people say about him. It worked just fine for Robert

While Stannis is definitely one of the best contenders, but I think that you dismiss Aegon far too easily. There is no evidence that greyscale is contagious, so that line is irrelevant. Aegon has the backing of the Golden Company, probably Dorne and possibly Daenerys. This gives him one of the largest armies in Westeros, far larger than Stannis' few thousand and sufficient to challenge the Tyrell-Lannister alliance. And there's a good case for him being a Blackfyre, meaning he may actually have the loyalty of the Golden Company. He has already taken Storm's End extremely quickly, demonstrating military ability, has competent advisors he actually listens to (unlike Daenerys) and appears mentally stable and reasonably sensible.

There is no denying that Stannis is an excellent military commander, but he really seems better fit for the position of a King's Hand. He is extremely intelligent and competent, perfect for a Hand who does the actual work, but unpopular and hard to get on with, not good qualities for a king. And his current military position is extremely tenuous, to say the least. he has, what, a few thousand men in his army? Dorne alone has 5 times that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313809479.0" user="ytpies" delta="False">
    <text>The Golden Company has around 10,000 men, and around half of those made it to Westeros, making Aegon's current military strength on a par with Stannis'. If Dorne backs him that's all set to change, but not if he turns out to be a fake.

I think Aegon listening to his advisors might be his downfall. JonCon is impatient to see Aegon on the throne before he dies, so he'll advise him to rush into things rather than wait. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313831507.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>The other half of the Golden Company are coming over soon, as is shown in the last JonCon chapter. And as seasoned fighters, they could easily beat any similarly sized force of poorly trained peasants which most lords would have, And Aegon's perceived claim, combined with the romance of the prince returning to claim his birthright is likely to gain him support, so I think that it's fair to assume that his forces will increase. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
