<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37033809483.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you're trying to have your cake and eat it too here. If you can't say a genre is good or bad because doing so is ultimately just expressing your own personal taste, the same is true of saying an individual artist/song/whatever is objectively good or bad. To use your food analogy: maybe the pizza *you* think is average is the best pizza I've ever had.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035420748.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is a more gooder answer than all the others. Pick a lane, objectivity or subjectivity. Subjectivity is best reserved for the exceptionally ambiguous and aesthetic. Music taste is subjective. Skill, not so much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035573394.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This might be a Hot Take, but I actually think there's an extent to which skill is also subjective. Because who decides what criteria have to be met for someone to count as "skilled" at something, and who decides what a display of skill looks like?

To use just one example that leaps to mind because I was just listening to the Pixies: one could argue that Kim Deal is not a skilled bassist because her lines are very simple. One could also argue she is skilled because she is very good at writing interesting, memorable basslines that work well with what the drums are doing. It's going to depend on one's own subjective determination of what's a more meaningful criterion of "skill".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035839605.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>Just because a behavior is complex and relative doesn't mean it can't be objective. Hot and cold are also up for debate between individuals, but nobody is going to say lava isn't hot relative to a snow cone. We might disagree about who is skilled and unskilled, but that doesn't mean skill isn't objectively measurable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035889470.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is "skill" carries with it a lot more possibilities for what it could mean than "hot" or "cold" does. It's more like talking about the word "comfortable." It *seems* like there's some objective ways to measure certain kinds of things that relate to what we mean when we say something is "comfortable," but part of what we have to do in the first place is decide what we actually want to measure or care about.

ETA: Or maybe a better analogy is: what makes someone an "expert" at something? Just knowing a lot about it? Being able to demonstrate that knowledge in some practical way? Being able to *teach* that knowledge? These things are less obvious and more open to interpretation than it seems at first glance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036076815.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>The boundaries with which a designator like "expert" or "comfortable" might be rather open to interpretation, but that doesn't seem to exclude those domains from objectivity. Maybe we'll never know the exact answer to the expert question, but one certainly exists, and it could very well be that there are multiple answers to that question. We don't know how many birds are in the sky at this very moment, but there is an objectively accurate answer. 

It occurs to me that a domain like skill is something that is objectively measurable, even if there is widespread disagreement about how to exactly do that. I think you're setting the bar unreasonably high for objectivity. We can disagree about how to count (Looking at you, Terrence Howard) and even how to act (moral imperatives), but those are still objectively measurable properties of the world and human behavior. 

This is the idea behind the "moral landscape" that Sam Harris posits as a framework for determining how science can solve ethical problems. The TED Talk punches way above its weight class (weight, another thing that is objectively measurable yet stubbornly opposed to universal consensus).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036097193.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The boundaries with which a designator like "expert" or "comfortable" might be rather open to interpretation, but that doesn't seem to exclude those domains from objectivity. Maybe we'll never know the exact answer to the expert question, but one certainly exists, and it could very well be that there are multiple answers to that question. We don't know how many birds are in the sky at this very moment, but there is an objectively accurate answer.

My own perspective is that if the question is unanswerable in an objective way then that's as good as there not being an objective answer.

&amp;gt;It occurs to me that a domain like skill is something that is objectively measurable, even if there is widespread disagreement about how to exactly do that. I think you're setting the bar unreasonably high for objectivity. We can disagree about how to count (Looking at you, Terrence Howard) and even how to act (moral imperatives), but those are still objectively measurable properties of the world and human behavior.

Could you sketch out what you think would be the objective measures of musical skill?

&amp;gt;This is the idea behind the "moral landscape" that Sam Harris posits as a framework for determining how science can solve ethical problems. The TED Talk punches way above its weight class (weight, another thing that is objectively measurable yet stubbornly opposed to universal consensus).

That book and Sam Harris in general are not generally taken seriously by actual experts in ethics or moral philosophy so I don't think this is a great example to appeal to, though it does amusingly bring us back to the question of how to determine who counts as "an expert."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036272908.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My own perspective is that if the question is unanswerable in an objective way then that's as good as there not being an objective answer.

Can you tell me how many birds are currently between 50 and 150 AGL right now, or at any point in time? Can you tell me the sum total of the decibels for all crying babies? You can't, but those questions have unambiguously objective answers rooted in scientific measurement. And to say that's as good as the absence of an objective answer, to me, is a grave mistake in epistemology and certainly a vast missed opportunity to study a phenomenon with rigor. 

&amp;gt; Could you sketch out what you think would be the objective measures of musical skill?

I can't, at least not in a way that would be broadly agreed upon. But I can probably sketch out the objective measures of juggling skill in a way that makes my point. 

And that is my point. Complexity muddies the waters of objectivity and makes answers harder to pin down. But elusivity is not tantamount to non existence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036315832.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Can you tell me how many birds are currently between 50 and 150 AGL right now, or at any point in time? Can you tell me the sum total of the decibels for all crying babies? You can't, but those questions have unambiguously objective answers rooted in scientific measurement. And to say that's as good as the absence of an objective answer, to me, is a grave mistake in epistemology and certainly a vast missed opportunity to study a phenomenon with rigor.

So two points here:

1) I agree that these questions have objective answers, I don't agree that they have objective answers "rooted in scientific measurement," in part because I don't even really know what that means (when is a measurement *unscientific?* Measurements are just ways of counting quantities or degrees of things), and in part because it's obviously not actually possible to develop any sort of system of measure that would tell me, right now, the sum decibels of all currently crying babies.

2) Because of how unanswerable they are, the questions *just aren't interesting*. It's interesting to think that there's an objective fact of the matter that we'll never know, but there's also basically nothing interesting or useful I can do with the fact that there's an objective but unknowable answer to some question. That's what I mean by "as good as the absence of an objective answer."

Of course, some unaswerable questions *are* interesting (does God exist), but I'd argue this has more to do with the political, social and cultural (and I guess metaphysical) stakes of the question than the question itself.

Like you say dismissing those questions is "a vast missed opportunity to study a phenemonon with rigor" ... I *can't* study how many birds there are between 50 and 150 AGL. What exactly am I missing by just shrugging my shoulders at the question?

&amp;gt;I can't, at least not in a way that would be broadly agreed upon. But I can probably sketch out the objective measures of juggling skill in a way that makes my point.

I'd prefer you do it with music, the character of the phenomena makes a difference here. Whether or not someone is good at juggling seems pretty self-evidently measurable: they're good at juggling if they accomplish the act of juggling. Music isn't the same thing since there are so many diifferent ways to play music and so many different aspects to musicianship (technical instrument-playing ability, songwriting, sound engineering, performance, etc.).

&amp;gt;And that is my point. Complexity muddies the waters of objectivity and makes answers harder to pin down. But elusivity is not tantamount to non existence.

Let's be clear here: I never claimed there's *nothing* objective about musical skill. I claimed that it's to some extent a subjective measure because the criteria we even want to count as relevant in the first place is something we determine subjectively.

Once we *do* narrow down criteria, things get objective very fast, but then I think it's perfectly valid for someone who favours a different set of criteria to ask us, "Well, why didn't you talk about *this*?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036428512.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Let's be clear here: I never claimed there's nothing objective about musical skill. I claimed that it's to some extent a subjective measure because the criteria we even want to count as relevant in the first place is something we determine subjectively.

As far as I can tell, this is literally true for literally everything. The only difference from one domain to the other is the ease with which and extent to which those measurement criteria are agreed upon. We subjectively determine how the criteria for measuring temperature (F or C? At sea level or in the mesosphere?) or speed, or weight. Can you identify any measurement that doesn't involve some degree of subjectively determining the context of that measurement?

When I said skill is objective, what I'm saying is skill is a human behavior that, with a great deal of variety and room for interpretation,  tends to lend itself to measurable observation that can be evaluated on a scale. There will certainly be disagreement, especially between "peers," but there is no world where anyone who knows anything about basketball can say that Lebron James isn't objectively more skilled at basketball than a 4 year old with cerebral palsy, just a there's no sense in suggesting my 3 year old nephew is objectively more skilled on the violin than Yo-Yo Ma,</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036454970.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As far as I can tell, this is literally true for literally everything. The only difference from one domain to the other is the ease with which and extent to which those measurement criteria are agreed upon. We subjectively determine how the criteria for measuring temperature (F or C? At sea level or in the mesosphere?) or speed, or weight. Can you identify any measurement that doesn't involve some degree of subjectively determining the context of that measurement?

I mean, sure, yes, deciding what is meaningful to measure is always to some degree subjective. Using certain measurements for certain purposes is done in science even when scientists know those measurements are in some sense wrong: there's a really interesting literature on philosophy of science on how this work in the case of scientific modeling, for example, where the model is useful because it helps us predict things and have actual outcomes but we also know it's idealized to a large degree and doesn't actually reflect the real world.

&amp;gt;When I said skill is objective, what I'm saying is skill is a human behavior that, with a great deal of variety and room for interpretation, tends to lend itself to measurable observation that can be evaluated on a scale. There will certainly be disagreement, especially between "peers," but there is no world where anyone who knows anything about basketball can say that Lebron James isn't objectively more skilled at basketball than a 4 year old with cerebral palsy, just a there's no sense in suggesting my 3 year old nephew is objectively more skilled on the violin than Yo-Yo Ma.

I never meant to imply that cases like "3-year-old vs. Yo-Yo Ma" were going to be hard to determine. But what about Yo-Yo Ma versus Jimi Hendrix? Here we have to answer all kinds of questions: well, which instrument is harder to play? Is Bach harder to play than 60s-era hard rock? Is it fair to call Yo-Yo Ma more skilled than Jimi Hendrix because he mostly plays the work of other composers while Hendrix wrote his own songs? And so on and so forth.

And I don't think that's even a particularly complex case. It's just comparing two musicians who play different instruments in different styles who are generally both considered to be very skilled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036649783.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I never meant to imply that cases like "3-year-old vs. Yo-Yo Ma" were going to be hard to determine. 

I didn't mean to make any claims about ease or difficulty, only that objectivity was present. 

I think we've landed on the same page here, or at least adjacent ones. Objectively calculating the skill differential between two immensely skilled artists like Yo-Yo Ma and Hendrix is precisely the kind of problem that defies reliable measurement. 

I would venture to say that it has no objective answer that our current faculties and tools can confidently identify. But I don't think it necessarily means there can't be an answer. I mean if we can say with confidence that both of them are objectively skilled, then theoretically we could someday compare those skills and arrive at an answer; I am skeptical we will ever be able to do this reliably however, there are simply too many variables.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036677819.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I didn't mean to make any claims about ease or difficulty, only that objectivity was present.

It's easier to be objective about really obvious cases though. Obviously someone who has never picked up a cello is not going to be as good a cellist as Yo-Yo Ma. I played basketball like once, I'm obviously not as good as anyone in the NBA. The interesting cases where the subjectivity of determining what counts as "skilled" are not going to be the ones like that.

&amp;gt;I would venture to say that it has no objective answer that our current faculties and tools can confidently identify. But I don't think it necessarily means there can't be an answer. I mean if we can say with confidence that both of them are objectively skilled, then theoretically we could someday compare those skills and arrive at an answer; I am skeptical we will ever be able to do this reliably however, there are simply too many variables.

So perhaps some of our digressions got us away from this, but I really think my fundamental disagreement with you is this: it's not that there aren't things that can be objectively measured to figure out what "skilled" might mean in this context, it's that you simply cannot start measuring without making some subjective determination about what you will and won't measure, and probably other sorts of subjective valuations on top of that. We won't ever have the tools to to compare Jimi Hendrix's skill to Yo-Yo Ma's skill, even in some hypothetical far future, unless you think we could theoretically compare entire genres or periods of music against each other for how much skill each one takes to play -- as just one example of the sort of subjective valuation you have to make there.

ETA: This is also why, to be clear, I'm not particularly interested in cases like juggling or basketball. We can fairly uncontroversially say that to be good at basketball is to be able to consistently win games or score points or whatever. We can't really make a similar easy sort of uncontroversial claim for music, and that's why we're always going to have to make subjective valuations as part of determining what counts as skilled there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036801052.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We can fairly uncontroversially say that to be good at basketball is to be able to consistently win games or score points or whatever. We can't really make a similar easy sort of uncontroversial claim for music

Not an easy one, but I think we can make a similar claim. Music doesn't have the bright clean lines of basketball that make it much easier to judge, but we can uncontroversially say that to be good at music is to play music that requires exceptional skill and talent to produce, and to be bad at music is to not be able to play music that requires skill or talent. 

There is a spectrum here, elusive and bewildering as it may be. To say otherwise is to claim that art is itself incompatible with the measurement of skill. But there are great artists. There are good artists. There are mediocre artists. Determining who is who involves a great deal of subjective wheedling, but Monet's sell for more than your best flea market water color landscape ever will for a reason. 

I think my final answer is, it's a little bit of both, and it depends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036821631.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not an easy one, but I think we can make a similar claim. Music doesn't have the bright clean lines of basketball that make it much easier to judge, but we can uncontroversially say that to be good at music is to play music that requires exceptional skill and talent to produce, and to be bad at music is to play music that requires no skill or talent.

I mean, no, we can't uncontroversially say that for reasons I thought I'd made pretty clear at this point, and moreover it's essentially a tautology: "to be skilled at music is to make music that requires skill." That doesn't tell us *anything*.

&amp;gt;There is a spectrum here, elusive and bewildering as it may be. To say otherwise is to claim that art is itself incompatible with the measurement of skill.

I mean there's a non-trivial degree to which that's true. My reaction to art ultimately has nothing to do with how much skill it took to produce; it has to do with a whole bunch of subjective things to do with what I look for in art.

&amp;gt;Determining who is who involves a great deal of subjective wheedling, but Monet's sell for more than your best flea market water color landscape ever will for a reason.

Appealing to visual art is *not* the support for your position you think it is, especially if your measure is "will people pay a lot of money for it". Have a look at some of the stuff that sells for huge money at Sotheby's and Christie's. I can assure you a good deal of it does not reflect what I think most people would traditionally think of as "artistic skill."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036879648.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>The cash value of visual art was a bad example.

Going back to music, there are various metrics we can objectively measure to approximate the skill of a particular musician. These metrics are, like every metric for measuring anything, subjectively identified. There's a lot of them, and they would be virtually impossible to reliably compare to each other and evaluate. 

But doing so allows us to identify great musicians from ok musicians from bad musicians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036885948.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So what are those metrics?

ETA: Even just list a few as a basis for discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036961390.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>You mentioned some of them, but technical ability, compositional ability, the ability to invoke a positive emotional response in others, the ability to inspire others, to entertain others, to create harmony, to make music that others find interesting, etc. Not all musicians will check these boxes, but they are all the ingredients, among many others, for how to bake high quality music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036990337.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so let's just take one of these for a second. What, to you, is a good way of objectively measuring technical ability when it comes to music?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037061175.0" user="tayezz" delta="False">
    <text>Well, to put it in relatable terms, when I pick up a guitar, I have absolutely no idea what to do with it. I know one hand goes up high and the other low. I know the strings make sounds. I don't have the first clue how to make sounds that virtually anyone would enjoy hearing or find remotely worth listening to. If you were blindfolded and listened to both me playing guitar and a toddler walking on one, you couldn't tell the difference. 

Put me on a piano, and I know exactly which keys to press in exactly which sequence. If I played for anyone, regardless of their affinity for piano, they would know I've spent many years practicing. I sound nothing like a toddler walking on a piano. 

The difference is I have technical competency on the piano.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037741243.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, that's a good first step, but then how do you judge who is more skilled when comparing you on piano and someone with the same level of technical proficiency on another instrument?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
