<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143643292.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dirvg/cmv_of_all_the_people_with_a_claim_on_the_iron/">
    <title>CMV: Of all the people with a claim on the Iron Throne, Stannis Baratheon would make the best king.</title>
    <original_poster>ytpies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can't really talk about this without avoiding spoilers, but I'll try and spoiler tag things that haven't happened in the show yet, so the discussion isn't restricted to book readers only.

Let's have a look at Stannis' competition:

- Dany

A young girl with little experience ruling, the Westerosi equivalent of nukes, and a tenuous grip on sanity. She's female, her father went power crazy and started killing people, she can't control her dragons, and her army is made up of slaves. It should come as no surprise that the nobles of Westeros won't exactly welcome her with open arms, forcing her to stage an invasion just to get close to ruling. Not to mention she's infertile, so when she dies there will be yet more drama over who succeeds her. Unstable would be the best way to describe both her rule, and Dany herself.

- 
[Spoiler](/s "Aegon.")

[spoiler](/s "Having been raised to rule, and claiming to be the son of Rhaegar, who was much more popular and much less insane than this father, he would have a much easier time of convincing various Lords to his side. However, there's a good chance that he isn't who he claims he is, and his army is made up of sellswords, only a fraction of which actually made it to Westeros. Plus he hangs around with a Greyscale victim who might inadvertently infect him.")

- Tommen

A puppet ruler. controlled by his mother. Although getting him onto the Iron Throne would be no problem, since he already has it, keeping him on it is another thing entirely. If Cersei doesn't singlehandedly destroy the dynasty, the yes men she put on the Small Council will. Confidence in him is very low, since the tale of Tommen's parentage has also been spread far and wide, and though many people don't believe it, everyone knows it.

- Myrcella

Free from her mother's influence, and rightful queen under Dornish law, Myrcella would make a much stronger ruler than Tommen. However, her claim is under Dornish law only, so for her to be recognised by the rest of the realm Tommen would have to die. She's strong-willed, but I doubt that she would go along with killing her own brother. [Spoiler](/s "It is doubtful that even Dorne would support her fully, since they are also likely to back Aegon."). There is also the whole incest thing to contend with.

- Jon Snow

If R+L=J is true, then Jon would also have a claim on the throne. He would be backed by the North, due to his Stark blood, and has [Spoiler](/s "experience as a leader from being Lord Commander of the Night's Watch."). However, since he is a part of the Night's Watch, his oaths would forbid him from ruling.  Even if he were to escape his vows somehow, and if R+L=J turns out to be true, he would still be a bastard. His claim would be very weak. [Spoiler](/s "He also might be dead.")

There are very few other real contenders for the throne. Gendry would have to find proof of his parentage, would still have a very weak claim, and would probably be just as bad a ruler as Robert. Rickon could become King in the North, but he's a child and believed dead. People seem to think that Sansa will become queen with Littlefinger backing her, but that involves trusting Littlefinger. Almost all of the various "x is a secret Targ" theories are stupid.

Compare those with Stannis the Mannis. He is an experienced leader, commander, and king. He rewards people based on merit rather than birth, and hates brown-nosers. He prefers to act based on honor, but will not let it bind him when the stakes are higher. He leaps to defend the realm from the Others rather than continuing to squabble over the throne. He actually is the rightful king of Westeros. He has Melisandre, who can do legit magic, and a good chunk of the realm already recognises him as king, so he doesn't have to climb over a mountain of corpses to get to the throne.

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27313749964.0" user="Kai_Daigoji" delta="False">
    <text>You've left out the most important claimant: Aegon Targaryeon.  His claim is better than Dany's, he has a loyal army behind him, but most importantly, he understands something Stannis does not - that being King comes with obligations as well as privileges.

Stannis spends a large amount of time complaining about the people who owe him loyalty, but Aegon understands that this is a social contract.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313756784.0" user="ytpies" delta="False">
    <text>He's there, just under a spoiler tag. I'm guessing you're on mobile or something and can't read it.

There's a good chance that Aegon probably isn't the real deal. He could be a Blackfyre, or just some guy with Valyrian features, but he probably isn't the real Aegon Targaryan. His army is made up of sellswords, and a large portion of them didn't make it across the narrow sea, and his chief advisor wants to try to claim the throne as fast as possible before he dies, so he probably won't fare well in a war.

Maybe Stannis didn't understand that kingship was a responsibility rather than a right at the start of the series, but now he definitely does. He intervened to save the Night's Watch from the Others, and his every other line is something about duty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313759392.0" user="Kai_Daigoji" delta="False">
    <text>Not on mobile, just stupid from lack of sleep.  :)

&amp;gt; and his every other line is something about duty.

And half the time it's about someone's duty to him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313759795.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The spoilers all link to "Page not found" and I am on a PC. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313794761.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>If you hover over the link it shows you it as alt text. Or if you look at the link itself or the source, you can see the spoiler</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314437312.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Ah. I despise hover text and so clicked on the spoiler. That is a failing of this subs spoiler system if clicking sends you to a page not found. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314450264.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if you clicked on the link and looked at the URL it would have the spoilers in it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314456031.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The URL given when you click on it is reddit.com/s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314504114.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, odd. Some other spoiler tags worked like that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313757785.0" user="guruPanda" delta="False">
    <text>He didn't leave him out, he is under the spoiler tag.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313759556.0" user="Kai_Daigoji" delta="False">
    <text>My bad.  This is what I get for redditing on the overnight shift.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313758961.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>He also forgot Edric Storm and Mya Stone. Both recognized Bastards of Robert who are better claimants than Gendry. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313760114.0" user="Kai_Daigoji" delta="False">
    <text>I think the bastards all have lousy claims, at least by the way laws seem to work in Westeros.  From what we've seen, bastards have no claim whatsoever unless they are specifically acknowledged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313761532.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Not Acknowledged, legitimized. 

Acknowledged is what allows them to use the Bastard names. Legitimized is what allows them to take the House name, or in some cases make their own house name. It puts them in line after True born son and daughters. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313784972.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>Bastards hardly have claims, plus Mya has no claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313784243.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>Except he is fake. Good luck for him proving he isn't. Ok, he has Jon Con on his side who is conned by Illyrio.

That aside, he doesn't really have a better claim. Robert usurped the throne and became the legit king, so the next legit king would follow robert's line and be Stannis. that is as far as the claim is concerned.

But since they can still get the throne by force, question is who would rule better and I say Stannis due to experience - he has grown a lot since the start, intelligence (Aegon so far doesn't seem remarkable although he is educated), etc. 

I don't really see anything overly impressive about Aegon as an individual. He seems as arrogant as Dany, easily manipulated, and pretty much like a puppet himself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313801716.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>Who cares about legitimacy? Aegon has a massive army, that should be sufficient claim to get the Iron Throne</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313823883.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>I was just addressing the legitimacy point. The real question here is who will make the best king.

As for Aegon, Dany has dragons. She isn't there yet, but I don't think there will be much love between them when they meet. Stannis' best chance is to fight for the realm up north and let the others fight for the throne, then come as a hero with North behind him and least amount of surviving enemies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313833128.0" user="Zephyr1011" delta="False">
    <text>Well, Aegon is a *lot* more popular and likable than Stannis. Stannis is awesome and competent, but is hardly well-liked, which would make it pretty hard for him to have a stable rule</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313846327.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>By whom though? Dorne? Fair enough but they will be going against Lannisters first while Stannis is up North. And what Stannis is doing now will change his status and likability drastically. With North on his side, he might have a chance. 

If Stannis were to rule, he would be liked well enough, in a sense that his demands are clear, and people can know what to expect of him. Davos is his ticket to be liked by more common men. And the big houses all dislike each other anyway at this point, so Stannis is hardly the least popular. Once he brings stability and improves the debt situation, I don't think anyone would be starting rebellions.

Aegon on the throne is a bit harder to judge (it's easy to hypothetically compare Stannis to Dany) since we don't really know yet what kind of ruler he would be. Whether he is the real Aegon would always be a question. Plus, Targs were pretty unpopular when Robert took over, so it's not like what Dany thinks, that everyone is just waiting for them to come back. As a personality, so far he seems a bit arrogant and not that smart, plus he is young and has no real experience... but he would have Illyrio and Varys. All in all, I am not sure what he would be like.

I don't think either of them will end up winning the throne, realistically speaking, but I think Stannis' would rule well and eventually get respect. I also think that any interpersonal charm he may lack he would make up for by appointing decent, capable men who are loyal to him and would do good to the realm. He can take advice but isn't a puppet, and he does end up inspiring loyalty in his own way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
