<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143643292.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dirvg/cmv_of_all_the_people_with_a_claim_on_the_iron/">
    <title>CMV: Of all the people with a claim on the Iron Throne, Stannis Baratheon would make the best king.</title>
    <original_poster>ytpies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can't really talk about this without avoiding spoilers, but I'll try and spoiler tag things that haven't happened in the show yet, so the discussion isn't restricted to book readers only.

Let's have a look at Stannis' competition:

- Dany

A young girl with little experience ruling, the Westerosi equivalent of nukes, and a tenuous grip on sanity. She's female, her father went power crazy and started killing people, she can't control her dragons, and her army is made up of slaves. It should come as no surprise that the nobles of Westeros won't exactly welcome her with open arms, forcing her to stage an invasion just to get close to ruling. Not to mention she's infertile, so when she dies there will be yet more drama over who succeeds her. Unstable would be the best way to describe both her rule, and Dany herself.

- 
[Spoiler](/s "Aegon.")

[spoiler](/s "Having been raised to rule, and claiming to be the son of Rhaegar, who was much more popular and much less insane than this father, he would have a much easier time of convincing various Lords to his side. However, there's a good chance that he isn't who he claims he is, and his army is made up of sellswords, only a fraction of which actually made it to Westeros. Plus he hangs around with a Greyscale victim who might inadvertently infect him.")

- Tommen

A puppet ruler. controlled by his mother. Although getting him onto the Iron Throne would be no problem, since he already has it, keeping him on it is another thing entirely. If Cersei doesn't singlehandedly destroy the dynasty, the yes men she put on the Small Council will. Confidence in him is very low, since the tale of Tommen's parentage has also been spread far and wide, and though many people don't believe it, everyone knows it.

- Myrcella

Free from her mother's influence, and rightful queen under Dornish law, Myrcella would make a much stronger ruler than Tommen. However, her claim is under Dornish law only, so for her to be recognised by the rest of the realm Tommen would have to die. She's strong-willed, but I doubt that she would go along with killing her own brother. [Spoiler](/s "It is doubtful that even Dorne would support her fully, since they are also likely to back Aegon."). There is also the whole incest thing to contend with.

- Jon Snow

If R+L=J is true, then Jon would also have a claim on the throne. He would be backed by the North, due to his Stark blood, and has [Spoiler](/s "experience as a leader from being Lord Commander of the Night's Watch."). However, since he is a part of the Night's Watch, his oaths would forbid him from ruling.  Even if he were to escape his vows somehow, and if R+L=J turns out to be true, he would still be a bastard. His claim would be very weak. [Spoiler](/s "He also might be dead.")

There are very few other real contenders for the throne. Gendry would have to find proof of his parentage, would still have a very weak claim, and would probably be just as bad a ruler as Robert. Rickon could become King in the North, but he's a child and believed dead. People seem to think that Sansa will become queen with Littlefinger backing her, but that involves trusting Littlefinger. Almost all of the various "x is a secret Targ" theories are stupid.

Compare those with Stannis the Mannis. He is an experienced leader, commander, and king. He rewards people based on merit rather than birth, and hates brown-nosers. He prefers to act based on honor, but will not let it bind him when the stakes are higher. He leaps to defend the realm from the Others rather than continuing to squabble over the throne. He actually is the rightful king of Westeros. He has Melisandre, who can do legit magic, and a good chunk of the realm already recognises him as king, so he doesn't have to climb over a mountain of corpses to get to the throne.

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27314232570.0" user="Denny_Craine" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with Stannis, and the disadvantage he has compared to say, Jon Snow, is that he's just not a good leader. Yes he's an experienced commander and an accomplished warrior, but he rules by fear and demands respect. He doesn't necessarily earn it. Shit the books describe him as both feared and respected, but never loved. 

On top of that he's a firmly stubborn legalist. Look at what he did to Davos after Davos literally saved his life! He cut off his fingers because Davos had *smuggled* food to him, which is technically a crime. That's not being fair or just, that's being capricious.

Stannis would be someone who wholeheartedly believes in zero-tolerance policies. To him it's irrelevant if the law is unjust, if it's cruel, to him the letter of the law must be followed above all else. On top of that he's spent a great deal of time following a crazy ass cult leader who encouraged (and succeeded) in getting him to participate in human sacrifice!

Stannis is not a kind, fair, or stable man. He would make a great tyrant, and undoubtedly make Westeros "stable". But he'd do so with an iron fist. He has no concept of social contract theory, only that he is the king, he is noble, he is upper class, and you are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314994400.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>As a confirmd CG person myself, I have to give credit where credit is due: Stannis is LN enough to blister paint, and I give him my grudging admiration for that. 

CG sees the welfare of the individual as the greater good, and will sacrifice order to achieve it. 

LN is just the conservative equivalent of CG. They see order as the greater good, and will sacrifice the individual to achieve it. 

Both are expressions of Asimov's famous principle: Never let your sense of morals prevent you from doing what is right. 

By cutting off Davos' fingers, Stannis was cruel - but he sees that as a necessary price to pay for a stable society under the rule of law. In his mind, the cost of *not* doing so would be the spread of corruption and banditry, harming a lot more people overall.

By sacrificing people to the red god, he hopes to attain a stable, well-run kingdom, under the one who whose duty it is to run it.

He's not perfect by any means; he *was* tempted and did cede to temptation - but not by the lust for power, but by the prospect of a son. 

He is certainly not kind, but you cannot call him unfair. And while I most certainly don't agree with his philosophy, I completely disagree that he is coming from a position of entrenched greed and privilege. As I read him, he cares deeply about his people, and sees himself as the father whose job it is to be stern for their own good. 

He would be most unlovable, and life under his rule would be draconian and harsh, but you can be certain that corruption and a lot of the nastier excesses would be utterly stamped out. 

He's not the king that Westeros deserves, but the one that it needs right now. Or is that the other way about? At any rate, I wouldn't vote for him as king, but I can respect the people who would.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
