<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37032993751.0" user="DelectPierro" delta="False">
    <text>Christian Rock is objectively awful. It doesn’t make Christianity any better, it just makes Rock &amp;amp; Roll worse. Even the most talented artist could not perform Christian Rock without sounding cringe. Same goes for Christian Rap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033336787.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Christian Rock is objectively awful

*proceeds to write a bunch of subjective opinions about Christian Rock*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033344243.0" user="DelectPierro" delta="False">
    <text>No, everything that follows is also an objective fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033363240.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you understand what "subjective" and "objective" mean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033431336.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it just makes Rock &amp;amp; Roll worse.

"worse" is a subjective opinion, YOU think it makes rock and roll worse

&amp;gt;Even the most talented artist could not perform Christian Rock without sounding cringe

"cringe" is also a subjective opinion, what you find cringe isnt necessarily what i find cringe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033359107.0" user="zuluportero" delta="False">
    <text>Musically christian rock isn't different than normal rock.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033883898.0" user="Omnipleasant710" delta="False">
    <text>Ain't this the truth 🤣. You seen the way people get down to that shit tho. Whole crowd is fucking vibing and crying and shit. Mind blowing. Lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036631188.0" user="Dances_with_Bucks" delta="False">
    <text>Lol I got the reference. That's from King of the Hill</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
