<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37033452054.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>[Hatecore/Nazi Punk](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_punk) is the worst because of the messaging. It’s a bad music genre.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033453938.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Nazi_punk](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nazi_punk)** 
 
 &amp;gt;A Nazi punk is a neo-Nazi who is part of the punk subculture. The term also describes the related music genre, which is sometimes also referred to as hatecore. Nazi Punk music generally sounds like other forms of punk rock, but differs by having lyrics that express hatred of some ethnic minorities, Jews, communists, homosexuals,  anarchists, and other perceived enemies. It is a subgenre of punk that contrasts sharply with the anti-authoritarian ideas prevalent in much of the punk subculture.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | Credit: kittens_from_space)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033673500.0" user="Yashabird" delta="False">
    <text>for punk yeah fascism is stupid as well as distasteful, but a lot of black metal is pretty hateful and misanthropic, but it would make less sense as music if it weren’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033863958.0" user="Omnipleasant710" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough... unfortunately subjective,  but I for one agree with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37065774734.0" user="AccountClaimedByUMG" delta="False">
    <text>The message doesn’t affect the music though so you may still enjoy the music itself without needing to agree with the lyrics, meaning the musical genre you may not objectively consider bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37065923157.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>The message is kinda inseparable from the music in this case</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
