<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143643292.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dirvg/cmv_of_all_the_people_with_a_claim_on_the_iron/">
    <title>CMV: Of all the people with a claim on the Iron Throne, Stannis Baratheon would make the best king.</title>
    <original_poster>ytpies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can't really talk about this without avoiding spoilers, but I'll try and spoiler tag things that haven't happened in the show yet, so the discussion isn't restricted to book readers only.

Let's have a look at Stannis' competition:

- Dany

A young girl with little experience ruling, the Westerosi equivalent of nukes, and a tenuous grip on sanity. She's female, her father went power crazy and started killing people, she can't control her dragons, and her army is made up of slaves. It should come as no surprise that the nobles of Westeros won't exactly welcome her with open arms, forcing her to stage an invasion just to get close to ruling. Not to mention she's infertile, so when she dies there will be yet more drama over who succeeds her. Unstable would be the best way to describe both her rule, and Dany herself.

- 
[Spoiler](/s "Aegon.")

[spoiler](/s "Having been raised to rule, and claiming to be the son of Rhaegar, who was much more popular and much less insane than this father, he would have a much easier time of convincing various Lords to his side. However, there's a good chance that he isn't who he claims he is, and his army is made up of sellswords, only a fraction of which actually made it to Westeros. Plus he hangs around with a Greyscale victim who might inadvertently infect him.")

- Tommen

A puppet ruler. controlled by his mother. Although getting him onto the Iron Throne would be no problem, since he already has it, keeping him on it is another thing entirely. If Cersei doesn't singlehandedly destroy the dynasty, the yes men she put on the Small Council will. Confidence in him is very low, since the tale of Tommen's parentage has also been spread far and wide, and though many people don't believe it, everyone knows it.

- Myrcella

Free from her mother's influence, and rightful queen under Dornish law, Myrcella would make a much stronger ruler than Tommen. However, her claim is under Dornish law only, so for her to be recognised by the rest of the realm Tommen would have to die. She's strong-willed, but I doubt that she would go along with killing her own brother. [Spoiler](/s "It is doubtful that even Dorne would support her fully, since they are also likely to back Aegon."). There is also the whole incest thing to contend with.

- Jon Snow

If R+L=J is true, then Jon would also have a claim on the throne. He would be backed by the North, due to his Stark blood, and has [Spoiler](/s "experience as a leader from being Lord Commander of the Night's Watch."). However, since he is a part of the Night's Watch, his oaths would forbid him from ruling.  Even if he were to escape his vows somehow, and if R+L=J turns out to be true, he would still be a bastard. His claim would be very weak. [Spoiler](/s "He also might be dead.")

There are very few other real contenders for the throne. Gendry would have to find proof of his parentage, would still have a very weak claim, and would probably be just as bad a ruler as Robert. Rickon could become King in the North, but he's a child and believed dead. People seem to think that Sansa will become queen with Littlefinger backing her, but that involves trusting Littlefinger. Almost all of the various "x is a secret Targ" theories are stupid.

Compare those with Stannis the Mannis. He is an experienced leader, commander, and king. He rewards people based on merit rather than birth, and hates brown-nosers. He prefers to act based on honor, but will not let it bind him when the stakes are higher. He leaps to defend the realm from the Others rather than continuing to squabble over the throne. He actually is the rightful king of Westeros. He has Melisandre, who can do legit magic, and a good chunk of the realm already recognises him as king, so he doesn't have to climb over a mountain of corpses to get to the throne.

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27314286517.0" user="Vanbone" delta="False">
    <text>I'll agree with your statement, but I also think there's a better way. There are serious problems for every contender for the Iron Throne. This begs the question: Do you really think Westros will benefit from having one united King? I would favor a return to the divisions similar to what existed before the [War of Conquest](http://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/War_of_Conquest). 

* **The North** - The North would have some internal struggles before settling on a new King. I would hope they would settle on a confederation; I don't want to see Ramsay in charge any time soon. But frankly, I don't see any other contender for the throne doing a better job of ruling than even Roose Bolton. The North is simply too large, with different needs from the rest of the kingdom. 

* **The Iron Islands** - The Iron Islands is flat out ungovernable. If the other kingdoms could cooperate (or at least the Lannisters and the Confederation of the North), they might send a small army to occupy them and ideally teach them to amend their not-sowing ways. But it's also not urgent. They're no major threat at the moment. 

* **The Vale** - The Vale is an issue. Robert Arryn is the only person with a real claim, and he's psychotic. Since we're just talking about who the best ruler would be, I'd give the vale to Dany, presuming she ever crosses. It has a strong history of Targaryen rule in any case. 

* **The Riverlands** - Leave the Riverlands to the Blackfish, assuming he's alive. He seems competent enough, and has a good claim. 

* **The Westerlands** - Let Tommen and Margaery  be wed, and together rule the Westerlands and Reach, hopefully with this good match Tommen is able to overcome the corruption of his family. 

* **The Stormlands** - Let Stannis rule in the Stormlands. He won't be happy about it, but hopefully he could accept that. If not, perhaps Gendry or Edric could do the job. 

* **Dorne** - Prince Doran seems capable of doing an able enough job. 

The new kingdom would face it's difficulties. They would likely need to cooperate against the Others, and eventually Dany may actually come to invade. But maybe not. For the people of Westeros, this still seems like the best option for survival and prosperity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314366334.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>if were talking about things that will not happen... Why not a republic? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
