<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37032984017.0" user="asurtio" delta="False">
    <text>There're no good or bad artists either. Taste is entirely subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033005299.0" user="pearoli" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that’s taste is subjective  - but there are some popular artists who are objectively bad musicians/vocalists. For example (no offense to her fans) but Selena Gomez is not a great vocalist yet she is one omg thee most popular pop artists in America/South America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033196920.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>By what metric is Selena Gomez one of the most popular pop artists?  She is *A* pop artist, sure, but I always thought she was only mildly successful and nowhere near as relevant as artists like Billie Eilish or Doja Cat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033288602.0" user="YogiBerraOfBadNews" delta="False">
    <text>I can only offer my perspective as someone who doesn’t ever listen to the radio or really anything currently popular. I’m familiar with Selena Gomez, never heard of Doja Cat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033334154.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>I listen to a lot of music so I will just tell you that Selena Gomez isn't super successful and this can be attributed to the fact that she is significantly less talented than more successful artists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033401297.0" user="pearoli" delta="False">
    <text>She has a huge South American fan base and is moderately successful in the US($75mil net worth as of 2021), but perhaps she’s a bad example. Taylor swift - genuinely one of the biggest pop/country stars ever - can hold a note, but an objectively good vocalist she is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033424986.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;She has a huge South American fan base

Where are you getting this from? She only just began her real shift to Latin pop this year, and her first single only just barely broke into the top 100 on the Latin pop charts (peaking at 92).

&amp;gt; Taylor swift - genuinely one of the biggest pop/country stars ever - can hold a note, but an objectively good vocalist she is not. 

That's because she is a songwriter first and foremost, and an insanely talented one at that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033461424.0" user="pearoli" delta="False">
    <text>I’m just giving examples of objectively bad artists being enjoyed based on subjective criteria of the listener. I don’t care about either of these women, or debating with you to be quite honest. Cheerio!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033035249.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>So my two year old niece singing out of tune is arguably on par with Adele?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033076077.0" user="asurtio" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, since there's no way to objectively measure quality of music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033128733.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>Intonation is 100% objective. Notes have specific and measurable frequencies. If you heard a melody and another melody that was tuned a hair above the other, it would sound so grating that many would practically consider it torture.

Why do casinos bother to ensure that every slot machine is in the same key if there were no objective measures in music?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033192049.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Both of your examples have two or more objects playing music together. Of course if they don’t have the same intonation it would sound off. 

But that persons niece singing is doing it alone, there’s no choir backing them up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033201711.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>If she starts in one key and ends with another (which is inevitable when singing out of tune), then it's still the same result. You have an idea in your head of what key this is in, and it changes from there, leading most people who hear it to cringe.

At the very least, my point can extend to anyone singing with any accompaniment whatsoever. A solo singer is not a common form of music that people listen to, so it seems odd to even be discussing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033864272.0" user="Skavau" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't account for deliberately dissonant, grating and atonal music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034055422.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>I assume you mean something like Trout Mask Replica. As much of a train wreck as that album is, it is at least in tune.

I couldn't name you a single recording where anyone is clearly intentionally singing or playing out of tune. The microtonal guitar playing that King Gizzard and the Lizard Wizard is using is still a structured atonal scale where most of the notes are still in the right place anyway. But music producers will always fix anything out of tune. It's why a lot of artists use autotuning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034063339.0" user="Skavau" delta="False">
    <text>That, sure, but I also mean stuff like grindcore, black metal, noise (harsh noise), death metal, aggrotech etc. Plenty of stuff that is deliberately lacking in melody and would be grating to 90% of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034066765.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>None of that is typically out of tune.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034075694.0" user="Skavau" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but I was focusing on the focus on melody (and the idea that "grating" music = bad) in your statement and noting genres that would be inherently repulsive to most people if they heard it.

Also there is the curious case of The Shaggs which contrarians have isolated as a hidden masterpiece.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034078731.0" user="malachai926" delta="False">
    <text>Then you're not focusing on anything relevant to my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033040811.0" user="Andresk99" delta="False">
    <text>If I pick up a guitar and start playing random notes, Jimmy Hendrix isn’t necessary a better guitarist than me ‘cause it’s all subjective? If I start yelling at a microphone, am I not necessarily worse than Freddy Mercury at singing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033086209.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Jimmy Hendrix isn’t necessary a better guitarist than me ‘cause it’s all subjective

Correct. People can have weird tastes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033160430.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>This is asinine.  Just because there is no absolute certainty or truth to a subjective assessment means that we shouldn't bother with subjective assessment at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033175632.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not at all what I said. People can have their own opinions, and I’m sure the *vast* majority would consider Jimi Hendrix better, but that’s not an objective fact.

You can say someone is better, but that doesn’t mean they are *objectively* better</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033202513.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>The image of OP plucking random notes in a horrible, discordant mess while *Jimi Hendrix* works miracles on a guitar, while you stand there with a finger on your chin going "hmmmm, but which of us can say one is objectively better than the other?" is fucking hilarious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033220560.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Who knows? Maybe toddlers like the random bumbling of OP on a guitar more because it makes them laugh. Unless you poll everyone on earth, there’s no way to say that it’s objectively better</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033266841.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, let's have toddlers decide fiscal policy based on which economic advisors can make the best googly faces at them as well. Let's have toddlers working in city planning departments and base our infrastructure around their scrawling. Who's to say their opinion isn't objectively better than a civil engineer's, am I right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033308405.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>What? 

&amp;gt; Who's to say their opinion isn't objectively better than a civil engineer's

It’s the people hiring, if you really want to get into it. But using “opinion” and “objective” in the same sentence is contradictory. Sure, if there was a child prodigy that had a 100000 IQ, people could choose to hire them. 

Employers hire people who they think is best for the job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033330174.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>And there's no way to decide who's objectively better suited for a job, is there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033346656.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Correct. You can decide who you think is better personally, but someone else might value other characteristics that make them “better”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033360404.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>Really think about how *absurd* your position is here. 

You're saying that someone who studied medicine for seven years could be just as well suited to being a surgeon as a *toddler* because another person likes the toddler's "can-do" attitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033417836.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, let me clarify. 

Any choice that people make is inherently subjective. That doesn’t mean all things are subjective. 

In this example, things like test scores are objective. The person in med school can ace every test, while the baby would be lucky to know what a test is. People make their final (subjective) decisions on who would be a better doctor based on objective factors like test scores.

People’s opinions are subjective, even though the factors that influence them aren’t necessarily</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033427389.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>Is the ability to sing in tune subjective or objective?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033452582.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s objective. But I’m realizing where the confusion came from. 

“Better” in my mind meant more enjoyment. How much someone enjoys something is subjective. But someone can have more technical skills than someone else. That’s objective. So they are “better” in that regard. Sorry for any confusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033276209.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>Haha you really just shot down your own argument because we absolutely can run a poll to find out that 99.99999999% of listeners are going to prefer Hendrix.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033287737.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s…proving my point. 99.99999% does not equal 100%. Nothing is truly objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033324178.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>So 99.9999% is not objectively a greater percentage than .0001%? Really weird take man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033356278.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Those are two different statements you’re making. 

It’s an objective fact that more people like Hendrix, but that’s not the same as saying “X is objectively better than Y”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033403100.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>But you're not showing why objectivity matters at all.  Why is objectivity the right lens with which to assess one artist relative to another? Especially when objectivity is going to lead you to obviously absurd conclusions like Hendrix is not better or worse of a guitarist than somebody who can't really play guitar at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033443413.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is objectivity the right lens with which to assess one artist relative to another? 

I don’t think it is. With things like art there’s no objectivity, since interpretation is up to the viewer. Yes, you can judge based on technique and compare them that way. Based on what a guitarist is supposed to do, Hendrix is better in that regard. But I was trying to say that enjoyment is subjective. 

It really boils down to the definition of “better” you use. I assumed better meant “more enjoyment”, not “better technique”. I can see where the confusion came from</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033310526.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>you think jimi hendrix couldnt make "random bumbling" on a guitar?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033363578.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>He could, but that doesn’t mean he’s objectively better .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033460948.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>he can play all the music that you could play, plus a hell of lot more.

how is that not objectively better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033474064.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve realized that I’ve been using a different definition of better. I interpreted it as better = more enjoyment. How much someone enjoys something is entirely subjective. But yes, Hendrix does have more technical skills and knowledge, so he is better in that regard</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033485212.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>oh yea i definitely agree that hendrix isnt objectively more enjoyable guitarist but hes objectively a more skillful and talented guitarist

just depends on how you decide to use the word "better"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033499793.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I was just operating under the assumption that we all were using the same definition of better. My bad</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035267929.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Toddlers are objectively bad at distinguishing between bad and good music.

A poll wouldn't work either. Quality in music isn't a matter of popularity. There are masterpieces that are extremely hard to listen to, or very unpleasant to look at. Take Guernica for example. If nobody told you it was a masterpiece, you wouldn't know.

I know it's not a popular opinion, but art after a certain point, takes education to be appreciated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035295692.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I know it's not a popular opinion, but art after a certain point, takes education to be appreciated.

I agree with that statement. 

Have a good one!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033266107.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but you are saying that for an artist to be considered good or bad at all, the lens must be objective.  That seems completely arbitrary to me.  Subjectivity may not lead to absolute certainty, but that doesn't mean we just ignore it as a mode of assessment.  Even objectivity has epistemological problems such that absolute certainty may be impossible if you dig deep enough.  At least when it comes to art and aesthetics, there is absolutely no reason why we shouldn't value subjectivity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033341919.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not what I’m saying at all. Whether you consider an artist good or not is your own subjective opinion. It’s a person choice that everyone makes. Of course subjectivity matters. 


&amp;gt; Even objectivity has epistemological problems such that absolute certainty may be impossible if you dig deep enough. 

Correct. We can call things objective if we want, but it’s never absolutely certain, at least in regards to perception


&amp;gt; At least when it comes to art and aesthetics, there is absolutely no reason why we shouldn't value subjectivity.

Exactly. Subjective opinion has value, but people proclaiming that their opinion is an objective fact is where I find the issue. I guess if you really want to get into it, someone’s opinion is objectively true to them, but not to others</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033306912.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>anything a amateur guitarist could play, jimi hendrix could too

you think Hendrix couldnt produce the random noise that you or i could?

hes a better guitarist, in that hes more skilled. anything i could play he could play better + a hell of a lot of shit i could never dream of playing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035221998.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Of course I can. I can write a book on exactly why Bach or Ravel are objectively, better musicians than Justin Bieber, according to every definition of art ever conceived by a human being.

Just because it's hard to categorize musicians of the same range of quality, doesn't mean there is no scale at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035253030.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t want to copy and paste my previous comments, but I was previous under the impression that “better” in this case meant more enjoyable, which is obviously subjective.I agree that technique wise, it’s very easy to clarify people as better or worse</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035291741.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Oh no. You don't judge art by how "enjoyable" it is. Art is not a burger or a joy ride. Joy is only one feeling, and art is a way of conveying countless different feelings or ideas. Picasso wasn't painting to produce something that's "enjoyable".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035309948.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a fair point. But from the perspective of a layman who doesn’t have a deep knowledge of art, people just gravitate to things they find neat. 

A large majority of people conflate “better” with “this brings me more enjoyment”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035893882.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. And this is where the notion that "*quality of an artistic expression is only a matter of personal taste"* originates.

Well. this, and the fact that art works between the artist and the audience. There are masterpieces that are "compatible" with almost everyone to a degree, like the songs of Rolling Stones, and art that requires some sort of background to be appreciated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035911380.0" user="arrgobon32" delta="False">
    <text>Well dang. You know a lot more about art theory than I do. Granted, I don’t know anything about it so it’s not too high of a bar to cross. But thank you for your response! I learned a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034483723.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>I take it you haven't heard "well I should have" by Jon Benjamin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035325520.0" user="ZanderDogz" delta="False">
    <text>I think that Jimi Hendrix could be considered the "better guitarist" because he is simply capable of doing more on a guitar than you are, but who is the "better artist" is still subjective unless your definition of a good artist is influence, popularity, etc. 

Maybe someone just hates Jimi Hendrix and doesn't mind what you do so much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033044179.0" user="DeathStarVet" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree with you about taste, but if someone sings out of key and has no rhythm (if they are not expressly trying to comment on music by purposely being arrhythmic and out of tune) then they are a bad artist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033058824.0" user="Freezefire2" delta="False">
    <text>This is correct. To respond to the other replies, "good" and "bad" are not synonymous with "skilled" and "unskilled".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033080342.0" user="blatant_ban_evasion_" delta="False">
    <text>How does that work? 

"Ah yes, he's a master chef who makes terrible food"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033099508.0" user="Andresk99" delta="False">
    <text>What is your definition of a “good” artist if skilled =/= good?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033109129.0" user="Freezefire2" delta="False">
    <text>Whether or not someone likes that musician</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033331584.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>so everyone is good at every instrument because theres probably someone out there that would like the music they produce?

a bad musician doesnt exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033351124.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what they're saying. They're saying *nobody* is objectively good or bad. Whether someone is "good" is a function of both the target person *and the person making the judgement*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033455350.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>eh i think someone can be a good musician even if i dont like their music

im sure there are people out there that dont like Jimi Hendrix music, but hes still a "good" guitarist

maybe i just disagree with their definition of "good". they would say "not good but skilled" and i would say "not enjoyable but good"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033488164.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>"Good" or "bad" is one of the most incredibly complex gestalt judgements we can make. Personal enjoyment is one aspect, personal judgement of skill can be another, or impact on others or the opinions of valued friends or...

So yeah, you certainly could call someone "good" even if you don't enjoy their work. But it's not objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033503819.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; personal judgement of skill can be another

are you saying someone cant be objectively more skillful than someone else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033629043.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>A valuation of "skill" requires determining what criteria matter and how much, which is a subjective process.

Some of the specific criteria may be objectively measurable, but that's not the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033704950.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>yea thats a really good point

ability to be in tune, on beat, volume control, etc are all objective in the sense that i can objectively say someone is more in tune than someone else 

however theres still the subjective element in that i personally think that being in tune is a good measure of a persons musical skill</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034523216.0" user="dantheman91" delta="False">
    <text>A "good" artist is someone who puts out music I enjoy. That doesn't mean the music is the highest quality, physically demanding to play or anything else, simply that I enjoyed it. 

There can be very gifted musicians who play music that I just don't like. I generally wouldn't say "Oh yeah he's really good" if I'm not enjoying it, but I'll certainly agree he's gifted at a given instrument or w/e.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036086142.0" user="Gaygayallday" delta="False">
    <text>they make good sounding music, which doesn't need skill, because good is subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033436367.0" user="zuluportero" delta="False">
    <text>usually it is tho. For example people do enjoy the room, but those people still don't call it a good movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033154101.0" user="OneWordManyMeanings" delta="False">
    <text>Taste is subjective, but subjective things can still be critically assessed.  What OP is really saying is that the best way to critically assess music is to not write off entire genres as bad, but rather assess music within those genres by the characteristics that fans of those genres appreciate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033336268.0" user="SixxTheSandman" delta="False">
    <text>This, exactly. All art is relative to the person perceiving it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033487753.0" user="MajesticFxxkingEagle" delta="False">
    <text>Respectfully disagree.

While the consuming public has subjective tastes that can deviate from the average, there are objective standards of craftsmanship, applied musical knowledge, effort and creative collaboration that goes into making a “good” song.

What makes a “good” song depends on the artist’s goal. It could be making the audience feel a certain emotion, conveying a specific message, making people want to dance, making people think deeply about something, simply attracting the most listeners or maybe a combination of multiple factors. However, once that goal is established, yes you definitely can objectively judge how effective an artist was in creating music that achieved those goals.

EDIT: like another comment pointed out, a concrete example of this is a vocalist hitting the right notes when performing a song. If the vocalist’s goal is to sing the melody as accurately and harmoniously as possible, then that can be objectively measured and a vocalist can be judged as good or bad based on that criteria.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37033749734.0" user="stikos1337" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree, but if you **have** to define *good &amp;amp; bad,* then I'd say that *popular opinion* is your best metric. It might be biased in all sorts of ways (*from* the level of outreach and the demographic characteristics of it *to* sheer luck, because a song just happen to pop up on the top of the charts for a multitude of reasons) , but I think it's still the closest to the big picture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37034584330.0" user="DownvoteMagnet6969" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#x200B;

There are no good or bad artists; mainly there are just the ones you connect with when you're in your teens and will forever cherish because they resonated with you during the emotional process of discovering yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035187988.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Nonsense. 

Even though categorizing art is extremely difficult, there are artists that are objectively of higher quality.

Johann Sebastian Bach is objectively, a musician of higher quality than Justin Bieber.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035297103.0" user="asurtio" delta="False">
    <text>By what measurable metric?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37035375096.0" user="What_Dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Quality isn't always demonstrated by measurable metrics.

In this case, we could define "art", and examine how one musician serves that definition compared to the other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
