<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37034132779.0" user="WMDick" delta="False">
    <text>OK. Thought experiment time. I just invented a musical genre. It's called RaSoaC, standing for 'random scrathing on a chalkboard. To be included in this genre, the goal is to make as random as possible scratches on a chalk board. Music should be as painful as possible to the human ear.

I so happen to be the world's foremost artist of this genre. I can annoy people like no other. Is the genre good or bad? 

If you agree that the genre is inherently bad, then that does suggest that there are objectivly bad genres of music. This suggests a spectrum of genres that tend to please people vs. tend not to. 

Thoughts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37036544057.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you agree that the genre is inherently bad, then that does suggest that there are objectivly bad genres of music. 

I have a friend who would enjoy that. You know that deliberately awful [Pterodactyl Song?](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FY9ToUwxLmg) He regularly jams to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039014871.0" user="WMDick" delta="False">
    <text>Which raises the question: can anything about art be trully objective?

My position is that there are things that are so bad that 99.999% of people don't like it. I call this 'functionally objective'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042940618.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;can anything about art be trully objective?

Yes, lots of things. In painting, you can observe how masterful the brushstrokes are and critique the level of technique. In music, you can observe how much skill is being displayed. In literature, you can observe the sophistication of linguistic techniques. From this perspective, you can make objective assessment of quality based on certain observable criteria. 

&amp;gt;My position is that there are things that are so bad that 99.999% of people don't like it. I call this 'functionally objective'.

My position is two-fold. First, what people like is always 100% subjective. There is no criteria for liking something, thus it can never be objective by definition. And second, what people like has zero bearing on what is "good" or "bad." 

Do you consider MacDonalds good food? I consider it crap. I like it, but using objective culinary standards of quality, it's hot garbage. It just happens to be absolute crap that a lot of people like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37059726116.0" user="WMDick" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In painting, you can observe how masterful the brushstrokes are

All the examples you listed are still highly subjective as people will disagree on what it means to be 'masterful' or 'skilled'. Imagine fans of differant painting schools discussing the strokes of impressionist art. Da Vinci would look at a Van Gogh and dismiss it as the work of a child. 

&amp;gt;From this perspective, you can make objective assessment of quality based on certain observable criteria.

You seem to go back and forth. 'Subjective' just means that not every single human on the planet will agree on an opinion that has to do with personal taste. It's important that we emphasize the **personal taste** thing. It is an objective fact that vaccines work. Holding the opinion that Prince is a more talented guitar player than Slash is a matter of personal taste and that is, by definition, subjective. 

&amp;gt;There is no criteria for liking something, thus it can never be objective by definition

Which I why I envoked the term of 'Functionally Objective'. It's a useful concept, too. How many people would prefer a painting made of smeared feces across a blank canvas to a Van Gogh masterpiece? There's probably some deranged people who would prefer the shit the first but we can still say with confidence that the first painting is crappy. 

I sometimes describe this as the 'grandma' test. Would my grandma enjoy 98% of 'modern' art? Nope.

Sometimes it's more nuanced though. You have genuine music experts who can't agree whether Ringo Starr has the talent of a reluctant 10th grad band-class drummer or if he's a subtle genius. 

&amp;gt;Do you consider MacDonalds good food?

This is WAY more subjective than the other examples. The word 'good' is doing a lot of work here. There is a time and place for McDonalds and other things that people think are 'not good'. Sometimes, a bud light lime is about the most refreshing thing there is. Is it 'good' beer? No, but it's good for what you may be wanting at that moment in time. And sometimes a drive-through egg McMuffin is just the thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37064155712.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All the examples you listed are still highly subjective as people will disagree on what it means to be 'masterful' or 'skilled'. 

The people who disagree with that would be the artistically ignorant. There are people who "disagree" about evolution. They are ignorant and don't understand the objective facts. Within the framework of different styles, you can objectively ascertain the skill being displayed.

&amp;gt;'Subjective' just means that not every single human on the planet will agree on an opinion

100% wrong. "Subjective" means it is a matter of opinion, not a matter of fact. When something is objective, it doesn't matter how many people think what. Objective statements can be given a value of "true" or "false." In art this means that displays of skill meet certain established standards or they don't. Did you sing on pitch or not? Did you perform with the correct dynamics? Did you articulate correctly? Etc. It gets complex, but it is very possible to evaluate the quality of any work of art under established criteria. 

&amp;gt;Which I why I envoked the term of 'Functionally Objective'. It's a useful concept, too.

Actually, no. It's just a fancy way of saying, "really popular." Which is completely irrelevant in a discussion of artistic quality. 

&amp;gt;How many people would prefer

Gonna stop you right there. Every statement you make about what people prefer is completely irrelevant.

&amp;gt;You have genuine music experts who can't agree whether Ringo Starr has the talent of a reluctant 10th grad band-class drummer or if he's a subtle genius.

Objectively speaking, you *can* assess his talent based on his feats of drumming. The people who call him a "genius" are referring to his popularity, which, as said, is irrelevant. 

So, the core flaw with your reasoning is that you keep on conflating what people "like" with actual quality. People like =/= good. Ever. In anything. It's integrated into all of your arguments, and you can't speak to anything I'm saying until you discard the notion of people liking things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37067918887.0" user="WMDick" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There are people who "disagree" about evolution.

This is the distinction that I am trying to illuminate. The term 'subjective' only relates to maters of personal taste. Here is the definition:

sub·jec·tive
/səbˈjektiv/
1.
based on or influenced by personal feelings, tastes, or opinions. 

It does not relate to 'personal feelings' about evoluition as that is an objective fact of the natural world. If we can't agree upon that then we have too little English in common to have a productive conversation. 

&amp;gt;Which is completely irrelevant in a discussion of artistic quality.

We'll disagree there too. There is a reason why 99.999% of people on the planet agree that Leonardo was artistically talented while my cat is not. It is as close to an objecitve fact as one can get with personal feelings. 

&amp;gt;his talent based on his feats of drumming. 

You're smuggling in objectiveness into something that is not objective. His 'feats of drumming' according to whom?

&amp;gt;you keep on conflating what people "like" with actual quality

Actual quality decided by whom? The fault of your reasoning is that you keep smuggling in some sort of objective gatekeeper in matters that are entirely subjective, ie. related to personal feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
