<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1436896267.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nrho97/cmv_there_are_no_good_or_bad_music_genres_just/">
    <title>CMV: There are no good or bad music genres, just good or bad artists.</title>
    <original_poster>Andresk99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it. Rock is your favorite music genre, you hate country or pop. Whatever it is, it doesn’t make your favorite genre “the one”.

Music is like food. There’s pizza, hamburguers, sandwiches, tacos, burritos, nuggets, etc. That doesn’t make one better than the other. But there are people or restaurants that can make great delicious pizzas and others who make average pizzas. The same way, there are amazing rappers with great lyricism and rhythm, and others who use an overproduced beat and have poor lyricism. There are Metal guitarists with great technique and years of experience, and others who don’t.

And this whole “my favorite genre is better than yours” thing applies to almost everything: books, videogames, movies...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37038365887.0" user="WalterPolyglot" delta="False">
    <text>Reggae is awful. I believe this so hard that my brain won't let me believe it's subjective. I'm a musician and there are artists, songwriters and performers in every genre that I can appreciate. Except for Raggae.

You know when you say something stupid and someone parrots your words back at you, but in that exaggerated derpy voice, to let you know how stupid you sound? Reggae sounds like it's doing that to music. 

Derp-derpy-durpDerp, derp-derpy-durpDerp. 

Plenty of people will disagree, *but* in order for your argument to be something we can tangibly dissect, shouldn't you be forced to allow for the possibility that I am correct and they are all wrong? Otherwise, all you have to say is "taste is subjective." Which, it is. Sure. People are welcome to have bad taste and listen to shitty music if they want to... that doesn't mean that the music is good. 

Are there aspects of bad things that could be considered admirable? Sure! Reggae has a rich history and culture associated with it, which shouldn't be dismissed out of hand just because their music sounds like agonizingly repetitive derp-derps. 

In fact, I'd say the second half of your own title disproves your own assertion.

"There are no good or bad music genres, **just good or bad artists.**"

If there can be good and bad artists, then you are claiming there is an aspect of music that is NOT subjective to some degree. So how can you argue that a whole genre is incapable of being bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038473363.0" user="Skavau" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If there can be good and bad artists, then you are claiming there is an aspect of music that is NOT subjective to some degree. So how can you argue that a whole genre is incapable of being bad?

The argument would go (from the OP) that there are a level of goals, objectives associated with each genre. So you may not like 'peak' Reggae, so to speak, but if an artist achieves it, and is well regarded by fans of Reggae - then it has accomplished what it set out to do and may be considered a 'good artist'.

Where as objection to a genre is just rejection of its artistic vision, and would seem somewhat self-absorbed to say that it's inherently bad because you personally find nothing redeeming in it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040312973.0" user="WalterPolyglot" delta="False">
    <text>If the argument is that art is subjective, and that the artists get to determine whether or not they succeeded in their own goals, that's a pretty unwinnable argument. I don't disagree with the sentiment, but CMV's that use subjective terms and assert the claim that they cannot be judged objectively feel like a setup. So, while I agree that art is subjective and that a whole genre cannot be considered inherently "bad" (a term whose definition is severely lacking to begin with), I am trying to point out that if the CMV is going to put objective parameters on this subjective field, we need to first agree to tangible terms. Is good/bad defined by personal, immeasurable success? Is it defined by skill? Complexity or popularity? Is it based on delivering a message? Who gets to determine what the goal is? 

I suspect the answer is any of those and that everyone gets to make their own choices as to whether the genre succeeded, and a singular "win" means that the entire genre is redeemable and "good..." so even if a genre like Raggae set out to be one thing and lost its way entirely, the argument cannot be won to the contrary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041835786.0" user="Skavau" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;
If the argument is that art is subjective, and that the artists get to determine whether or not they succeeded in their own goals, that's a pretty unwinnable argument.

Not artists. The general audience would be the 'determining' factor.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
