<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143643292.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dirvg/cmv_of_all_the_people_with_a_claim_on_the_iron/">
    <title>CMV: Of all the people with a claim on the Iron Throne, Stannis Baratheon would make the best king.</title>
    <original_poster>ytpies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can't really talk about this without avoiding spoilers, but I'll try and spoiler tag things that haven't happened in the show yet, so the discussion isn't restricted to book readers only.

Let's have a look at Stannis' competition:

- Dany

A young girl with little experience ruling, the Westerosi equivalent of nukes, and a tenuous grip on sanity. She's female, her father went power crazy and started killing people, she can't control her dragons, and her army is made up of slaves. It should come as no surprise that the nobles of Westeros won't exactly welcome her with open arms, forcing her to stage an invasion just to get close to ruling. Not to mention she's infertile, so when she dies there will be yet more drama over who succeeds her. Unstable would be the best way to describe both her rule, and Dany herself.

- 
[Spoiler](/s "Aegon.")

[spoiler](/s "Having been raised to rule, and claiming to be the son of Rhaegar, who was much more popular and much less insane than this father, he would have a much easier time of convincing various Lords to his side. However, there's a good chance that he isn't who he claims he is, and his army is made up of sellswords, only a fraction of which actually made it to Westeros. Plus he hangs around with a Greyscale victim who might inadvertently infect him.")

- Tommen

A puppet ruler. controlled by his mother. Although getting him onto the Iron Throne would be no problem, since he already has it, keeping him on it is another thing entirely. If Cersei doesn't singlehandedly destroy the dynasty, the yes men she put on the Small Council will. Confidence in him is very low, since the tale of Tommen's parentage has also been spread far and wide, and though many people don't believe it, everyone knows it.

- Myrcella

Free from her mother's influence, and rightful queen under Dornish law, Myrcella would make a much stronger ruler than Tommen. However, her claim is under Dornish law only, so for her to be recognised by the rest of the realm Tommen would have to die. She's strong-willed, but I doubt that she would go along with killing her own brother. [Spoiler](/s "It is doubtful that even Dorne would support her fully, since they are also likely to back Aegon."). There is also the whole incest thing to contend with.

- Jon Snow

If R+L=J is true, then Jon would also have a claim on the throne. He would be backed by the North, due to his Stark blood, and has [Spoiler](/s "experience as a leader from being Lord Commander of the Night's Watch."). However, since he is a part of the Night's Watch, his oaths would forbid him from ruling.  Even if he were to escape his vows somehow, and if R+L=J turns out to be true, he would still be a bastard. His claim would be very weak. [Spoiler](/s "He also might be dead.")

There are very few other real contenders for the throne. Gendry would have to find proof of his parentage, would still have a very weak claim, and would probably be just as bad a ruler as Robert. Rickon could become King in the North, but he's a child and believed dead. People seem to think that Sansa will become queen with Littlefinger backing her, but that involves trusting Littlefinger. Almost all of the various "x is a secret Targ" theories are stupid.

Compare those with Stannis the Mannis. He is an experienced leader, commander, and king. He rewards people based on merit rather than birth, and hates brown-nosers. He prefers to act based on honor, but will not let it bind him when the stakes are higher. He leaps to defend the realm from the Others rather than continuing to squabble over the throne. He actually is the rightful king of Westeros. He has Melisandre, who can do legit magic, and a good chunk of the realm already recognises him as king, so he doesn't have to climb over a mountain of corpses to get to the throne.

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27313763462.0" user="guruPanda" delta="False">
    <text>I think it would be the right thing for Tommen Baratheon to sit the Throne, simply because he already sits there.

Every other contender would have to win a war to get it. Let's focus on Stannis:

Let's check if waging that war would be a good idea: Just war theory knows several criteria to determine whether a war is just. Most of these Stannis can claim to fulfill, like Just cause (He is, debatably, the rightful king after all), Competent authority etc. However, he fails in two important ones:

Probability of success: Let's face it, it's unlikely that Stannis will win this war he's waging. This invalidates his right intentions, as you can't say the ends justify the means when it is unreasonable to assume that the means will successfully reach the end.

But more importantly: Proportionality. Will waging a war to bring him the Throne ultimately lessen suffering? No it won't. Even if Stannis is a competent King, better one than Tommen/Cersei, he will not do more good than the bad a civil war in a time where the people should really be gathering their last harvests before the winter will do. Just not gonna happen.

This is also why I supported Renly before he was murdered: He didn't have the claim, but usurping his brother was justified as his being a bachelor brought the Tyrells in to allegiance, something Stannis couldn't have done. And having the Tyrells gave him the probablility of success Stannis didn't have, so much even that the war would have been a quick and dominant one, lessening the suffering. Also, gentle and open-minded Renly with Margeary as his wife could have done way more good than harsh Stannis ever could have, who might be a just king, but a good one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313768135.0" user="ytpies" delta="False">
    <text>It's worth noting that when Stannis first declared himself king, he was planning on joining forces with Renly. It's just that Renly was stupid and declined Stannis' deal of making him his Hand and heir over Shireen. With a force that large, he could have easily marched on King's Landing with time to spare and crushed the Lannister forces. Instead he had to make do with a smaller force, and was delayed by Cortnay Penrose at Storm's End.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313811290.0" user="guruPanda" delta="False">
    <text>No, because the Tyrells would never have accepted an alliance where Margeary wasn't queen. They would have gone over to Joffrey weren't it for Renly pressing his claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313819568.0" user="ytpies" delta="False">
    <text>I think they would have still gone for an alliance that would make Margeary queen when Stannis died. Even if they didn't, Renly could have told Penrose to stand down. He wouldn't have delayed them by a few days, and the Baratheon Brothers Dream Team could have taken King's Landing before Tywin showed up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314009932.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Stannis showed up before a massive army with a miniscule one, and demanded to be the King.  If Renly was "stupid" it is only in misunderestimating Stannis' ability/willingness to assassinate his own brother.  Stannis could have easily made a more reasonable offer, even including a willingness to "negotiate the details of which is to be King" after taking King's Landing.  He was simply too rigid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314157146.0" user="Senoide" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect Renly knew his brother too well to believe he'd even consider compromise. "A willingness to negotiate" would have been a lie, Renly knew that, and more importantly, Stannis knew that. His iron nature is what's probably going to break him in the end, but meanwhile it's also his greatest asset - people know Stannis will keep his word if it means he dies doing it. He can't just set aside duty for a while when it's convenient.

In game theory terms, Renly should have known that Stannis will always play hawk until he dies, even when Renly is on the Iron Throne and Stannis exiled somewhere in Essos, so there's no point in trying to make him play dove. If Renly truly wanted to play king, he should have just crushed Stannis immediately, or headed to King's Landing and then dealt with Stannis. He had a lousy claim to begin with, so just drop the pretense and conquer the throne like Robert and Aegon I did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314166555.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Stannis bowed to his stronger brother Robert rather than obey the Targaryen with the true claim to the Throne.  Renly had no way of knowing Stannis could not likewise bow to his superior force.  Furthermore, he had no way of knowing that Stannis could do more than sulk on Dragonstone faced with Renly's overwhelming army.  For Stannis to "play hawk" would be no problem except that he just so happened to have formerly-unknown black magic.


Renly was heading to King's Landing to conquer.  He was trying to do so with as little bloodshed as possible.  By moving slowly and gathering overwhelming numbers, he made it likely that he could conquer without fighting a single battle or killing any men.  This is hardly to be despised.  He just didn't reckon on the new magics that had secretly been unleashed on the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27314267888.0" user="Senoide" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that Renly would have been a good and relatively nonviolent king, but I don't think a good king is a stable equilibrium, especially if you're looking to usurp the throne. Blood will be shed, and sooner or later you either die, or become the monster you were fighting and all that. I don't think he conquers King's Landing without Tywin Lannister and the Goldcloaks giving him a fight, whether he moves slowly or with haste.

But you're right, he had no way of knowing about Stannis' magic. Still, he *would* have survived had he smashed him immediately or moved towards KL, but hindsight is always 20/20. Besides, like Stannis, he probably had a deontological conundrum as well - without being accomodating, amicable, diplomatic and merciful, he wouldn't have had the support of so many powerful houses, so immediate action may have been off the table.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313788702.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>If Tommen had Tywin behind him that would be different, but things are falling apart there. Everyone has an issue with Lannisters now and wants to fuck them over. Cersei is only making it worse because she alone can't deal with it (and its turning her into Aerys), Jaime doesn't care, and that's pretty much all Tommen has now. 


We know that Stannis isn't exactly the popular guy, but he is winning over the north now, is the only remaining Baratheon and all things considering, they aren't the most hated family out there.

With Mel and possibly growing support if he manages to help the realm he could come back much stronger. I am not saying he realistically will, but he could emerge a hero and is the only one in competition for the throne (Jon excluded) who is doing something for the realm.

Plus he has Davos who can help his reputation with the commoners and be the soft side of Stannis.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313812778.0" user="guruPanda" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that Stannis on the Throne would be good for the realm because it needs a strong King right now, but considering his meagre chance of success and the suffering his war will bring even in victory, he should just call it quits. The right thing for Stannis to do is to stop pressing his claim, and going north to fight the others with Mel and his army, maybe he could even talk to the Lannisters and make it happen that the Boltons leave him be at the wall as long as he stays there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27313821270.0" user="KruegersNightmare" delta="False">
    <text>If he fights the Others as he might, the other candidates might easily cancel each other out. Lannisters are strong in manpower but everyone hates them and they lost strong leadership. Dany and Aegon might easily become enemies. Dorne isn't that strong in numbers and who knows where they will end up in the whole Dany/Aegon thing. Tyrells might even lose sooner than we think and go down with Lannisters. 

Perhaps if Stannis survives the others, he will come to the realm that welcomes him with open arms. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
