<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="91" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37039152450.0" user="blu3tu3sday" delta="False">
    <text>Kink has, for so long, been a central part of the gay community. The freedom to have gay sex gave us the freedom to explore how we like having that sex. No one should be fucking in public, but that’s already illegal, and by all means, NOT unique to gays in the slightest. But kink? Walking around in collars and leather and latex and masks? That’s almost an essential part of gay sexuality. As far as being family friendly, Pride events have no business being family friendly, especially after straights spent so long shutting us out of their families.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039919405.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Pride events have no business being family friendly, especially after straights spent so long shutting us out of their families.

For fucks sake, what a remarkable way to make people allies right? What a great way to ensure other people in your group are treated equally, by shutting everyone else out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040158999.0" user="blu3tu3sday" delta="False">
    <text>Pride is about celebrating the LGBT community and how far we’ve made it despite our continual oppression. It’s about showing that hey, we’re still here, even after sodomy laws, the “gay plague”, censorship, drugs, bathroom bills, military bans. I don’t give a fuck if allies come to Pride or not. Are we dependent on cishets for our survival? Unfortunately, we probably always will be. Is it my responsibility to make you feel like you should be celebrated for being a decent human being? Absolutely fucking not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040799074.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;despite our continual oppression

...

&amp;gt;I don’t give a fuck if allies come to Pride or not.

You really don't see how the latter leads to the former? How being exclusionary makes enemies and leads to oppression?

Equally that you can't celebrate how far you as a community has come without walking around in public with butt plugs showing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040894420.0" user="blu3tu3sday" delta="False">
    <text>“Walking around in collars and leather and latex and masks?”

Where exactly did I write that I think wearing buttplugs at Pride is ok? Please, show me.

Also, Pride is a celebration for gay people. Not allies. I will not applaud someone for not being a shitty person. Just like we don’t use Black History Month to applaud white folks who aren’t racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041249843.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>It was intentionally a ridiculous exaggeration, although does that change with your categories? Can you not celebrate pride without collars and latex? I'm not saying you have to or should, I'm saying can you? 

&amp;gt;Just like we don’t use Black History Month to applaud white folks who aren’t racist.

We use black history month to educate people about black history. Then it follows we use gay pride events to educate people on gay pride. Except people are hesitant to involve themselves and their children when it looks like a fetish convention. There's nothing about "celebrating" allies, it's getting more people on your side because that's how you end discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041258796.0" user="blu3tu3sday" delta="False">
    <text>Pride parades are a celebration. Pride parties and festivals are a celebration. They’re not storytime at the county library.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041270086.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>So change it to MLK day. You're missing the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041308858.0" user="blu3tu3sday" delta="False">
    <text>You have been intentionally missing my point from the moment you replied to my original comment, so 🤷🏻‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
