<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37038088681.0" user="freedcreativity" delta="False">
    <text>Look, you seem unconvinced by the other posters. The adult world is messy, deranged and frequently inappropriate. Pride reflects this messiness. The gays are not perfect people; we are an oppressed people expressing a highly complex cry of semi-sanctioned rebellion against the normative hegemony of WASP-y late-capitalism. Without people being grossed out, avoiding popular public places because of the queerness, is it really a pride event? No, it is some gay rights political rally... Pride is problematic, I'll grant you that. However, that problematic expression of gay angst IS the point. 

If you don't want to hang out with drunks don't go to the bar. If you don't want to be part of queer culture attempting to stake out a little piece of the public consciousness for consensual sexual torture, degradation and sodomy, then don't go to pride parades. It isn't a place for children, intentionally. 

Is the pride parade of gyrating, glittery 40-somethings expressing their love for their fellow queers worse than a Proud Boys pro-racism rally? Is it worse than a street preacher yelling at college students with spittle flying that they're all going to hell? Is it worse than your local Trump brigade rolling coal down the street? 

Those are the groups that Pride is specifically fighting against, the bigots. If our oppressors can hold fascist rallies in the city streets, yelling out, "the Jews will not replace us," are a few queers with their tits out the place to worry about limiting public expression?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038177476.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>Some pride parades are in fact intentionally for children, all age pride parades do exist. Like????

Also, humans have the brain capacity to be concerned about more than one thing. I can take issue with the proud boys and also find it weird that you want to expose sexually explicit kinks in front of children lol.

Specifically at all age presence, why the flying shit should elements of sexual degradation, torture, and sodomy be a thing. Pride events, whether you want to admit it or not, are in fact turning into family events. People do bring their children of all ages. If you’re at pride where everybody is 18+, then go ahead who gives a fuck. But outside of that, keep it to yourself. Nobody is silencing you, nobody is oppressing you by asking you to not do it in front of children or in family oriented spaces.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038235617.0" user="freedcreativity" delta="False">
    <text>I would contend that a pride parade for children ISN'T a pride parade. The carnival atmosphere, the kinks, the sexual energy is the political statement, in the same way fascists chanting antisemitism is their political statement.

No, the lack of 'queer sexual energy' in the public consciousness is part and parcel of oppression. If the important part of pride month is all the corporations changing their US twitter handle's logo, the gays should pack it up and get a supreme court justice or whatever counts for representation these days. Just because it isn't actually illegal to be gay anymore, doesn't mean that pride needs to become more like the memorial day parade. Pride is for the queers, it isn't a recruiting drive, it isn't a huge orgy, it isn't a kiddie event. Pride is literally screaming into the void of public discourse that non-normative sexuality is not destroying the social fabric. The gays will go back to their jobs, be productive members of society, and consume product but for a few days people can get weird.

What you're describing exists! Sex clubs, gay bars, festivals. Pride is not those things, it is a political expression. It is no different that other political rallies with problematic content, like anything with Trump involved...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038255493.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>Family oriented pride parades, are pride parade. There are different pride parades.

Some are family oriented, some are for older folks, some are geared towards teenagers.

The sexual energy, the kinks, the carnival atmosphere isn’t the only thing about pride that makes it pride. There are a lot of elements of pride.

I don’t know what queer sexual energy is, the BDSM community isn’t specifically queer-based. There are a variety of sexualities in these communities, even straight people get ridiculed for going out in public when they’re a part of these communities. This isn’t particularly LGBTQ plus focus, people just don’t like it when you do it in public or family oriented spaces.

Again with the pride for the queers (which literally, what the fuck does this even mean lol) queer people are not just sex crazed adults. There are a variety of queer people. Some people aren’t sexually focused. There are queer children. There are communities of queer people that cannot participate in sexually driven activities because of their respective cultures or family dynamics.

Nobody is really advocating that you kind of have to damper down your sexual expression, it’s just that you shouldn’t do it in family oriented spaces. Like, why can you not just do it in an 18+ or 16 and up space? I don’t get it.

Even then, there are more ways to shows sexual expression within the LGBTQ plus community that isn’t attached to BDSM and kink.

You have a very specific definition of what pride is, and that’s fine. But that does not mean every person on the planet has to subscribe to this definition, and many people don’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038514241.0" user="freedcreativity" delta="False">
    <text>You’re really trying hard to miss the point. Gay pride is a political event which is reminding people, “we’re here, we’re queer.” It is not a family event. It is not a happy, good time trip to a Disney sponsored resort. It is not the state fair. It IS problematic and that is allowed. The nebulous parts you’re calling problematic are the point of a pride parade. The sexuality is the political event! 

Look I’ve avoided this the whole time: you’re a minor. If pride is SO problematic that we can’t have gross leather daddies being gross, why are you on Reddit? The whole of social media has the same problems (and worse) lurking a click away. Shut it all down, we’ll all go back to Club Penguin. 

We are obligated legally to allow actual Nazis to hold rallies. But the gross mostly naked queers need to go away, because you’re offended and “won’t someone think of the children?” Your feelings are not the arbiter of what is allowed to happen in public, neither are my feelings. That queer sexuality in public spaces is the political discourse. It isn’t an inclusive space. Pride is about creating sexual frisson, no matter if the neoliberal gay marketers try to make pride into some corporate sponsored all ages rainbow party. 

Would you feel any differently about a group of glittery, mostly naked middle aged straight people having a sex parade? It’s called New Orleans or possibly Rio during carnival season. The dull people say the same thing about the drunk topless women there too! Hasn’t stopped them either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038891449.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>Lol.

Some are family events.

I’m not obligated to agree with your specific definition of what pride is.

BDSM doesn’t have to go away. It just shouldn’t be a thing at family oriented events. Do it at 18+, or really any event that doesn’t have children</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041894994.0" user="freedcreativity" delta="False">
    <text>Again, my point is the sexual expression is a political statement which underlies the actual pride events. The 'reason for the season' is creating discourse (like what we're doing now) through the normally forbidden expressions of sexuality. Everything else is something which could be called pride, but lacks the political underpinnings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041898913.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>That’s cool, doesn’t address or change my opinion about really anything I just said</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039396617.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>Are.. Are you gatekeeping pride events? That's a new one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
