<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037861008.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037999667.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Many places there ARE events geared specifically for children. And when those do exist at a location, it's very strange to try to police.. everything else. I don't think anyone will ever argue for fewer Pride events. If you notice something's missing that you'd like to attend.. be vocal! Try to start something, ANYTHING, even if it's just in your own back yard with your own household members! That's definitely celebrating Pride too!    


The reality is there are places that biker culture is far more accepted than LGBT+ existence is. You might be in one of those places. But the entire nation isn't the same way. And where, unfortunately, things haven't caught up, we DO still need people to lead smaller, more focused events. And that can't start without individuals stepping up and doing the initial planning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038075090.0" user="VictorZiblis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you notice something's missing that you'd like to attend.. be vocal! Try to start something, ANYTHING, even if it's just in your own back yard with your own household members! That's definitely celebrating Pride too!

That... actually yes.  I should, but what happens when I run into the same crap in real life as I do online, people telling me I am a bigot for trying to arrange something family friendly?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;The reality is there are places that biker culture is far more accepted than LGBT+ existence is. You might be in one of those places

Between you, me, and the sexy redhead's thighs I say this much:  I'd far rather my son be gay than a biker, but I will support any choice he makes.  

I haven't heard of a gay man supporting Trump.  Bikers not so much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038171626.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>No one should criticize you for hosting an event geared specifically for a target audience. The criticism we're seeing is about people trying to change the nature of large, main events that already exist. Also, the explanation 'I did not see an event geared for Y. I wanted to take my son to one, but I didn't want to intrude on events/communities that already exist.' is a really, REALLY solid argument, and I genuinely hope you have the confidence that you'd be able to ignore anyone criticizing that, because their argument (if one even existed) would be incredibly weak. Remind them that you're doing your best to add to Pride, not take away from it. Organizing things is hard, and every community has a chance of noisy busybodies. Thus also my recommendation of the backyard household members even because that would be all I'd have the energy for after just trying to exist right now, lol.

&amp;gt;Between you, me, and the sexy redhead's thighs I say this much:  I'd far rather my son be gay than a biker, but I will support any choice he makes.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;I haven't heard of a gay man supporting Trump.  Bikers not so much.

If it helps at all, the only bikers I personally know were incredibly anti-Trump and have also been great allies for me. I definitely don't have a sample size of 30, but there are great people in there, I promise!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038568413.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>you most not know many gay men xD

My uncles are the co chairs of a literal Gays for Trump fan club. These are men who grew up in the 60’s and have told me stories that bring me to tears. 

It’s absolutely mind boggling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038943798.0" user="Killfile" delta="False">
    <text>That is a whole other can of worms...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039247495.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>lmao yeah. we don’t talk much these days. 

They just moved to Texas because, and I quote, “the faggots have taken over”. 

Totally oblivious to the fact that the sole reason they moved to SF was to be around like minded (read: GAY) people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039459448.0" user="Killfile" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "The faggots have taken over."

lolwut?  

Seriously though, I'm really sorry they're becoming estranged from you.  It hurts to lose loved ones to extremism of any variety.  

✌️🏳️‍🌈</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039580254.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>I really appreciate your kind message. Thank you. 

yeah it mostly sucks because they were my examples of how Gay men are literally just men who happen to fuck dudes instead of women. 

I give all credit to my being accepting of folk different than me to them. 

Just a stark reminder that propaganda and psyops are very real, and very effective here at home. The thing i’ve found to work best is to hold my ground without stopping to their emotional level. Some of my cousins are the type to immediately match their childishness then storm off. This makes the uncles feel like they’ve won unfortunately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039200478.0" user="shuynt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That... actually yes.  I should, but what happens when I run into the same crap in real life as I do online, people telling me I am a bigot for trying to arrange something family friendly?

I dunno, why don't you ask all the people who just want to wear their leather gear to pride but don't want to run into the same crap in real life as they do online: bigoted conservatives and heteronormative queers telling them they aren't allowed to participate in a cultural event that they spent decades helping to build back when said conservatives and heteronormative queers were trashing it as a bacchanal of indecent sexuality?

But to be real for a second, PLEASE. Nobody is going to call you a bigot for wanting to organize a *separate* event focused on families just like nobody (at least within the community) calls people who organize drag queens reading to children a bigot. A lot of pride celebrations ALREADY have separate family-friendly events and nobody gives a shit about them much less goes out of their way to try and shut them down or posts entire reddit threads about how they should be banned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039265446.0" user="raccoon_ralf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I should, but what happens when I run into the same crap in real life as I do online, people telling me I am a bigot for trying to arrange something family friendly?

You’re making up problems to be angry about, stop it. Like gimme a break 🙄</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038048841.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37066949388.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/kkzhc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20kkzhc&amp;amp;message=kkzhc%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jhxe1/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038261078.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>Can't find a space that is safe and respects boundaries you want to expose your kids to? Make your own. Every single part of pride was fought for. You don't get to take advantage of their fight and try to change the space they fought so hard for.

Go fight and make your own space. That isn't meant in a confrontational or judgmental way. Simply the truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039568838.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/VictorZiblis – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20VictorZiblis&amp;amp;message=VictorZiblis%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jdwgg/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
