<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37036699723.0" user="McClanky" delta="False">
    <text>What percentage of pride events do you think revolve around kink and BDSM? Just as you said, the idea of Pride is to be who you are and embrace yourself. For some people, that is a kink or BDSM. From my experience a small minority, which seems to be decreasing each year, use these events to highlight their kink. For the most part, it is a time to simply be proud to be gay. Even then, they are not trying to wave it in the face of children, they are simply trying to be free, which is the point of Pride. 

On the topic of nudity. The issue is not with nudity at Pride, it is with oversexualization of American entertainment. Nudity is not inherently related to sex; however, we have been conditioned to think that way through media, movies, and TV. A lid seeing nudity is going to to nothing unless they have been told it should.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037328590.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>But not everyone is involved in the scene and wants to be part of it at such a place too. Daytime public Pride shouldn't allow for it, I'm an adult but I would want to go and show my pride in my sexuality not just as something that goes as to how I have sex.


I'm European, nude beaches and nude people by rivers are normal here, I don't give a damn about shirtless people on pride as I'm a defender of the "don't sexualize breasts" idea, especially in consideration of breastfeeding mothers, but that would also go hand in hand with the fact that breasts aren't inherently sexual. But it turns sexual when it's in link with kink and bdsm.

I also wouldn't turn it into full body nudity because nonetheless, a city parade isn't a place where you get butt naked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037712712.0" user="free__coffee" delta="False">
    <text>Are boobs not inherently sexual? They’re a sign of fertility, just as a sign of wide hips are a sign of ease of having a baby</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037736044.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Boobs aren't inherently sexual. We often were raised to see them as such but the only difference between female chests and male chests is that female chests produce milk. A dog's teets and a cow's udder is not sexual either. 

Many cultures and societies didn't see a need to cover women's torsos up and they've never associated a topless woman as something sexual. People in the west have even been called infantile due to this obsession about breasts and to push them as a sexual thing. An attraction to breasts, no matter the size, would be a kink or a fetish, must as much as liking other bodily traits would be (like legs aren't sexual either but many people are attracted to them).


Plus, no, breasts are not an indicator of fertility. Small breasts and big breasts alike can produce milk. Size doesn't determine production volume.


Unless you see the male chest as sexual, no, boobs aren't inherently sexual. Your socialization brought you up to think so, but the world doesn't agree.


Edit1:

Just to add: The only thing that is universally seen as sexual and causes arousal despite socialization and where you're brought up is intercourse. Everything else that you see as sexual is because of how you're raised.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037878639.0" user="free__coffee" delta="False">
    <text>Alright I might have seen you on breasts, but when you say nothing is inherently sexual, I’m going to have to disagree with you, based on biology. So i did some research, but before i get to that, I’ll explain why i disagree,

Evolution - your ability to pass on your genes is based in your ability to have and raise children to sexual age. So, something like fitness, and a muscular nature to protect children, will be sexually desirable generally. Or in a resource-scarce society, a sign of extra fat would be sexually desirable since it shows health, and an ability to survive. And something like wide hips - or the ability to have a child successfully, will be sexually desirable, pretty much regardless of the situation, and what I’d call inherently sexual. Although you’re right, sexuality is certainly subject to change

As far as breasts - this article says that the research is extremely mixed, and there are cultural differences, but also that theres some evidence for breasts being sexual, although its controversial:

https://www.livescience.com/23500-why-men-love-breasts.html

&amp;gt; Recent studies have found that nipple stimulation enhances sexual arousal in the great majority of women, and it activates the same brain areas as vaginal and clitoral stimulation. When a sexual partner touches, massages or nibbles a woman's breasts, Young said, this triggers the release of oxytocin in the woman's brain, just like what happens when a baby nurses. But in this context, the oxytocin focuses the woman's attention on her sexual partner, strengthening her desire to bond with this person.

&amp;gt;In other words, men can make themselves more desirable by stimulating a woman's breasts during foreplay and sex. Evolution has, in a sense, made men want to do this. According to Young, the theory "just makes a lot of sense." Young elaborated on the theory in his book, "The Chemistry Between Us" (Current Hardcover, 2012), co-authored by Brian Alexander.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037935949.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>You're conflating preferences with things that are sexual.  


People have things that they like, yes. I have my own preference and things that I find attractive. Things you find attractive are not inherently sexual, though, just because you see them as such.  


Regarding the traits one finds attractive like fat and muscle:  
Not everyone finds these traits attractive. They can, in circumstances, indicate a certain success or promise to raise better offspring. That's still not the same as the sexual nature of sex itself. Having muscle is not the same as intercourse, and with the discussion at hand, your argument would be "it is attractive to people, therefore it is sexual, anything that is attractive to people should be covered up then".  


Also, if your argument about other bodily traits were true about some other things that were inherently sexual, then everyone with a sexual interest in someone would express that feeling about these traits. Then everyone would have that sexual interest in muscle build or in fat. But these traits as to what is seen as attractive also change through circumstances of life. If they were inherently sexual, their sexual association would be constant and not a cause of their environment.  
If it were always the case regardless of environment, then it would be inherent. But it isn't.  


Also, if your argument about other bodily traits were true about some other things that were inherently sexual, then everyone with a sexual interest in someone would express that feeling about these traits. Then everyone would have that sexual interest in muscle build or in fat. But these traits as to what is seen as attractive also change through circumstances of life. If they were inherently sexual, their sexual association would be constant and not a cause of their environment.  


And yes, there is more than just the genital area that can cause arousal through touch. I know that petting doesn't just happen between the legs. The skin on the neck and wrists is also quite sensitive. Caressing it can also cause arousal. The skin on the neck and the wrist are not sexual just because the right touch \*can\* cause arousal, just like touch to the breasts and nipples \*can\* cause arousal, but it does not \*guarantee\* arousal. Plus, men's chests and nipples can be stimulated and \*can\* cause arousal as well. Arousal is no argument if one tries to separately sexualize women's chests and men's chests because again, the only difference is that women produce milk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37051029738.0" user="free__coffee" delta="False">
    <text>No i am not conflating. Are you saying that a man wanting a women with a big butt, or big boobs is not a sexual preference?

You seem to be misunderstanding what sex means. Sex, in it’s most basic form, is about passing on your genetic material to the future generation. There is no other purpose, as far as evolution goes

Now, in humans, that basic purpose has been changed slightly, since most of our children will make it to reproductive age. But the underlying purpose of sex remains, and shapes everything about it, including sexual preferences. Your sexual preferences are shaped, to a large extent, by this basic purpose, by the environment you are born in, by your genetics, and by how you grow up. The first two are inherent, the third is less so. 

Now I think where this convo is breaking down, is that there is no 1 answer as to what drives all sexual preferences - nature vs. nurture. But certainly both drive sexual preferences, and someone thats sexual preferences do not allow for high rates of reproduction will be bred out (to a certain extent) by those that do. 

And again, this process has been corrupted in humans, because barring unavoidable accidents, we all survive to reproductive age. But the fact exists that we have hundreds of thousands of years of evolution driving things like sexual attraction to large men (see “only men over 6’” on all dating sites) and women with wide hips (self explanatory)

And yea i get your argument for breasts not being sexual, but i also get the argument for breasts being sexual - the verdict is still out on that. What i do have a big problem with is your saying “nothing is inherently sexual” , because that’s just not true</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37051980078.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>It is a sexual preference due to your sexual attraction to them.

I'm not arguining that people aren't attracted to them, but I'm arguining that in a vacuum breasts aren't sexual, and they're not inherently so when not everyone is suddenly losing their brains about it and popping boners or getting sopping wet when seeing them.

Just because there are people that find feet attractive doesn't mean that feet are sexual body parts.

I don't give a damn about people's preferences. My only point and the thing I'm arguining for is that due to nurture breasts are sexualized, and if they're being sexualized, it is because without the sexualization they're not sexual, because by nature, they're not sexual parts any more than any other body part is. And nothing that indicates a higher success if their offspring is still sexual like that. Someone being attracted to something doesn't make the thing itself sexual.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
