<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037218759.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>so, i’ll present the largest argument i’ve heard. pride isn’t just about equality, it’s about liberation, especially sexual liberation. billboards have people that are almost naked on every highway, and the internet is even worse. So realistically, sex isn’t going to be hidden from kids, and what they do see, they probably won’t understand. It might be gross, but it’s reality.
So if we accept that, then it’s easier to understand the benefits of it being allowed. It’s called “pride” for a reason. it’s about being proud of who you are down to your deepest parts. it’s meant to be about freedom. It’s not necessarily meant for children. There should be ways for children to understand sexuality, but this might not be it. feeling pride in ones sexuality and their liberation is going to be sexual, it’s called sexuality for a reason. in order to show pride in sexuality, sex is a part of it, and while queer identities should be shown to children in a way that children can understand, a place for sexual pride is not the place for that.
also, i have bad adhd, i didn’t plan my sentences, i just kinda wrote, so if it’s out of order and doesn’t make sense, let me know. i’m always happy to clarify anything</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037331953.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>i have no idea why the fuck i said largest argument. best argument. most convincing argument. smartest argument. i’m a moron</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037721949.0" user="EmptyHearse" delta="False">
    <text>\*double snap\* 

Your argument was the best one I've heard in a while</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038038772.0" user="Laetitian" delta="False">
    <text>You wanted to emphasize that it covers most angles of attack. "Convincing" wouldn't have communicated the scale and "best" and "smartest" aren't specific enough. 

"Comprehensive"/"Sweeping"? Perhaps something along the lines of "all-encompassing"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037661244.0" user="EddieValiantsRabbit" delta="False">
    <text>That's just a terrible argument. Using this logic, why not just go fuck on a park bench next to a middle school? We can't protect them from sex anyways, it's on the internet and billboards after all, and it's liberating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037674706.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>sorry for the fast response, im on reddit too much.

the concept of sexual nature and sexuality is not sex. kink at pride is not people having sex in public. it’s about showing deep parts of sexuality that aren’t as “acceptable” and this is the time to be proud of them. expression of sexuality isn’t just reckless free for all sex. 
And for children, i’m not saying to give them sex whenever they want and show it to them, i’m saying that the concept of sexuality is ingrained in our media and is not hidden from them, not sex itself. sex is not equivalent to sexuality or sexual presentation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037721750.0" user="AnotherRichard827379" delta="False">
    <text>You know how lgbtqia+ advocates are constantly on about how nobody should care what consenting adults do I the privacy of their own homes? Well pride events basically show case that’s all bull shit. 

Some things should not be acceptable, especially in public. Among them being adults running around naked with children in the streets. Any other context and they’d be labeled pedophiles.

Sex shouldn’t be liberated. How high do the rates of HIV and other stds need to get before this woke-idiot crowd figures it out?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037746126.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>ok, first of all, they wouldn’t be naked. nobody would be naked. kinks aren’t about running around naked. it would be things that are still controversial, like leather suits, harnesses, and furries. nobody’s gonna be running around genitalia out at pride. i’m not in support of that.

second, my entire point is that it’s not an event for children, because children don’t have the same grasp on sexuality, emphasis on the sexual part. they feel attraction, but it’s not as SEXUAL, which is what pride is largely about. It’s important to try to not bring your kids to pride. it’s not that they can never go, but this is something that might happen, so it’s not smart. you don’t bring your kids certain places because it’s just not a good idea, and one day of the year to not take your kids on certain streets is perfectly reasonable.

Pride is about taking those things that people might otherwise be ashamed of and being PROUD of it, that’s why it’s called pride. it’s about being proud of sexuality, of things that they would otherwise be ashamed of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037888900.0" user="KyroNoHane" delta="False">
    <text>If it's not for children, then it shouldn't be present in an avenue where children could end up seeing it. I.e; not in public.

Events where these things happen are called rallies precisely because they take place in a public avenue.

Something that EVERYONE in the BDSM community strictly adheres to is that their kinks are for consenting adults only. If it is in a public avenue, you are taking away onlookers ability to consent to being exposed to BDSM.

This is why those in the BDSM community are not ashamed of their kinks, but willingly choose to keep them behind closed doors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040101274.0" user="sleepybitchdisorder" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, but the point here is that implied sex is everywhere in our culture. Haven’t you seen billboards for strip clubs? Movie posters for things like Friends with Benefits or even Fifty Shades? Flip to the wrong TV channel and you’ll find soft core porn, and there’s implied or actual sex in extremely mainstream TV shows such as Grey’s Anatomy and the Simpsons that children could easily be exposed to. 

Nobody is actually walking around naked at Pride. The skimpiest are usually more like music festival outfits (mesh, girls wearing pasties, shirtless with booty shorts, etc) and less like kink. The kinky outfits are people wearing leather, harnesses, and maybe furry gear. The most a kid is gonna ask is “why is that person dressed as a dog mommy?”, which is extremely easy to answer in an age appropriate way (“that’s just something some people like to do for fun, sweetie. let’s go somewhere else”.) 

Sex and sexuality is inherent in our culture, why is it worse at Pride?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042637036.0" user="jonpaladin" delta="False">
    <text>you'll find bars and liquor stores on basically every street in any town. bars especially are often explicitly sexual locations for horny people to meet fuck candidates.

why are bars allowed on main street? they are not for children!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038032016.0" user="awakeinny94" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. Might I add that not only would they be otherwise ashamed of but things that they have been persecuted for and are told they should be ashamed of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038428409.0" user="BruhWhySoSerious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ok, first of all, they wouldn’t be naked. nobody would be naked. kinks aren’t about running around naked.

In practice, I've only seen 2 dicks in public in my life, and they have both been at a pride parade.

&amp;gt;  It’s important to try to not bring your kids to pride.

So like, fuck those families who live in the apartments that are on the route, or working families who may not have that option?

Nudity is illegal in the US. You bet your damn ass if I walk around in some of the outfits worn at these things on a non pride day I'm getting into a police cruiser at the end of the day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039069685.0" user="Lostmyfnusername" delta="False">
    <text>Pride day doesn't have to just be about showing pride. It can also get people to ask questions. For example, if you're just a nudist and you aren't fucking in the park in front of kids, do you really need to be sent away in a police cruiser? If cultures where nudity is fine exist, then does that mean I was just raised to believe it was bad or does this actually harm kids? Is it just people who live in the apartments arguing about this or are there others with more nefarious agendas spending hours on the internet to overblow the severity of all this? How many kids will actually need therapy seeing the gay version of something they will see in a music video or in a locker room? Are there other reasons for wearing kink besides hornyness such as a history of laws that arrested LGBT for wearing the clothes for the opposite sex? Do I need to ask the people with different beliefs who were labeled indecent to be more like me and be made more decent? If we ask the gays to be like you or go be weird somewhere behind closed walls, doesn't that miss the point to let people know you don't need to control, shame, or kill others if no harm is being done? If I can say "I never consented to see someone naked" can they say "I never consented to seeing your comment"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038486044.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>LMAO 1 of 2 pride events i’ve attended had more than a few dude hanging dong. You’re either ignorant to the differences in these events or purposefully misconstruing reality.


I do also attend adult themed events in my city during the festival season. There’s tons of people in varying states of undress, and typically some real nasty shit goes on at some point. The difference is it’s advertised as adults (21+ only) and in a private space with layers of security. 

There is *absolutely nothing* wrong with celebrating sex and/or your sexuality. People do take issue with the lack of discretion though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040438949.0" user="QQMau5trap" delta="False">
    <text>yep. I went to the CSD in my home city and saw a few very inapropriate individuals openly brandishing their guns 😅 was very startling to see . Basically in see through attire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038684570.0" user="abooth43" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;, first of all, they wouldn’t be naked. nobody would be naked

I saw plenty of dicks at my cities pride parade. Many other people in this thread have cited the same experience. What were you saying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039124035.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>i’m not saying that’s good. When I say kink at pride, i’m referring to links. Almost nobody wants a dick festival. That doesn’t mean no sexual pride at PRIDE.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039234976.0" user="shawn292" delta="False">
    <text>You can be proud of who you are sexualy and not be inappropriate for kids. I would pose that by making it such a hyper sexualized event like it is now it not only gives lgbt folks a bad rep by reinforceing the flamboyant sterotype but prevents children amd preteens from being able/comfortable going and in a world where more and more young people are coming out that is incredibly sad. "sorry johnny you cant go because some woman wants to wear a very revealing outfit and a guy wants to wear a gimp suit."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039730657.0" user="Mellow-Mallow" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that it’s not helping them be more accepted. The “pro-straight” rednecks already think you’re gross, this is not going to change their mind. The question is is that the goal of pride? I don’t think the goal of pride is to convince people (at least these extreme examples) to change their mind, because that’s not an easy thing to do. 

It’s about showing how many people are like them, giving them a place to fit in and show that they’re not alone. It’s not for the straight community, it’s for the LGBT+ community. 

I do think there’s a line about how people should dress and act to allow children or at least teens to attend comfortably but I don’t know where that line is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040114190.0" user="shawn292" delta="False">
    <text>So i think this argument has 2 flaws but first just for sake of clarity im a conservative arts major so I have personally fought for gay rights (cause in my view they were common sense) but generally have more conservative views.

So the big issue I have is the people you turn away are not the "pro stright rednecks" its the moderates and pro lgbt people I agree there are some very homophobic people in the world but many including conservatives are pro gay marriage but by being so innopropriate you say this is what all gay people are which I hope you understand isnt the case. You create the idea that all gay people are "not for kids amd hypersexual"

As for the not for straights honestly that could be a whole other topic as for the problems with that but the thing i was surprised by is how many of my non flamboyant gay friends site pride as being part of the reason they waited so long to come out because it is this hyper sexual parade that is associated with being gay. I honestly have met many "pro stright rednecks" who genuinely think that all gay people are flamboyant. I would argue that currently pride not for non flamboyant gay people any more than its not straight people and thats the problem with having such sexualized content at pride.


Its meant to be a safe space to celebrate who you are but that doesnt mean and shouldnt mean that in doing so you can make it an unsafe space for others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040221015.0" user="Mellow-Mallow" delta="False">
    <text>I am not saying all gay people are inappropriate, you misunderstand what I’m saying. I’m saying the extreme cases that are generally showcased in pride turn a lot of people off because they don’t want to see that. That’s not necessarily good or bad, it just is. I am not creating an idea that being gay isn’t for kids, I never said that, apologies if that’s how I came off. 

As for you third paragraph I’m not sure what you’re trying to say. Are you agreeing with me that pride being such a spectacle turns people off? Are you pro specialized pride or anti?

I agree with your last paragraph and that’s essentially what I was trying to get across with my comment. I was never disagreeing with you at any point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040384580.0" user="shawn292" delta="False">
    <text>Oh! Then maybe we agree on the overall problem but just get there in two different ways. I am very much against hyper specific pride. I also would be firm in saying that turning a lot of people off is bad as it creates waves that affect other people as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040400022.0" user="Mellow-Mallow" delta="False">
    <text>Glad we agree! I’m not great at being clear over text so it was probably my bad lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040521275.0" user="shawn292" delta="False">
    <text>Haha im the same way so we can split the blame!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039419415.0" user="KlausBaudelaire" delta="False">
    <text>People have been giving you many responses, but I'd just like to add that I'd never define pride as being about sexual attraction; it's definitely included but it's a rather narrow and specific way to describe pride, which is about the entire LGBTQIA+ community, not just sexual attraction or identities that have to do with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039157079.0" user="Illustrious-Can-8540" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039295029.0" user="DaStalkingBiscuit" delta="False">
    <text>what a hot take. 

&amp;gt;nobody should care what consenting adults do I the privacy of their own homes? Well pride events basically show case that’s all bull shit.

no it doesn't. the argument "consenting adults can do what they want in privacy" has no connection the issue at hand. You're mistaking "it's *definitely* okay in private" with "it's *only* okay in private", an entirely different argument.

&amp;gt;Some things should not be acceptable, especially in public. Among them being adults running around naked with children in the streets. 

this isn't an argument. this is a moral stand point. there's nothing wrong with that per se, but there's no argument for why i can't have a different moral standpoint.

&amp;gt;Any other context and they’d be labeled pedophiles.

sure, in the context of them knowingly and purposefully exposing themselves to kids, they would be labeled pedophiles. but that's not what's happening here, so what's the point? just because it's not okay in some context, doesn't mean it's not okay in every context. nudist beaches exist for example. are they pedophiles?

&amp;gt;Sex shouldn’t be liberated. How high do the rates of HIV and other stds need to get before this woke-idiot crowd figures it out?

if new HIV cases per year was actually growing as sexual liberation increased, this would be a great argument. [sadly it's been steadily falling in the US] (https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/mm5021a2.htm)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039400007.0" user="PM_ME_GARFIELD_NUDES" delta="False">
    <text>This comment is just a bunch of disconnected thoughts and opinions but you’re stating them like they’re facts. There isn’t an argument here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039430401.0" user="AnotherRichard827379" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you’re just slow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039581798.0" user="PM_ME_GARFIELD_NUDES" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You know how *lgbtqia+ advocates are constantly on about how nobody should care what consenting adults do I the privacy of their own homes*? Well *pride events basically show case that’s all bull shit*.

Disconnected argument. I know plenty of LGBT advocates who are opposed to things like BDSM being included in pride, OP is one example of this. What is the reasoning behind believing these two things are related?

&amp;gt;*Some things should not be acceptable*, especially in public. Among them being adults running around naked with children in the streets. Any other context and they’d be labeled pedophiles.

Disconnected argument. What things should not be acceptable? Why should those things be unacceptable? Do you have a justification for holding this stance or is it just something you believe strongly? There are plenty of people who represent BDSM culture at pride without nudity, is that still unacceptable?

&amp;gt;*Sex shouldn’t be liberated*. How high do the rates of HIV and other stds need to get before this woke-idiot crowd figures it out?

Disconnected argument. Why should sex not be liberated? Is that just another thing on your assumed list of unacceptable things? Still curious how you determine what is or is not acceptable. Are rates of STDs tied to sexual liberation? If you were presented data that showed that STD rates have *decreased* while sexual liberation *increased* would you change your stance on this? Or would you move the goalposts to a different issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039609376.0" user="AnotherRichard827379" delta="False">
    <text>You could have just said “yes, I’m slow”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038187042.0" user="Brother_Anarchy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;why not just go fuck on a park bench next to a middle school?

Cops</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037697100.0" user="Plebe-Uchiha" delta="False">
    <text>You had me and then you lost me with the “it’s not necessarily meant for children,” because that is, in my interpretation, what the OP is saying. These displays of pride should be in 18^(+) events not at “all ages,” if you will. 

But, really great points though. [+]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037724122.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>thank you!

my thing here is, sexuality for children is different from sexuality for adults, and i don’t think it’s entirely possible to celebrate them together. so while events for teenagers and children to be proud should exist, i just can’t say that pride is the one to be that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038021195.0" user="Laetitian" delta="False">
    <text>In more crude words, it doesn't necessarily have to matter whether OP is "disgusted" or whether there is consent in seeing sexual displays in public. Sometimes the message matters more than how the participants are affected. Demonstrations often exist for the opposite of making you comfortable, and that doesn't exclude minors by principle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038505303.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;sexuality for children

holdup</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038957015.0" user="CratesManager" delta="False">
    <text>In the context it means "sexuality is different for childrend" and yes, children have a sexuality. I assume you're joking but there are probably people who need to see this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039259160.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>you’re right, and I was joking. Children do have their own sexuality. I just prefer no adults except specifically trained ones to research it. 

I do think child and adult sexuality are wholly incompatible though, and shouldn’t be celebrated at the same event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037858130.0" user="ourstobuild" delta="False">
    <text>You have to take into account that this is all very cultural as well. I presume OP is American cause most redditors (especially the ones not mentioning the country they're talking about) seem to be so I'd point out that from my (European) perspective the relationship with for example nudity seems quite different over there than it is here.

We weren't talking about just nudity though, so why does it matter? I'm glad you asked, I think the point of Pride is to try to create a space where people can be themselves no matter what their gender / sexual orientation / identity / etc is and that simply requires pushing the boundaries. In a strictly conservative environment this would never change without people pushing their limits to a certain extent.  The reason I raise the example of nudity is to demonstrate exactly this: it's clear (to me at least) that in America the views on nudity are a lot more restricted than in many European countries for example. It is equally clear to me that these European countries are not producing damaged psychopaths even if the views on nudity are a lot more liberal. Therefore it is clear to me that American views on nudity could be more liberal without "damaging the children". Hence, it's an example of an area where I think the limits can be pushed more or less safely, even if you push those limits so far that it goes beyond "common decency" (as defined by many American views).

I do want to point out, that I'm not saying that we should just drop all limits either. I'm not promoting having public sex or whatever and I do agree there obviously needs to be some lines that shouldn't be crossed. That said, if those lines are the same as commonly agreed decency, the events are not going to be effective. You cannot normalize something without acting it.  Without the act it's all just rhetorical debate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037850916.0" user="the-good-side" delta="False">
    <text>exactly. pride is the one event where you can go and express that you are proud of something that society has taught you to feel ashamed of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038043248.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038843222.0" user="deyesed" delta="False">
    <text>When you had kids you projected your neuroses onto them. It's valuable and human, but also biasing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040577366.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040633523.0" user="deyesed" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, that really means a lot based on your comment history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041741556.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/kkzhc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20kkzhc&amp;amp;message=kkzhc%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0l04eu/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37062237289.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/kkzhc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20kkzhc&amp;amp;message=kkzhc%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jht2o/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038169009.0" user="Jezoreczek" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There should be ways for children to understand sexuality, but this might not be it.

Why not? Children know more than you think - at young age you are taking in all the details of life to figure out how stuff works. I think this sugar coating we have in society does no good to anyone.

Educate: explain sexuality alongside concepts of consent and respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038362139.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>We're talking about CHILDREN, here. Like, 8 years old. When there are naked and semi-naked adults in fetish/kink gear, up to and including butt plugs and nipple clamps, there should not be children around. But these events take place in the streets. That's the problem. If adults want to act like that, then do it in the club. That's what I do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038854292.0" user="Jezoreczek" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, have you not checked out your dad's _special magazines_ when you were that age? Children will see it one way or another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038930311.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>Usually dad's special magazines were of the Penthouse variety. So they were at least vanilla. But I don't think that people really understand just how dangerous the kink community can be if they're not involved in it. Predators lurk there because they know they can prey on the naive. And they know how to tie people up so that there really is no escape. And they know how to inflict pain and injury. And how to be very persuasive. And the people who don't know what they're doing can be almost as bad. At the very least you can sustain long-term or even permanent nerve damage. The potential for psychological scarring is very real. I've seen dislocations, sprains, severe nerve damage, permanent physical scars, burns, and extremely bad psychological damage. And this was from people who didn't have bad intentions. They just didn't know what they were doing.  This stuff is no joke. And I have at least one story about someone I know, related to each and every one of those injuries I listed. I will gladly elaborate if asked. That's the major problem with vanillas going to events that allude to kink and thinking that they truly understand what's going on. This shit is for adults. Period. You're putting your children in danger. I play in this heavily, and I take constant and numerous precautions. Seriously. I love it, but if you're not exceedingly careful, you can get really, really, really hurt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039014133.0" user="Jezoreczek" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This shit is for adults. Period. You're putting your children in danger.

By no means am I advocating for children to _participate_, wtf! Only saying them witnessing it is not harmful _if they are educated about it properly_.

&amp;gt; Predators lurk there because they know they can prey on the naive.

Absolutely but there are shit people in every community. That's moreso a reason to educate your children and explain how consent and boundaries work.

&amp;gt; You're putting your children in danger.

Not having any, I personally hate children :P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039156711.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>"Not having any, I personally hate children"

Lol, I can understand that! But my issue is at least in part, the age at which some people think exposure is ok. 8 years old is NOT ok. And seriously, I know a girl who occasionally gets her lips sewn shut. I knew a girl who would occasionally get her pussy lips temporarily pierced shut. I first saw that shit in my 20's and it gave me nightmares. I know that seeing a guy at a pride event with a butt plug up his ass isn't nearly that disturbing, but I still think we shouldn't be exposing children to that. Leather boots and hats is cool. But cock rings and nipple clamps? No. Not for kids eyes, IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039188661.0" user="Jezoreczek" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the age at which some people think exposure is ok.

OK, so what's the age at which you'd say explaining to your child what a cock ring is would be fine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039216061.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good question. 8 is way too young.  I feel like 16 would be the absolute youngest, and even then I'm not sure. I'd definitely explain vanilla sex to them at a younger age. But once people start breaking out the pain toys, I think it's too much for a kid to emotionally comprehend. If I had a teenager asking me about this stuff, I think I might consult with a psychologist about age appropriate answers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039331274.0" user="there-will-be-cake" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry but that 16 year old already knows about cock rings and a multitude of other kinks/toys at that point. Its the 2021 and porn is just a swipe away. Kids are not as ignorant as you think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039430798.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>I have no problem with teenagers knowing about sex, but some of the kinkier stuff is too much. I've seen what happens when 18 year olds hit the dungeon, and haven't had any guidance besides the internet. They get hurt. I mean, physically they get hurt. And they don't deserve it. They're just kids. They're legal adults, but they're still too young to know what they need to know in order to stay safe. And it's because people around them are so busy being sex-positive (which isn't a bad thing), that they forget to look out for their kids' well-being. They forget that teenagers don't usually have as much common sense because they're kids. They paint things all rosy. It's so easy for an 18 year old to go off property with someone that they really think is trustworthy, and then get raped in that person's car at 2am by the warehouses. This stuff is not being taken seriously enough by many of the advocates online. The younger you learn about only the fun aspects of kink (like at pride events), the more at risk you are for trusting someone who doesn't deserve that trust.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039501760.0" user="there-will-be-cake" delta="False">
    <text>Hence why parents and educators ought to step up and stop tip toeing around sex like we're in the 50's and educate kids and teens before anyone can get hurt.  
  
Kink and bdsm, like sex, is not inherently harmful. Engaging in it with out knowledge, consent, and boundaries is. And the only way these kids and teens will understand these things is if we stop treating sexuality like the boogeyman out to corrupt them and talk openly and constructively about it.  
  
And I don't mean by the time they already got their hands on daddy's Playboy or Pornhub account. Start young with an open, continuous dialogue that gradually expands as they grow up. Is it really so hard?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039554442.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>How young, is my question. Because I really don't think children should be around adults who are displaying sexual behavior. That's seriously borderline pedo stuff. And daddy should do a better job of hiding it. And yes, it's hard to know what's age appropriate. I seriously doubt that you, or anyone else on this thread who is speaking with such authority, has consulted with a psychologist or any kind of expert regarding age appropriateness. The difference is that I've already stated that I would do that. And in the 50's, people barely held hands in public. Yes, that was way too uptight, but do you really think it's ok for an 8 year old to see grown men wearing buttplugs and cock rings? Do you honestly think that's ok? At what age do you think that's ok?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039626181.0" user="there-will-be-cake" delta="False">
    <text>Okay you're diving into the extremes here. Nobody is saying provide real time examples to 8 year olds or whip out the dildos for little Suzy to oogle. I say start with the basic vanilla mechanics and concepts (consent, birds and bees, and all that jazz) at the same age you teach kids to keep their hands and feet to themselves. As they get older, you build upon those early conversations. By the time they hit adolescence, they understand the gist of healthy sexuality and ready to explore their own in a safe, age appropriate manner. You continue to provide guidance as they figure things out, assuming you built a trusting, open line of communication with your child up to that point.
  
It's really not rocket science.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039683640.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>See that's reasonable. You weren't saying to provide real time examples to 8 year olds, but there's a person on this thread who was complaining because pride events are too explicit to take his 8 year old to, and there were people arguing with him. Legit, there are people, including on this thread, who refuse to give a minimum age for this stuff. That's what I find disturbing. The person I was speaking with when you entered the conversation basically said "oh, just tell the (8year old) kid it's a costume", when I brought up the example of how to explain a naked man on all fours being walked on a leash. This might be TMI, and I apologize in advance. But I lost my virginity when I was 15. But it was vanilla. I just think that's too young to start sorting out kinks. Especially when you're just starting out with your first partner. But again, I'll definitely consult experts on this when I need to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039885994.0" user="there-will-be-cake" delta="False">
    <text>I'm inclined to agree with the sorting out kink stuff too early, but it happens organically over time as you explore your sexuality. Of course you don't whip out the butt plugs or clamps. Your dorky, awkward teenagers just getting used to seeing another naked body. Once the initial awkwardness/clumsiness passes and you're comfortable with the vanilla stuff, kinks naturally followed. You discover other things that please each other and make the experience all the more exciting.  
  
While I think anything under 12 is too young to start sorting out kinks, I think it's reasonable to expect anyone over that age to start exploring themselves and others their age. I say as long as they're aware, informed, and safe let them.  
  
As for the kinksters on a fours at Pride, well I see it as a teachable moment for the 8 year old. Ask them how they feel about. Don't project your own biases onto the kid. They have minds of their own.  
  
If they think its gross and uncomfortable, well remove them from the situation and discuss their feelings. If not, well indulge their curiosity and explain why the man is acting like a dog. Tell them its an adult thing that doesn't concern them at their age. No need to divulge into what kind of kinks the kid is into, because 9 times out of 10 the kid has none nor are they interested. As far as the 8 year old knows, the man on all fours is just another weird adult doing weird adult things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039914794.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>That all makes a lot of sense. I'll think about what you said. Especially the age stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039155633.0" user="Apollo_Hotrod" delta="False">
    <text>Why did this leap countries from "kids shouldn't see it" to "kids could get hurt participating in sexual bdsm acts"??? 

Nobodies getting nerve damage from seeing a gimp suit or leather furries. It's completely harmless in fact. Might damage some peoples sensibilities but I think they just might pull through. 

Really this whole arguement is silly, obviously nobody should be having public sex at pride (something I've never encountered myself, and I doubt ever happens with any regularity) but nudity is perfectly fine and healthy to normalize. Just because I'd never go outside partially nude doesn't mean I'm not going to support those that do. And hell, seeing more body positivity when I was young probably would have made me less ashamed to try it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039190826.0" user="CharlieAlright" delta="False">
    <text>The person I was talking to seemed (AFAIK), to be making the argument that there's nothing psychologically damaging about an 8 year old seeing  a guy walk another guy around on all fours on a leash. The problem with that logic, IMO, is that first, it leaves way too many questions that the kid could Google and wind up seeing shit he shouldn't see. That being said, a 16 year old could certainly find themselves in over their heads if they went looking for other people to engage in this stuff with. I just feel like people are being really flippant about letting kids see stuff that they couldn't possibly be prepared for, or properly understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038657304.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think your wrong about the intent, but the *effect* is further alienating younger lgbtq people *and* furthering the stereotype that all lgbtq people are sexual deviants. I agree with OP that in today's environment it's counterproductive

There are people out there whose only knowledge of the gay community comes from Hollywood and coverage of pride. Is it any wonder some people think being gay means wearing latex shorts while your boyfriend follows you on a leash in a gimp suit? Or why a young teenager might be hesitant to join in on that environment?

Edit: I'm not saying that's all of pride, but the most sensational pictures are the ones that get spread the most</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038947526.0" user="CratesManager" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to present the larget argument i have for &amp;lt;18 events (not necessarily labelling some events 18+ and censoring everything else, i'd wager labelling some events SFW and making those a safe space for people uncomfortable with sexualisation would be the way better option): what about sex repulsed asexuals? They do have issues with the sexualization in the media and society you mentioned, and they want to be proud of their sexuality and be part of the community too. 

I don't think "regular" pride events should need to be SFW, i agree that any minors that wish to go are already exposed to sexualization everywhere else. But i do think having some "tame" events with rules on what's okay in place wouldn't hurt anyone, as long as you don't try to impose that on everyone and every event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040896518.0" user="LeftyLore" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely do understand the point, and I think it’s near impossible to really appeal to everybody. off the top of my head, i’d say the best idea would be to section it so that there’s a sexual area and a non-sexual area, although both would be 18+</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039421269.0" user="GrouseOW" delta="False">
    <text>While I'm not entirely against sexualized pride in some respects (I think there should be a daytime pg pride and a nightime pride), the problem a lot of people including myself have is that sex isn't just a part of pride as it stands, it's one of the main focuses.

I know one of the reasons so many are so openly sexual in their pride is as a reaction to the repression of that sexuality, but there's so much more to being queer than just sex and I feel like it isn't celebrated enough in the community. Especially considering how the frankly excessive hornyness is genuinely harmful for aspects of the community, I know so many gay/bi men who are terrified of sex because of how aggressive spaces like grindr and tinder are.

Saying pride isn't for kids sends a horrible message, young queer kids grow up with so much trauma as a result of their sexuality and excluding them from one of the biggest events that validate their existence makes no sense.

It's not just children that are excluded. I'm not going to argue about whether or not asexuality is LGBTQ+ or not, it is, the wider community accepts that it is. And as an ace person who finds comfort with a lot of LGBTQ+ communities, pride and discussion surrounding it feels like yet another place where I don't belong just like the rest of straight society. A time about acceptance and liberation where it still feels like I'm an "other" for being me.

Again I'm not saying no sexual aspects of pride, I'm not a prude, but additionally I would appreciate if sex and being queer wasn't always synonymous. There should be more focus on solidarity and romantic libertation alongside the expression and celebration of sexual liberation.

I will also say that most of my issues with pride absolutely apply to the rest of oversexualised straight society, which is why a lot of talk around "protecting children" and shit like that is bs rooted in homophobia. I'm more so arguing for accomodations for people who's sexuality mightn't be related to sex, like children and aces.

Same as you I got bad adhd so apologies if this is incoherent, I know the struggle of rambling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
