<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="56" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37038456999.0" user="Shimme" delta="False">
    <text>So I see people making a lot of arguments about where to draw the line at what's kink, but that doesn't really go and answer your main problem about Pride parades being overtly sexual, and I'd like to try and answer that question.

Modern LGBT+ pride parades directly tie their history into the Stonewall Riots in New York City, when NYC cops would frequently target, harass and attack queer bars, which were one of the few places at the time where queer people could be open about their sexuality.

Now, this is when being LGBT+ in most ways could come with jailtime, losing your job, total social ostracization and more. Police raids on gay bars, and getting caught in one of those raids was a serious thing.

For whatever reason, one night when they were raided the people at the Stonewall Inn fought back. Accounts vary about what sparked it, but by the time things were getting going the cops were barricading themselves *inside* the bar, calling for backup. The riot police that showed up figured they were dealing with "weak" gay people that they could beat into submission, and instead got a riot of people that were alternating between throwing bricks, dancing the can-can, catcalling, shouts of "Gay Power" and more. People that were there described the rioters *chasing the riot cops* for hours and hours.

These riots lasted for most of a week, and are the genesis of all modern LGBT+ rights movements. 

-----

It is very important to note, that this wasn't polite picketing, or handing out leaflets. It was a violent riot where the crowd both was very flagrantly sexual in rebellion of the mistreatment they were receiving, and quite literally attacked their tormentors.

As a matter of historical importance, the moment that all modern LGBT+ movements can trace their roots from was *not* polite, or quiet, or decent. People literally needed to beat the shit out of cops and send them running to finally be left alone.

-----

Modern Pride parades don't (in some places) have to deal with violence from cops or onlookers, but they still are overtly sexual.

Why?

Well there's a few reasons. Showing **overt** non-heterosexuality can be a powerful framing device. For one purpose, it can be used to draw ire. Some people might be disgusted by queer people being flagrant, to which the remark might be said "straight/cisgender culture is just as if not more *constantly* extremely sexual. Why are you mad at us, but not that?" In another way, person might see some leather daddies marching in the parade, and find it gross, but they also might think about their out coworker who wears nothing but polos and khakis and think "comparatively, that's not so bad."

For some people it's also just *fun*. If you've ever seen a Carnival, or Mardi Gras, big rolling block parties/parades with people reveling while publicly being extremely sexualized is a thing in some manner for a significant chunk of the planet. Compared to what Brazil and New Orleans gets down to, Pride parades are *extremely* tame.

It also can show to other queer people that they don't have to hide. If someone can see a woman run around in a bikini, kiss their girlfriend and wave a rainbow flag in public and it's okay, then they can realize that they're not alone in the world, that they have "permission" to be themselves. Showing up can help to normalize and make people realize that they have that freedom.

------

There's plenty of other reasons I could bring up, but the important thing, from a political sense is that Pride is the *opposite* of invisible. It's baked into the whole concept of Pride, being unashamed to be yourself and refusing to hide anymore.


Also, nobody does gross stuff beyond wear skimpy clothes or like a leather harness. Nobody's fucking in public or stuff like that, it's a fun parade not a sex party. And because I feel like it needs to be pointed out, most people at Pride aren't even going so far as that The people being really flagrant are a fraction of whose all there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038642474.0" user="trifelin" delta="False">
    <text>This is an excellent summary, thank you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37064509350.0" user="brunettedude" delta="False">
    <text>[Here is footage of the first Pride parade in 1970.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OevqwHmeEFI&amp;amp;t=282s) Hundreds- if not thousands- of men and women in attendance! Can you count the amount of leathermen attending? I'll give you a hint: it rhymes with *hero*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
