<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037126808.0" user="KrabbyMccrab" delta="False">
    <text>There nothing disgusting with nudity. We are all just apes tryna look civilized. A random boob isn't gonna hurt anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037906456.0" user="Bmart008" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people are talking about boobs to be honest. Where I live it's legal to have women topless just like men (as it should be).  But it's always weird to see old men naked wearing a backpack walking in pride. I mean, not usually part of a float or anything, there always seems to be a group of older men doing it, like they're in the steam room or something. Being bottomless unless it's on a nude beach is illegal here, but I guess not during pride. Maybe they get off on it, I dunno, but in a world where if a guy does this on a bus he gets arrested for sexual assault or harrassment, people doing it out in the open on public streets seems like a bit of a double standard. 

I mean, I still go to pride, and I support the movement, but it just seems a little odd. Nude beaches? Fine, no problem. But in the middle of the city on public streets, I dunno about that. Topless 100% fine imo. If men can do it, it's only fair. 

P.s. it's never women totally naked, it's never young men, it's only ever older men. I also wonder why that is. Maybe someone could enlighten me?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041120011.0" user="KrabbyMccrab" delta="False">
    <text>This is one of the values we are more behind the times on. Most of Europe have embraced this for a long time.

Genitals are just an appendage to the body. Just like arms and legs. Everyone has one. Your parents have them, your friends, acquaintances all have them. If we don't find arms disgusting, why are genitals so special? From a sanitary point of view, everyone's hands actually carry much more bacteria than their genitals. Are gonna ban hands too?

You can argue that genitals are distracting because they are sexual. Therefore, the state of arousal is distracting to the functioning of society. Then the question would be, if a women wishes to wear showy clothing, is it our right to denounce her freedom to do so? Or if people with foot fetishes are distracted by bare feet, do we have to ban sandals too? It's not their obligation to live by other people's standards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37043136843.0" user="Bmart008" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, laws are exactly what other people's standard are right, and as I said above I have no problem with nudity in the proper place, like a nude beach, but going down a public street in a city of millions in my opinion, is different. 

Also, there wasn't any answer as to why it's only old men, not young men, not young women, not old women, but only old men. If someone walks around naked at work, they get fired, and sued for sexual assault or harrassment, on the bus too, or a school, or a government building. Usually it's old men who do this too. It's not women exposing themselves to subordinates, or on the bus. 

So, if you're okay with genitals, fine, I mean, I am too, and honestly, I usually just laugh at the old naked men at pride, everyone makes the joke that "it's never who you want to be naked eh?" But I'm just wondering why the double standard exists, and why it's all old men doing it. 

I mean, when I was a kid someone exposed himself in a laundry mat, I went to my mom and told her, and the police came and arrested him, what's the difference with old men at pride showing off their genitals in a public place?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
