<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="60" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37038607946.0" user="xxam925" delta="False">
    <text>I think your edit is a good place to start.

Seeing two men kissing is indecent and an affront.

Is the exact same argument as:

Seeing someone with a collar on is indecent and an affront. 

Being gay would get you arrested in America until 2003:

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sodomy_laws_in_the_United_States

I would encourage you to click through those links and notice that the verbiage they use to describe homosexuality is the same that you use to describe kink. It’s the same fight, you are just pulling the ladder up behind you. People should be able to love how they like and the rest of the world can piss off with their opinion. It’s the prejudice that is the problem. Your judgement. Making it(whatever it may be) mainstream is the key to destroying your judgement and normalizing their love, whatever form that may take. Right now you are swimming in the wins that the old school kinksters, homosexuals, queens and transsexuals literally fought and died for and yet you want to argue against them? That’s hella sad. 

There is nothing wrong with sex between consenting adults in any form. It’s social bullshit from the churches that we have internalized. I am a very straight very white very cis dude and it’s obvious to me that it’s all the same shit. Maybe you need to work on acceptance and seeing other peoples viewpoints? I have actually seen this argument a few times from members of the lgbt community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038609715.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Sodomy_laws_in_the_United_States](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sodomy_laws_in_the_United_States)** 
 
 &amp;gt;Sodomy laws in the United States, which outlawed a variety of sexual acts, were inherited from colonial laws in the 17th century. While they often targeted sexual acts between persons of the same sex, many statutes employed definitions broad enough to outlaw certain sexual acts between persons of different sexes, in some cases even including acts between married persons. Through the 20th century, the gradual liberalization of American sexuality led to the elimination of sodomy laws in most states. During this time, the Supreme Court upheld the constitutionality of sodomy laws in Bowers v.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | Credit: kittens_from_space)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
