<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037620303.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037628542.0" user="akoudagawaismywaifu" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, that's gold. And imo not indecent if the post was the reason you showed me that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037936310.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>So topless men are not indecent, I assume topless women would be?

Breasts on women are still sexualised so I get it but pride is about liberation and free the nipples is part of a liberating movement. 

That's how I view it at least</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038001118.0" user="Laetitian" delta="False">
    <text>She's a lesbian pupil, I doubt she has issues with topless equality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038767344.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>From her other replies it kind of sounds like it so idk, the part about doing things that can get you arrested for indecency which topless women can afaik</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038040403.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038155598.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038165360.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>u/kkzhc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20kkzhc&amp;amp;message=kkzhc%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jhqvn/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038180959.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>In my own opinion, breasts aren't inherently sexual but we're raised to see them so, in America it's worse than it is in my own country where we often enough have people nude at beaches or at river banks, and therefore if men can go around topless, women should be able to do it too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038567258.0" user="ThatOneBadWhiteGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Well they're erogenous for a start.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038574030.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>So are men's nipples and the skin on the neck and wrists can also be stimulated and cause arousal. Your point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038588024.0" user="MrPopanz" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like we should insist on covering up those area as well to keep consistent!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038678311.0" user="helloworldhgahshs" delta="False">
    <text>You rub my nipples I’m not getting a boner sorry to disappoint you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038692756.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>You rub my nipples I'm not getting wet sorry to to disappoint you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038797092.0" user="StumpNuts" delta="False">
    <text>You two should just rub my nipples. I promise that I'll get hard and wet for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37046348050.0" user="_ilikecoffee_" delta="False">
    <text>99.9% of women disagree with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37047944697.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Are you 99.9% of women? Are you taking your data from porn? Just rubbing nipples isn't going to make them weak in the knees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038687576.0" user="Haycabron" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't some people turned on by a broad back? Or good forearms? Something can be attractive and the only thing taught is to cover it or not. Most people attracted to breasts aren't taught that, they just are</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038699209.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying you are attracted to stuff because of people telling you that you are. Just saying that things aren't inherently sexual just because people can be attracted to them, just like a broad back is.

I like boobs too. My point still stands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038741458.0" user="Haycabron" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if I understand you haha I don't want to assume what you mean. Aren't they both at the same time? Sexual in nature because they are evolutionary indications of fertility and also they just are?

They just are, as in they function, they can be for just feeding a child, but that's not all they are</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038784693.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, breasts actually aren't indicators of fertility and size isn't a measurement of milk productivity.

If it was sexual in nature then everyone would find it appealing but it's not universal. The one thing that's seeing as consistently arousing is.. Well, depictions of the actual sex act. And you'd get aroused by watching it if is sexual. But when you're used to nudity the novelty of it kinda.. Stops.

Yeah, you still have certain likings, I suppose, but people won't be consistently aroused at nude beaches or in saunas because it just.. Doesn't matter.


Plus, if our requirement for "it's sexual because it is sexy to someone", then everything would be sexual. Like, any kind of clothing, any kind of bodily trait, but they're not inherently sexual. They're a non-sexual thing sexualized by the individual (or masses), but the thing itself is still not actually sexual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038845934.0" user="Haycabron" delta="False">
    <text>Agree to disagree! For something to be sexual doesn't have to be universal. Larger breasts are also usually induced by higher levels of estrogen, which do have an impact on fertility and that's why they can be outward signals of healthiness and fertility. 

These things are attractive naturally in a sexual way. So, it is what it is, agree to disagree!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038853542.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, meh? Kinda? It should be on the same level as liking veins on arms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039054063.0" user="Haycabron" delta="False">
    <text>It is lol but there's also a spectrum of reactions they can induce. Good forearms with veins can be indications of ability to work, gather resources, you might think "wow, looks strong". Evolution isn't making us attracted to things randomly. A good perspective is Biology is the foundation and society is derived from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039287726.0" user="TheBlasterAberoth" delta="False">
    <text>Broad back, good forearms? Holy shit, thanks for the confidence boost. I've never really had many compliments in my life because I don't talk to people, but damn was I taken aback by this. Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039417593.0" user="Haycabron" delta="False">
    <text>Hahah hell yea man, show what you got and confidence is a bigger indicator than anything else as to happiness 👍 but, to not make it fake, make sure you're competent at what you want to do in life and it'll start a positive feedback loop</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039359235.0" user="ShadoShane" delta="False">
    <text>Some upper arms can be a turn on too for some people. So really it's anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039096207.0" user="foggy-sunrise" delta="False">
    <text>Don't forget that tissue in the nose can become erect just like a penis. It's what causes horny sneezes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039100550.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>I have never heard of horny sneezes before</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039207527.0" user="foggy-sunrise" delta="False">
    <text>Some people sneeze when they get aroused. It's because tissue in their nose becomes engorged during arousal, just like the penis. 

Human horn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082033361.0" user="ThatOneBadWhiteGuy" delta="False">
    <text>So? What's your point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082031636.0" user="ThatOneBadWhiteGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Woahhhh ease it with the attitude mate. You really came in guns blazing, you must be the sensitive type. I was actually going to write in brackets that I realise some men also get sexual stimulation from their nipples. I was simply pointing out a possible reason why it might be case. I never said or implied I agreed with it? Why did you jump straight to that conclusion? Are you always an immature little baby?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082092324.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>You seem quite rubbed up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082043448.0" user="ThatOneBadWhiteGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Everything is fucking erogenous if you ask enough people. Fuck I hate Redditors like you. Such smug entitled fucken know it alls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082098994.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>You're not really arguing for your point here. Geez, no need to get your dick in a twist about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038618638.0" user="missSPRINKLETON" delta="False">
    <text>What about the ears? Should we start making little ear hats to cover them up too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038680577.0" user="lepuma" delta="False">
    <text>Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039080054.0" user="WenzelOfMidgard" delta="False">
    <text>I think this dude is a bot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082012341.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37082016580.0" user="LetMeNotHear" delta="False">
    <text>u/ThatOneBadWhiteGuy – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20ThatOneBadWhiteGuy&amp;amp;message=ThatOneBadWhiteGuy%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h19o7ud/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37107872723.0" user="Agreeable-Walrus7602" delta="False">
    <text>So are the back of the knees, armpits for some, stomach for me. Not an argument imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038674684.0" user="helloworldhgahshs" delta="False">
    <text>Breasts have a biological function related to reproduction so of course they’re sexual used because big breasts mean your child will be well fed. It’s funny because “sexualization” usually means they care about somebody other than themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038690839.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Feeding a child through breast feeding is for the sake of keeping your born children alive, not making them, and by saying that you're insiuating that mothers that breast feed engage in sexual acts with their babies.
And if breastfeeding is sexual, then so would a bird feeding its babies. You do realize that it sounds dumb, right?

Breast size doesn't determine your ability to produce milk either.


And sexualization means you get horny about it. Sexualizing something doesn't mean you care for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038822192.0" user="HelloThisIsFrode" delta="False">
    <text>They're a sexondary sex characteristic, but like... so are adams apples. Like, it doesn't mean that they have to ve covered up/that people automatically get aroused by them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039129755.0" user="binarycow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;if men can go around topless, women should be able to do it too.

Completely legal in New York. Toplessness, in and of itself, is not a crime, no matter the gender. 

Staring at someone, while kicking your lips and rubbing your nipples? That may be illegal. But just being topless is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039174750.0" user="pishiiii" delta="False">
    <text>Yea it really isn't as sexualized in other places. America is  pretty much as bad as a religious state is with it. 
 
It would be great if my non-binary sibling could go out without a shirt like they want to. Hell, I want to but I already get enough harassment as a woman even with all my clothes on. 
 
Oh btw bra not ok, bikini ok? Bras have way more coverage! Makes no sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039194936.0" user="jocoseriousJollyboat" delta="False">
    <text>Idk how chill the cities are but I think in Europe the nudity taboo is not as extreme.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039228083.0" user="pishiiii" delta="False">
    <text>When I was in uni, it was technically legal for women to go topless in San Francisco...but I don't know if it still is. Not many people did it outside of parades and parties but I def have seen a few casually walking around. But this is the only big city in America that has that I think...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038184613.0" user="Nobletwoo" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with OP. Here in toronto its legal for everyone to go topless. So i see no problem there. Boobs arent inherently sexual ffs. If i can show my tits, women should be allowed to show theirs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038682480.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37066911284.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>u/helloworldhgahshs – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20helloworldhgahshs&amp;amp;message=helloworldhgahshs%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jvib4/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37070991079.0" user="freddietohe" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. The idea one has a more negative moral/social implication is purely a social construct. 

It' was legalized in my specific state/region (US), under specific protocols m</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038624360.0" user="helloworldhgahshs" delta="False">
    <text>So pride is just being a sexual deviant to you? There is more to life than masturbation my dude. The whole love is love thing comes because people want it to be more than people just pushing their fetish sex acts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038771426.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't even understand how you came to this conclusion but ok</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038880373.0" user="clever304" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what it's about and you're missing the point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038733502.0" user="ItzMeDude_" delta="False">
    <text>They are sexualised cuz they are sexy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038849668.0" user="Calfer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm assuming it's less about the nipple and more about the clamps.

I hold OP's opinion, or at least a similar one to it. There's nothing wrong with celebration and the core concept of pride, but there should be a focus on LGBT+. While sexuality and BSDM both fall under sexual preferences, sexuality is something that had been a source of condemnation whereas BDSM should always be private - even people who are into public experiences engage in a way that stimulates *them* without effecting others who aren't participants.

So being topless because it's a warm day, sure, whatever. Wearing the harness, or collar, or clamps, or any of the stuff you would typically reserve for your partner(s) and over-sexualizing yourself doesn't benefit the core message and alienates a demographic that is at a critical point of development (youth and teens) as well as other adults who may be uncomfortable for various reasons. *Even if someone is an ally* they don't necessarily want to see *that* which is not exclusive to non-heterosexual relationships anyway.

Pride is about sexuality, which isn't about *being* sexy, or fetishes. BDSM and other fetishes or sexual desires that are separate from the base question of "who/which genitalia are you attracted to" shouldn't be included in Pride because imo they aren't connected. One is attraction, the other is a sex act. One has faced criticism and oppression and been forced into a public light while the other is a private occurence between consenting parties, which may have faced some criticism but has been supported in equal measure by various groups and demographics, or at minimum left as "it's their business" and personally I wish we reached that point with all things that only effect the self.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038867255.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>My reply to OP was sparked because OP apparently don't have a problem with kinks per se (like leather pants and collars) and more about public indecency, see their edit. 

Topless women is definitely regarded as public indecency still. So question then is what OP considers public indecency and if it's consistent with many current laws or if they have their own version of public decency that should be followed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038894486.0" user="Calfer" delta="False">
    <text>In Canada I can walk around topless as a woman with no charge of indecency. The human body is not indecent in and of itself, it is how we display it that leads it to be considered as such.

I myself enjoy BDSM, but I don't want to see it if I'm not looking for it, nor would I put another person aside from my partner in a position that makes them feel indecent or compromised.

If OP has expressed there's no issue with *nudity* because being topless is fine, and is accepting of kinks in general, than I stand by my interpretation that OP feels similarly to me. It's the expression of sexualized behaviour that is indecent.

Maybe *you* find breasts indecent, but there are swathes of the population who don't give a fig to see them, but care and become uncomfortable when you start doing something sexual as a display.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038913986.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>There's no way to know what OP currently thinks about certain types of nudity so idk, I'm just saying that their concept of public indecency might not be so clear cut

And no I do not find breasts indecent and it is similar in Sweden regarding toplessness but obviously not as accepted as when men do it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038966481.0" user="Calfer" delta="False">
    <text>May I ask why you projected that view, then? The comment of yours I responded to stated your assumption that OP found breasts indecent, which is the entire reason I brought up clamp vs nipple.

And pants and a collar are different and very tame compared to what is sometimes seen. OP's edit said it was the things that fell into legal grey or would get you publicly questioned. Being topless, wearing a necklace style or pants style aren't things that would be legally grey or questioned outside of Pride, nor do they fall into any category of indecency - reiterating here that the human body is *not* indecent and the argument "it is because people say so" will not be valid here^1 - what *does* fall into indecency is clamps, harnesses, straps, gags, cuffs and all the stuff that is bedroom/sex exclusive (and still not exclusive to the LGBT community) but still makes its way to Pride because "it's liberating/expression/I wanna."

^1 I won't accept an argument based on a flawed view that we are trying to change as a society. If everyone accepted the answer of "well that's how it's always been" or "that's how it is" we would never progress as humans. If you disagree, do it based on your own view, not by holding up sexist outdated ones which are rapidly losing relevancy anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039025594.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>Simply because OP stated that acts that can get you arrested or queationed for indecency is what they disagree with. And since they commented that male toplessness wasn't indecent I was curious to know if they consider female toplessness indecent since it is considered indecent in many places (law wise and norm wise) and which is something that you can often see in pride parades. What is their definition of public indecency?

That is all really, I don't really feel the need to argument about your view on certain types of BDSM behaviour on Pride because it isn't what I'm curious about in this case</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039073449.0" user="Calfer" delta="False">
    <text>Well perhaps you should re-educate yourself on the legal aspects, considering most of Western culture (NA, much of Europe, Australia, etc) *does not* consider the breast indecent. Canada has ruled it not indecent, Australia only treats it as indecent if there's sexual intent, only three states still hold laws regarding it and you've expressed that in Sweden there is no issue, and I'm aware other parts of Europe also allow the breast to be visible. The norm is actually that breasts are accepted or becoming accepted.

So, are you basing your legal view on the locations in the world which have women's rights issues as a seperate problem anyway? Because if those are laws that are being challenged, they shouldn't be used as a supporting argument.

What exactly are you curious about, then? You haven't asked questions, you simply assumed OP was against female toplessness and then continued to say "well the world says it's bad" when I tried to separate nudity from indecency, which is also false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039122748.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>Usually breasts aren't inherently indecent but if I take Swedens law as an example:

&amp;gt; In Sweden, on the other hand, it is permissible to be topless or naked everywhere, provided that one does not behave in a way that is likely to arouse annoyance in the public (annoying behavior) or discomfort in an individual (sexual harassment)

Basically you can be naked everywhere but does that mean you won't get into legal problems? Nope because there's a pretty big interpretation on when you're trying to incite annoyance or discomfort.

There's a reason women (in the west at least) aren't typically toplessa when men are, even at beaches. There's a reason why topless beaches are still a thing. There's a reason why free the nipple movements are still a thing and why women who don't wear a bra at work are considered unprofessional etc. The norm is not that breasts are decent and if you still think that I've got no clue why.

I'm curious about their definition of public indecency, that is all. Maybe their view of public indecency can be challenged, which is the whole purpose of this sub.

I feel I've made my point as clear as I can now, I won't have any more time to Reddit today so I'll just leave our discussion here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038914473.0" user="Zarzurnabas" delta="False">
    <text>Not from a biological point of view. Breasts are inherently sexual. To be clear: i still dont get why it should be illegal in many places to go around topless and i definitely dont want to argue against that movement. Its just that the point of "breasts arent inherently sexual" is wrong. Atleast regarding evolutionary biology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038938438.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>In what way are breasts sexual from a biological view? Because they're used to feed babies or how do you mean?

Regardless I still wouldn't view them as inherently sexual just because they serve a baby feeding function, whats sexual about that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039321283.0" user="logicalmaniak" delta="False">
    <text>They're part of our sexual selection instincts. Healthy boobs means healthy babies, which means a good sexual partner from an evolutionary perspective.

Not to say that they're not over-sexualised by our culture though, but they are a very big part of human attraction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039015251.0" user="cakeisgreat" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve seen men literally fisting each other’s assholes to a crowd of cheering men at a pride parade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039034536.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>OK?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039058354.0" user="cakeisgreat" delta="False">
    <text>Saying pride is just about liberation and trying to equate it to women going topless is downplaying what actually happens there.  It’s also about doing sexually explicit acts in public a public place where many people are actively encouraged to bring their children.   It’s also about 30 year old men in dog gimp suits exposing their penises to children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039068006.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not trying to downplay anything, I'm trying to understand OPs definition of public indecency</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039133784.0" user="KyotoMachina" delta="False">
    <text>That is completely irrelevant to this conversation. The “Free the nipples” movement doesn’t have anything to do with Pride.

That’s like me trying to phone in a reason to bring up BLM because I’m black. Sure, both are the same in that they are social justice movements. But it’s apples and oranges and that’s not what this post is for. Lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039142739.0" user="RainBooom" delta="False">
    <text>Some here would disagree with you, I've already read people that mean that pride is more than just about lgbtq+. That isn't really my point though but I'll leave the discussion for now

Also:
&amp;gt; Gay pride or LGBT pride is the promotion of the self-affirmation, dignity, equality, and increased visibility of lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) people as a social group - Wiki</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039188459.0" user="KyotoMachina" delta="False">
    <text>That’s just inherently wrong. LGBTQ+ has always been (since before I was a child) about gay rights, personal identity and the struggles of not being accepted based off the gender you’re attracted to/love. 

The “free the nipples” movement is already a movement and is unrelated to this one. 

Once again, I can call back to the BLM example, but by bringing up BLM on this post I’d feel a little morally corrupt for hijacking the topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039200801.0" user="KyotoMachina" delta="False">
    <text>Also, that excerpt you posted doesn’t say anything about women walking around topless... this just seems like an attempted hijacking of the intended post lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039201876.0" user="Sethanatos" delta="False">
    <text>I just ask myself "How would I feel if a minor was doing X or dressing like Y?"

If I cringe, then we're left with two options:

* Children shouldn't go or be a part of Pride.

* Pride needs to be restricted to children's standards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039251533.0" user="I_fail_at_memes" delta="False">
    <text>I think breasts will be sexualized as long as they remain a turn-on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039525134.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Read a thread about men’s forearms sometime on Reddit. Some of the write ups sound like they’re pulled straight from an erotic novel. Yet men’s forearms are exposed everywhere we go. 

Something being a turn-on for certain people does not mean it should be covered for all. That’s basically the reason burkas exist, and I don’t believe you’re advocating for those.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039289930.0" user="MonstahButtonz" delta="False">
    <text>This. Many men have larger breasts than some women do for God's sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039304031.0" user="Arachnidzz" delta="False">
    <text>Instead of desexualizing women, how about we sexualize men? /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039328826.0" user="DuckyDoodleDandy" delta="False">
    <text>We’ve got decades or longer before cis-het-males don’t see women’s breasts as sex objects. Men still sexually harass and assault 11 year old girls because the child developed breasts. I do not see women going topless discouraging that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037821236.0" user="Spare_Apple3338" delta="False">
    <text>Also a big time gay here and I fully agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037959457.0" user="cocobear13" delta="False">
    <text>This is awesome!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038045868.0" user="Izaiah212" delta="False">
    <text>They look like shirtless G.I Joe’s 🤣🤣
At first I was like how can a military parade be gay but after looking at that it’s definitely super gay</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038820093.0" user="very_clean" delta="False">
    <text>It’s literally Mac from Always Sunny’s dream parade</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039326382.0" user="Nextasy" delta="False">
    <text>I was gonna say they look like somebody playing with action figures lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038124121.0" user="ParioPraxis" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. Well, I wasn’t gay before clicking. Now… supergay. Also, I kinda blacked out for a bit and when I came to I was in the checkout line at the grocery store with WAY more canola oil than I could ever use. I mean… I still bought it just in case my buddy will let me stand on top of his Durango, but I’m still waiting for him to return my messages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038281721.0" user="ProfessorHeronarty" delta="False">
    <text>Not to be the one who spoils the party, this is indeed funny for our eyes. But if we look at history and not from a far time ago this isn't that gay (in the cliche term of showing manly bodies). This rather connects to display of hypermasculinity as something that has to do with battle, fights, being a warrior. Of course this imagery was used by the gay community as well but to *just* connect it to this is not just a westernized view in this case but a pretty ahistorical one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038305325.0" user="Izaiah212" delta="False">
    <text>We’re not on Reddit for accuracy we’re here to say haha look how gay this was 10 years ago and they didn’t even know

Edit: oh shit it was 2020 that makes it even more gay, who is Egypt trying to flex on with like 88 at most shirtless guys. GAYYYYYY</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038343024.0" user="InkyAddams" delta="False">
    <text>They look like creepy mannequins with bronzer painted all over them o.o</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038363146.0" user="nbelium" delta="False">
    <text>I guess their strategy is to seduce the enemy into submission.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038430796.0" user="WatdeeKhrap" delta="False">
    <text>Toxic masculinity flowing out there like the Nile</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038544915.0" user="TinktheChi" delta="False">
    <text>Totally off topic.   Love that your username is Gladys Kravitz.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038615188.0" user="helloworldhgahshs" delta="False">
    <text>See the real reason I hate gay people is because they try and call anything that’s masculine in any way gay. It’s like jojo fans saying everything is a reference. Nah you’re weird and trying to convince yourself everybody else is a freak.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038764075.0" user="xfearthehiddenx" delta="False">
    <text>I'm gonna guess based on everything you've said in this thread that you....

A) do not know many if any gay people.

B) are young and live, or have lived in a conservative household.

C) have not had much sexual experience.

D) feel attacked when you hear about a movie, show, or video game containing a gay character. 

Seriously nothing you've said makes any sense, and feels deeply rooted in incel/homophobia logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040957201.0" user="Cronyx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Seriously nothing you've said makes any sense, and feels deeply rooted in incel/homophobia logic.

Incel *slash* homophobia? Could you explain how those are related? What's the Venn diagram there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041018779.0" user="xfearthehiddenx" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think its too far off to say that sexual insecurities are traits both incels, and homophobes have in common. So that would be in the crossed over section. But besides that. It was more that they fit the bill of both based on their comments. Not that being an incel, and being homophobic are specificly related.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041082390.0" user="Cronyx" delta="False">
    <text>Aright that's fair. It had sounded to me at first, that you were pooling the two together -- homophobia, a recognized prejudice -- with being involuntarily celibate, a state of turmoil and anxiety brought about by goal frustration.

One is to be condemned to be sure, but the latter I feel deeply compassionate for, where others just mock and laugh. I feel bad for anyone experiencing the psychological state of goal frustration so strongly that they fall into a bottomless well of diaper, and then to be treated so callously by others and have your self described status be turned into a pejorative term of opprobrium, must feel like the world gathering around to get their rib kicks in when you're down. Just awful and cruel.

I thought that's what you were participating in at first, that's why I jumped up. My apologies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041307077.0" user="xfearthehiddenx" delta="False">
    <text>I think the general disconnect, and miscommunication comes because like many words through time. Incel has gained new meaning, and is recognized more as a insult for toxic masculinity, than as an abbreviated "involuntarily celibate." 

Additionally I don't know that I share your great empathy for such people. If these people are in such a bad way. They should be seeking help, not taking it out on other people. Which is (I believe) what often happens. Innocent people bear the brunt of toxic masculinity. Something that is often a major part of being involuntarily celibate. "Goal frustration" as you put it. Doesnt justify the way incels often treat other people, women especially. And watering it down with fancy words doesn't change the fact that people in such a desperate mental state, who live outside of reality, are often dangerous. Thoughts like "she wants me, she's just playing hard to get", or "we're in a relationship" when the other person doesn't even know who they are. Even worse, acting on these feelings thinking they're doing nothing wrong. Because in their head the other person "really does love them".

I have empathy for people who recognize they have a problem, and seek help. But far to often that is not the case, and they go about their lives angry at the world for not conforming to their expectations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038632897.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039315825.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/CoolWhipMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20CoolWhipMonkey&amp;amp;message=CoolWhipMonkey%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0jug1t/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038743416.0" user="annacat1331" delta="False">
    <text>Holy shit, I  think the only thing gayer than that is Sean and Cody.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038855433.0" user="Gauntlets28" delta="False">
    <text>That is very true. Although it starts to push over into the uncanny valley after they've been standing stock still for over two minutes straight. Starts to feel like a parade of hyper-realistic muscle man-nequins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039028688.0" user="LeafFallGround" delta="False">
    <text>My boss asked what I was chuckling at and now he's giving me the side eye because I said "just gay stuff"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039124928.0" user="ThePanzerGunMan" delta="False">
    <text>As seen in one of the comments

POV: you’re a small skinny boy on grindr</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039172814.0" user="DerbleZerp" delta="False">
    <text>That has “gay steel mill” vibes all over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039245312.0" user="Cheeseguy88_RS3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not even gay and that was hot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039312730.0" user="Jimmy-TinkerBull" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I wasn't gay until I saw that, but here we go. That's plenty gay.

By the way, do you know Turkish oil wrestling? I guess that's topping everything I've seen until now, including the Egyptian pride army.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039323171.0" user="arkmuscle" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039346361.0" user="LadyMirkwood" delta="False">
    <text>That is fantastic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039771873.0" user="themaskedserpent" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Gladys_Kravitz_ – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Gladys_Kravitz_&amp;amp;message=Gladys_Kravitz_%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0j8qq7/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/Gladys_Kravitz_ – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Gladys_Kravitz_&amp;amp;message=Gladys_Kravitz_%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0j8qq7/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
