<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037007359.0" user="joka002" delta="False">
    <text>But in your first paragraph you mentioned why they should be there... because they have played a huge role in movement and helping (not only the lgbtq+ community) people accept their sexuality. 

I also feel like your missing one of the original points of pride which is to make people feel uncomfortable. People who are homophobic are supposed to look at pride parades and rallies and realizes that our group doesn’t care what they think and we are happy. The BDSM community does a great job at making an uproar and making homophobic people stare and feel they unease. 

 I’m not saying nipples should be flying or cockrings should be out, but since when has LGBTQIA+ every been about been being exclusive</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037374370.0" user="WitheredBarry" delta="False">
    <text>"Uncomfortable" and "this could possibly expose a child to something that could mess with their sexual development at a very young age" are not the same thing.

The public doesn't get to decide how young people react to this. They may take it well, or it may very well fuck them up for life at a young age. It's our duty as adults to respect childrens' development and vulnerability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037867409.0" user="TheYang" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "this could possibly expose a child to something that could mess with their sexual development at a very young age"

unfortunately we don't get any specific examples of things that shouldn't be there in this thread, but I have to say...  

I do think that children seeing gay people being happy might start considering that being in a relationship with someone of the same sex is an option, which I think can be considered "messing with their sexual development".  
I mean, it's probably for the better, but it's still messing.  

So I've got trouble agreeing that this is a good reason.  

But I'm from europe... we don't think seeing boobs or dicks messes with children...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038596656.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>There are countless ways to show children queer people being happy that involves absolutely no sex. 

No I don’t think typical PDA counts as sex</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039219272.0" user="Firebirdie713" delta="False">
    <text>Then you will be happy to know that no sex happens at Pride.  Nudity is not sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037548651.0" user="akoudagawaismywaifu" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree that it is an important part of pride. I just feel iffy about doing things in public that could get you arrested or questioned for indecency. Like the cock rings and nipples. I don't really care if you wear leather boots or something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038056725.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>Kissing your partner in public could have got you arrested 50 years ago, that's why pride was a protest, solidarity in numbers. Kink should be a part of that in my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038293681.0" user="RinArenna" delta="False">
    <text>Except, kissing in public couldn't get straight couples arrested.

Let's not pretend that wearing cock rings in public is the same as public displays of affection.

The majority of people are in support of age restricting porn, and include images of sexual kinks in that category. So why do we make an exception for sexual kinks only for pride?

As a trans lesbian I would love to participate in pride events and celebrate our community without being exposed to naked men in dog harnesses. Is that really an unreasonable request?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038310521.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As a trans lesbian I would love to participate in pride events and celebrate our community without being exposed to naked men in dog harnesses. Is that really an unreasonable request?

Don't you think some pearl clutching Christians would say the same thing about lesbians kissing in public? I don't really see what is different. 

Why are you uncomfortable seeing naked men in dog harnesses? How is it different to how the aforementioned people might feel when they see lesbians in public?

We need to fight for liberation of all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038858474.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>Because one may involve indecent exposure that involves someone in your kink without their concent, regardless of the sexuality of the participants, while the other does not and is something that people were persecuted for specifically because of their sexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038875973.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that in some places of the world and historically, two men kissing is considered "Indecent exposure".

The line seems very arbritrarily drawn, and exclusive of some peoples lifestyles. I think we should challenge that, so all are welcome to be who they want to be. 

I think men should be able to hold hands and kiss in public, and people who want to walk around collared on all fours should be able to, as should nudists for that matter!

The line is very easy to draw, if you are explicitly making it sexual and non-consensually involving others then that's obviously across the line. If you are just dressing as your true self who are we to judge?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039084592.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My point is that in some places of the world and historically, two men kissing is considered "Indecent exposure".

But the act of kissing is not. The issue there is not the kissing, it was the horrific double standard amd stigma when it came to same sex couples. Involving other people in your kink without their consent is bad regardless of sexuality. 

&amp;gt;The line seems very arbritrarily drawn, and exclusive of some peoples lifestyles. I think we should challenge that, so all are welcome to be who they want to be. 

How far does that extend? It's obviously great to be inclusive of, for example, a group in a polyamorous pansexual relationship and give them a platform to not only be accepted, but appreciated. On the other hand, what if someone is an exhibitionist and that's a key aspect of their sexual identity? Do they get to masturbate on the bus because that's their lifestyle and who they want to be? I appreciate that this is an extreme and un-nuanced example for the sake of highlighting the point that problems arise once you start to intrude on people's concent when it comes to sex.

&amp;gt;The line is very easy to draw, if you are explicitly making it sexual and non-consensually involving others then that's obviously across the line. If you are just dressing as your true self who are we to judge?

That's more or less the point. I've not seen anyone here complain about people dressing in drag or anything like that (granted I've not filtered by controversial), just about overtly sexual acts at a public event. And even then, the consensus seems to be that if you're at an adult event where attendees consent to explicitly sexual behaviour then it's completely fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039121664.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>I guess maybe the issue is some people see people in leather acting as dogs as an overtly sexual thing, and I don't. I think there is a lot of grey area here so something specific would be useful as a reference point for the discussion. Is there any incidents you have in mind? 

I just think it's weird to want to find for sexual liberation for one group and not for others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039344924.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>
I don't think it's unreasonable to see clothes specifically geared towards a sexual fetish, alongside behaviour that is the basis of an adjacent sexual fetish, and come to the conclusion that there might be some sexual undertones. But that's very much implicit and not really what people have an issue with (at least as far as I can tell). It's certainly not what I'm talking about. To be more specific, it starts to cross the line when the dog costume incorporates a butt plug as the tail and assless chaps. 

People here aren't arguing against sexual liberation, and I think it's a little disingenuous to act like they are. Sexual liberation doesn't require involving people without their concent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039519448.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To be more specific, it starts to cross the line when the dog costume incorporates a butt plug as the tail and assless chaps.

That's a blurry line, I really don't see how that's a problem, and say a gay couple making out wouldn't be. Like there isn't really a consistent logic applied, other than some base "I don't like this" feeling. As someone who doesn't get that feeling from what someone else wears, I find it hard to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039597794.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>
It's overtly a sex act - using a sex toy for its intended purpose to elicit sexual stimulation, while bringing in an audience without their consent. I don't belive for a second that you don't understand how that is different from kissing.

The logic is completely consistent - involvement in sexual practices requires consent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039634570.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>To me it seems fair to argue that a couple kissing is overtly a sex act though, it's stimulation for arousal by another person. 

It really boils down to context though doesn't it. What would bother you more on the bus, someone stood minding their own business with assless chaps and a tail, or a couple aggressively making out next on the seat next to you?

Personally I'd be much more bothered by the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039780486.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't involve a sex organ, sex toy, nudity (partial or otherwise) nor is it for the express purpose of sexual pleasure - people kiss their parents. This really seems like you're arguing in bad faith.

The only grievance I have with people kissing on a bus is that it's an enclosed space, so they should probably be wearing a mask. Someone exposing their genitals to people without their consent and involving them in a display of sex acts, again without consent, is absolutely a problem. It's why it's bad to send unsolicited dick picks, or grope people. Consent matters. And pretending that you don't the difference between kissing and penetration does not give you the right to ignore it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039844509.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This really seems like you're arguing in bad faith.

Sorry if it comes across that way, I'm really not trying to. I find it an interesting topic, and I'm not sure where my position really is, so I'm trying to find out. 

I think my core position is:

"Wearing kink gear, or acting in a roleplay in public should be fine, *so long as you aren't involving others non-consensually*. If the mere sight of non traditional sexuality is the grounds to force people to hide their true self, would that not apply to LGBT people too?"

It's the difference between seeing a naked man in the park, and seeing a naked man masturbating in the park.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040002083.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;I think my core position is:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;"Wearing kink gear, or acting in a roleplay in public should be fine, *so long as you aren't involving others non-consensually*.

The problem is that you consistently argue that involving people without their consent is fine. Wearing a bit of leather is not the same as using a sex toy in front of an audience. And when someone points out that the latter is involving others without consent you just kind of pretend that they must have a problem with the leather, or that using a sex toy couldn't possibly be considered a sex act. Those both come across as disingenuous ways of avoiding the issue of consent.

&amp;gt;If the mere sight of non traditional sexuality is the grounds to force people to hide their true self, would that not apply to LGBT people too?"

Are you suggesting that the only way to embrace sexuality is to engage in distinct and explicit sex acts in front of others? Nobody (here) is saying hide your true self. They're saying "don't fuck in public".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040153437.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>It's clear there is a huge grey area in what people consider exhibitionism or not, and that's probably where we have the disagreement. 

I can understand why today someone walking down the street naked could be seen as exhibitionism and non-consensual, but I'd like to live in a world where that was not the case, not because I want to do that, but because it would mean people don't have to hide who they are. Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040320209.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>But even in that scenario the person doesn't have to hide who they are. They can still say "exhibitionism is an important part of my sexuality, and I'm proud of that". They can still loudly and proudly acknowledge who they are, while simultaneously saying "but this might not be the most appropriate place to indulge it to its fullest". And there are of course many places where it is completely appropriate. They can still discuss the ins and outs of it and why it's meaningful to them and why they're proud. There's nothing there that requires hiding - hiding who you are would be actively taking precautions to make sure nobody finds out. You're the only person here suggesting that is necessary.

I understand your point, but it seems to be based on the assumption that there's a dichotomy between ignoring consent and hiding who you are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042140685.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>It is a very area though, think not of the exhibitionist but the nudist. They want to live their life free from clothing, but society sees them as exhibitionist and prevents them from living how they want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042240615.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>And some people want to live free to physically harm others, but society prevents them from living how they want too. There are people who want to live free to take other people's possessions,  but society also prevents them from living how they want. Because when your actions impact other people, it can be a problem. Saying "I want to be free live that way" doesn't give you the right to harm others by ignoring their consent, or otherwise. Living within a society means being conscientious of everyone who lives in that society, not just yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042378574.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>I totally agree, but when some people think that seeing a lesbian couple kissing is harmful to them, we fight that. 

When some other people think seeing a naked person, or a person in a gimp suit is harmful to them, we should fight that too no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042461223.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>When some people think that rape is harmful, we should fight that too, no?

That's how you sound. You're advocating to bring people into sexual encounters without their consent. I'm starting to think you sincerely do not understand the concept of consent and why it is important when it comes to sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042620943.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>Eh that's a leap, quite a bad faith one, obviously rape is a violent physical act against another person. 

Lesbians kissing in public, or people wearing kink gear is a passive act, no one is forcing you to participate. If one should be defended I don't see why the other shouldn't also be defended.

EDIT: I just thought, maybe you see the wearing of fetish gear as inherently sexual?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37043431059.0" user="Any_Piano" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Eh that's a leap, quite a bad faith one, obviously rape is a violent physical act against another person. 

I've tried good faith, but you're not too keen on it so I thought I'd try it your way:

How is that different from kissing? I just can't tell, darn it! To me they're basically the same thing. It's a gray area - how could we possibly differentiate between the two? There's no way, they're just too similar. I don't even know how you could consider rape sexual to begin with. If a rapist wants to wear clothes they like, you shouldn't be against it. I know that's your real gripe here - it couldn't possibly have anything to do with the role consent plays in sex. And what if the rapist just wants to be free to live their life the way they want? Surely that takes precedence over something trivial like unconsenually involving bystanders in your sex acts?

&amp;gt;Lesbians kissing in public, or people wearing kink gear is a passive act, no one is forcing you to participate. If one should be defended I don't see why the other shouldn't also be defended.

See, you're doing that thing again where you ignore the sex act (using a butt plug in our example) and pretend this is about the clothing when I've explicitly stated more that once that the clothing is not the issue. If you have to watch someone gratify them self with a sex toy, you are involved at the point. That's like saying sending unsolicited dick pics is fine because you're not physically in contact with the penis and nobody if forcing you to have a phone. It still requires projecting sexual activity on people without their consent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039522554.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To be more specific, it starts to cross the line when the dog costume incorporates a butt plug as the tail and assless chaps.

That's a blurry line, I really don't see how that's a problem, and say a gay couple making out wouldn't be. Like there isn't really a consistent logic applied, other than some base "I don't like this" feeling. As someone who doesn't get that feeling from what someone else wears, I find it hard to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039091933.0" user="next_right_thing" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you keep equating nudity to sex or sexuality.

Being nude in public is not the same as being engaged in a sex act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37042341435.0" user="Jiffygun" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between nudity and nudity at a pride parade is that on a nude beach there’s people doing normal things, just nude. You don’t see someone with a butt plug chillin on a nude beach. There’s inherent sexual implications when you’re nude and wearing something other than clothes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038591926.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>are you seriously comparing kissing, which is totally legal for anyone, to performative sex acts in public?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038612691.0" user="Midasx" delta="False">
    <text>Kissing can be seen as a preformative sex act too. Why should one be legal and the other not?

Provided you aren't actually involving others in your play, what's the harm?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038831824.0" user="Trolledy" delta="False">
    <text>“wait people get made when I masturbate publicly?? we live in a society”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038052747.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038163164.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>u/kkzhc – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20kkzhc&amp;amp;message=kkzhc%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0ji0ej/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038070191.0" user="montarion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I also feel like your missing one of the original points of pride which is to make people feel uncomfortable

Why would that be the point of something called pride?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038156698.0" user="libertyman77" delta="False">
    <text>But is making homophobic people feel uneasy really a good strategy?

I mean I think most lgbt people would prefer to be viewed as completely normal people, not as freaks. The pride parade culture of kink and indecency reaffirms the idea that all lgbt people are indecent. Not a single homophobic person is gonna go see a pride parade and be like "oh I was wrong these people are normal and just like me" lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038205478.0" user="HuldraGarborg" delta="False">
    <text>If they are watching it in real life and not just on TV, where they just show the shocking stuff, they absolutely will. The majority does not look wild, but some people do. Unless they are actively closing their eyes to most of the people there, they will see a huge variety - including plenty of “normal” people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038827050.0" user="Trolledy" delta="False">
    <text>“Make people feel uncomfortable”. That won’t change a thing. I’m bisexual and wouldn’t want any child near BDSM folks.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
