<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037957915.0" user="rcn2" delta="False">
    <text>Hi youngster. Great that you want to take part in Pride.

The people you are criticising are the ones that fought for Pride, in many cases fairly recently. The indecency is part of the protest; this isn't about you in particular. This is about your freedom to join, as it is. If you don't want to, that's fine. You didn't fight for anything, and your desire for less kink is part of what people fought against. If you're joining Pride, you have an obligation to find out what Pride is first. Your disgust is part of what the protest is protesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038074487.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Don't you think that  in the great scheme of things it was maybe counter productive to link LGBT with "kinky sex"? or at least that if it was relevant at some point of history, it isn't anymore?

Note that I'm honestly asking the question because I have very conflictual feeling about it as I really get the freeing aspect of pride parades but also think it gave a lot of people a wrong idea of homosexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038231026.0" user="HuldraGarborg" delta="False">
    <text>It was already linked in the average person’s view. Some people just took the fact that they were already considered perverted no matter what they did as freedom to explore. And bless them for that. They paved the way for liberation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038343528.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Well I watched footage from pride parade from the 70's and 80's and it was way less "kinky" that it became in the 90's. For example: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kW1D8_ynDVM

Then yes people had already stereotypes and I can get the idea that sometimes it's clever to take back the stereotype to yourself instead but I really cannot get past the idea that it went too far and become counter productive. At least it had this effect on "kid me" in the 90's: it really sold me the idea that LGBT people were really obsessed with partying and sex because not only it was how they were displayed in various media but even when they had their parade, they focused on this point (of course I realised years later that I was wrong) 

Now I also know that it had a lot of positive aspect and it's not really like the great board of LGBT had a plan and was all calculated but still, I'm with OP and think pride event should be way more family friendly nowadays than about sexual kinks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038576054.0" user="HuldraGarborg" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn’t a case of taking back the stereotype, really. It wasn’t about strategy, or being clever. If you read my comment that way, I may have been unclear. What I tried to say was that since there was no way not to be considered perverted, there were few bounds to exploring other perversions. That became culture. Not the entire culture, or even the majority, but an important part all the same. Hope that’s clearer. 

And - excluding a group that has been part of something from the beginning is generally not great. If it is necessary (which I don’t think it is here, but I see that it sometimes is) it needs to be named as such. 

As for how the footage have changed, that’s complicated. In the nineties, showing those things on TV for shock factor became a thing. The visual expressions have changed too, for sure. And that’s just part of it.

The sex and party thing of pride - yes, that’s part of pride for many people, but it’s a small part of the sum total. Granted, there are many pride celebrations I have never attended. It’s a bit different from city to city, year to year, etc. But if you look at a pride parade - not the pictures that gets on the news, but the actual parade - you will see that most people are not drunk, not wearing fetish gear - not dressed up much at all, in fact. Perhaps a t-shirt with a slogan, or whatever. A lot of young people do pride hair with dyes - but most don’t. What you see is variety. Saying that they focused on sex and partying at the parade just isn’t accurate for any pride I have been to. It sure looks that way when I see it on the news later, though.

There is plenty of focus on “normal” gay people at pride. Plenty of room for it. That’s not really an issue, except for the news coverage after. There’s room for the wild, too. The drag, the leather, the confetti, the wild variety of expression of pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038725059.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Well as I said in my last paragraph and I want to reiterate: I understand and agree with you that pride is much more than kinky stuff and has a lot of positive aspect! Also it's true that my negative view of the pride in the 90's when I was a kid was 100% created from the biased vision of television.

But that confirm a bit my intuition that all the kinky stuff is not very productive anymore. 

But in the end I think I just have some sort of problem with the 'kink community' being linked to LGBT like they are related because it kinda send the message that LGBT is a kink and not something totally normal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038371155.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Nothing wrong with kinky sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038403761.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>There's no need to link LGBT pride with kinky sex. It's just unrelated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038439228.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what I asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038472650.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Let's state it like this:

* it's totally legitimate to be prude and not like display of kinky sex in the street even if there's nothing wrong if two consenting adult doing kinky stuff in private
* it's totally illegitimate to not like to see LBGT people in the street.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038475441.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>Again not what I asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038480867.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>So you want my opinion on kinky sex? what's the point?

But ok: it's totally fine between two (or more!) consenting adult in private but not something I want to see in public space. So yay to kinky sex in your room, nay to kinky sex in the bus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038482932.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>What is bad, about lgbt community/pride, being linked to kinky sex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038521082.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Because you push prude people out of LBGT parade when there's no need for it.

And again, you can be prude! there's nothing wrong with it like there's nothing wrong with liking kinky stuff. It's subjective opinion and you don't want to link a subjective debate with something universal. It's like linking "anti-racism and drug legalisation" or "vaccine and vegan"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038566926.0" user="Aristotle_Wasp" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't anything wrong with being prude. And thats why you don't see kinksters going around policing prude people.

But you are trying to police kinksters because you're a prude, which isn't okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038607730.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>I never talked about policing kinky sex, I said the cause are unrelated and you don't really want to make people believe that LGBT is just a kink</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038679899.0" user="The_Great_Scruff" delta="False">
    <text>People have been having this exact same argument since the inception of Pride  


Except that it was to exclude anyone who wasn't gay or lesbian. Being bi or pan was seen as a kink. Drag was a kink. Trans was a kink. In it's own way, Ace was a kink. Delegitimizing someone else's sexuality as "just a kink" is the same oppressive language once used to keep gay people in the closet</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038818769.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's quite complicated to formulate my opinion clearly without sounding like I'm making fun or judging but I think there's a difference between sexuality and how you behave during a party. 

For exemple, if you're dancing with a big dildo in your hand, that's not your sexuality, you're just being over the top. 

Now again I'm not saying there's something inherently wrong with kinks. But it's just that I don't see why some people are so adamant to group "LBGT march" with "super kink party" like one can go without the other or if they share common goals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038906878.0" user="The_Great_Scruff" delta="False">
    <text>Kink is a catch all of dozens of different groups and communities that are wildly different from each other. Several of these communities, such as pan and trans, are now accepted by the community at large. Others, like polyamory, is just starting to gain traction. 

Pride, to alot of people, is open and unabashed expressionism of who they are. Sexuality is a core part of who people are. More often than not, the ones that are oiled up or waving dildos are not part of any kink community, but a budding queer person finally allowing themselves to let go

Banning kink wouldnt change that, and that isn't something that should be stifled. The entire world is awash in heteronormative sexual expression because sexual expression is a fundamental aspect of human nature. Why is it suddenly a problem that sexuality is open when its pride, but 10 foot tall posters of lingerie models in malls near Victoria secret are fine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039243310.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>I just want to make a difference between sexuality and "unabashed expressionism" of sexuality.

And I don't like unabashed expressionism of cis-hetero sexuality either. I just don't think public space is there to display all your sexual fantaisies in the open so I cannot be called hypocrite on the subject and you will see me facepalm when I see guys with hentai hoodies, people putting vulgar wallpaper on their phone and I don't like when advertisement over-sexualise everything in bad taste either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038650458.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t think there are prude LGBt people? One thing i’ve noticed is absolutely no one acknowledging they 1) exist and 2) may be uncomfortable. 

Also, LGBT people are significantly more than how they fuck. Focusing so heavily on it isn’t a good representation. There will be people who’s first exposure to LGBT irl will be at a pride parade. 

Is it so crazy that people like/are comfortable with different things? it doesn’t necessarily make either right or wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038674268.0" user="PashaBiceps24" delta="False">
    <text>You can fight the good fight while not being ass naked with a 10 inch dildo up your oiled up ass for all the world to see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039223905.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37062357425.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>u/tacosaladchupacabra – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20tacosaladchupacabra&amp;amp;message=tacosaladchupacabra%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0k742p/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
