<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037713920.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>Isnt this the same arguments used by homophobes as to why gay people should not kiss in public?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038072807.0" user="montarion" delta="False">
    <text>Could you elaborate?

Nothing about their argument is homophobic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038175769.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>I said its the same logic. She thinks kink is disgusting therefor it should not be shown in public because it can harm children.

Putins Russia apply this logic to homosexuality. Putin thinks gay people kissing is disgusting therefor it should not be shown in public because it can harm children.

Never said she's homophobic. She said openly she finds kink disgusting.

The point of pride is to normalize sexual expression so people find it less disgusting and become more open to it.

Keep in mind that perspectives matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038221591.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>People have an issue with people exposing their kinks in public regardless of their sexuality, there’s a time and place. Kissing and then explicit sexual acts are not the same thing lol.

There’s more to pride than just actual sex acts. Pride is turning into a family event. There is no reason for why you have to normalize BDSM specifically at a family event around children. I don’t care what the fuck your sexuality is, that’s extremely creepy. Now if you want to promote healthy sexual conversations with younger people, I’m all for it.

Pride isn’t just about sex. BDSM and kinks are not the only form of sexual expression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038660238.0" user="The_Great_Scruff" delta="False">
    <text>There is more to BDSM than sex, and the fact that you exclusively think that kink representation means "people fucking" is indicative of the exact prejudice the person you are replying to is talking about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038884559.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s just that lol.

There is certain attire that is extremely sexually, such as puppy play attire, sorry I don’t want you to just wear that around children.

(also notice how you didn’t address anything I said lol)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039088920.0" user="The_Great_Scruff" delta="False">
    <text>Puppy play isn't inherently sexual. Your internal bias may tell you different, but it is no more sexual than anything portrayed in media

It isnt heteronormative. That does not inherently make it more sexual


I didnt address the rest of your message because there was nothing else in your message worth addressing

No one is advocating for actual sex acts in public. That is a straw man and doesn't apply to any real world discourse

Pride is not, and has never been, a "family event". It is a protest and expression of open and unashamed sexuality. Always has been. Want to go to a family event? Great, go to a youth Pride, or any of the family friendly side events. Dont just step into a space and demand that it conforms to your sensibilities.

If Pride maintained a "family friendly" atmosphere, alot of the country would say that drag queens and trans folk shouldn't be there either. "Think of the children" is the exact same phrasing that society has said for decades about the rest of Pride, and still says about Pride</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039096629.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>Some pride events are literally all ages, sorry for whatever reason that’s hard for you to understand. Sorry it’s hard for you to understand that I don’t give a fuck about BDSM, just not around children. I literally don’t understand what the fuck is the problem about that lol.

Whether you like it or not, some pride events are family events. I don’t understand why the fuck I have to keep saying that, it’s not like I’m wrong. People do bring their children to some pride events. Once you bring your children, once families start going. It’s a family event. That’s how family events work.

I’m not talking about every pride under the sun, some are for families some aren’t. Keep sexual stuff to the ones that don’t include kids. Why is that a problem?

This whole bullshit argument about conformity is not what I’m talking about, I repeatedly had said family specific focused spaces. The fact that your extrapolating that to everything means you clearly did not read what I wrote. Please try again.

There are a variety of ways to celebrate pride, you pointed out family friendly and youth pride. That’s what I’m talking about. There are people who believe that BDSM communities should be allowed at these specific events, no they shouldn’t. Which is what I’m talking about. If you want to do whatever the fuck you wanna do in a space that doesn’t have children, go ahead. If you feel like I seem to believe all spaces of LGBTQ plus people should just conform to a specific look, you’re free to quote where I said that. Because not once did I actually say all spaces should conform, family friendly and spaces with children should not have sexual scenes attached to them. Literally that is it, all of this other fluff adding I don’t know where you’re pulling it from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038835724.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>So you wish to enforce conservative values on a movement you dont understand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038874999.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>Not openly wearing BDSM attire is not conservative lmaooo

Which, I don’t have a problem with certain BDSM attire (leather choker). It’s the ones that are openly sexually suggestive (puppy play)

Also, there’s more to the movement than just sexual expression. I’m not really sure why everybody on this thread wants to pretend like pride is sexual expression and literally the only way to do it is through BDSM and kink

Just don’t do it around kids, what is the problem? Do it literally at any other event.

(also notice how you didn’t address anything I said)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039657342.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>I dont address what youre saying because you missrepresent what Im saying.

Dont bring your children to a demonstration you know will feature sexual content and some heavy subjects?

I call you conservative because you sound like my conservative brother talking about pride. There is no nuance, just heavy handed right-or-wrpng rethoric.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039735650.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>*child friendly all age events should not have sexual demonstrations in the first place*

Lol, why is that so hard to understand</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039808363.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>I understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039962665.0" user="moosemoth" delta="False">
    <text>But Pride was never supposed to be a "child friendly all age event."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040123042.0" user="flawednoodles" delta="False">
    <text>…family pride events exist

It’s like I’m a broken record lol.

Obviously not all, but some are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039209548.0" user="tacosaladchupacabra" delta="False">
    <text>Is having a shred of basic decency and not behaving like a complete degenerate in public a conservative value now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039614718.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>Im saying that by limiting others peoples right to freely express themselves and shaming them to stay closeted you are comitting to conservative values. That is all.

Remove the provocative nature of pride and you no longer have pride. You have closeted people who suffer in silence.

I dont visit pride cause it often makes me uncomfortable, but ill be damned if this is taken away from people who want it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039632101.0" user="tacosaladchupacabra" delta="False">
    <text>I guess if "stop fucking in front of children you fucking degenerates" is a conservative value, that makes me a conservative. It also makes conservatism the obvious correct position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039974157.0" user="moosemoth" delta="False">
    <text>Dang, what Pride did you go to where people were fucking in front of kids?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038160068.0" user="439115" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's slightly different; that argument is flawed because straight people are able to kiss in public, hence the right is available to everyone regardless. OP's arguing that nobody should have the right to expose themselves indecently, ie having a special "right" just because they're into the kink</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038885780.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>I grew up with conservative siblings and this is what they said about homo-relationships. To them its not kissing- its indecent exposure.

BDSM is much more than a kink. Have ypu talked to any of these indecent people and asked them what and why they are doing?

I heard pride is a great place to strike up conversations about that..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039058158.0" user="439115" delta="False">
    <text>If your siblings think that nobody at all should be allowed to kiss in public, then that's a valid and more conservative stance on OP's argument - that nobody should be allowed to display their sexuality or orientation in public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039145779.0" user="Asleep-Bug-9147" delta="False">
    <text>They are fine with hetero kisses and cuddles in public. Its just that homosexuality is just a kink to them. Its a phase and a choice. Keep it to yourself they would say.

Just like you think BDSM is all about sex and kink. 

BDSM has a place in pride because people with orientations outside of norms often find it hard to live work and love openly without persecution.

And its not like they have sex on the streets.

And if its nudity you are against I would very much call you conservative.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
