<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037362605.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Point 1:    
Naked does not mean kink. In the city I live in, it IS legal for women and people with breasts to be topless. And yet, for some reason, it's only seen as 'kink' during June. If naked boobies are an issue or not needs to be a discussion that doesn't only happen because of Pride. That's definitely homophobic if it's only an issue during Pride.  

Point 2:    
Saying 'no kink' or 'no BDSM' at Pride is way, WAY too vague and, as a transgender person, I risk being able to even attend public events -at all- if the 'no kink at pride' thing catches on. Where I grew up at in the bible belt, it was a FIRMLY held belief that transexuals inherently underwent surgeries for sexual gratification. There was NO discussion of dysphoria whatsoever. If you argue that kink should be excluding from Pride, you're risking transphobic people (and yes, there are transphobic gay/lesbian/bi people as well) chasing transgender people out of Pride events in places that aren't as progressive. Unfortunately, there are also people that view ALL LGBT+ romance as kink. This just isn't a path we want to go down.  

If we want to say that certain things shouldn't be at Pride, we should be VERY specific about exactly what we don't want to be there. Saying that people shouldn't run around with erections is different from saying people should leave their chains at home. Be specific about what you don't want to see, and it's very likely that the responses you get will change.  

Point 3:    
Your argument seems to be about disgust and consent of seeing kink or BDSM (which again is undefined--arguing that there should be consent to see outfits is definitely different from consent of viewing actual sex acts), but I've got... quite some news for you about how people have responded to seeing LGBT+ people in public. 'Disgust' is on the top of the list when people roll down their windows to yell at trans people or same sex couples holding hands. It feels really ironic to try to ban something on the sole argument that said actions or attire gives you the same feeling that other people have historically felt about you--right down to 'think of the children!'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037717723.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>In regards to point 2, no BDSM is not at all unclear. It specifically refers to any form of bondage (preventing a person from moving) or sado-masochism (enjoying being hurt, or enjoying hurting another), which are both incredibly specific. 

However, I can get behind the vagueness of the term "kink", you made a fair argument there.

Though, I would argue that BDSM covers most kink that would be at pride that would be not ok.

In regards to point 3, I am not Op, but I would be curious how you would respond to a point about not showing LGBTQ+ children 'inappropriate' stuff. 

In particular, my mother did not allow me to go to pride until I was 18. She did so because she did not want me to be exposed to the 'inappropriate' part of pride. She was quite accepting of my being trans and supported me through a lot of my struggles and fought to get me hormones when my father said "no", so I don't believe she was rainbowphobic in any capacity. I did not go to pride until I was 18, but I imagine that kind of a space would've been helpful for teenage me.

Air quotes on "inappropriate" because the term is somewhat vacuous, but its definition is not the important part of the response to point 3.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037899378.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Does BDSM refer to only the acts or does BDSM refer to attire as well? Dog collars? How do you know if someone's wearing a dog collar because they're displaying BDSM or if they're just into emo wear? Is consensual authority for non-sex acts deemed as BDSM or does it get a pass? How do you KNOW if someone's participating in consensual authority? Even the phrases 'go have fun' and 'meet me back here in half an hour' could fall in to this. Not allowing BDSM in Pride is absolutely unclear to me.   

Where I grew up two people of the same sex having a romantic relationship was deemed as inappropriate and something I needed to be shielded from until I was an adult. There is no part of Pride that people would have deemed appropriate for me. Appropriate vs inappropriate is, just like the word kink, too vague to be useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037913238.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>Right, hence the last sentence. My point was less about the vacuousness of the words “appropriate” and “inappropriate”, and more about the fact that many young people whose parents aren’t homophobic won’t be allowed to attend pride because of the NSFW stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037969780.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Then let's explicitly state what we don't want to see. Point 2.    


I also don't think that convincing adults to let their children attend every non-age-specific Pride event is a priority. Not having my rights stripped away by the 82 bills introduced to legislatures this year is. I will always support people holding more Pride events. Ones geared for middle school kids. Ones geared for teens. Ones geared for children of trans people. Ones geared for grandparents. ~~Ones geared for companies to show how much swag they can put rainbows on.~~ But I'm not convinced that every generic Pride gathering should default to pandering to parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038010826.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>Right, I agree. But again, my response to point 3 was not related to this. I was making a point about children needing to but not being allowed to attend Pride because of such issues. The specific definitions do not matter in that part of the argument. Anyways.

I’m not quite sure why you brought up the 82 bills introduced this year.

Like yes, those are a problem, and pride is a place to protest those bills. But you’re making it out to be as if protesting rainbowphobic bills and SFW-pride are a dichotomy, when they’re very clearly not.

I just don’t understand why you’re ok with creating &amp;lt;18 Pride, but not NSFW Pride. 

Moreover, isn’t it that any general Pride should be welcoming to all LGBTQ+ people and allies? So why not make it SFW so that LGBTQ+ children can attend?

Also that’s a hilarious joke about corporations. Too fucking accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038064906.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>I brought up the 82 bills this year because the current momentum is not in favor of rights, for my part of the acronym at least. I do want to celebrate, but currently there is more reason to protest than to celebrate. I... personally do think that protests are not great to take minors to. The first Pride is famous for brick throwing. Recent protests that have happened in the US have gotten thousands of people tear gassed (especially in my location), even when peaceful. This is definitely a sidepoint, and ultimately I'm not a parent, so if people feel safe bringing their kids when they know they might be tear gassed that's not my business, I guess.

And all that said, the thing about 'NSFW' stuff is that minors aren't forbidden from these events. NSFW and 'no minors'/'being welcoming to all' are also not a dichotomy. Parents are allowed to buy their kids NSFW video games and take them to NSFW movies. Kids are allowed to walk around in public--the very same public that BDSM attire, kink wear, and topless women are allowed to exist in. There's no reason that we allow minors and these things to mix legally and then say that they can't mix during June. If it IS an issue, it needs to be dealt with OUTSIDE the context of Pride.

And again, I'm not against the community/organizers making -explicit- rules about what can and can't be done at Pride. These rules may result in a situation that's SFW but also allows people to wear dog collars and determines that casual naked boobs aren't kink or BDSM, but pants must be worn. That's the point of point 2, and I think that IS related to this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37037985521.0" user="Xros90" delta="False">
    <text>BDSM wear or talk that is vague and inoffensive to the casual observer isn't really the point here is it? Like, a collar or choker isn't anything wildly inappropriate or saying phrases. I think this discussion should be about articles of BDSM wear that are obviously identified as BDSM wear by the general public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038012341.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>The original point was 'no kink or BDSM'. The casual observer isn't taken into consideration. Additionally, the queer community should not be expected to have to put in the mental energy of 'I know that this is LEGAL to wear, but will people that view things in a way that I don't have a sense of be able to determine that this is BDSM?'  

Why should queer/kink/BDSM people be expected to not wear things that are legal to have on in public?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038071192.0" user="Xros90" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re changing the view by making *them acknowledge some kinks or BDSM are impossible to even think about restricting. This sub accepts that, so that makes sense (though I don’t really see how that really does anything for anybody, since it’s more like a loophole in *their wording than anything).

OP has changed *their view elsewhere in the thread to having a problem with purposeful public indecency instead of kinks or nudity. What is indecent is a direct representation of public perception and social expectations. Everyone, not just the LGBTQ+ community, is expected to know what constitutes public indecency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038090497.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Public indecency is an entirely different consideration from the concept of kink and BDSM. I hope more people can realize that, because I think that's a lot of where this discourse is coming from, when reality random people running around totally naked or being provocative isn't kink or BDSM at all, and 1) saying no kink/BDSM is misdirected and 2) is reinforcing even more stigma even in situations that those communities have nothing to do with what's being discussed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038106868.0" user="Xros90" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP realized that and that is why they have changed their view on that end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038168044.0" user="Brother_Anarchy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this discussion should be about articles of BDSM wear that are obviously identified as BDSM wear by the general public. 

So what, no showing up strapped to a Saint Andrew's Cross?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038191265.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>well played lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038300796.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038300817.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Xros90 – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038515544.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>totally fine if you’re fully clothed lmaoo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038493397.0" user="r1veRRR" delta="False">
    <text>A big part of the problem to people is of kids seeing these things. But does the average child viewer know jack shit about BDSM? To them, leather, harnesses, chains are all just funny clothes or toys.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37048263425.0" user="CocoSavege" delta="False">
    <text>Thinking out loud here, and very much not an expert...

There's lots of sexual cosplay which can be interpreted as bdsm.  It can get confusing too! 

Eg In the parade there will be a priest/pastor/faith leader.  Now it's entirely possible that said person is in fact a faith leader and is displaying solidarity.  But there's also a priest roleplay thing which can have overtones of bsdm, as it could represent an imbalance of power.  Some sort of priest altar boy kink shit.  There's no ropes or restraints but very much the power dynamics of church.  

(Side note - priest cosplay feels super creepy to me.  I don't like normalization of that shit.  See also "sexy catholic school girl".  I would very much prefer that catholic school girls seek consensual relationships with age appropriate partners)

The nurse fetish feels a little bsdmy as well.  There can be dynamics with authority and helplessness.

Standard dom leather boy shit is so much less creepy imo even though Karen will clutch more pearls at the sight of mustachioed assless chaps bro but not blink an eye at some creeper playing hide the confessional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038028584.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>BDSM would refer to attire as well.

If someone can wear a regular choker, they can wear a dog collar. There is no significant distinction between a choker and a dog collar. 

This is a flawed question because your definition would mean that the Presidency or College is a BDSM act. This is a part of the flawed question. 

Can you elaborate please? Neither of those are used exclusively in sexual contexts and naturally do not apply. Either of those could be said by a parent to their child.

Moreover, the line is, if it looks approximately what you could wear into a Starbucks, it’s fine. If wearing it in a Starbucks would get you thrown out, it’s not. And no particular reason I chose Starbucks, just that it’s a clear enough situation that most North Americans/Europeans can understand clearly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038118779.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Oh my sweet summer child, BDSM is not just about sex. That's not flawed at all lol. (And that might be part of the problem: OP may be concerned about only sexual aspects, but by saying BDSM is actually shifting the focus on to things that weren't even on their mind.) Master/slave relationships (someone PLEASE swing in here if there's an updated term, this doesn't feel right at all but my quick searching hasn't resulting in any new terminology) are absolutely part of BDSM, and the contract can be held in normal life. 'Go have fun' and 'meet me back here in half an hour' would be COMMANDS that, if not carried out, would result in punishment. This is BDSM. That's what I mean--how on earth would you be able to tell if someone saying practically ANYTHING was said in a normal way or was being said as a command?

Starbucks is a private company. Why do their (or any private company's) standards apply to events held on public grounds, which already have a set of laws, if event organizers have not made more specific rules? Laws are their for a reason. Event organizers have the opportunity to explicitly prohibit certain action or attire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039944201.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but the punishments would not occur in public.

The reason I bring up Starbucks is because even though it is a private company, if you commanded your BDSM partner to get drinks, but Starbucks was out of the white mocha, you would not take a riding crop out in the middle of Starbucks and whip them with it.

And as well, a public decency law could be interpreted to ban a gimp suit.

Really what I want you to do here is understand I can’t possibly go through every single rule ever, especially since I’m not organizing a pride parade. But what I’m trying to do is convey an understanding of the kinds of rules and behaviors that would or would not be acceptable at a SFW pride.

Yes, the edge cases will always be vaguely defined, but no that doesn’t mean that we can’t have a mutual understanding for generally the kinds of actions in question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040613584.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>I think we're going to have difficulties reaching a mutual understanding right now. Where I live, the public space is not guaranteed to be SFW. As I stated in my original post, bare breasts are totally legal here, and not inherently considered public indecency. I never said that Pride should be SFW, and I also think that 'SFW' is an unreasonably broad term with lots of personal subjection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37063063075.0" user="zwagonburner" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't heard of a new term for Master/slave, but the people I know prefer that usually. :)

 Kudos for pointing out BDSM is way more than just being tied up and spanked. &amp;lt;3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038750222.0" user="MadMeow" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think its fair to compare LGBT+ which is something you did not consciously choose to nudity and oversexualisation which is entirely your choise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040294456.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand how that relates to my comment that you replied to. Can you explain more?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37045916978.0" user="MadMeow" delta="False">
    <text>I probably should've replied to your first comment. Being proud of who you are when you are LGBT+ can't be inappropriate even if some people think it is because it's your identity that you didn't choose, doesn't harm anyone and is something that is important to see for children and teens.

At the same time it's not appropriate to be overly sexual in public and its something that you have full control over if you do it or not.

Imo regular, in day pride should be child and teen friendly so that they can feel they are a part of it too. The sexual part of it still can be explored, but would be better suited at a more "adult" time and place.

Yes, kids can watch porn and what not but they do it out of their own will. But if an LGBT+ kid wants to be part of pride he is "forced" to see things he might not be rdy to see.

Idk I'm rambling a lot here, but I hope I could get my point across</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37047711303.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to redirect you to this comment because I think the conversation I was having with that user is really close to your comment (and if you look at the comment chain, the one before mentions Pride as a protest which is also important):    


https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv\_kink\_and\_bdsm\_should\_not\_be\_at\_public\_pride/h0leva0?utm\_source=share&amp;amp;utm\_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37044063495.0" user="Niboomy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; How do you know if someone's wearing a dog collar because they're displaying BDSM or if they're just into emo wear?

 Because they don't go with a "touch" of leather. If you see a dude basically naked but with leather straps and a dog leather mask you don't say "hey it's just his emo phase"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038201137.0" user="demalteb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; no BDSM is not at all unclear. It specifically refers to any form of bondage (preventing a person from moving) or sado-masochism (enjoying being hurt, or enjoying hurting another), which are both incredibly specific. 

[Bondage. Discipline. Dominance. Submission. Sadomasochism.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BDSM)

Believe me, you will not recognize it when my wife and I engage in play. In public, in consists of nothing but small gestures, like me fetching the drinks. But hoooly moly, if it isn't kinky af!

Erotic practices are notoriously hard to define, and hence to police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038202087.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[BDSM](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BDSM)** 
 
 &amp;gt;BDSM is a variety of often erotic practices or roleplaying involving bondage, discipline, dominance and submission, sadomasochism, and other related interpersonal dynamics. Given the wide range of practices, some of which may be engaged in by people who do not consider themselves to be practising BDSM, inclusion in the BDSM community or subculture often is said to depend on self-identification and shared experience. The term BDSM is first recorded in a Usenet post from 1991, and is interpreted as a combination of the abbreviations B/D (Bondage and Discipline), D/s (Dominance and submission), and S/M (Sadism and Masochism).
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | Credit: kittens_from_space)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038286694.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Good bot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039916179.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that those are actions that result in BDSM, but that are not BDSM themselves.

Telling someone to go get drinks is a normal and common action that when not followed in this specific case results in BDSM after the fact. Your partner would not take out a riding crop in public and whip you with it, but disobeying their commands in public means a BDSM action when you return.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038410342.0" user="chuckf91" delta="False">
    <text>If theres no bdsm allowed at pride then I dont want to see any crucifixes either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039917907.0" user="Autumn1eaves" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah sure</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038366803.0" user="teh_hasay" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re worried about conservatives conflating any kind of lgbt orientation with kink then why explicitly reinforce that connection? Seems contradictory to me personally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040973598.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>I think some conservatives always will conflate any sort of lgbt orientation with kink. As long as certain extremely religious niches exist, that will happen. I'm... annoyed about the lack of distinction, and very annoyed when my existence is viewed as disgusting, but my priority is that my rights are guaranteed and conservatives will respect my right to exist EVEN IF they see me as disgusting. If we were to achieve rights by only appearing in such a way that panders to conservative views, we really risk not actually having all of those rights anyway because our very existence is still being permitted based on the view of the non-marginalized community. We need to have rights based on our own existence, not based on our palatability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038690546.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of your objections can be resolved the same way: would *you* feel comfortable if a middle school student emulated what you're doing/wearing? If not then it crossed the line.

The point isn't that these things are inherently wrong, but that they alienate younger lgbtq people from the most public expression of their identity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039058242.0" user="next_right_thing" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't feel comfortable if a middle school student took a shot of tequila or kissed a middle aged man, but that doesn't mean me doing it "crosses a line" or alienates anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040268294.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>It would be illegal for a middle school kid to drink a shot of tequila in the United States. For them to drink a fun beverage that is legal for them to drink, would be perfectly fine. 
As far as kissing a middle-aged man that's also twisting the point. Kissing an appropriately aged partner in public is something many middle schoolers will do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040411753.0" user="next_right_thing" delta="False">
    <text>Your point is nonsensical, which I was attempting to point out to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040535135.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>This is also subjective and based on what an individual views as appropriate or not. Parents have drastically different opinions on what they consider to be okay or not. It also isn't helpful for some neurodivergent people or people raised in situations (be it abuse or just alternative lifestyles) to be able to determine if something is normal childhood behavior or not.

As a more minor point, it also undermines parent's abilities to teach their own kids what is kid appropriate or not--I wasn't allowed to emulate smoking, wasn't allowed to cuss, and wasn't allowed to emulate the high school cheer team's lewd moves, but wasn't prevented from being around these things. I imagine many of us have similar experiences to some extent or another.    


I think there's a really big issue if this isn't an issue if we give cishetero-normative activities that we don't want kids to emulate a pass but suddenly these things are a big issue in an LGBT+ space. That inherently points to an issue of how LGBT+ is being differently than the same issues occurring at, say, music festivals.

Now, I won't say it's an invalid argument if people want to clamp down on these things existing in ALL public spaces (not that I'd inherently agree, but I'd respect the basis of the argument), but those conversations need to be happing on a larger scale, NOT just about Pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040644075.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not asking for a universal standard where we draw a single line and say "this is the universal rule". I'm absolutely saying there's no way around it being subjective. So you, personally, before you go to pride, remind yourself that there are more and more children and teens coming to terms with their sexuality every day, and for many of them pride is their first and possibly only exposure to the community. If you do that and still feel comfortable with whatever actions you're taking or outfits you're wearing, then I think you'll probably be ok.

I think where that line is drawn will vary greatly, but the attempt at including the younger generation will overall be effective.

Edit: I'll also say that I *am* looking at pride differently than other gatherings simply because I believe reaching kids who are questioning their sexuality and showing them that they're normal people just like anyone else is critical. This whole CMV is based on a kid who has difficulty relating to the lgbtq community because of the perceptions they had from pride. That seems like something to, at the very least, be aware of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040730376.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone is still going to come to terms with their sexuality and genders regardless of an event. If anyone is repressing any part of their identity because they're traumatized by an event, they need professional help to realize that their identity is not tied to an event. Being LGBT+ does not mean you have to like the events at Pride, even if you're an adult. You can respect that Pride exists and not want to attend, or want to attend only events specifically created for certain audiences.

But Pride has been about liberation, as are so many protests. The goal of protests are not to make everyone in their community to feel comfortable, but the goal is that all may attend if they would like so that they can work to liberate their marginalized communities so \*even those that don't attend\* can have better lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041102787.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>I always saw pride as being a way for people to celebrate who they were. To accept their identity with others who went through similar struggles and come together in a place where they could be proud of who they were.

If you think it's ok to exclude the people who are likely at the peak of that struggle in favor of uninhibited expression, then I guess we just have very different ideas of what pride is meant to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041265368.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>(Also consider this amazing comment: [https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv\_kink\_and\_bdsm\_should\_not\_be\_at\_public\_pride/h0jh3la?utm\_source=share&amp;amp;utm\_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/h0jh3la?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3) )  


People choosing not to attend an event because they're afraid of seeing this is absolutely not the same as excluding people. I have always been welcomed to Pride with open arms, even when I was insecure and wasn't ready to go. Not a single person at Pride tried to stop me from attending.    


I will always advocate for a world in which we can celebrate who we are on any day, in any public space. I see Pride as a way of helping us get there (and hopefully becoming redundant when equality is truly reached), not as a meet up.    


I also advocate for there being a billion LGBT+ events both at Pride and all year round that focus on providing resources for different audiences. Some of these can absolutely be meet ups and general social hours. There's nothing wrong with that at all.    


If we still disagree, then that's that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041567867.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>That's a fair point. I do think it's easy to fall into the idea of pride as one singular event rather than a collection of many events. Where I am pride means you either drive to Atlanta, or you sort of mingle around downtown with people holding poster boards while you get honked at by people annoyed that traffic is being slightly disrupted. It's not an all month thing, it's maybe a weekend if you're lucky.

I suppose the better argument I would make if I took a step back is not that anything should be banned from pride, but that there should at least be some facet of it that is available to people of all ages.

That's not a thing around here, but if it's common in other places then that's very good news</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37041696092.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I suppose the better argument I would make if I took a step back is not that anything should be banned from pride, but that there should at least be some facet of it that is available to people of all ages.

This is absolutely what I'd like to see. I've gone from living in a city where 'Pride' was two tiny blocks of booths and everyone that attended had to get past a line of anti-LGBT+ hell and brimstone preachers/protestors to a place where there's a day long parade, simultaneous events in different parts of the city, a separate trans parade, and scattered smaller events all month long. (When there's not a looming pandemic, at least.) I really hope you can experience it one day, it definitely gives one a better sense of hope and confidence to see mass attendance and diversity/intersectionality.    


When there's only a small venue, it's absolutely a natural response to try to control the only thing that seems to be available. But really the answer is to try to expand and make more events for more audiences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039298952.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040256596.0" user="ISeeStorms" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you're not OP, so I inherently wasn't calling you phobic--this wasn't directed at you.    


If you think that this is me calling you phobic, you either believe that naked boobies are a problem only in the context of LGBT+ events, which is phobic, or you have a problem with trans people attending Pride, which is also phobic.    


If you don't have issues with either of those, then you're trying to feel victimized where you're not being victimized, and that's not my issue to deal with at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37062415695.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Enk1ndle – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Enk1ndle&amp;amp;message=Enk1ndle%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0k8pzc/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039372143.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37062425244.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>u/bauhaus_robot – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20bauhaus_robot&amp;amp;message=bauhaus_robot%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her%20post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0kaagf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/bauhaus_robot – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20bauhaus_robot&amp;amp;message=bauhaus_robot%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[his/her+post\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/-/h0kaagf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37044023935.0" user="Li-renn-pwel" delta="False">
    <text>You’re point about nudity is spot on. I have a Franco father and an Anglo mother and the line between what is nudity between the two sides of the family varies wildly. I think it’s incredibly unfair that women can’t be topless in the same spaces men can be. Personally, I wouldn’t do it but if someone else wants to I see no problem. There are many men with bigger chests that many women so it’s not even a shape thing. I think the thing that bugs me the most is the people who get bent out of shape with bra straps. Those parts don’t even touch the breast! They are literally no different than shirt straps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37049112026.0" user="LegOfLambda" delta="False">
    <text>This just seems like another iteration of "evil people have different lines than you do, and therefore drawing lines in general is wrong" which is not a valid argument.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
