<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37037600427.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>A huge chunk of the vanilla stuff I've seen at Pride has been overtly sexual too. Lots of nudity or near-nudity, lots of oiled-up bodies, lots of highly sexualized behaviour. 

You are never, *ever* going to mistake a pride parade for a bunch of mormons, are you?

So why does everyone turn into such terrible prudes as soon as kink gets involved? Oh my god, will someone please think of the children, for god's sake hide the leather from them, quick, get the (200) (topless) Dykes On Bikes out here instead!  

I don't see a problem with extending the concept to 'non-mainstream concepts of gender or sexuality', tbh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039373309.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>Because some people want to expose their children to LGBT culture? If you bring a kid to a pride parade like OP is talking about do you think they're going to think "Oh these are regular people who happen to like the same sex" or are they going to think "Oh being gay is just some sexual thing"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039427499.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how your comment relates. 

P1: various kink stuff at pride is overtly sexual  
P2: sexual stuff is nasty and bad and think of the children  
C: therefore, kink stuff should not be at pride.   

However: 

P1': various vanilla LGBT stuff at pride is overtly sexual  
P2': sexual stuff is nasty and bad and think of the children  
C': therefore, vanilla LGBT stuff should not be at pride.   

If you don't want C', you can't have C.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37039945628.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;various vanilla LGBT stuff at pride is overtly sexual

What? There are plenty of PG level stuff at pride events, a majority even.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040100924.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>Our experiences may differ. The Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras tends to be *super* raunchy in my experience. 

Which is fine, honestly. I thought the whole point was not having to hide or minimize or downplay anything - and in fact to play it up for a whole bunch of reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37040812268.0" user="Enk1ndle" delta="False">
    <text>It is fine, there's nothing wrong with 18+ pride events and I don't think anyone was interested in bringing their kids to expose them to LGBT culture there. The fact that it works it's way into basically every event is what OPs point is about.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
