<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1437482501.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nru8lh/cmv_kink_and_bdsm_should_not_be_at_public_pride/">
    <title>CMV: Kink and BDSM should not be at public pride events and should be kept for 18+ ones</title>
    <original_poster>akoudagawaismywaifu</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start, I am a lesbian. And I've been seeing recent controversy about this topic. 

Look, no denying that kink plays a big role in the creation of pride. It is a part of embracing sexuality and shouldn't be excluded from the community. 

However, it should not be at public pride parades. Pride should be for everyone of all ages. Many people say "stop catering to the straight capitalized ideal of what pride should be" and "pride isn't a party, it's a protest don't police us" and "children should go to disney if they want family friendly" This has nothing to do with straight rainbow capitalism. I figured out I was LGBT at age 11 and trust me if I saw a kink act in public I would be kind of disgusted. I'm still a minor now, and I'd be less disgusted but still. I know people say that it's up to you to bring your children to pride, but by making all pride events "wear whatever you want even if it's nothing" we are also kinda excluding minors from it. It's also non consensual to anyone who is exposed to such acts, because nobody wants to go to pride to see naked people right? The "think of the children" phrase holds true here. Young children and teens embracing their sexuality shouldn't be forced to see adult acts against their will. 

Again, no denying the role kink plays in the community, but it should be kept at 18+ events. There should definitely be a separate pride for people who just want to do leather and other kinks. That way, you can do whatever you want in a safe space where you know you won't offend others, and because people consented to come to an 18+ event, it's all good. 

That's just my personal opinion on it, but it seems to be the minority. I'd like to see how you guys think about this.

Edit: it appears after reading and responding to several comments, I don't really have a problem with kink, but more with public indecency. I don't care if you wear a collar or leather pants. But I'd rather not see things that could get you arrested or questioned for doing in public.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37038011736.0" user="awakeinny94" delta="False">
    <text>I think the shock value when it comes to pride events is exactly the point. The blatant nudity and the in-your-face-this-is-my-sex depictions, the kink and all of it is the point. I think this is because of what is being highlighted and what is at stake. Disgusting people gets their attention and therefore their recognition. The fact that gay and transgender people were murdered because of their sex should have been shocking to the world but it never was. Instead the community was forced underground and. Sex in general ( nudity, exhibitionism, kinks and fetishes ) disgust people because they are considered indecent and taboo. And that’s perfectly alright. Society demands decency, hence laws. But society also murders gay and transgender people because their sex does not lie between the lines it considers decent. So sex is the topic here and the displays of kink and nudity are part of its presentations. 

Maybe in a few hundred years no one will care about anyone’s sexuality and there will be no need to demand recognition and highlight one’s sex by going naked in public. 

A good example of nudity and indecency use was  when old women in Africa stripped naked so that innocent men who had been falsely imprisoned could be freed. They were led by Nobel Peace Laureate Wangari Maathai who helped save the trees.

PS: I’m not LGBT and I don’t have many LGBT friends so I have less information than you do about the community. I just think the reason the nudity and kink are in pride is the result of the hypocrisy that allowed a decent community to murder gay and transgender people for decades.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038065734.0" user="kkzhc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think the shock value when it comes to pride events is exactly the point. The blatant nudity and the in-your-face-this-is-my-sex depictions, the kink and all of it is the point. 

One of the prime reasons why the lgtbq community is ridiculed more than ever. People don't care who you have sex with. People just demand decency and it's not much to ask</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37038654755.0" user="blackgandalff" delta="False">
    <text>lmao it’s the same logic as dipshit teenagers yelling the N-word on xbox live.

If people get angry i’m doing something good! right? right???</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
