<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315628931.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. 

You are contradicting yourself here. I want my family, my friend and my girlfriend to live longer and I'm happy with it. That's majority of opinion.

&amp;gt; Instead of finding ways to prolong life

See above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315693275.0" user="ragdala" delta="False">
    <text>Say your wife was in bed dying.

A treatment would give her maybe an extra month. Would you give it to her?

A whole month, knowing that she'll die afterwards doesn't seem like a good idea. Just accept the fact that people die, and move on.

Otherwise, it would just seem selfish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315754865.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Why it's instantly all selfish?

This was your original statement. 

&amp;gt; Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable.

If my wife want to live just a month longer but to spend time with me and it's her pleasure, we are doing her favor by prolonging her life for a month.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
