<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27316025354.0" user="5510" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument would make more sense to me if it was some sort of Nihilistic "so lets all just kill ourselves."  I wouldn't agree, but it would make consistent sense.    
    
But you place value into making our current lives enjoyable and worth living.  If somebody finds life at least somewhat enjoyable / pleasurable, why not continue to do so for as long as possible, or with enough scientific breakthroughs, forever?  The only thing truly meaningless is death, because obvious there is no meaning in anything after your very existence is obliterated.    
     
I mean, imagine you were a tourist from an alternate world, where everybody lived forever and death didn't exist.  You visited our universe, and saw people grow old and frail and then stop existing.  Would you really be like, "wow, this is way better!"    
     
Here is a good quote from HPMOR about death:    
    
"Uh huh," Harry said. "See, there's this little thing called cognitive dissonance, or in plainer English, sour grapes. If people were hit on the heads with truncheons once a month, and no one could do anything about it, pretty soon there'd be all sorts of philosophers, pretending to be wise as you put it, who found all sorts of amazing benefits to being hit on the head with a truncheon once a month. Like, it makes you tougher, or it makes you happier on the days when you're not getting hit with a truncheon. But if you went up to someone who wasn't getting hit, and you asked them if they wanted to start, in exchange for those amazing benefits, they'd say no. And if you didn't have to die, if you came from somewhere that no one had ever even heard of death, and I suggested to you that it would be an amazing wonderful great idea for people to get wrinkled and old and eventually cease to exist, why, you'd have me hauled right off to a lunatic asylum! So why would anyone possibly think any thought so silly as that death is a good thing? Because you're afraid of it, because you don't really want to die, and that thought hurts so much inside you that you have to rationalize it away, do something to numb the pain, so you won't have to think about it -"    
    
....    
    
""Then look within the part of yourself that flees not from death but from the fear of death, that finds that fear so unbearable that it will embrace Death as a friend and cozen up to it, try to become one with the night so that it can think itself master of the abyss. "</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
