<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315580926.0" user="excultist" delta="False">
    <text>I am currently 62 years old, which is not remarkably old for the current society in which we live, although it is considerably older than the average lifespan for most of human history.  I do not feel that because I have lived my meaningless life for such a long time, I might as well die now.  I still have comments to post, before I die.  And generally, that is how people feel.  Even people who are 100 years old are not in a hurry to die.  Chances are, you too will want to continue to live, even when you are older.  There can be exceptions, of course.  I don't know if you have seen the movie "Harold And Maude" which I recommend, if you haven't seen it.  Maude is a character who has decided that she just wants to live to be 80 years old, and so on her 80th birthday, she kills herself, thereby causing considerable distress to her younger friend Harold, who loves her.  It's a fascinating and ironic movie.  Up until the time Maude actually kills herself, both Harold and Maude are death fetishists, they both love to attend funerals, they constantly contemplate their own death, they embrace death with enthusiasm, yet when the time comes for Maude to actually die, Harold discovers that death is not all that it's cracked up to be, after all.  You may make a similar discovery, some day.

That said, I will at least partially agree with you; people can be overly obsessed with prolonging their lives.  I am, for example, not a believer in the value of having yourself frozen at death, in the hope of being eventually thawed out and then brought back to life by some advanced medical technology which you hope will eventually be invented.  I think that's going too far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315667867.0" user="ragdala" delta="False">
    <text>I like the idea of that movie.

I'll look it up</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
