<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315450603.0" user="notevenapro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable.

How about we do both. 

Health care is not so much about prolonging life as it is about ending suffering. Most life ending disease processes are painful, so curing these processes ends pain. Pain cessation is primary over extending life. The extension of life is a by product of relieving the pain. 

&amp;gt;Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning

This varies from person to person. We all connect to other people throughout the day in same way or another.Some of us have more of an impact on society than others, in both positive and negative forms. 

The things we do as we go through life make other people happy,sad or indifferent. Making a change in someones emotion has meaning, it has meaning to the person whose emotional state was changed. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315570950.0" user="Melancholicdrunk" delta="False">
    <text>I sort of disagree a tiny bit with your saying that the extension of relieving pain is prolonging life and that most healthcare is about ending suffering.

Ok, now I've typed that I see it's wrong but I can't think of a better way to put it. I was just going to mention that a lot of end of life health care does seem to be about prolonging life. Chemotherapy for example. Makes total sense for someone my age, but when it's offered (and in my experience, pressure is put on) to elderly people (such as my grandparents), it extends their life by maybe two years, but a lot of that time is spent sick from the chemo. I think a lot of health care when it comes to elderly people is like this. Is the cure worse than the disease? I think for my gran it might have been less traumatic to just have strong painkillers and be well when she dies. As it was it was dragged out so she suffered, and everyone else had to watch that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315626965.0" user="notevenapro" delta="False">
    <text>I work with cancer patients. Some cancer pain cannot be controlled with pain killers unless you give them enough to make them comatose. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315635835.0" user="Melancholicdrunk" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I didn't mean that. I didn't explain well. What I meant was that I thought the chemo was misjudged. Yes, it's a painful death either way. Just it lasted longer with chemo. In that one situation. I wasn't trying to say for everyone, just I think there can be issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
