<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315490250.0" user="jetpacksforall" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.  

&amp;gt;Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.  

We already spend a vastly larger share of resources on enjoying simple pleasures than we do on immortality or extending life. For example, the budget for the SENS Foundation ([Strategies for Engineered Negligible Senescence](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SENS_Research_Foundation)), one of the largest American nonprofit foundations that pump money into life extension research, is about $4 million per year. 

On the other hand, the [global tourism industry](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tourism) accounts for around $1.03 *trillion* per year. The [US/Canada film industry takes in $10.9 billion](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Film_industry) per year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27316012153.0" user="5510" delta="False">
    <text>It pisses me off to no end every single day that those numbers aren't reversed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
