<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315449742.0" user="jayjay091" delta="False">
    <text>If you were diagnosed with cancer today, and a cure existed, would you use it or not?

If a friend/family died, wouldn't you be sad? Wouldn't you prefer if that person was alive?

If life is meaningless, everything is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315667403.0" user="ragdala" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you were diagnosed with cancer today, and a cure existed, would you use it or not?

Personally, no. If i were to die, i will accept it as fact. I will try to make the best of what time i got, and when i reach a point that i can't even do that, I'll end it myself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315700043.0" user="jayjay091" delta="False">
    <text>yeah.. I don't believe you.

If a doctor tell you that you are going to die tomorrow, and the only thing you have to do is take a pill and you'll be fine, you won't take the pill? No cost, no pain, no whatever. Just a small pill, 1 time, and you'll live 60 more years.

Everyone value his life enough to take the pill.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315830851.0" user="cdubose" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Everyone value[s] his life enough to take the pill.

Not necessarily. People who are depressed, suicidal, or paranoid may not take the pill. Someone who thinks they may die soon anyway (e.g., someone who is 90 years old) may not take the pill. Someone who believes the cancer is his own fault (e.g., a smoker with lung cancer) may not take the pill, out of guilt or a sense of punishment perhaps. Someone with health anxiety or a fear of doctors/hospitals may not take the pill. The list could go on and on.

Besides, why don't you believe the OP? It seems weird to a ask a question of him/her but to not believe his/her answer. They very well may not take the pill in that situation, particularly if they are at peace with the idea of death and dying.

A better question would be: the doctor says there is no cure for your cancer, but it will take a long time for the cancer to kill you, and you will be in pain the whole time. Or, if you prefer, there is this pill. It will put you in a coma state, so you would technically be alive and the pain will go away. But you'll be in a coma for the rest of your life, so in effect you would experience it as if you were to die. Would to take the pill to induce the coma but escape the pain, or deal with the pain of cancer for the rest of your life?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315852575.0" user="jayjay091" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, I should have been more precise. Obviously if you are suicidal or if you don't believe the pill will work it doesn't apply.

&amp;gt; Besides, why don't you believe the OP? It seems weird a ask a question of him/her but to not believe his/her answer. They very well may not take the pill in that situation.

I just wanted to be sure he didn't misinterpreted the first question. Somewhere else in this thread he said something conflicting with his response : "You have the flu, by all meams take some medicine for it. Cancer? Go treat it if you can."







</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315858736.0" user="cdubose" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. It think this would be easier if there was a clear distinction between prolonging life and making it more pleasurable. I was thinking cancer treatment falls strictly under prolonging life (especially considering that most of the treatments we have for cancer are pretty brutal in and of themselves), but I guess it could also be interpreted as making life more pleasurable depending on how you treat it, especially if you are going to die around the same time anyway. Hence, in my question it forces the OP to choose between prolonging (conscious) life (not taking the coma pill) or making life more pleasurable (taking the coma pill). If life is really meaningless, then the more logical choice would be to take the coma pill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315902503.0" user="jayjay091" delta="False">
    <text>well, I said "cure" in my first question, not treatment. It's why I switched to a pill after, to prevent any misunderstanding.

But, anyway, my guess is that OP's view is more like : "There is a point where it is useless to prolong life" or "You shouldn't try to prolong life no matter what"

And not (what he wrote) : "trying to prolong life is absolutely useless".

The last quote would mean that it is **always** useless to prolong life. No matter the age, no matter the situation, no matter the type of injuries/diseases. Hence why I asked the question of the pill.

If you were young, healthy, not suicidal or anything, but randomly catch a disease that will kill you in 24 hours unless you take a pill. Would you take the pill? If you agree to take the pill you are prolonging your life, and it goes against what OP is saying. 

I don't think many people would choose to not take the pill.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
