<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315513236.0" user="schwagle" delta="False">
    <text>So what about all the medical advances that have been made in the past 100 years that have extended all of our lifetimes by a significant amount, or otherwise increased our quality of life? Polio was all but wiped out by the invention of a vaccine for it. We've also found ways to manage influenza, hepatitis, tuberculosis, even cancer to a certain extent. I'm sure there's others that I haven't listed as well. The effects of these afflictions if left untreated range from inconvenient to life-threatening, but regardless, they all negatively affect your quality of life; your "pursuit of pleasure", if you will. If you're bed-ridden for two weeks because you have the flu, I'd say your options for pursuing pleasure become pretty limited. 

But some nice scientists took the time to research these diseases and figure out how to cure/mitigate them. Instead of dying of tuberculosis or some other disease at age 30, you're free to live your life and pursue all the pleasure you want until you die of old age. This wouldn't be possible if scientists hadn't invested time and money into researching how to cure these diseases.

As a result of vaccinations and various medical treatments, overall quality of life has gone up worldwide. And everything I've listed has all been in the past 100 years or so. With the rate that science and technology is advancing, imagine how much more progress could be made in the next 100 years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315578210.0" user="Melancholicdrunk" delta="False">
    <text>I can't honestly say I know what the op was thinking. But I read it not as "curing things that cut life short is pointless" but as "extending life as much as possible is pointless". Like, not that if your baby gets meningitis "oh well, it was time", more as, if we're already living to our nineties, is there a huge amount of worth to making that our hundreds? (through artificial means, not just through stopping us getting flu. Does that make any sense?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315689982.0" user="ragdala" delta="False">
    <text>That's what i am saying.

You should try to enjoy your life. But actively pursuing to prolonging it is useless.

You have the flu, by all meams take some medicine for it. Cancer? Go treat it if you can. But when that cancer has progressed so far that your doom is all but inevitable, why prolong it as much as possible?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
