<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321280365.0" user="BraveryKid" delta="False">
    <text>Ragdala hopefully this isn't getting too personal, but from your point of view I'm  assuming you are late teens or early twenties, and you also probably don't have any children. Late teens and early twenties is when school tells you over and over again by liberalistic psychopaths that you are only now and will die and turn to dust. In turn that makes a huge impression on the young society, they are educated in a way that tells them there is nothing after life. I would tell you one thing that really helped me after school and this liberally sick stance, DO YOUR OWN RESEARCH. I'm not religious but I'm also not brainwashed into thinking the evolution of the universe is so cut and dry as your college textbooks make you believe. If that's your opinion that's fine, an opinion such as yours right now is hard to overcome because it's an extreme idea but I feel there's a deeper though process you could get to by simply looking into "evolutionary fact" try searching for JoeCoder here on reddit, he's an old earth creationist that only uses science not as proof of god but to help get the word out that evolution is not so one sided as you might think. I'm not personally decided if I believe in an afterlife but knowing that the possibility something after life may be real is enough for me. I'm worried about you because I used to be you. Message me if you are curious to learn more about these things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
