<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="143818034.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dmipe/cmv_life_is_meaningless_and_theres_no_point_to/">
    <title>CMV: Life is meaningless, and there's no point to trying to prolong it as much as possible.</title>
    <original_poster>ragdala</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whatever we do, ultimately, has no meaning. In the grand scheme of things, we are but a tiny speck of dust on a meaningless planet.

That's why i say that trying to prolong life is absolutely useless. This includes tries to reanimate dying people, trying to find a special formula for immortality, and similar medical/engineering advances.

Instead of finding ways to prolong life, we could better spend resources to make the life we've got more pleasurable. This would be a much better way to spend our time and resources, by actively trying to become a better and happier society, where death is just part of the cycle, with no taboos attached to it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27315475482.0" user="Unconfidence" delta="False">
    <text>Meaning is a human construct.

Humans are part of life.

Therefore life has meaning.  More accurately, life *creates* meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315654110.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Taste is a human sense

Humans are a part of life

There life has taste. More accurately, hamburgers.


Let me explain. If I think therefore it am, and a dog technically doesn't "think" since it lacks ToM (theory of mind), then a dog doesn't actually exist. If a dog doesn't exist then a hot dog doesn't exist which has no taste. Ergo, taste does not actually exist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27315671263.0" user="LaoTzusGymShoes" delta="False">
    <text>Dat misapplied Cogito tho.  

Descartes indicates, in the Cogito, that he knows that, even if a demon is deceiving him about everything, he must exist to be deceived, in some form or other.  He might just be a brain in a vat, but there must be an "I" that is being deceived.  It's not that only things which think exist, rather, it's that my thinking is proof, to me, that at the least I exist.  If only thinking things existed, things like rocks, computers, numbers, and my shoes wouldn't exist, but I have strong reason to believe that they do.

Plus dogs totally think, I remember watching mine try to figure out where the ball went when I pretended to throw it.  

I realize this may be a joke post, but I'm not really awake yet, idgaf.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27316376341.0" user="Unconfidence" delta="False">
    <text>Your syllogism is correct.  Life does have taste.  Mmm, burgers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27316653160.0" user="Field-K" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I think therefore it am, and a dog technically doesn't "think" since it lacks ToM (theory of mind), then a dog doesn't actually exist. If a dog doesn't exist then a hot dog doesn't exist which has no taste. Ergo, taste does not actually exist

Actually, this is a common logical fallacy. "if A then B" is not equivalent to "if B then A" or "if not(A) then not(B)". "I think therefore I am" is a proposition of the form "If A then B" where A="I think" and B= "I am". But your statement "dog doesn't think therefore is not" takes the form "if not(A) then not(B)" for A="dog thinks" and B="dog is".

It is completely possible for "if A then B" to be true while "if not(A) then not(B)" is false. A (fairly trivial) example would be letting A="I am human" and B="I have DNA".

"If you are human, then you have DNA" is true, but

"If you are not human, then you don't have DNA" is not.

[Here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Converse_accident) is the wikipedia page on it, but its kinda wordy and I don't like the explanation.

I prefer looking at it from the perspective of Logic and Mathematics. [Here](http://www.algebra.com/algebra/homework/Conjunction/THEO-2011-08-22-03.lesson) is one I like, which explains itself rather well.

P.S. I used a hodge-podge of English and Symbolic notation from propositional logic. I was unsure if you were familiar with the latter, so I felt using less symbols would be clearer.

Edit: whoops mixed some words up</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
