<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321428766.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after.

Shoplifting is "something minor" and that's why people are upset. This video's implication is that Brown was a criminal, so why are people upset that he's dead? But he shoplifted, that's it. Lots of people shoplift and aren't shot to death over it. Brown bring a criminal does not excuse the manner of his death.

&amp;gt; I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.

In what way should they acknowledge that he had just committed a crime? Should the family to on record and say, "it's not as bad that Brown was killed because after all he had just been shoplifting some cigars."?

&amp;gt; The police officer **may** not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior **might** have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter

If the officer didn't know what Brown had just done, why was he stopped? Notice how you use the words "may" and "might" but also talk about how "this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind..."? You're just guessing that committing a crime made him "more on-edge, scared, and impulsive" and caused "mannerisms/behavior" that "alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter." If this video was really providing you with such insight, you wouldn't be guessing anymore.

Anyway, even if Brown's mannerisms and behavior did escalate the situation - did they escalate it to the point that Officer Wilson was justified in shooting him? That's the only question here, his prior actions are moot unless they were violent or threatening others considering the results of the altercation.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321453091.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This video's implication is that Brown was a criminal, so why are people upset that he's dead? But he shoplifted, that's it. Lots of people shoplift and aren't shot to death over it. Brown bring a criminal does not excuse the manner of his death.

I don't think there is an implication behind the video. I'm not saying shoplifters should be shot either. I'm saying that having just committed a crime, albeit a minor one, he must have been quite scared to see a police officer and this would have affected his behavior. This is important and highly relevant information that needed to be released. Had they just said, "michael brown is a suspect in a robbery," there would have been an even greater outcry of anger since there would be no supporting evidence.

&amp;gt; In what way should they acknowledge that he had just committed a crime? Should the family to on record and say, "it's not as bad that Brown was killed because after all he had just been shoplifting some cigars."?

Ok, my view is that the family and many protestors have simplified the incident down to "white cop shoots unarmed black teen." However, this footage reveals a far more complex situation. It cannot be boiled down to white cop executes black teen. 

&amp;gt; If the officer didn't know what Brown had just done, why was he stopped?

He was stopped initially because he was walking down the street with his friend and ordered to move onto the sidewalk. I believe that when he didn't comply, Officer Wilson began to pay more attention to him and then noticed the box of stolen cigars. This realisation ultimately escalated the situation and Wilson's subsequent use of excessive force.

&amp;gt;Anyway, even if Brown's mannerisms and behavior did escalate the situation - did they escalate it to the point that Officer Wilson was justified in shooting him? 

Once again, I **never ever ever** said that Wilson was justified in shooting him at all. My entire post was dedicated to the fact that the release of the footage is important to the public and the investigation to reveal a more nuanced case versus white cop versus black civilian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321462740.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think there is an implication behind the video. I'm not saying shoplifters should be shot either. I'm saying that having just committed a crime, albeit a minor one, he must have been quite scared to see a police officer and this would have affected his behavior. This is important and highly relevant information that needed to be released. Had they just said, "michael brown is a suspect in a robbery," there would have been an even greater outcry of anger since there would be no supporting evidence.

You're saying, "he must have been..." as though it's a fact established by the video. But the video only establishes that he committed a crime, not his behavior prior to being shot. You're making a leap from, "he committed a crime" to "and it caused him to act in such and such manner."

&amp;gt; Ok, my view is that the family and many protestors have simplified the incident down to "white cop shoots unarmed black teen." However, this footage reveals a far more complex situation. It cannot be boiled down to white cop executes black teen.

The footage does not reveal a far more complex situation. Brown was an unarmed black teen, he was shot by a white cop. The fact that he had just committed a crime has no bearing on the shooting.

&amp;gt; He was stopped initially because he was walking down the street with his friend and ordered to move onto the sidewalk. I believe that when he didn't comply, Officer Wilson began to pay more attention to him and then noticed the box of stolen cigars. This realisation ultimately escalated the situation and Wilson's subsequent use of excessive force.

Look at your logical reasoning here. He was stopped, then *you believe* some actions took place that escalated the situation. You're providing nothing but conjecture , so the video can't have been that enlightening. You're making an assumption.

&amp;gt; Once again, I never ever ever said that Wilson was justified in shooting him at all. My entire post was dedicated to the fact that the release of the footage is important to the public and the investigation to reveal a more nuanced case versus white cop versus black civilian.

But it is a white cop verses an unarmed black civilian. Or are shoplifters not civilians?

Maybe I'm missing something here but to me it looks like you're saying the fact that Brown was a criminal was what caused his actions, whatever they were, that lead to his death. But if the use of force was unjustified and excessive, then the cause of those actions isn't important is it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321486708.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're making a leap from, "he committed a crime" to "and it caused him to act in such and such manner."

I don't think that its a leap to say that his fear of being caught for the crime he just committed affected his behavior. 

&amp;gt; The footage does not reveal a far more complex situation. Brown was an unarmed black teen, he was shot by a white cop. The fact that he had just committed a crime has no bearing on the shooting.

Yes, he was an unarmed black teen. But in watching the video, you can see how he easily manhandled someone as he was 6 foot 4 and 292 pounds. The footage reveals a more complex situation because prior to the release of the footage, he was portrayed as never getting into fights and being a model kid. It does NOT justify his shooting, but I believe it helps explain the events that led up to and during the shooting.

&amp;gt;Maybe I'm missing something here but to me it looks like you're saying the fact that Brown was a criminal was what caused his actions, whatever they were, that lead to his death

I'm saying the fact that Brown was a criminal does not mean he deserved to be shot. But I'm surprised anyone can argue that his having just committed a crime would not have changed his behavior that would have led the officer to perceive him as more of a threat. This subsequently escalated tensions and the altercation as a whole. 

&amp;gt; But if the use of force was unjustified and excessive, then the cause of those actions isn't important is it? 

What? In looking at the vast majority of legal cases, you cannot rely solely on the evidence of actions, but of motive and context as well. An American town is on fire and the country is up in arms around this case because a white police officer put 6 rounds into a black teen and the cause doesn't matter?? You might be able to change my view on the department's release of the CCTV footage, but you won't change my view on the idea that motive is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321494744.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think that its a leap to say that his fear of being caught for the crime he just committed affected his behavior.

It is literally a leap, you have some evidence he committed a crime, but you're ascribing behavior based on... What? Personal experience? Conjecture?

&amp;gt; Yes, he was an unarmed black teen. But in watching the video, you can see how he easily manhandled someone as he was 6 foot 4 and 292 pounds. The footage reveals a more complex situation because prior to the release of the footage, he was portrayed as never getting into fights and being a model kid. It does NOT justify his shooting, but I believe it helps explain the events that led up to and during the shooting.

So if none if these facts justify the shooting - how are they relevant exactly? The shooting itself is what's being discussed here.

&amp;gt; I'm saying the fact that Brown was a criminal does not mean he deserved to be shot. But I'm surprised anyone can argue that his having just committed a crime would not have changed his behavior that would have led the officer to perceive him as more of a threat. This subsequently escalated tensions and the altercation as a whole.

Again, if the officer's reaction was not justified by the actions - is the reason he was acting that way really relevant?

&amp;gt; What? In looking at the vast majority of legal cases, you cannot rely solely on the evidence of actions, but of motive and context as well. An American town is on fire and the country is up in arms around this case because a white police officer put 6 rounds into a black teen and the cause doesn't matter?? You might be able to change my view on the department's release of the CCTV footage, but you won't change my view on the idea that motive is irrelevant.

The motive of *whom*? Because the officer's motive is what we're trying to establish here - and as you've said over and over again Brown's actions do not justify his death. 

"Acting suspiciously" or whatever behavior you're ascribing to Brown is not justification for the officer's actions. Therefore, people being up in arms is understandable and warranted. Releasing a video that seemingly changes Brown's behavior is irrelevant *unless that behavior was life threatening*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321655280.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think that its a leap to say that his fear of being caught for the crime he just committed affected his behavior. 

It is a giant leap to assume, as you are, that he became violent as a result.

If he was afraid of being caught why wouldn't he try to get the police officer to move on by simply moving to the sidewalk?

Your response -- he was a criminal so he probably did something that caused his death -- is exactly why so many people are angry that police released the shoplifting video.  The video provides no new information, but it has triggered assumptions and stereotypes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321715345.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that his behavior was to immediately assault the officer. I believe that he was understandably nervous of getting caught and that behavior made the officer more aggressive/suspicious which escalated the conflict to the shooting incident it became. 

Look, it's a giant leap for you to assume that the course of action when one is afraid of being caught is to simply comply. Fight or flight responses are not based on concrete actions. We each have our own assumptions. I still don't believe that it's a leap to assume that being confronted by a cop even for an unrelated matter is frightening especially after one just committed a crime. Most people get nervous for no reason when a cop is even around them.

I have written this multiple times throughout the post and I'm sorry if it seems to you that my logic is that 
&amp;gt; "he was a criminal so he probably did something that caused his death."

The fact of the matter is it's NOT my train of thought. This is my logic: 

MB committed a crime. MB gets confronted by a cop. MB acts nervous/scared and when the officer becomes more aggressive, both parties escalate. Officer uses excessive force and results in the death of MB.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321817697.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>You are contradicting yourself when you can't say that you don't believe "he was a criminal so he probably did something that caused his death" but *assume* "MB acts nervous/scared and when the officer becomes more aggressive, **both parties escalate.**"

You are assuming that because he was a criminal he probably made the confrontation worse. You are justifying that with the logic that he was probably nervous because he had just committed a crime.

Lets look at the facts:  An officer confronts a civilian for walking on the sidewalk. The officer shoots and kills the civilian.

The officer has *said* that the civilian attacked him, but other witnesses contradict that statement.  You say you believe the officer used excessive force, but you seem to believe the officer's claim that MB is partially to blame for his own death, even though there isn't much evidence to support that claim.

Releasing the video is a clear attempt to bias people to believe without evidence, as you do, that MB was responsible for escalating the situation.  Even if that wasn't the deliberate goal, that has been the outcome.  Here's the most important point: the video does nothing to help us *actually* figure out who initiated violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321847081.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Two points:

- the civilian is walking away from a crime scene where he acted aggressively, intimidated a shopowner, and robbed their store.

- It isn't a fact that he was walking on the sidewalk since the officer has said that he was walking on the street which is what initially caused the confrontation.


These are the simple facts:
Officer confronts civilian walking away from robbery. Civilian and Officer get into altercation. Officer shoots and kills civilian. 

I think there is evidence to support the claim that MB got into an altercation with the police and is partially to blame when moments before he got into an altercation with a shopkeeper he robbed.

You're absolutely right, the video doesn't help who threw the first punch, but I believe it shows a more nuanced perspective of the set of events that transpired immediately after.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321856557.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>Oops, that was a typo. I meant to write that the officer confronts a civilian for walking on the street.

You are allowed to believe that, but here's the thing: an officer killed a guy for walking on the street.  That is a horrible outcome to that confrontation.  Regardless of what MB did, the officer should not have let that confrontation become lethal.  The video is a distraction, because it makes people like you think that because MB stole something it is more reasonable to expect that he'd end up in a lethal confrontation--when the real question we should be asking is why the fuck the officer ended up killing someone for walking on the street.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321876685.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's far too simplistic though to say that the officer gunned someone down for walking down the street. I really don't think that the officer shot him for that reason and that he was black. Maybe it's just me, but that seems very narrow-minded. I find it far more plausible that the two got into a physical altercation which the officer may have very well provoked by being belligerent. When MB, being the size that he is, and the officer began physically fighting, the officer pulled a gun and fired initially in self-defence (shots to the arm), but went too far and ended up using excessive force to kill MB (shots to the head).

Also, the officer can only do so much to prevent a confrontation from being lethal. The officer is facing someone who is very physically imposing. 6 foot 4 and 292 pounds is a lot of mass to be fighting and MB was reported by the coroner to be completely healthy. So he isn't a fat slob and he's that large. 

The video is not a distraction because it shows MB getting into a violent confrontation moments before getting into another with a cop. It's not unrelated, especially since it happened only minutes before. Anything that occurs in the minutes leading up to a murder/killing/any violent crime is important and I believe this video is an important thing to consider during this investigation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321918108.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>NOBODY is saying investigators shouldn't look at the video. We are talking about whether the video should have been released to the public. Apparently it is an effective character assassination, because instead of looking at the actions of the officer and trying to figure out why he ended up killing a guy he stopped for walking on the street, you are assuming that the victim was to blame for the confrontation.  It has effectively placated people like you who figure that if there is a hint of evidence that MB might have been a violent person, the officer probably had some reason for shooting him, and we shouldn't worry too much about having a detailed investigation to figure out why an officer ended up killing a guy he stopped for walking in the street.

You are letting guesses and assumptions determine your view instead of insisting that the investigation find evidence of what actually happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322163494.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Why am I not allowed to make conjectures as to what happened in those events? You are when you assume that the cop is entirely to blame as well? 

If you want, you can make a post specifically looking at the actions of the officer. This post is very much centered around the release of footage and I was hoping to have a focused discussion about that. If you make a CMV post that looks at the actions of the officer, I'm sure you'd get a more focused debate.

First, don't be so patronizing and say "placate people like me." It's pretty rude and doesn't really look at the questions posed. Additionally, it isn't just "a hint" of evidence. It wasn't like he punched someone in sixth grade. He robbed someone minutes before he got into an altercation with a cop that turned fatal. The video is important because it provides the public with more information. My entire argument throughout has been that the more information the public has, the better informed they will be. Information in a case like this cannot be restricted to the investigators while the public is blindly accusing each other of racism and believing this to be a cut and dry case of white on black crime. 

In short: It's not that simple. It's a mistake to think that way. There is more to this case and this video helps the public understand the events that transpired. Yes, it removes MB from the pedestal he was previously on, but that's not character assassination. I still don't believe that this footage justifies his death in any way. But it may help explain how this altercation started and escalated. And THAT'S why it's important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322244656.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But it may help explain how this altercation started and escalated. And THAT'S why it's important.

But it *doesn't*!  It doesn't give us *any* idea of how to better train officers to avoid situations like this.  It *doesn't* show us who was at fault.  (I do not assume the cop is to blame, though given the cop is in a position of power I think the investigation needs to focus on him--particularly since, if it was the victim's fault, no further action is needed.)

&amp;gt; Additionally, it isn't just "a hint" of evidence. It wasn't like he punched someone in sixth grade. He robbed someone minutes before he got into an altercation with a cop that turned fatal.

Did he hurt the guy he robbed?  Did he punch anyone?

&amp;gt; My entire argument throughout has been that the more information the public has, the better informed they will be. 

I think I asked you earlier *why* you think that is the case and I don't believe you answered.

&amp;gt; Yes, it removes MB from the pedestal he was previously on

Nobody was disputing that he had just robbed a store. I'm not sure why you think he was on some pedestal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322309941.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Did he hurt the guy he robbed? Did he punch anyone?

He didn't have to. He shoved the guy easily into a bunch of shelves after stealing and then when the guy tried to say something else, his mere presence was enough to intimidate the poor shopkeeper until he gave up. 

&amp;gt;I think I asked you earlier why you think that is the case and I don't believe you answered.

It's pretty straightforward. If there is more information available, people will be better informed.

&amp;gt; I'm not sure why you think he was on some pedestal.

He was on a pedestal. I've linked to multiple articles which stated that he would never get into fights, was non-violent in nature, was gentle etc... This video shows the exact opposite. It shows him being aggressive, stealing, and when the shopkeeper tried to stop him, being physically intimidating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322662860.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  Did he hurt the guy he robbed? Did he punch anyone?

&amp;gt;He didn't have to.

He could have and he chose not to.

Stereotypes and racism are dangerous partially because they are sometimes based on reality.  Let's assume that robbers are more likely than the average person to try to attack a police officer.  Even with that assumption, *most* robbers *don't* try to attack police officers when confronted.  It is statistically inappropriate to assume MB was violent because he robbed a store or because he was black, even though both of those conditions probably slightly increase the probability that he was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322970824.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Ummm... I never said he was violent because he was black? I don't quite know where you're getting this. I don't quite understand how you can divorce two violent altercations involving the same person and occurred within minutes of each other. 

He still robbed a store and when the shopkeeper confronted him, he shoved him into some shelves. The shopkeeper said something else and then he threateningly approached the shopkeeper until the guy basically cowered. The threat of assault is still a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323174567.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I never said he was violent because he was black?

I never said you did... but since you mention it, statistically, perhaps you should have. Black people are more likely to be jailed for violent crimes, so the fact that he was black means it is more likely he was violent towards the officer, right?

So before I explain that point, I want to pause for a second to say that you seem to have taken some of the things I have written as insults, and that is not how they are intended. I don't think you are racist or bigoted, and while I obviously don't know you well, I assume you are a caring, intelligent, decent human being.

I do think, however, you are vastly misjudging the probabilities in this case.  I suspect we can agree that while it is statistically accurate that black people are more likely to end up in violent altercations with the police, we should not use that MB is black as evidence that he initiated a violent altercation.

I don't have statistical evidence that can clearly show that the physical intimidation of the shopkeeper does not significantly increase the probability of a violent confrontation with a police officer, but those two types of confrontations are so incredibly different in nature that I have a hard time believing there is a strong correlation there. I think we would all expect that the outcome of shoving and threatening an unarmed clerk would be that the clerk would let you leave the store with some stolen goods. No rational person is likely to think that a police officer is remotely as likely to back down based on the threat of violence. Police officers have guns and batons, they have combat training, and it is part of their job to resist intimidation.  It simply doesn't make sense to think that people would behave the same way towards an unarmed clerk, who probably doesn't really care if they steal something, as they would towards a police officer.

The video may show that MB was more likely to intimidate people than the average person, but it is a giant leap to think that he is more likely to attempt to intimidate a police officer. There simply isn't evidence that those two behaviors are correlated.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321977465.0" user="poesionous" delta="False">
    <text>Officers of the law can do a heck of a lot to prevent things from being lethal. Why do you consider the physical advantage to mean anything when officers have law and firearms on their side? Being big just means a bigger body bag, and MB couldn't have not known that.

The video does distract. It's the only visual evidence in this he-said-she-said case and it's the first released. Would they have released a video of an officer showing violent behaviour beforehand, if such a video existed? I doubt it, and that's why it's a distraction and an attack on character. Whether it has any relevance or not - that question is the distraction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322155701.0" user="onafarawaybeach" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; an officer killed a guy for walking on the street

You're accepting one story as more valid than another though when it's ambiguous. The cop's version and a corroborating audio tape account makes sense. If he didn't rush the car/officer then yes but that is unknown.

Basically you believe that the officer told him to get off the street, he raised his hands up and started walking off the street and was shot in the back with his hands raised. Could've happened. It's not looking likely as more evidence comes out and you'd have to believe that the cop is a racist homicidal maniac. You don't have to believe anything outlandish about Brown - he's was a young adult, had just committed a felony and rushed the cop b/c he thought he was going to be arrested - in the hope of ultimately getting away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322238054.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not accepting any story. I'm saying we don't have enough evidence yet, and it does not help anyone for the public to have access to the video--*except* it does take attention away from the officer.

If you look at the police behavior from the area that has been caught on tape since then, it isn't a stretch to think that the officer could have over-reacted.

&amp;gt;  he's was a young adult, had just committed a felony and rushed the cop b/c he thought he was going to be arrested

That doesn't make much sense, particularly since he wasn't shot at close range.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321835098.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>You're misreading his comments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321847910.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>How so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321517434.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The tape shows he used his size to intimidate people. The only 2 stories immediately after the shooting were the officers and the suspects friend who was an accomplice to the strong arm robbery. The public immediately jumped on this racist bullshit and the teen was this angel and would never hurt a soul. The rioting had already begun without ever considering what the officer said might be true. That's why they released it. Now we have the autopsy which completely discredits the suspects friend, the only eyewitness. Also we have the audio recording which supports what the officer said happened. People have to try so hard not to offend other people this is what happens. Immediately the officer shot the teen because he was black and the officer was white. The officer may not have a racist bone in his body. Maybe he killed him because the suspect assaulted him and charged after him, the police aren't superheroes they don't know if someone is unarmed. Maybe the officer shot him because he's trigger happy. The fact that the public there immediately jumps to race is absolute bullshit excuse to go and act like fucking animals. Looting, burning and causing injury to others. I think it shows who's really racist. Now let's say the teen was armed and killed the cop, would anyone be looting or burning the town? No, white people wouldn't call it a racial hate crime. If you want equal rights stop creating a difference in race. Al Sharpton and Jackson are the biggest racists themselves and they thrive and capitalize on this shit. It should be one man killed another man and we need to investigate to find out why, end of story. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321603449.0" user="Casus125" delta="False">
    <text>You think outrage like this happens in a vacuum?

The Ferguson Police Department is 94% white, in city that is 67% Black.

The same ultra white police department was twice as likely to arrest Black persons as white persons, based on public records.

You grow up in environment like that, you're damn well going to be pissed off when the White Police again abuse their power, except this time, they killed an unarmed kid.

&amp;gt; If you want equal rights stop creating a difference in race. 

Creating a difference in race? When you're very literally policed differently because of your race, you're entire life? Please get real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321621294.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I live near a city which is predominantly black and the police force is about split, the chief of police is black as well as the mayor. The arrests are mostly blacks, why, because they are the majority in the town and are the ones committing the crimes sadly. It shouldn't matter what color the police are. They're not arresting people for the sake of arresting them. When you see a town acting like this it's a reasonable assumption that the population isn't interested or isn't qualified to be in the police department. The fact the teenager was unarmed is irrelevant, the police can't tell that without a search, and how dangerous this town is it seems likely people will be armed. My point is immediately this came down to race and not just a man killed another man and we need to find out why. It's very likely the teenager assaulted the police officer and reached for his gun, nobody knows that yet. But the town immediately jumps to he was black and the cop was white and the kid was innocent and wouldn't do such a thing. This cops life is ruined and his family is in danger for doing his job possibly correctly. He's guilty until proven innocent in that racist town, and I guarantee even if the facts come out and say he was assaulted and the shooting was justified they will still call it a racial crime. Now there's the video of the teddy bear teen strong arming a clerk and using his size to intimidate. Then witnesses unscripted saying the kid charged the officer. It isn't unreasonable to think the teen assaulted the officer and if he didn't then yes the officer should be charged, but it shouldn't be a racial thing. This officer could be the least racist person in the world nobody knows. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322516131.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I live near a city which is predominantly black and the police force is about split, the chief of police is black as well as the mayor. The arrests are mostly blacks, why, because they are the majority in the town and are the ones committing the crimes sadly.

Let's see some sources for that very undetailed claim if you please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322578983.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Sure visit acpolice.org. The chief of police is black and the mayor was up until last year, but was for a long time. I also used to work in the police department for over 10 years so I have first hand experience. If the town is majority one color or another black or white, the higher arrest rate will be for the predominant color, thats just common sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322607599.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the reply.  Too often in these threads do we get anecdotal evidence that is blindly taken for granted, and it leads to unfounded assumptions.

[source for the lazy](http://www.acpolice.org/) and [Here's some population statistic data](http://www.idcide.com/citydata/nj/atlantic-city.htm) 

For what it's worth, I couldn't find any evidence towards the claim that the arrests are mostly black people, or that they are committing a proportionate percentage of crime.  

I also have some qualms about the idea that because (for example) 10% of the people in the city are white, that there would be an expected ~10% of arrests vs white people; this particular idea completely ignores the effects of poverty and the disproportionate levels of poverty amongst minorities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322631371.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No problem, thank you. The point I'm trying to get across is not all police officers are bad and not all are racists either. This city which has so called pre-existing problems with it's police force for arresting blacks for the color of their skin, they are doing the exact same thing to this officer. They immediately are judging this man by the color of his skin without knowing anything about the officer. He could have been just doing his job and now his whole life is ruined over this. The news shouldn't have headlined as white cop shoots black unarmed teen. It should have read police officer shoots another man, investigation pending details. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324452506.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, and I'm sure that there are VERY few people who would make the claim that all cops were bad.  That being said, I sincerely doubt that this guy's *"whole life is ruined over this."* especially considering how rarely officers find themselves prosecuted for abuses of power.

And while I agree with you in regards to the news blowing this out of proportion, I think it's unrealistic to expect this to ever be achievable in these modern days of info-tainment news organizations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321622436.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Of course they're more likely to arrest black people they consist of the majority of the population. It's simple statistics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321846372.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you're saying, but there's a problem in your comment. If Ferguson is 67% black then that means there are more than twice as many blacks as non-blacks, so it actually makes very much sense if blacks are arrested twice as often as non-blacks.

I think the other figure makes a stronger argument. 94% is very high.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321853559.0" user="Casus125" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe if Ferguson was an outlier, but it doesn't take me very long to travel to areas with similar arrest rates and far fewer black people.

Racist Policing is practically a statistical fact at this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323703710.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How is it racist if, factually, African-Americans are more likely to commit crimes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321838910.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>But you have to consider the context.

By all accounts, Ferguson had police problems before this case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321874097.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Understandable, but by them assuming guilt on the officer is the same thing they're trying to change for themselves. Racial injustices aren't solved by more racial injustice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323604156.0" user="someone447" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; he must have been quite scared to see a police officer and this would have affected his behavior.

Or, he was scared because he was black and the police don't have a great record on race in the St Louis area.

&amp;gt;However, this footage reveals a far more complex situation. It cannot be boiled down to white cop executes black teen. 

The police officer didn't have any idea about Brown stealing cigars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323702907.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I've gone over this multiple times. I've read the same articles as you have and I know that the officer didn't realise Brown was the one stealing cigars. 

The footage gives people a better idea of the state of mind of MB, which is important because he was the victim of the shooting incident soon after. I believe, as I've said throughout, that Brown, having just committed a robbery, would have been more scared/on-edge when being confronted by a cop almost immediately after. Sure, the cop didn't know that he was the perpetrator, but MB may have been acting suspiciously/aggressively to warrant additional attention. So, I find it very likely that the cop became more aggressive and MB did as well and the conflict escalated.

I think that Officer Wilson has a lot to answer for, but until we get all the facts and step back from the emotions surrounding the matter, we could also find that MB is not entirely innocent or that Wilson is not entirely to blame. Nothing is black and white. Everything is shades of grey.

Edit: Meant to write "not entirely to blame" not "entirely to blame"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323773459.0" user="someone447" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe, as I've said throughout, that Brown, having just committed a robbery, would have been more scared/on-edge when being I believe, as I've said throughout, that Brown, having just committed a robbery, would have been more scared/on-edge when being confronted by a cop almost immediately after.confronted by a cop almost immediately after.

I think he would have been more on edge because he is a black man in Ferguson and both the city and county police have a horrible record on race. A few years ago a black man was detained and beaten--and then charged with **multiple counts of vandalism for daring to get blood on the officers uniforms.**

&amp;gt;we could also find that MB is not entirely innocent or that Wilson is not entirely to blame. 

An unarmed teenager is dead--shot by a police officer. Even if Brown **did** charge the officer, the officer has non-deadly weapons at his disposal(taser, baton, etc).

And given the area's horrible problems with race, it isn't a stretch to say that Brown would be alive if he were white.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323845180.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think he would have been more on edge because he is a black man in Ferguson and both the city and county police have a horrible record on race. 

Look, I'm not black so I can't relate to the racism aimed at the black community by cops nor am I from that area of the country. But I find it hard to believe that a black person is more on edge by the police on the sole basis of his/her race versus someone who HAD JUST committed a robbery. Perhaps he was on edge because he was black, which could very well be the case. But I think the fact that he was walking away from a crime is far more of a factor in changing his behavior to a law enforcement officer than his race.

&amp;gt; An unarmed teenager is dead--shot by a police officer. Even if Brown did charge the officer, the officer has non-deadly weapons at his disposal(taser, baton, etc).

Simply put, that is correct. Absolutely. But that teenager was also VERY physically imposing i.e. 6 foot 4, 292 pounds. I don't know the physical stats of the officer, but that person (regardless of age, race, gender, orientation, whatever) will be very tough to take down in a non-lethal manner. Of course, I'm not saying that the difficulty means that the officer should just shoot him because its easier. 

What I am saying is that the officer may have felt that his life was in danger and for all his training, he was afraid that he would be physically overpowered by MB. Thus, he drew his lethal weapon in self-defence. 

Hindsight is always 20/20. If you read accounts of people who have been in combat/shootouts, they aren't thinking things through logically. They're simply operating in the short-term on a self-preservation instinct. They make mistakes that get people killed. They shoot a civilian because they think they're holding a cell phone trigger to a suicide bomb, but they're just holding a toy plane. They could have used pepper spray or mace or a rubber bullet, but they fucked up and pulled a trigger. 

It is indisputable that MB's death is a tragedy. But we cannot scapegoat Officer Wilson as some white cop on a power trip lynching people on some psychopathic whim. Likewise we cannot simply present MB as some have as either an innocent angel who wouldn't hurt a fly or as a violent criminal who "had it coming." 

People are complex. This shooting is the combination of a number of things and we need to find the facts in an impartial manner and subsequently mete out justice. I am not opposed to the idea of Wilson going to prison on a murder charge if he does turn out to be some psycho power-hungry killer. But we need to have all the facts. Very few things are immutable or completely good or completely bad. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323869337.0" user="someone447" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But I find it hard to believe that a black person is more on edge by the police on the sole basis of his/her race versus someone who HAD JUST committed a robbery.

He stole a couple bucks worth of cigars. Hardly something to be so on edge that you fight a policeman. But [being black](http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/politics/2014/08/ferguson_protests_over_michael_brown_won_t_end_soon_the_black_community.html) in Ferguson is dangerous. A white person who steals ~10 bucks worth of cigars doesn't ever have to worry about getting shot(or hell, even going to jail.) A black man needs to worry about getting shot during any interaction with the police.

&amp;gt;Hindsight is always 20/20. If you read accounts of people who have been in combat/shootouts, they aren't thinking things through logically.

Without a doubt, but that shouldn't protect them from the consequences of their actions.

&amp;gt;But we cannot scapegoat Officer Wilson as some white cop on a power trip lynching people on some psychopathic whim.

It's far bigger than Wilson. I honestly believe most cops(as individuals) are not racist. But the system is. The system that made only 3 of 55 officers in a predominantly black city black. The system that allowed 90% of all Ferguson traffic stops and 93% of all Ferguson arrests to be black(even though whites were caught with contraband far more often) Ferguson is 67% black. So it is obvious the police department has some racial issues.

The problem is that this is simply a symptom of a systematic disease. Our criminal justice system is rotten to the core--and I'm not even a black male. Justice is supposed to be blind--and it is, provided you aren't a young black male.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27323942245.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, what he took isn't the important part. It wasn't shoplifting, it was robbery. According to wikipedia, "Robbery is the crime of taking or attempting to take something of value by force or threat of force or by putting the victim in fear."* Watching the video, it's pretty clear that's what MB did. He took something and when confronted, he shoved the shopkeeper into some shelves and when the guy confronted him once more, MB used his size to intimidate the guy i.e. "put the victim in fear." 

*http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robbery

The key point is that he used his mass and size to intimidate and demonstrated his willingness to physically assault someone. I believe this is highly relevant since he got into a physical confrontation moments later with a law enforcement officer.

As to your comments, I don't disagree with you regarding the institutionalised racism of the Ferguson Police Department (FPD) and the American legal system. If you could show references to those statistics, I would like to see them. (Not accusing you of making it up, but I really am interested in seeing)

However, I think its important to once again take everything with a grain of salt. A cursory google search showed this article which I thought was very interesting: 

- http://www.stltoday.com/news/local/crime-and-courts/police-stops-in-ferguson-what-are-the-numbers/article_012cf751-9cec-5733-8025-09e03abb9d86.html

Once again, let me clarify that I do believe that the American legal system has significant problems with race and there is clearly something very wrong with having a police department that is so clearly unrepresentative of the people its supposed to protect and serve. 

That being said, here are some interesting snippets from the article:

-  Last year, blacks, who make up a little less than two-thirds of the driving-age population in the North County city, accounted for 86 percent of all stops. 
- University of Missouri-St. Louis criminologist Rick Rosenfeld said the statistics for Ferguson dont stand out from many other St. Louis County municipalities.
- I dont think Ferguson would be at the top of many peoples lists for racial tension between police and the community, he said.
- Last year, Ferguson police searched 12.1 percent of black drivers they stopped, compared to 6.9 percent for whites. Contraband was found 22 percent of the time when the driver was black and 34 percent when the driver was white.
- Rosenfeld said he was puzzled about why the stop rate for whites was so low in Ferguson. He said one possible factor is that the black population in the area, as a whole, is younger than the white population. Older people are less likely to be stopped, he said, and are less likely to be on the roads in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324021641.0" user="someone447" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Honestly, what he took isn't the important part. It wasn't shoplifting, it was robbery. According to wikipedia, "Robbery is the crime of taking or attempting to take something of value by force or threat of force or by putting the victim in fear."*

Taking 10 dollars worth of cigars is vastly different than taking 1000 dollars worth of DVDs. It does matter what he stole. Taking 10 dollars worth of something is petty, it's essentially meaningless.

&amp;gt;I believe this is highly relevant since he got into a physical confrontation moments later with a law enforcement officer.

I disagree, it is a completely different situation. He knows he can't intimidate a police officer with his size. The little 5'5" convience store owner? Yeah. A cop with a taser and a gun? Not a chance.

&amp;gt;If you could show references to those statistics, I would like to see them. (Not accusing you of making it up, but I really am interested in seeing)

It was on the [second page](http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/politics/2014/08/ferguson_protests_over_michael_brown_won_t_end_soon_the_black_community.2.html) of the link I gave you. I misquoted and said 90% when it was only 86%. It's also 92% of all searches.

&amp;gt;That being said, here are some interesting snippets from the article:

So, what that article was saying was: Well, Ferguson isn't any worse than the rest of St. Louis; so there's nothing to see here. Move along.

I think that just proves how fucked up STL is in regards to race and the police...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321718169.0" user="deckman" delta="False">
    <text>Did you even see the video? That's no shoplifting that's brute force robbery.

The video and his initial actions towards the officer clearly show he was just another scum of society. What really irks me is the people posting pictures of him when he was 12 and making him out to be a fucking saint.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321731780.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>What really irks me is people assuming that our police force should be killing unarmed civilians like they're Judge Dredd.

Nothing that kid did justified the officer's actions unless he was actively putting someone's life in danger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321754329.0" user="deckman" delta="False">
    <text>I'm the first person to criticize police misconduct and a huge amount of my posts are vents about police injustices. 

But are you ignoring the fact that he committed a violent crime (it wasn't shoplifting like so many are saying) and assaulted a police officer and tried to take his gun?

His actions most definitely would leave an officer to believe his life could be in danger.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321770587.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Committing a violent crime is not a justification for lethal force.

And do you have any evidence of his actions right before he was shot? How do you know he was trying to take his gun? How do you know he was getting physical at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321802747.0" user="deckman" delta="False">
    <text>I'll concede that police are notorious for lying to cover up their mistakes so their "official story" should be taken with a grain of salt.

I only saw the robbery video today but my opinion of Michael Brown took a 180 degree turn after that. I may be biased because I have about 10 years of experience working in retail and have frequently dealt with similar situations, but that video spoke volumes to me about what kind of person he was.

It's incomparable to shoplifters. People who blatantly steal without even trying to conceal the fact, and who act violently when confronted, show a absolute lack of respect for others and the law. 

The fact that a jaywalking incident (before the officer had any knowledge of the robbery) escalated so quickly to the point where he attacked and wounded the officer, further supports the idea that he didn't respect people or the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321810778.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>A person's opinion of Brown is irrelevant to how justified Wilson was in shooting him.

I don't care if he was literally Pol Pot - unless he was actively putting someone's life in danger he should not have been shot. Period. End of story.

Calling him scum or a piece of shit makes it look like you're trying to justify *his death* because you dislike his character.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321851721.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is is that Officer Wilson may have felt that his own life was in danger when he starting fighting with someone so physically imposing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321859997.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe he did, maybe he didn't. You can't determine that based on the video, nor can you determine that Brown was fighting based on the video.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321865629.0" user="gasfarmer" delta="False">
    <text>DISCLAIMER: I am not /u/Deckman, who you were talking to earlier. (Purely to prevent confusion)

&amp;gt; unless he was actively putting someone's life in danger

That's a pretty gray area. It becomes even more gray when you're looking back on the fact. Hindsight is 20/20.

Police officers don't possess a magic ball that allows them to see how dangerous someone is, or if they're carrying a weapon, or what their state of mind is. For a cop, everything is treated the same, and it's sorted out later. It's safer that way. 

As a Fire Fighter, I can tell you it's the exact same in my situation. I have no idea what's inside the house, so I'm going to attack the situation in a way that's the safest for me, and my crew. I'm going to assume the worst. Always. Then we'll sort out the rest after the fact. 

It's easy for you to pass judgement on what's safe after the fact, in the light of day. When you're in the shit, you only know what you can see - the rest is programmed into to protect your crew, protect the public, and then do the job. 

Sometimes it turns out badly. 99 per cent of the time, it turns out favourably. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321886736.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, and I know that the police are human and not psychic and have to do the best with the information they have. I just think there needs to be accountability and systems in place to at least try and prevent needless killings. I can't say from where I'm sitting if Wilson was justified or not - I just plain don't know. I'm angry at the systemic abuse black people face at the hands of the police and for that I sympathize with protestors. But as far as this incident is concerned Wilson may very well have been in the right.

The fact that the police department tried to defame Brown's character before presenting any other information is a red flag in my opinion. If the officer was acting in the right than Brown's character is irrelevant isn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321919202.0" user="gasfarmer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I just think there needs to be accountability and systems in place to at least try and prevent needless killings.


There definitely is. People on here *love* to shit on Cops and think they're irresponsible assholes - when in reality, police departments are run as the tightest ships I've ever seen.

I'm a Volunteer Fire Fighter, as well as a photojournalist by trade, so I see **a lot** of cops in the run of a week. 

They construct SOG's using decades upon decades of experience, utilising best practices, and they're constantly under review and scrutiny. To think that this officer isn't under the gun right now is absolute lunacy - not to mention a completely unfair assumption. 

The reality of the job is that any time they leave the office, they're both throwing themselves directly into the path of danger, and holding themselves under the eye of public scrutiny. 

In the fire department, we have **books on books on books on books** of SOG's, SOP's, best practices, and certifications to maintain before we're even allowed to step on a truck with the flashy lights. When you're a police officer, you deal with more things, more variety, and you face less obvious - but almost more deadly - danger.

They operate under ridiculous amounts of supervision and instruction. Most of which is designed to protect the officer, because people are inherently dangerous. 

This is why when you're given legal advice about dealing with police, you're instructed to remain calm, make no sudden moves, and be co-operative. 

A cop has no idea if you're going to hurt them. They have no idea what weapons you might have on you. They have no idea what your capabilities are. 

Unless they become psychic, there's really no way to know. So in lieu of that, they're taught to react to the worst possible situation, because one misstep can lead to their own death, the death of a fellow officer, or the death of a bystander. All of which is completely unacceptable. 

They're not trained to kill on sight; they're trained to take action to prevent any of those things from happening. In very rare cases, that leads to the death of someone innocent. That's completely undesirable, but it's not 100% preventable. Not everyone is right 100% of the time - but when you're dealing with a situation like that, it's better to be safe than sorry.

An officer doesn't want to take a life, they don't want to have to deal with the avalanche of shit that will fall upon them, and they definitely don't want a burden like that; but it's the best they can do. 

I don't think anyone wanted this outcome. 

&amp;gt;The fact that the police department tried to defame Brown's character before presenting any other information is a red flag in my opinion. If the officer was acting in the right than Brown's character is irrelevant isn't it?

This wasn't a move to defame his character. The PD are truly in a 'no-win' scenario right now. Obviously the release seems badly timed, but that's just when it came out. 

If you want to defame someone, there are *vastly* more effective and less obvious means to do so. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322508547.0" user="fuckingseries" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What really irks me is people assuming that our police force should be killing unarmed civilians like they're Judge Dredd.

Seriously? No one thinks that. You are deluded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321838264.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The police cherry-picked the still frames that they released.  The confrontation at the door initially looked to me like the clerk was trying to get away from Mr. Brown.  Then in the video, it became obvious that the clerk was trying to prevent his leaving and got pushed away.  The police are obviously trying to steer opinion.  They are not interested in transparency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322510481.0" user="fuckingseries" delta="False">
    <text>If they weren't interested in transparency then they wouldn't have released the whole video now would they? Your bias is showing. Of course they are going to show the most pertinent frames.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322145069.0" user="supajamz54" delta="False">
    <text>He wasn't stopped over the robbery dude. 

If you're going to make an argument for the shooter it's more convincing to argue that he shot MB after he reached for the gun during their altercation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322199368.0" user="418156" delta="False">
    <text>Shoplifting is when you stick somethin under your coat.  This is a violent crime  he grabbed the stuff then physically assaulted the clerk.  This is an act of bullying.  And it points to a state of mind of a person that would assault a cop.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335715914.0" user="Lambeauleap80" delta="False">
    <text>He didn't "shoplift"... He grabbed a worker by the neck and through him against a shelf. That's called a felony robbery. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335722047.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>He could have burned that place to the ground and it wouldn't have warranted his death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335728428.0" user="Lambeauleap80" delta="False">
    <text>All police officers are trained to shoot when people get CLOSE to them. Michael Brown gave the officer a broken orbital bone. If an officer is given permission to shoot for getting near them, then Brown was just asking to die if he was punching the officer in the face. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335746226.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Source? Because there's video of the officer and he's walking around just fine after the incident.

In fact, he's an entire article about the myth you just propagated: http://littlegreenfootballs.com/article/43751_Jim_Hofts_Unsourced_Claim_That_Officer_Darren_Wilson_Had_an_Orbital_Blowout_Fracture_of_the_Eye_Socket</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335779220.0" user="Lambeauleap80" delta="False">
    <text>And did Brown also get shot in the back like 99% of the 'witnesses' say? Also, if the audio recording of the shooting is real, then it shows there was a pause between the first couple shots and the rest. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27335783717.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I've presented a narrative of the shooting. I was countering yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27336002821.0" user="Lambeauleap80" delta="False">
    <text>So then tell me what the point of this whole "movement" is with the "hands up" surrendering slogan?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
