<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321970407.0" user="TheGreatNorthWoods" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're making a mistake by positing that it has to be either (a) relevant or (b) character assassination. 

I agree that it is relevant because it goes towards establishing what Mr. Brown's state of mind might have been at the time of the altercation. To the extent that figuring out what happened there depends on figuring out which elements of competing accounts are plausible, knowing that Mr. Brown might have committed a crime earlier seems relevant, even if the police officer was not aware of this.

However, the way in which the authorities released the information seems to indicate that they might also have had an interest in painting Mr. Brown in the worst possible light, therefore making him seem like less of a victim. I would call that 'character assassination'. 

The local police have mishandled numerous elements of the investigation and the crowd-control challenges they have faced, they seem dug-in and defensive. That context is at least in relevant to understanding their state of mind when releasing the video as Mr. Brown's alleged crime is to understanding his state of mind during the incident that led to his death.

Lastly, let me add that 'character assassination' wouldn't be my prefered description of what the police are doing; rather, I think they're trying to muddy the waters. Releasing the video has helped them shift the conversation away from the central question that should be asked about what happened: did Mr. Brown pose an imminent threat to the police officer or others? Instead, they want us to ask: could Mr. Brown have been combative rather than, as we were encouraged to believe early on, cooperative? 

When a sworn law enforcement officer shoots an unarmed civilian as the result of confrontation stemming from a civil infraction, that burden of proof should rest on that police officer. This video seems like a distraction from that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
