<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27322319131.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>There are a couple of issues with that.

First, while the video appears to show a robbery, the store clerk didn't see the need to call police about it.  The clerk was the one who laid hands on Brown, not the other way around, and while there was indeed an altercation, we don't actually know that property was stolen.

Second, the police servant involved wasn't actually aware of the alleged robbery, so it's nothing *but* character assassination since there was absolutely no connection between this alleged event and the murder.

Third, we don't even know if the guy in the video was really him.

This all makes the video shady as hell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322336567.0" user="nachkturnalbeast" delta="False">
    <text>The Cigars were reportedly found on Michael Browns body.
Done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322349075.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>OK, so it was him.  But we don't know that he stole them.  From the video, it appears that he tried to get a bunch of them, didn't have enough money for all of them, and put some of them back.  If he had stolen them, the clerk would have called police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322415860.0" user="nachkturnalbeast" delta="False">
    <text>I'll give you the benefit of the conspiratorial doubt.
However, i don't think any of this stuff is truly in question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322622865.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>http://crooksandliars.com/2014/08/ferguson-cops-busted-new-video-seems-show

It's in question, certainly.  I'm not sure what the answer to the question is, and neither do you, I think.  What is beyond dispute, if you look at the chief's statements, is that the shooter knew none of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322941502.0" user="nachkturnalbeast" delta="False">
    <text>The initial statement by the chief did say that, and they did change the story to that the officer did actually hear over the radio a robbery had taken place. I have seen no where that the police were not called on a robbery except for by people's hearsay. Information is slowly leaking, as in the cops side of the story ( which we had not even heard till now ) and supposedly now 12 witnesses saying that Brown did charge the cop, while the initial reports are from 4 people 1 at least being his friend saying he was surrendering. What i see in this video is him handing off the 1 box to his buddy and grabbing another one over the counter. Never see any money, no reaching into his pocket for money or paying any where in the video. Why would the store clerk pursue him at all if a proper exchange was made. No store clerk would leave his register for no reason and try to block the man from leaving.This story seems like an attempt to cloud the facts, once again before the actual stories are presented. Where is the testimony of the store clerk? This looks like his buddy didn't want to be involved in stealing the one box and put it back. Both boxes are the same size. The typical box of 50. However there is a bonus box of 60 in certain flavours that would appear the same as well.

My "opinion" only is that the reason shots were fired is because Michael Brown assaulted a cop and resisted being detained. There are also new reports of at least 12 witnesses that corroborate with the cops story, before his official story was supposedly released. At any rate, the media jumped the gun on this and probably has ruined any credible unbiased trial from ever happening, and they continue to do it, for the sake of ratings (CNN) We will see.

This is probably meaningless and heresay but i saw this post this morning. Wonder if they will release a toxicology report.

Bob 28 minutes ago
2
9

Hello Ladies and Gentleman.

Reallity is a beech.
This guy Michael Brown, formally of the St. Louis suburb of Ferguson, Missouri, I know of this guy and have seen him from time to time, and have acquaintances that knew him better than I.

This martyr was nothing but a mamas boy thug, drug smoking, thieving, big fat bully, with a very long police record that fills up ten pages. If one looked at him the wrong way as he perceived he would start a fight or sucker punch you. He loved to smoke chemical laced marijuana blunts, so that's why he was steeling the cigars for seen in the video.

If you had gone to school with this dude, you would have seen and heard about him bulling others for lunch money and getting answers to tests exams etc.

This Michael Brown was at a party year ago brandishing a 9mm fire arm at another person in an argument, but it did not have any amo it. I was their when this happened.

It was only a matter of time that this guy would end up dead or in prison for theft or shooting someone.


LOL, So this guy was no innocent nice little boy as you all have see in those photos of him on the CNN news. Look at the pic's of him wearing a jean vest jacket with the arms cut off. He was high as a kite on angel dust/crack.


We African American people have to take responsibility for our individual actions.

I am African American.﻿

Oh, about his friend Dorian.

This guy is a liar, instigator. He has the balls of a hamster/mouse. ﻿

What happened to the use of stun-guns? This would have been the most idea situation for the use of one.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326713554.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>The police had already been called by a witness bystander.  There was no reason for the clerk to call the police again.  The police showed up and investigated the robbery, including taking the surveillance tapes.  The clerk sure as heck didn't tell the police, "Never mind.  No robbery here.  Nothing to investigate."  The police report is evidence of that.

Also, it is absolutely stunning that anyone could watch that video of a huge man grabbing and shoving around that small clerk, and try to claim that this was a normal convenience store transaction.  Let's just say this point of view does not reflect well on the local population.  Which is an under-statement by a mile...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
