<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321435079.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>The police officer who shot him wasn't even aware of the incident in question when the shooting took place. Even if he was it wouldn't make any difference as committing a relatively minor offence in no way justifies the unprovoked killing of an unarmed man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321462871.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Please please please check the beginning part of the post. I am strictly talking about the Police Department's decision to release the footage. I am in NO WAY saying that cops should shoot shoplifters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321466393.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'd be surprised if the police department's decision to release the footage was based on anything other than a desire to make a dead many seem more deserving of the death. They could have mentioned the shoplifting in a press conference, but instead they released the footage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321627622.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; seem more deserving of the death

Interesting, to me it seemed to show that he would be more likely to have attacked the police officer, perhaps because he thought he was going to be caught for theft.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321467610.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they release if they didn't believe it in some way justified his killing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321491503.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>What would the alternative have been? In a case as highly charged and incendiary as this, I would think that having as much information as possible would be critical to ensuring the investigation is done properly. If the police had decided to hide information, I believe it would have been far worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321496200.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what you're saying, the investigation was being performed by the authorities who already had the information so releasing it to the public was unnecessary. 

There was literally no reason for them to release the video other than the police thinking it would influence public opinion on the shooting with irrelevant information thus it was pure character assassination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321503767.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I think the public absolutely has a right to know why a police officer decided to shoot a civilian. The investigation isn't being conducted for the authorities, but for the public. yes the authorities had that information, but the public also needs to as well. Personally I don't think it's character assassination if the event/footage of the event is relevant considering it happened moments before the incident. 

I believe it would have been character assassination if the police said something like oh, we caught him with a joint 2 months ago. Or something completely irrelevant like sexual orientation etc...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321512773.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>But this wasn't the reason he was shot, the officer has even said that he didn't know the incident had taken place.

Also, you say that the incident doesn't justify the shooting but you also say that it's relevant, do these two ideas not conflict at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321517716.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>In short, the incident doesn't justify the shooting. BUT, it is relevant because I believe that Michael Brown's behavior was affected having just committed a crime and being confronted by a police officer moments later. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321525390.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>That is pure speculation when all eye-witness reports agree that this was an unprovoked shooting of an unarmed man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321542345.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I'm very hesitant to trust eye-witness reports, especially in a case as charged as this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321545062.0" user="therealduffin" delta="False">
    <text>How about an independent coroner's report which showed no signs of a struggle?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321556633.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>That is far more convincing, but to play devil's advocate, doesn't that just mean that the guy who's 6 foot 4 and weighs 292 pounds had the upperhand? According to other reports, Wilson had bruising and swelling from the injuries he sustained.

For anyone who's interested:
http://online.wsj.com/articles/independent-autopsy-shows-no-sign-of-struggle-in-michael-browns-shooting-1408381747</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321859000.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>Read up on eye witness accounts. Do your own experiments. Heck, play a game of telephone. Eye witness accounts are mostly awful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321840071.0" user="StopClockerman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that Michael Brown's behavior was affected having just committed a crime and being confronted by a police officer moments later.

This is exactly the problem with the release of this sort of information. You assume that it could offer an explanation as to why Brown could have provoked a physical confrontation with a police officer. The logic there relies on a HUGE assumption. Wouldn't it be equally likely if not more probable to assume that a person would be LESS likely to physically provoke a police officer since he just committed a crime, especially if the police officer said nothing of a robbery and called them out only on jaywalking? 

Unless you're in a courtroom, a person's view of what is "relevant" is wholly subjective. The release of this information is likely an attempt to exploit those subjective components of public opinion about criminals and criminal acts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321563109.0" user="Quetzalcoatls" delta="False">
    <text>The decision to release the video was solely made by the Ferguson Police department. It was not something the DOJ or the Missouri National Guard recommended because they felt it would inflame the situation. Putting things into the "court of public opinion" is actually the last thing you would want to do to ensure that a trial goes well.

So, why did the Ferguson Police Department decide to release this potentially inflammatory information against the advice of two other law enforcement agencies other than to assassinate Michael Brown's character? The Chief of Police released the stills of the video at a 10am press conference and deliberately waited till 1pm to bother to actually inform all the reporters that the information given to them actually had nothing to do directly with the shooting. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321617123.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>In this case, we are only concerned with the thoughts in the cop's head. He didn't even know about this, so it's immaterial. Mike could have also murdered a busload of children, and even that would be irrelevant based on the fact that the officer couldn't have known that.

Wilson had a set of perceptions on which he made a judgment call. The question is was that a reasonable call?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321818404.0" user="StopClockerman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In a case as highly charged and incendiary as this, I would think that having as much information as possible would be critical to ensuring the investigation is done properly.

Releasing the info about the robbery to the public wouldn't really change how the police conduct the investigation internally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321646218.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>If therealduffin is correct that the police officer who shot him wasn't aware of the incident, then the robbery incident is basically irrelevant and the public has no right to see it.

You wrote:

&amp;gt; Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.

You are implying that shoplifters are likely to attack police officers.  You are implying that because he was a criminal... well, really I don't know what you're implying. I frankly can't see why you think the video-recording of a nonviolent petty theft *is* relevant.  So, please clarify.  Why *shouldn't* we dismiss that the victim had just committed a petty crime?

Setting all that aside for a second, I can't remotely think of a reason why the public should see this video, unless the case goes to court.  There was nothing in the video that was disputed, so the public doesn't gain any information from watching it.  We don't get to see video-recordings of witnesses giving statements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321859615.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>If you watch the surveillance video, you can see it's not just shoplifting. He steals a box and when confronted by the store owner, he shoves him roughly into some shelves and when the guy says something else, he comes back in an intimidating manner. The man is 6 foot 4 and 292 pounds i.e. physically imposing. 

It is important to see this, because it contradicts past reports that he was a "gentle giant" who never got into fights. And this is moments before the incident with Officer Wilson.

I am not saying that shoplifters are more likely to attack cops. I am saying that a man who robs another man with force is more likely to lash out at an officer who confronts him over something unrelated than a man who has not committed a crime.

We shouldn't dismiss this video and the events that occurred within it because it contradicts past reports of him being gentle and shows his state of mind moments before the confrontation with Wilson. 

Note: Sorry I repeated myself a lot in this post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
