<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321440448.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>The release in and of itself is inflammatory. Whether you agree with it or not, you can't really deny that to release the footage has an implicit message that Michael Brown deserved to be shot because he robbed a store. Many people are going to be rationalizing that to themselves.

If anything the video does nothing to conclusively justify or clarify anything in regards to this whole situation. It just confounds the situation further. If the officer was responding to a different emergency, why did he have cause to pull over Brown and Jackson for just walking in the middle of the street?

Additionally, the timing of the release does nothing to help justify the report. The Ferguson Police obviously have little popular support in terms of media coverage and it just seems like a bid to garner some sympathy or masquerade inappropriate use of force as justice. People (rightfully or wrongfully) will think "Michael Brown was a robber so it makes sense he was shot to death" even though he was unarmed and apparently may have been surrendering. It's a far simpler and more digestible story for people to tell themselves rather than a possibly more complicated truth.  

Given all that, I don't really see the use of it at this point. You acknowledge the fact that these two incidents are more coincidental than directly related and I'd point out that speculation of how a person reacts to a situation is not evidence, it's opinion. The only thing you can definitively say is that Michael Brown may have robbed a store and then he was shot to death by a police officer. Eyewitness testimonies paint a different story than the police reports. So given all that, what did the video actually accomplish? If the police wanted to use this as evidence in a trial they certainly could/should but at this point what does the video do to help the Ferguson situation?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321462037.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Not to sound snotty, but when would have been a good time to release that information? You can't just say that after the riots would have been a good time. This sort of information reveals a far more nuanced case than was initially presented and can remove a lot of the disinformation surrounding the case.

It is relevant because it shows him acting violently and then when confronted with a police officer immediately after the crime, he gets into another violent altercation. He's 6 foot 4 and 292 pounds and footage of him acting violently dispels the notion that he was someone who "never got into a fight... a gentle giant."* 

*http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/aug/12/ferguson-missouri-shooting-michael-brown-civil-rights-police-brutality

In short, what this video accomplishes is to remove the idea that this is a simple white cop on black teen shooting. It is far more nuanced. This is a case of excessive force escalated to shooting by a white cop on a black teen, who moments before had committed a crime. Neither side is innocent and while Brown's death is on Wilson's hands, it wasn't cold-blooded lynching/murder as many people see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321507546.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say the best time to release the video is when the situation had actually calmed down (the protests and police attacking people are STILL happening and the situation has only escalated further) and cooler heads could have prevailed. Additionally, the police aren't obligation to release the video to begin with. You're saying this video removes a lot of disinformation but I think it just instigates faulty opinions and sows more distrust.

To answer your second comment supposition of a person's state of mind is not evidence. Yes, Michael Brown may have robbed store but that does definitively tell you what his actions were when he was shot beyond an opinion. This also does not to justify or clarify Officer Wilson's actions. The only thing the video does is to highlight that Michael Brown may have robbed a store, which does nothing to justify the fact he was killed. I could just as easily say it makes sense Brown would surrender since he was probably aware of the tensions in his community and the danger he would be in which lines up with eyewitness testimonies that have cropped up. 

That being said, this was never a simple situation to begin with and I think releasing the video is an attempt to try to simplify the situation in favor of the police department's actions. Yes, Brown may have committed a crime but people's complaints are that it's the unjustified killing of an unarmed teenager. Whether he stole some cigars does little to change the fact the police gunned down an unarmed person. This in within the context of the community's racial tensions and the fact the officer and department have done little to justify why Brown was shot or even pulled over to begin with. So to me, at least, to say the video was meant to highlight the nuances of a situation rings fairly hollow to me. It doesn't clarify anything since the police department has taken time to release evidence that Brown's character may not be perfect but they have not done anything to talk directly about the officer who shot Brown or offer up any more details on the shooting. Even Captain Nixon in your LA times article highlights that bringing the robbery into this is just confounding the situation as opposed to answering or clarifying any questions. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321513424.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>It's a good point that the release of the footage had to have been done alongside other information about the officer. I hadn't really thought about how lop-sided the information was. While I still don't think the footage itself is inflammatory and thus needed to be kept from the public, other information should have been provided to the public as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321530119.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>Well you don't see it as inflammatory because you're removing the information from the context of the situation. Imagine how this looks to the Ferguson community and to other people. To me it looks like a blatant attempt to cast blame on the victim for being shot and to justify the police department's actions. It looks to me like the video was release to garner sympathy for the police because support for them is at an all time low. Again, if the intention was to answer questions and clarify the situation and spread light onto what happened then the department could have done more with the information they have available. Instead the focus was to point a finger at Michael Brown and that to me is inflammatory. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321823798.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>To me, it doesn't look like that because the authorities admitted the officer knew nothing of the robbery.

To me, all it looks like is that someone very mistakenly thought it would be a good idea to release the video and I can no more divine their motives for doing so than I can for Brown committing robbery or the officer shooting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322216943.0" user="Stuck_in_a_cubicle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To me, it doesn't look like that because the authorities admitted the officer knew nothing of the robbery.

Keep in mind they didn't say that until hours after the video was released and the community and the media were starting to call it a character assassination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321666406.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Additionally, the police aren't obligation to release the video to begin with.

Actually, they were. There was a poorly written FOIA request issued to the Ferguson PD requesting all records and reports for Michael Brown, and  this is one of them.

It's the classic law of unintended consequences.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321815628.0" user="StopClockerman" delta="False">
    <text>There's nothing necessarily wrong in releasing information that is absolutely relevant to the shooting. However, it can be problematic if you take an otherwise proper action for an inappropriate purpose. For example, you can fire an at-will employee for any reason or no reason, but you cannot fire an at-will employee because of their skin color, religion, or nationality. 

The release of the video smacked of an inappropriate purpose - that is, to paint this kid as a criminal to undermine public sympathy towards him (to defuse the riots), to paint him as someone more likely to attack a police officer given a criminal history or agitated mindset, etc etc. 

There are reasons why a person's past criminal history is regularly excluded from courtroom trials for different crimes, and it's because that information is HIGHLY PREJUDICIAL. Juries are much more likely to convict a person of a crime if they already perceive them as a criminal. Evidence of the robbery in this case would be admitted to any criminal/civil trial related to the shooting because it's certainly relevant. However, we're talking about press conferences here and not a courtroom - the cops' selective release of this information is highly prejudicial to Brown's support among in the public eye. This looked more like a tactic in a PR campaign than in a proper police investigation.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321815964.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it definitely is relevant. So what, Michael Brown was not the gentle giant some people claimed? It's not like people were saying only gentle giants should not be shot to death for no apparent good reason. 

Hiding the truth is never a good thing. Never, ever, ever. I think that people are slowly realizing that truth and reason will out. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321467439.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>I would actually disagree with the notion that it is "in and of itself inflammatory." "In itself" means that by its very qualities it is inflammatory, when that is not true. It is a highly relevant video that speaks to the state of mind Brown was in. I do however agree that the effect of this video has been inflammatory both literally and figuratively. That being said, I believe it was important information that needs to be known to the public.

I don't have a team of psychologists with me to argue that people who just committed a crime will be more on-edge/scared of being caught by the police than the average joe, but you're right it is an opinion that I'm sure can be supported by professionals and experts.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321827315.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it's unreasonable to assume somebody who just committed a crime would be nervous near cops. Assuming the opposite is further from reason. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322181022.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly my point. I'm struggling to understand why this is something to argue over.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
