<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321878268.0" user="Clayboy731" delta="False">
    <text>No, the video is actually completely unrelated. The cops were not apprehending Michael Brown because he was suspected of strong-arming a convenience store. Neither the clerk nor the manager phoned the police that day. The person who called was another customer who believed [s]he had seen a robbery, when in actuality Michael Brown had paid for his cigarillos, gone for a second box and then put them back when he couldn't pay for them.

If you watch the video closely, you can see all of this. Why was he yelling at the clerk? I don't know, maybe the clerk pushed him when he reached for his second pack of cigarillos. But you can see a legitimate transaction happen, and the clerk or manager definitely would have called the police if they had been robbed.

Regardless, this tape can't be used to indict officer Wilson of the murder of Michael Brown, even if it does show a robbery, because the cops didn't even retrieve the tape until Michael was already dead and they were trying to cover their own asses. 

Because they had no evidence that Michael Brown had done anything wrong at the time of his murder, they are not allowed to use evidence collected afterwards against him; Evidence which, may I add, doesn't even support their claim and actually shows Michael paying for his cigars.

And even if all of this weren't the case and the PD weren't treading on thin ice to cover their own tracks, you still have an unarmed man, shot 6 times by a police officer, with no sign of struggle and one shot to the top of the head, despite Michael being taller than the officer.

Source:
http://www.newsweek.com/what-we-learned-michael-browns-autopsy-265247

TL;DR Let wilson rot in a cell. He's a murderer and there's literally no evidence that can exonerate him at this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326944401.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>http://documents.latimes.com/police-report-michael-brown-case/

Where are you getting the idea that no robbery occurred?  Just because someone else called the police?  This is a police report on the robbery.  If there had never been a robbery, the store clerk would have told that to the officers when they arrived, and this report would not even exist.  Obviously. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326976043.0" user="Clayboy731" delta="False">
    <text>I maintain that the clerk would've called the police had he actually been robbed. However, it was a witness that called, thinking they had witnessed a robbery. There was an altercation at the register, but I believe it was probably caused by the fact the Brown reached for a second pack of swishers. However Johnson placed the pack on the counter after they realized they could not afford it. The altercation at the door? The clerk was simply uncomfortable with the fact that Brown had confronted him. And yes, brown acted aggressively, but being aggressive is not a crime. 

Regardless, this footage cannot be used as evidence to exonerate the officer that murdered Brown, as it was collected after the incident occurred in an attempt by the police to cover their own asses and the officer in question was not responding to the alleged robbery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327000257.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/ferguson-police-name-michael-brown

Dorian and his lawyer have admitted that Brown robbed the store that night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327063080.0" user="Clayboy731" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I had not seen that document, and I stand corrected.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
