<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321578248.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public.

I don't fully understand why anyone thinks *anything* here is "essential information that needed to be released to the public", at least not right now when the investigation is barely underway. Why do you need to know details of the investigation that isn't finished yet? And this isn't a case of transparency, this is a case of the local police selectively releasing what *they* want you to know, against the advice of their superiors. I can't imagine what purpose releasing this footage serves to the investigation, and could even be destructive by coloring potential witnesses with information they didn't need to know.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321670429.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;against the advice of their superiors

Given that the Chief of Police released the information in response to a FOIA request, I want to challenge you to explain:

Who exactly is the Chief of Police's superior? and
Why should he not have followed the law and released the request pursuant to a legal FOIA request?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321734612.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>"superiors" was probably the wrong word. What I was referring to was from http://www.nytimes.com/2014/08/17/us/ferguson-missouri-protests.html?_r=0. 

&amp;gt; The Justice Department asked the Ferguson Police Department not to release the video because of concerns that “it would roil the community further,” a United States law enforcement official said on Saturday. The Ferguson department released the video on Friday and the Justice official said it “occurred over the objection of federal authorities.” The official said a copy of the video had been in possession of federal investigators, as well, “and there were never any plans by the federal investigators to release that copy.”

&amp;gt; The dispute showed further divisions among the authorities in the handling of the case. The surveillance video appeared to show Mr. Brown stealing a box of cigarillos. Shortly after the release of the video, Captain Johnson expressed his displeasure, saying he had not been told that the police planned to release it.

So maybe not "superiors" in the sense of their direct boss, but people who I think they should have listened to.

I don't know all the specifics of how FOIA requests work, but I'm skeptical that they don't have much legal leeway to have handled it better. I'm open to learning more though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321774043.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>The Missouri version of the Freedom of Information Act is generally referred to as the Sunshine Law. Specifically to these events, the applicable section is 610.100.

http://www.moga.mo.gov/statutes/C600-699/6100000100.HTM

Specifically to your query, 

&amp;gt;'2. Each law enforcement agency of this state, of any county, and of any municipality shall maintain records of all incidents reported to the agency, investigations and arrests made by such law enforcement agency. All incident reports and arrest reports shall be open records. Notwithstanding any other provision of law other than the provisions of subsections 4, 5 and 6 of this section or section 320.083, investigative reports of all law enforcement agencies are closed records until the investigation becomes inactive. If any person is arrested and not charged with an offense against the law within thirty days of the person's arrest, the arrest report shall thereafter be a closed record except that the disposition portion of the record may be accessed and except as provided in section 610.120.

So, the declaration that the investigation was exceptionally cleared due to the suspect's death made the record open.

The result is that if someone files a Sunshine Law request with the Ferguson Police Department for all records relating to Michael Brown, the PD doesn't have a choice as to whether or not they can release it. They are legally obligated, as it is an open record.

Moreover, there are teeth to this law.

Section 610.115
&amp;gt;A person who knowingly violates any provision of section 610.100, 610.105, 610.106, or 610.120 is guilty of a class A misdemeanor.

Section 610.100
&amp;gt;If the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the law enforcement officer or agency has knowingly violated this section, the officer or agency shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount up to one thousand dollars. If the court finds that there is a knowing violation of this section, the court may order payment by such officer or agency of all costs and attorneys' fees, as provided by section 610.027. If the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the law enforcement officer or agency has purposely violated this section, the officer or agency shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount up to five thousand dollars and the court shall order payment by such officer or agency of all costs and attorney fees, as provided in section 610.027. The court shall determine the amount of the penalty by taking into account the size of the jurisdiction, the seriousness of the offense, and whether the law enforcement officer or agency has violated this section previously.

An FBI agent, DOJ prosecutor, and the President can all get on the phone with me and ask me to break the law, and I'm going to tell all three of them to kiss my ass. I'm not going to commit a crime, lose my job, and all that because they don't think releasing the records is a good idea.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321838886.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>Was it a misdemeanor that they released it on Friday instead of Thursday? Would it have been a misdemeanor if they had released it next week or the week after? Do you think they've been consistently cooperative releasing all aspects of the police report?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321870578.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Was it a misdemeanor that they released it on Friday instead of Thursday?

No

&amp;gt;Would it have been a misdemeanor if they had released it next week or the week after?

Yes

&amp;gt;Do you think they've been consistently cooperative releasing all aspects of the police report?

I think that the Ferguson PD and the St. Louis County PD and the St. Louis County Office of the Prosecuting Attorney have been following the law appropriately and correctly. 

Their job isn't to be cooperative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321886027.0" user="Indon_Dasani" delta="False">
    <text>So what you're saying is, there ain't no sunshine where the police have gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321901466.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>No?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321903307.0" user="Indon_Dasani" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose you didn't *explicitly* note that the investigation of the shooting wasn't under a freedom of information act provision itself.

I just wanted to make the pun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321916741.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>Oh. No, the shooting investigation itself has had something like 5,000 Sunshine Law requests, all of which have been denied pursuant to 610.100.2

I think the ACLU and AP have sued, but they aren't going to win. The section is pretty clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321917595.0" user="Indon_Dasani" delta="False">
    <text>Thus, there ain't no Sunshine where the police have gone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
