<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321869087.0" user="puzzleddaily" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of people are either willfully confusing the issue or misreading your comments. Granted, the connection's not as clear as a "I pulled the fire alarm" - "the fire alarm rings" connection, but surely having just committed a violent robbery influences your state of mind to some degree and those arguing otherwise are not adding anything of value to this discussion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321883818.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. I couldn't phrase it as succinctly as you did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322207848.0" user="Stuck_in_a_cubicle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but surely having just committed a violent robbery influences your state of mind

Does it influence it in such a way that you go from shoving a clerk for cigarettes to jumping through the window of an SUV of a cop and trying to fight him for his gun?

I can't wrap my mind around how people think it is more believable that the above happened instead of not. This is also choosing to believe that even after the cop told him he just wanted those two to move out of the street that Brown still chose to be wound up and do the above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324309790.0" user="roughneck91" delta="False">
    <text>Is it not possible that Brown had a defensive mindset, after what happened at the convenient store... Thinking that the cop was following up on it? Even though the cop had only asked him to move out of the street, if I had just done what it appeared that he did, I would be nervous if an officer was talking to me. To add more, I would've just done what he had asked in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324318416.0" user="Stuck_in_a_cubicle" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, you would be nervous. I would be nervous, too. The question is, though: how probable is it that Brown *jumped through the window of an SUV, fought with a police officer, and then tried to grab his gun* all because he was nervous. As I said, this is excluding the fact the cop had already told him that he just wanted Brown and friend to get out of the street. Because, lets face it, when you take that into account, the scenario seems even less likely.

Basically, it is a **huge** leap that Brown was so nervous from shoving a guy for cigars (repeat those last 9 words before this next part) that he tried to fight a cop for his gun even though the cop said he only asked him to move out of the street.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324342194.0" user="roughneck91" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, there are many different reports out right now. From what I have read, they didn't say anything about him jumping in the window. But, there was an altercation that ended up with the both of them falling into the open officer's door. A FACT though is that one shot was fired inside the car. Is it probable that the officer said fuck it, I'm gonna shoot this guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326959143.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>I can't wrap my mind around someone committing a violent robbery, and ten minutes later while still carrying the stolen goods, refusing to stop walking in the middle of the street when a cop tells him to.  Refusing to just walk 15 feet over to a sidewalk.  That is a level of arrogance, stupidity and rebellion against police that is simply stunning.  WHO does that?  Really.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
