<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321824125.0" user="TitoTheMidget" delta="False">
    <text>Here's the thing about that:

The video shows him paying for the cigars he allegedly stole. He then tried to buy more, but didn't have enough money. Then you see the cashier come out from behind the counter, there's some shoving, but you don't know what's being said. What you clearly see is Brown handing the cashier money.

The owners of the store have gone on record that neither they nor any of their employees called the police about the matter, so whatever happened, they obviously didn't feel it was important enough to report as a robbery. The video was requested apropos of nothing by the police department. Given those circumstances, I'd say they were most likely looking for a reason that he was shot after he was already shot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322099610.0" user="twoVices" delta="False">
    <text>upvoted for visibility.  I'm not able to investigate whether this is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322116893.0" user="DarxusC" delta="False">
    <text>References are nice: http://www.addictinginfo.org/2014/08/18/ferguson-pd-busted/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322127822.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>Just to be clear, you're alleging some sort of massive conspiracy complete with falsified video evidence, dispatch tapes, dispatch logs, police reports, and other evidence, as well as coercion of a witness into testifying that Mr. Brown robbed the business, and other witnesses to describing Mr. Brown?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324182720.0" user="DarxusC" delta="False">
    <text>No conspiracy.  Some concerned citizen apparently called from the shop.  The cops watched the video, and saw what they wanted to see - theft - instead of what actually happened - purchase.  The shop employees never called the cops, because there wasn't a problem:  http://www.addictinginfo.org/2014/08/18/ferguson-pd-busted/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326992783.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/ferguson-police-name-michael-brown

So is his friend Dorian and Dorian's lawyer also mistaken?  Since they both admitted that Brown robbed the store.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322142199.0" user="onafarawaybeach" delta="False">
    <text>Not true: http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2014/08/report-convenience-store-manager-terrified-of-being-murdered-by-stores-customers/

&amp;gt;“The convenience store where the robbery took place was boarded up, but open for business on Friday. A store manager, who declined to give his name, said he fears for his life and pleaded with reporters not to suggest that he called police.

&amp;gt;““It’s very dangerous,” he said. “They kill us if they think we are responsible. People don’t understand that.””
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322153432.0" user="TitoTheMidget" delta="False">
    <text>I trust an article from The Gateway Pundit about as much as you would trust one from AlterNet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322163306.0" user="onafarawaybeach" delta="False">
    <text>It's a summary from other more trusted sources and they're linked to. Please take at least a second to read something before dismissing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27326972478.0" user="throwaway7145" delta="False">
    <text>http://documents.latimes.com/police-report-michael-brown-case/

Here is the released police report on the robbery.  Another witness was the one who called the police, but the store clerk definitely said he was robbed when the police showed up.  Brown's friend who was with him has admitted to the FBI that Brown stole the cigars, according to his own lawyer.  I can't believe that anyone is even trying to dispute this.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
