<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321887561.0" user="officerkondo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated.

How can you know if excessive force was used until the matter has been thoroughly investigated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321895103.0" user="Thorax123" delta="False">
    <text>Key words: "I believe"

I never said, "I know"
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321896758.0" user="officerkondo" delta="False">
    <text>And what is the basis for the belief in the absence of a thorough investigation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322166341.0" user="stinatown" delta="False">
    <text>The six bullet holes in an unarmed man is a start.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322187686.0" user="officerkondo" delta="False">
    <text>Prisoners are unarmed. Is there no cause for prison guards to have weapons?

Would one bullet hole have indicated excessive force?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322217091.0" user="stinatown" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Would one bullet hole have indicated excessive force?

Maybe, maybe not. You asked what made someone (not me, by the way) believe that **excessive** force was used. I offered that six shots would lead someone to believe the force was excessive, especially if the target is not armed and therefore not shooting back. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322365282.0" user="Pwnzerfaust" delta="False">
    <text>Consider the following scenario.

You are an average sized police officer, perhaps 5'8", 160 lbs (I don't know Wilson's actual height and weight, but used a typical size for an adult male). You are engaged in a confrontation with a male civilian, standing over six feet tall and weighing over two hundred pounds. You are well aware that if you and he were to engage in a hand to hand fight, there's a good chance you'd lose,  and even if you don't, serious injury is all but guaranteed. Now suppose that individual is charging at you.

You are armed with a 9mm service pistol. You know, as all officers do, that a single 9mm round is unlikely to immediately neutralize a person, especially not a large person.

You fear for your safety or possibly your life. 

What do you do? Do you shoot once and hope for the best, or do you shoot until you are certain the threat is neutralized? 

Note that I'm not saying that this is definitely what happened but it is a possibility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322571690.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>Another point that for some reason keeps on getting ignored / neglected, is the non-lethal (or less lethal) means officers have at their disposal to handle situations like this.  Tasers, Batons, the close combat takedowns and techniques, etc. are all good examples of options that law enforcement should resort to (or at least attempt) before drawing their gun vs **ANY** unarmed suspect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322804823.0" user="Pwnzerfaust" delta="False">
    <text>Tasers aren't guaranteed to instantly incapacitate. The others require closing to hand to hand combat, which is exceptionally dangerous, especially against someone that outclasses you in size and weight. There's only one tool in a police officer's possession that is guaranteed to neutralize a threatening agent rapidly, and that's the gun and its ability to shoot a bunch of times. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324457631.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>No they aren't but it would be nice if officers at least TRIED to de-escalate situations like this rather then simply dumping rounds into the person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27324479143.0" user="Pwnzerfaust" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know they didn't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327253921.0" user="Ashendarei" delta="False">
    <text>In this specific case we don't know yet whether or not the officer tried, but it's a very visible trend in the recent police interaction stories where the officers have abandoned almost entirely any effort to de-escalate.

Now, I don't mean to suggest that all officers are like this, but we are exposed to more and more of it because it's news (in today's media).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
