<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321860522.0" user="drnc" delta="False">
    <text>These are the following problesm I have with the release of the footage.  

The first is the tape is incomplete.  A new tape has come out which seems to show Brown paying for a purchase.  I don't want to speculate too much, but the owner never called the police and the police haven't charged Dorian Johnson with a crime.  Johnson does say that Brown took cigarellos, but this still doesn't really clear up what happened.  I really wish this tape had audio.  

The second issue is the timing of the tape.  I know you've heard this before.  The police said they were holding a press conference to name the officer who committed the offense, which they did, but then they added the tape without anyone knowing it was coming.  

Which is my third issue.  Literally nobody saw it coming.  And this includes Missouri Highway Patrol Captain Ron Johnson, who was supposed to be in charge of Ferguson, Missouri at the time.  Ferguson Police Chief Thomas Jackson broke the chain of command.  Even Governor Jay Nixon was not happy about the way this was handled.

And finally my fourth issue is that this really does not seem like the robbery had anything to do with the interaction between Brown and the officer.  The video was released on the same day the police named the officer, but Chief Thomas Jackson would not answer any questions.  A day later, at a second press conference, he answered that the officer did not know anything about robbery.  Then there was a friend of the officer's claiming that he did hear about the robbery on the radio and turned around.  It's a very conflicting story which is constantly being retconned.  

The only way this robbery video is relevant is if the officer actually did hear about the robbery and turned around.  Many people have speculated this to be true, and then it was confirmed by one semi-anonymous friend of the officer.  This is about as relevant as releasing his toxicology report and announcing he had marijuana in his system.  Which you might think is relevant.  But a lot of people, myself included, would say this is about as disgusting as releasing risque photos of a rape victim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321896173.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Literally nobody saw it coming. And this includes Missouri Highway Patrol Captain Ron Johnson, who was supposed to be in charge of Ferguson, Missouri at the time. Ferguson Police Chief Thomas Jackson broke the chain of command. Even Governor Jay Nixon was not happy about the way this was handled.

Ummm... The Missouri State Highway Patrol was not, is not, and has never been in charge of the Ferguson Police Department. The governor does not have the power to remove a Chief of Police and replace him. Ever. Under any circumstances.

There is no way for a Chief to break the chain of command. He's at the top, he can do whatever he wants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321952371.0" user="SuB2007" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is about as relevant as releasing his toxicology report and announcing he had marijuana in his system. 

I agree 100%. Having marijuana in his system shows his disregard for the law when it is convenient for him. So does jaywalking and refusing to respect the officer's request to get onto the sidewalk. While neither of these things justify shooting someone, it very much speaks to the likelihood of certain actions by the man who was shot. 

There are conflicting statements about what happened when Michael Brown was killed. One witness (the officer) is saying that he had no regard for the officer's authority and went for his gun or otherwise physically attacked him, and another witness saying that Brown was compliant and was shot in cold blood. With no camera there is no way to know what happened, but it makes sense to examine the likelihood of both of those scenarios in deciding which witness is more credible. Blatant disregard for the law, either by robbery or smoking marijuana, makes it somewhat more likely that Michael Brown showed disregard for the law in his interaction with the officer.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
