<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321987970.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>The police officer didn't know about the robbery or that the person shot was the suspect according to the police chief. 

[link](http://www.cnn.com/2014/08/15/us/missouri-teen-shooting/)

The officer stopped him because he was walking down the street blocking traffic. People got angry at the fact that the police department released the tape just before releasing the name of the shooting officer and because the tape had no connection to the shooting. If the tape had no connection to why the officer shot the kid, why release it at all expect to try to turn public opinion.

The outrage is not over whether or not the kid ever committed a crime or not, the outrage is over whether or not this police officer used excessive force against an unarmed man. The outrage has intensified when protesting has created a police state where many core American rights have apparently been suspended and the cops are taking away the right to assemble and freedom of the press.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322011399.0" user="damn_yank" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The police officer didn't know about the robbery or that the person shot was the suspect according to the police chief.

That may not be true. 

Reports are coming out that while Wilson didn't know about the robbery during the initial confrontation, he did get a radio transmission describing the robbery and the suspects which prompted him to confront Wilson and Johnson a second time. It does explain eyewitness reports that Wilson backed up his car after initially driving off.

From http://www.cnn.com/2014/08/19/us/ferguson-michael-brown-dueling-narratives/

"In Josie's version, Wilson may have heard a call about a strong-arm robbery and saw the young men carrying something that might have been stolen cigars."

Still need more info. Allegedly there are over a dozen eyewitnesses who back up the police report.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322075130.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>okay, you are reaching here. The article clearly states that "Josie" was an unidentified person calling into a radio show. This in no way is a credible witness. 

Even if the police officer had heard about the robbery, and saw Brown holding a cigar, AND somehow had super vision that allowed him to see the brand of cigar, he didn't have enough evidence in the matter. Swisher Sweets are probably the most common cigar in the USA and are extremely commonly used by black people. 

Even if Wilson had all that evidence does it justify shooting an unarmed man in the middle of the street 6 times including twice in the head. Are you really telling me you believe that the police officer after shooting Brown twice hadn't incapacitated the teen? three, times, four? According to the radio show person Michael Brown has an insane and crazed super villain that can take several shots to stop. Not only that but just the fact that the police officer shot an unarmed man in the head twice shows that he used excessive force.
 
&amp;gt;Still need more info. Allegedly there are over a dozen eyewitnesses who back up the police report.

What we know so far is that there was an altercation with the officer sitting in his squad car and Michael Brown outside the car. The medical accounts say Wilson had swelling in the face implying that he was struck and Brown was shot 6 times including twice in the head. 

I think it's safe to assume that Wilson did not call into the police station before going back to confront Brown because we would have heard of this by now. The police departments actions imply that Wilson was in the wrong and this is why people are outraged by the release of the footage</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322093180.0" user="damn_yank" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Even if the police officer had heard about the robbery, and saw Brown holding a cigar, AND somehow had super vision that allowed him to see the brand of cigar, he didn't have enough evidence in the matter. 

I disagree. If the radio report included suspect descriptions, including a description of someone unusually tall and large, it would not be unreasonable for a cop to investigate.

&amp;gt; Even if Wilson had all that evidence does it justify shooting an unarmed man in the middle of the street 6 times including twice in the head.

If the man is acting erratically and charging him, then that justifies shooting him until he stops. 

&amp;gt; Are you really telling me you believe that the police officer after shooting Brown twice hadn't incapacitated the teen? three, times, four?

If the officer missed, then yes. He would have been justified in shooting more. The autopsy details gunshots on Brown's arm and to his head. I assume that the shots to the arm would not stop brown and the last two were to the head. Only two shots hit Brown in a place that would have stopped him.

Additionally, had Wilson shot a man who had stopped and actually surrendered, I'd assume all of the shots would have hit Brown. The fact that only two hit him lead me to believe that Brown was a moving target, not standing still surrendering.

&amp;gt; I think it's safe to assume that Wilson did not call into the police station before going back to confront Brown because we would have heard of this by now. The police departments actions imply that Wilson was in the wrong and this is why people are outraged by the release of the footage

Or that the police department is trying to follow procedure and investigate the case thoroughly before releasing information as to not taint the investigation. 

The police have to be thorough, and rightfully so. I look forward to what the FBI finds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322122808.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If the officer missed, then yes. He would have been justified in shooting more. The autopsy details gunshots on Brown's arm and to his head. I assume that the shots to the arm would not stop brown and the last two were to the head. Only two shots hit Brown in a place that would have stopped him.

The autopsy showed Brown having been shot 6 times total all on the front of his body, twice to the head. You don't have a strong understanding of the story.

Also, even if the last two were the ones to the head, he got shot 4 times before that. Us tall people feel just as much pain as you shorter people (I'm 6'5). 4 gun shots is enough for someone to bleed out. There is no way Brown was not incapacitated at that point. 

Okay but the police department tainted the investigation by releasing the security footage of the robbery because now Brown's accomplice will not be charged for that crime. This was my whole point.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322126612.0" user="damn_yank" delta="False">
    <text>If the first four shots were superficial and on the arm, he might not have been incapacitated at all. That's especially true if you include adrenaline into the mix. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322148469.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but all known accounts say that this is not the case. All public accounts say that Brown said "stop shooting, I'm unarmed." 

Also, even if Brown was not incapacitated by four shots he probably didn't pose much of a threat to the officer. You seem to be putting your own judgments on this case. You are also stretching a bit to try and say that adrenaline kicked in and caused him to keep pursuing the officer. Like I said, you are painting this person as a crazed zombie or something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322165699.0" user="damn_yank" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah but all known accounts say that this is not the case. All public accounts say that Brown said "stop shooting, I'm unarmed."

The operative word is "known". A local reporter stated that the police had over a dozen witnesses who corroborate Wilson's story. Take it with a grain of salt, but I'm certain not all eyewitness accounts have been made public yet. 

&amp;gt; Also, even if Brown was not incapacitated by four shots he probably didn't pose much of a threat to the officer.

That's a very big assumption. The man was 6'4" and weighed 300lbs and was allegedly charging Wilson. Are you trying to tell me that isn't much if a threat? 

Are you kidding me?

Any reasonable person would certainly consider that very threatening, especially if your gunfire didn't stop him initially. You don't have to be a crazed zombie to be in an adrenaline rush. People ignore all sorts of injuries when the fight or flight mechanism kicks in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27322248019.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>yes but my point is that you are making assumptions based on testimony you haven't heard and may or may not exist. 

Why would the police department release the video tape and not the other corroborating stories? This police department has already proven that they are poorly run and inept. 

The story the way you construct it just doesn't add up. Let's say the people who have actually come forward were lying (I don't know what motivation the girl would have to lie but whatever). At least one bullet was fired by the police officer from inside the car and at least one was fired from out of the car. Lets say Brown was trying to force the officer to stay in the car and trying to grab his gun. Now the officer somehow fires at Brown. Whether or not the bullet hits Brown it gives the officer enough time to get out of the car. Now, if your story is true  Brown would have charged the officer after the officer got out of the car and the officer would have hit Brown with 3-4 bullets and a 5th bullet in the head. First off, if you think a person is still running forward after getting hit with several bullets you are insane. Secondly, how does the final (and second shot to the head) fit into the equation? 

For the officer to get out the the car Brown would most likely have to had ran or backed up or got shot. If Brown were crazed, why would he let the officer get all the way out of the car and point a gun at him first? Crazy people don't work like that. 

I don't know. It's hard to say. To me, after seeing countless video of police losing their minds on people around the country, shooting and killing a handcuffed man in Oakland, repeatedly punching a handcuffed elderly lady in the face in LA, the cop that beat the handcuffed lady who was in custody, I have to think that the stress of that job makes many officers lose control in high pressure situations. Who wouldn't. 

I also feel that there is a situation where police officers allow the power of the job warp their judgement. I have a friend that was defending his friend who was getting wrongfully arrested and the officer threatened to arrest him and murder him in a jail cell. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
