<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144976262.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ebcee/cmv_we_could_better_manage_agricultural_resources/">
    <title>CMV: We could better manage agricultural resources if safe appetite suppressants were recommended (even supplied) by the FDA.</title>
    <original_poster>Soycrates</original_poster>
    <original_post>If the government began to suggest that appetite suppressants were a normal, healthy, and even recommended part of the daily diet for teens and adults of all ages (save extreme seniority), we would consume less agricultural resources on average, learn to better manage these resources to reduce starvation and hunger (when applied with humanitarian interest groups), the US populace would spend less money on healthcare, and people would choose their meals more wisely, opting for fresh and non-greasy food choices.

This is not motivated by a hatred or disdain for the image of people considered overweight or obese - some people would still appear to be overweight due to genetic and environmental factors, as well as the possibility for lack of exercise - and should not be considered a "the world would be better without fat people" opinion. The world would be better if we could learn to eat primarily for sustenance instead of pleasure. [Being overweight has been identified as a cause of cancer](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overweight#Health_effects), and is projected to overtake smoking as the primary cause of cancer in developed countries as cases of cancer linked to smoking dwindle. Our health and finances would greatly improve.

We would reduce the amount of environmental damage that is caused by the agricultural industries as well, preserving land and water and creating a culture that could more easily foster eco-friendly practices and biodiversity.

The only people not expected to take appetite suppressants would be those whose RMR (Resting Metabolic Rate) was below normal.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27327481017.0" user="steinvanzwoll" delta="False">
    <text>I think a very dangerous aspect of this idea is that people might take too many pills and become seriously underweight. We are already having trouble with eating disorders, chemical aid would make it a lot worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27328311398.0" user="Soycrates" delta="False">
    <text>If you're overdosing on appetite suppressants, losing weight would not really be your first concern. You'd develop other health issues due to overdosing first. 

Just because some people can't handle moderation doesn't mean something should be revoked from all people. We haven't outlawed fast food or alcohol, for instance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27328353139.0" user="steinvanzwoll" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you're overdosing on appetite suppressants, losing weight would not really be your first concern. You'd develop other health issues due to overdosing first.

I wasn't really talking about overdosing. I meant something like taking four a day instead of two, which, on the long run, will lead to serious malnourishment.

&amp;gt; Just because some people can't handle moderation doesn't mean something should be revoked from all people. We haven't outlawed fast food or alcohol, for instance.

There is a difference between outlawing something and not promoting something.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
