<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144976262.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ebcee/cmv_we_could_better_manage_agricultural_resources/">
    <title>CMV: We could better manage agricultural resources if safe appetite suppressants were recommended (even supplied) by the FDA.</title>
    <original_poster>Soycrates</original_poster>
    <original_post>If the government began to suggest that appetite suppressants were a normal, healthy, and even recommended part of the daily diet for teens and adults of all ages (save extreme seniority), we would consume less agricultural resources on average, learn to better manage these resources to reduce starvation and hunger (when applied with humanitarian interest groups), the US populace would spend less money on healthcare, and people would choose their meals more wisely, opting for fresh and non-greasy food choices.

This is not motivated by a hatred or disdain for the image of people considered overweight or obese - some people would still appear to be overweight due to genetic and environmental factors, as well as the possibility for lack of exercise - and should not be considered a "the world would be better without fat people" opinion. The world would be better if we could learn to eat primarily for sustenance instead of pleasure. [Being overweight has been identified as a cause of cancer](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overweight#Health_effects), and is projected to overtake smoking as the primary cause of cancer in developed countries as cases of cancer linked to smoking dwindle. Our health and finances would greatly improve.

We would reduce the amount of environmental damage that is caused by the agricultural industries as well, preserving land and water and creating a culture that could more easily foster eco-friendly practices and biodiversity.

The only people not expected to take appetite suppressants would be those whose RMR (Resting Metabolic Rate) was below normal.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27327202407.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The premise of this is that there isn't enough food to feed everyone.

[There is more than enough food to feed everyone on Earth.](http://www.worldhunger.org/articles/Learn/world%20hunger%20facts%202002.htm#Does_the_world_produce_enough_food_to_feed_everyone)

Further, we are getting so much better at farming, that [the amount of land devoted to agriculture is declining even with food consumption rising.](http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/AG.LND.AGRI.ZS/countries/1W?display=graph)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327228704.0" user="Soycrates" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I don't think you need to believe there isn't enough food to feed everyone to think that if we used less resources, we would find the time to better manage them. Even though there currently is enough food to feed the world's population, yet millions of tons of viable sustenance is thrown out by corporations each day, that still doesn't say that if we had more food to go around, we'd have the exact same number of human persons starving to death. I think it's reasonable to suggest that hunger would reduce given better management of food sources, *including* consuming less. Ideally, we would both eat less and learn not to waste food for consumerist/capitalist reasons.

And even though the amount of land devoted to agriculture may be declining, a further decline in the amount of resources used would only be a good thing, not a bad thing.

Just because we have enough in theory to go around doesn't mean we can't use multiple different approaches to reaching global food security - the approach I'm suggesting here is to *simply eat less*. This doesn't have to go against other approaches; they can be used simultaneously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327306509.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think it's reasonable to suggest that hunger would reduce given better management of food sources, including consuming less. Ideally, we would both eat less and learn not to waste food for consumerist/capitalist reasons.

The cause of mass starvation is that there are men with guns between the people who need food and the food that we want to give them.  Your proposal does nothing to solve the men with guns problem.

Further, and more to the point, you presume that these appetite suppressants are perfectly healthy?  Which appetite suppressants are you suggesting exactly?  As far as I'm aware, the ones that are actually effective have some really bad problems like causing heart attacks (like fenfluramine) or being highly addictive and causing heart attacks (like nicotine).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327334747.0" user="Soycrates" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The cause of mass starvation is that there are men with guns between the people who need food and the food that we want to give them. Your proposal does nothing to solve the men with guns problem.

That's one of the bigger causes, but it's not the only cause, and there's no reason why we can't fight the problem from all angles instead of just one angle.

&amp;gt; Further, and more to the point, you presume that these appetite suppressants are perfectly healthy?

It's not a "presumption", it is implicit in my title that given *if* safe appetite suppressants are available, *then* they should be recommended by the FDA. Heart attacks and addictiveness are linked to almost every pharmaceutical product on the market, written on the massive ingredients and side effects pamphlet you'd receive with purchase. The minor risks of most pharmeceutical products does not outweigh the benefits - take birth control or anti-depressants, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327348930.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If the government began to suggest that appetite suppressants were a normal, healthy, and even recommended part of the daily diet for teens and adults of all ages 

This is phrased as if they *are* part of a healthy diet and you think the government should espouse that.

And the risks of fenfluramine and nicotine are not minor.  They increase your risk of heart problems [a lot](http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM199708283370901).

And this is to be expected.  An effective appetite suppressant has to very substantially alter your metabolism.  That's not generally a good idea.

&amp;gt;That's one of the bigger causes, but it's not the only cause, and there's no reason why we can't fight the problem from all angles instead of just one angle.

Even granting your premise that this would reduce food consumption in the US, it doesn't follow that it would drop food prices worldwide.  Apart from reasonably nonperishable items like salt and cooking oil, food markets are remarkably local.  Shipping fresh produce from the US to the places where mass starvation exists (war torn parts of West Africa and North Korea mostly) is incredibly expensive.  And in the case of both places, you'll get shot/robbed.

Perversely, dropping food consumption and demand in the US might lead to more cropland being used in the rest of the world.  The US is a huge leader in agricultural technology.  A big chunk of the improvements that have let world cropland usage fall come from developments in the US market.  If the US market became smaller, and the need to efficiently use cropland here dropped, there would be substantially less innovation in agriculture worldwide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327631754.0" user="sweetsails59" delta="False">
    <text>Fenfluramine isn't in use anymore. Phentermine has been isolated from the Fen-Phen combination and is used either by itself or with Topamax now. It's a relatively healthy option (compared to the side effects of obesity), however, it has a tendency to lose potency over time. Thus, it wouldn't work long term in a situation where the participants are putting in minimal effort. You couldn't just recommend it to everyone like you do with a multivitamin or aspirin. You would have to ensure healthy habits and behaviors in participants for any of these medications to effectively work long term. When does it cost more money to develop/market/advertise a miracle drug and monitor patients as opposed to just investing in agriculture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27328307575.0" user="Soycrates" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When does it cost more money to develop/market/advertise a miracle drug and monitor patients as opposed to just investing in agriculture?

Money is not more important than the Earth's finite resources.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27328449675.0" user="sweetsails59" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, it's not. However, money has to come from somewhere and investors aren't exactly going to be clamoring for the more intensive, radical, and expensive option. Why bother investing in reduced consumption when there is already [so much waste](http://endhunger.org/PDFs/2014/USDA-FoodLoss-2014.pdf)? Surely there would be much more interest, both financially and ethically, for investors to find ways to get involved in agricultural policies that minimize waste?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27328313332.0" user="foolsfool" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it is implicit in my title that given if safe appetite suppressants are available

The best appetite "suppressant" is whole foods. Eat carbs as they are meant to be, along with lots of fiber to fill the belly and move along the system so the nutrients can be fully absorbed.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
