<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144976262.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ebcee/cmv_we_could_better_manage_agricultural_resources/">
    <title>CMV: We could better manage agricultural resources if safe appetite suppressants were recommended (even supplied) by the FDA.</title>
    <original_poster>Soycrates</original_poster>
    <original_post>If the government began to suggest that appetite suppressants were a normal, healthy, and even recommended part of the daily diet for teens and adults of all ages (save extreme seniority), we would consume less agricultural resources on average, learn to better manage these resources to reduce starvation and hunger (when applied with humanitarian interest groups), the US populace would spend less money on healthcare, and people would choose their meals more wisely, opting for fresh and non-greasy food choices.

This is not motivated by a hatred or disdain for the image of people considered overweight or obese - some people would still appear to be overweight due to genetic and environmental factors, as well as the possibility for lack of exercise - and should not be considered a "the world would be better without fat people" opinion. The world would be better if we could learn to eat primarily for sustenance instead of pleasure. [Being overweight has been identified as a cause of cancer](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overweight#Health_effects), and is projected to overtake smoking as the primary cause of cancer in developed countries as cases of cancer linked to smoking dwindle. Our health and finances would greatly improve.

We would reduce the amount of environmental damage that is caused by the agricultural industries as well, preserving land and water and creating a culture that could more easily foster eco-friendly practices and biodiversity.

The only people not expected to take appetite suppressants would be those whose RMR (Resting Metabolic Rate) was below normal.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27327244908.0" user="ulyssessword" delta="False">
    <text>It would have a negligible effect on agricultural production.  Keep in mind that I'm doing a rough calculation, but it should illustrate why:

To run some numbers, ~30% of Americans are obese.  As a rough estimate, let's say that that is 200 pounds in extra weight.  I didn't find numbers on how many are overweight, but let's say it's another 30% that could lose 100 pounds.  100 million obese people * 200 pounds + 100 million overweight people * 100 pounds = 30 billion pounds of excess person-weight in the US.  

1 pound of food doesn't turn into one pound of fat.  I don't know the exact numbers, but cows get up to 1:8 feed conversion (this ignores the cost of maintaining their body), so let's say it takes 4 pounds of food to make 1 pound of excess weight.  That makes 120 billion pounds of food that went into creating our current obesity.

The US corn production is 250 million metric tons per year, or approximately 500 billion pounds.  

Excess body weight in the US represents stored energy equivalent to a quarter of year's harvest of a single crop (the most common one by a good margin).  Therefore, getting rid of that stored energy would free up an equivalent amount, spread out over however many years the weight loss takes.

I agree with the health benefits, but it would not have a significant impact on agriculture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327260076.0" user="Soycrates" delta="False">
    <text>Again, as stated in the original comments, this is not about obesity; I think you are addressing issues other than the ones I'm bringing up because of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27327277119.0" user="ulyssessword" delta="False">
    <text>It's about how much food is eaten, right?  If everyone ate a healthy amount, it would not have a significant effect on agriculture.  The best thing I could find for estimating how much extra food people eat is the obesity figures, so I used them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
