<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332133156.0" user="tinkerbetter" delta="False">
    <text>Have you considered that you may be  focusing on the events that confirm your opinion while subconsciously dismissing those that would infirm your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27332270186.0" user="hastyanon" delta="False">
    <text>Possibly, I have only worked in 8 different offices. It isn't exactly a controlled study.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27332288423.0" user="tinkerbetter" delta="False">
    <text>I wanted to say that the number of offices you've worked in may not be as relevant to your opinion as much as the stereotypes you are looking for when you're interacting to coworkers. It's called [confirmation bias](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias). You attribute bitchiness and disagreements to women, while you consider men productive and professional. You only consciously register events that confirm your preconceived notions.

Edit:I've worked in 3 offices. I can tell you the women I worked with (and from other departments) have been very cooperative and supportive, while the men were always complaining and slacking off. This shows that I manifest positive sexism towards women (since I attribute predominantly positive traits to women) and it might say something about the individuals I worked with. It doesn't say anything about all the women and men out there or prove that men should be excluded from the workforce due to lack of productivity. 

Your opinion of the women you worked with does not reflect the gender as a whole, but it does reflect your view of women, and should not be used to restructure companies/the workforce.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
