<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1454822724.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/o25wec/cmv_there_is_no_compelling_reason_for_me_to_come/">
    <title>CMV: There is no compelling reason for me to come out as bisexual to my close friends and family</title>
    <original_poster>LexVeritas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Happy Pride month, all! This is something I've been thinking about for a while and I would love your input. 

I am a cisgender male who is bisexual (probably Kinsey 1-2, significant preference for women) and heteroromantic. While I occasionally enjoy sex with men, I have no interest in emotional or physical intimacy or romance with them--I don't even like kissing guys, basically I'm just into cock. I also enjoy sex with women, and have a strong urge towards intimacy and romance with female partners.

I've come out or mentioned my bisexuality to some acquaintances, mainly random internet strangers and sexual partners of both genders. However, I haven't brought it up with any of my close friends or family members, for the following reasons.

First: my sex life is my business. I haven't told any of my close friends or family members that I like feet either; it's irrelevant to those relationships. 

Second: I have no interest in dating men or i.e. making out with them at bars, and therefore don't feel that being closeted is at all restrictive or oppressive. I will never need to vent about the way a man I'm dating treats me, or about a man I'm crushing on, etc. like I sometimes do with women. 

Third: If I did come out, it would require explanation of all of the above. I really don't feel any need ever to say the words "Hi mom, I'm bisexual but heteroromantic, that means I sometimes like to suck cock but I'm not going to bring any boyfriends home to meet you." I certainly will have this conversation with my eventual spouse because they will be a core part of my sex life, but I don't feel that discussing my sexual preferences with family and friends would be at all liberating or fulfilling. 

EDIT because I forgot to include it: Fourth: The LGBTQ+ "scene" doesn't appeal to me at all. I will happily wear a rainbow shirt and go to a parade and I have many friends of all persuasions, but I'm not interested in putting a rainbow flag at my house or habitually hanging out at gay bars (though I'd have no problem going to one if a group of friends wanted to, and have done so before). Equal rights, preventing discrimination, AIDS research, and safe sex are all important issues to me, but not more so than i.e. climate change, criminal justice reform, or funding education. If I came out, there would be at least implicit pressure to participate in the LGBTQ+ community; I don't consider this a core part of my identity and so don't feel any desire to do so. 

While I'm fully aware that coming out or not is my own choice and prerogative, I am curious to hear your thoughts on this. Thanks all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37136168568.0" user="mildlunacy" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I find the 'just sex' thing to be..... not so clear cut. I'm a mostly heteroromantic bisexual female.... I used to want to qualify that even more, but I've come to believe that essentially no one cares if I'm demisexual, and me being bi at all is pretty theoretical 'cause I don't date *or* have casual sex, so on the one hand, I understand your point... But even so, calling your bisexuality essentially a kink is really iffy to me. And I'm not part of the LGBT scene or community either.

It feels dismissive to the subject-- of both other people's feelings and your own-- to say it's equivalent to liking feet. Further, I feel like it's too close to the sort of behavior the 'bad closeted' self-hating queer men are famous for (compartmentalizing, dismissing, acting out total straightness). I'd feel uncomfortable with doing that on purpose, while also not feeling like I *have* to go out of my way to come out, either. It's just about not hiding it or making it an issue. If the subject comes up (and it does), I feel like withholding this information gets a connotation like you're ashamed or you think being bi isn't important or normal or OK. Basically, society still sucks, and it's a sign of privilege that makes me personally uncomfortable to hide this when you're able. Like, why is it so often queer men saying they would rather not come out, and it's just sex? Sometimes gay men say this, too. I feel like there absolutely has to be something going on here which is deeper.

Maybe I'm wrong. Like I said, seeing primarily straight-passing white men have this attitude just makes me suspicious, even though essentially I'm in a similar situation and can relate to the reasoning. I just think even if it *is* only sexual, that doesn't mean it's private in the sense that it's automatically associated with the act of sex in conversation, unlike talking about ball gags and fetishes. I mean, I dunno, I just feel there's a double standard. You wouldn't feel conflicted at all about saying you like big breasts on women in a very casual setting, right, without expecting people to then visualize you in a sexual context with actual big breasted women. If you said you're bi, no one's going to think about sex. If you said you just like checking out a man's package, even then.... depends on how you say it and to whom. Fact is, it's society-level homophobia which creates a double standard here, but you can avoid it depending on how you put it. 

Also, one still has good reason to show respect and support for one's potential sexual partners and do one's small part to increase awareness and visibility. It's arguably even more important now for people only tangential or adjacent to the main LGBT community (read: straight-passing men in particular) to communicate with others and show that they're still 'safe' and 'normal'.

Basically, I don't think you'd have to explain it if you came out. Or rather, put it this way: what is it that's the problem if you let people simply assume you're an average, 'normal' bisexual? Like, whatever that barrier is, are you *sure* it has nothing to do with anyone's homophobia that you don't want to deal with, because you think it's not worth it for you? Because that's fine, but it's a different rationale. Basically, you've created these excuses and they may even be 'true', technically, but society still doesn't accept bisexuality that deeply, and so any such decision is automatically suspect if you claim it just doesn't matter or doesn't make a difference. It definitely matters, one way or another, and basically I think it's privilege to not *have* to deal with people's reactions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37136733239.0" user="LexVeritas" delta="False">
    <text>You make some really good points here. Not all are relevant, but some hit home. I'll go in order.

I have a high libido and no emotional requirement at all to enjoy sex. Of course sleeping with someone I'm emotionally connected to is way better than a random fling, but shitty pizza is still good pizza. I don't care at all about the bodies, faces, asses, or personalities of the guys I fuck--my erotic attraction is solely to the penis, which is why I compare it to feet. I don't mean to marginalize anyone else's sexuality; this is just the way I feel. 

That said, I am exactly the stereotype you sketch in your comment: a straight-passing white dude who compartmentalizes his bisexuality. Not ideal. But as I described in the OP, if I thought my bisexuality would influence other parts of my life, I wouldn't compartmentalize it. You say it makes you uncomfortable for me to compare my bisexuality to a kink, but... is an ethical penis fetish necessarily an oxymoron? In my heart &amp;amp; loins it feels more like a dirty thing I like to do than a core part of my identity, in the same mental drawer as liking shapely feet and dominating petite women.

Re: talking about sex in polite company, I absolutely would not voice a preference that specific to anyone but a current sexual partner who matches the description. I've actually noticed frequently that women tend to be much more open about their sexual experiences &amp;amp; preferences with their friends than men. The most specific I've gotten with my buddies is along the lines of "I'm an ass man" or "I prefer slender women." I have certainly never voiced my preference for small-breasted women (or domination, or feet) to my best friends. And I don't consider myself at all repressed, I'm happy to talk about sex in general all day long--it just wouldn't occur to me to have a conversation that detailed with my platonic friends. For what it's worth, if someone said to me "I prefer women with big breasts," I would absolutely picture them motorboating big ol' titties right away. This is maybe a demisexual vs. hypersexual thing.

Your fourth paragraph is accurate, but I'm afraid I'm not that altruistic. I also feel that I can be supportive and respectful of non-heterosexual men while still being closeted (a term that implies a level of restriction I don't feel) to my close friends &amp;amp; family.

I disagree with your last paragraph. Just saying "I'm bisexual" shouldn't necessarily be interpreted as "I'm bisexual and biromantic," but in today's world that's how it is. My family and friends are all very liberal and tolerant people, and I'm sure they would support me no matter what, but alas they're not at the point where they'd just say "ok cool" and leave it at that. It would be a discussion, and in order to remain honest in that discussion, I'd have to reveal things that I consider private--not because I'm afraid to share them, but because revealing them comes with unneeded complexity and frankly a ton of TMI.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37137097348.0" user="mildlunacy" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the in-depth response! I was thinking of adding an addendum saying 'there's no right or wrong here' but I was concerned I was supposed to straight up argue in a top-level comment, haha. Yes, I do think you can be an ethical penis fetishist, especially if you're self-aware. I actually feel the worst part about The Stereotype (that obviously doesn't apply to you) is the denial more than anything else. Denial is definitely not something I can support... though if you asked me why, I dunno if I have a good answer.

It's also interesting, in that my ideas of men talking about liking breasts and asses openly, over beers, come from movies.... Maybe that's outdated. Or dependent on social strata and/or culture more than gender. I've definitely overheard men sounding very crass in the company of other men (way more than my mild comment about breasts), so... I'm curious if they're all sitting there picturing it (how homoerotic!) I just assumed they weren't. But you're right, I wouldn't personally just by nature.

This whole thing about 'dirty thing' vs 'identity' just isn't clear-cut in a general sense. I mean, for someone to take their bisexuality seriously or publicly acknowledge it, it doesn't mean they are necessarily romantic. A lot of times, young, hypersexual hetero men aren't romantic at all (my impression from Tinder/et al) and yet they don't hide their proclivities. Plenty of gay guys also just wanna fuck and have never been in love/are fooling themselves even if they think they are. Sex is sex and men are men, from what I can see. But the straight men don't have to announce it, the gay men can't help it, and the straight-passing ones definitely generally don't center their identities around it because they don't have to. That's where privilege enters into it, for me. However, that's *in general*.

I hesitate to say this, but I get the impression that straight-passing masculinity, like whiteness, provides a certain amount of confidence that you can construct a comfortable identity that doesn't 'need' labels. I dunno, unless you're a nerd. Queer people, like nerds, must find that confidence through found community. It's not necessarily that they're more romantic than you, I guess. Even with women, there's a lot of out bisexuals who just want sex (often married female bisexuals, judging from the personals). I don't think it's usually like a tipping point of it becoming your identity as opposed to 'just sex'. I suppose you can argue that who you love influences your personality more than who you want to have sex with, but I'm not so sure about that. Many people are *really* fixated on sex, and use their kinks to define them (BDSM people, fetishists of all kinds, even pedophiles become fixated on it). Freud may be outdated and even discredited, but there's a reason he'd say something like that subconscious desires are what defines us. Making them conscious and being self-aware is one of the best counters. I think desire of any kind infiltrates your psyche more when you just let it lie. But yeah, orientation is definitely heavily about sex. It wasn't until recently that dating even became an option, for what it's worth.

Maybe as a demisexual, I'm a bit jaded, but I'd say most people are sexual and only secondarily romantic. So the orientation is definitely heavily driven by people's sexual behavior (in clubs and in bars, for example). It's simply that people were once persecuted and shamed for sexual deviancy, and had to band together to get leverage and also to get a pool of available partners since most people are straight. Basically, I suspect you're more normal than you think... for what it's worth. :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
