<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332136535.0" user="awesomeness0232" delta="False">
    <text>There is no superior gender when it comes to productivity, but there is certainly a difference in how men and women accomplish goals. You're right that this conflict in personality and how those who fit into the typical gender roles effect the way work gets done. Having conflicting approaches can certainly lead to a drop in productivity. However, it also leads to a drop in innovation. In a workplace with no conflict everything will run as smoothly as it can given the current circumstances, but a little conflict can result in creating better circumstances in which more work can actually be accomplished. Now obviously there is a limit to how much conflict you want in the workplace and this is why many businesses seek to limit or eliminate office romances and things of that nature. However, the fact that men and women tend to look at problems differently can go a long way toward making the system itself more efficient.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
