<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1454822724.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/o25wec/cmv_there_is_no_compelling_reason_for_me_to_come/">
    <title>CMV: There is no compelling reason for me to come out as bisexual to my close friends and family</title>
    <original_poster>LexVeritas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Happy Pride month, all! This is something I've been thinking about for a while and I would love your input. 

I am a cisgender male who is bisexual (probably Kinsey 1-2, significant preference for women) and heteroromantic. While I occasionally enjoy sex with men, I have no interest in emotional or physical intimacy or romance with them--I don't even like kissing guys, basically I'm just into cock. I also enjoy sex with women, and have a strong urge towards intimacy and romance with female partners.

I've come out or mentioned my bisexuality to some acquaintances, mainly random internet strangers and sexual partners of both genders. However, I haven't brought it up with any of my close friends or family members, for the following reasons.

First: my sex life is my business. I haven't told any of my close friends or family members that I like feet either; it's irrelevant to those relationships. 

Second: I have no interest in dating men or i.e. making out with them at bars, and therefore don't feel that being closeted is at all restrictive or oppressive. I will never need to vent about the way a man I'm dating treats me, or about a man I'm crushing on, etc. like I sometimes do with women. 

Third: If I did come out, it would require explanation of all of the above. I really don't feel any need ever to say the words "Hi mom, I'm bisexual but heteroromantic, that means I sometimes like to suck cock but I'm not going to bring any boyfriends home to meet you." I certainly will have this conversation with my eventual spouse because they will be a core part of my sex life, but I don't feel that discussing my sexual preferences with family and friends would be at all liberating or fulfilling. 

EDIT because I forgot to include it: Fourth: The LGBTQ+ "scene" doesn't appeal to me at all. I will happily wear a rainbow shirt and go to a parade and I have many friends of all persuasions, but I'm not interested in putting a rainbow flag at my house or habitually hanging out at gay bars (though I'd have no problem going to one if a group of friends wanted to, and have done so before). Equal rights, preventing discrimination, AIDS research, and safe sex are all important issues to me, but not more so than i.e. climate change, criminal justice reform, or funding education. If I came out, there would be at least implicit pressure to participate in the LGBTQ+ community; I don't consider this a core part of my identity and so don't feel any desire to do so. 

While I'm fully aware that coming out or not is my own choice and prerogative, I am curious to hear your thoughts on this. Thanks all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37134002943.0" user="dudemanwhoa" delta="False">
    <text>I mean from a strict need-to-know basis, yeah, but there are plenty of things I talk to my family and friends about that are "my business" and private. That's actually kind of the point of having friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37134025679.0" user="LexVeritas" delta="False">
    <text>Yes for sure. I'm also certain there are things that are "your business" that you don't discuss with them. 

I'm not saying I don't tell my friends *anything* private, just that I don't feel a need to disclose *this* private thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37134983939.0" user="PeakThis" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t talk about sex much with my friends, we are all straight. I’m curious where that comes from. Respect for your partner, taboo, perhaps they just won’t understand? It’s sort of like when you try and explain a situational joke and no one laughs and you go “oh you had to be there”

Words just can’t encapsulate all the little things that happened that made that moment special.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37136590220.0" user="LexVeritas" delta="False">
    <text>Same. I've talked about this a lot with friends of both genders--it seems like women are much more likely to get into detail about their sexual preferences &amp;amp; experiences than men are. (I assume you're a guy.) May have something to do with our ape-brain's possessiveness.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
