<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332464372.0" user="quadrapod" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure the paradoxical nature of dividing an office which is meant to be performing a single task into two, non communicating groups so that they can do their job more efficiently is not wasted on you.  Have you considered how these groups will treat each other though?  In general when you have a clear division in the workplace, and you're meant to pass work back and forth some clear animosity begins to build.  Think of all the times where you've heard something along the lines of "Fucking Accounting/HR/Sales/IT" when someone does something which ends in more work for people you work with or impedes their ability to do work.  In this case you're meant to be effectively the same office, you'll be interacting frequently despite the division and whereas before inter office politics would occasionally enter into things, here you almost guarantee they do by creating a clear demarcation.   This will be the case especially if you are right and the women's office is less efficient over all.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
