<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332331529.0" user="K-zi" delta="False">
    <text>Alienating men and women at work creates a huge communication gap between two parties who work together to reach a common goal. If it was segregation between two dept. where women are lets say in finance and men in marketing, it would still be feasible but when both work in same dept. the lack of communication will be costly. Considering that both parties are now segregated, I can imagine communicating will be more difficult and will be represented by the increase in costs. I can imagine more phone bills for one, as men and women try to communicate in different offices. Also, since men and women will not have a personal relation brainstorming will be a slow process which too will have its costs. Ideas that might have bounced around more freely will not be as easily let known; who knows how much loss that could cost. Overall, I feel the advantages are minimum and debatable if it even exists but the disadvantages are apparent and real.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
