<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1454822724.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/o25wec/cmv_there_is_no_compelling_reason_for_me_to_come/">
    <title>CMV: There is no compelling reason for me to come out as bisexual to my close friends and family</title>
    <original_poster>LexVeritas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Happy Pride month, all! This is something I've been thinking about for a while and I would love your input. 

I am a cisgender male who is bisexual (probably Kinsey 1-2, significant preference for women) and heteroromantic. While I occasionally enjoy sex with men, I have no interest in emotional or physical intimacy or romance with them--I don't even like kissing guys, basically I'm just into cock. I also enjoy sex with women, and have a strong urge towards intimacy and romance with female partners.

I've come out or mentioned my bisexuality to some acquaintances, mainly random internet strangers and sexual partners of both genders. However, I haven't brought it up with any of my close friends or family members, for the following reasons.

First: my sex life is my business. I haven't told any of my close friends or family members that I like feet either; it's irrelevant to those relationships. 

Second: I have no interest in dating men or i.e. making out with them at bars, and therefore don't feel that being closeted is at all restrictive or oppressive. I will never need to vent about the way a man I'm dating treats me, or about a man I'm crushing on, etc. like I sometimes do with women. 

Third: If I did come out, it would require explanation of all of the above. I really don't feel any need ever to say the words "Hi mom, I'm bisexual but heteroromantic, that means I sometimes like to suck cock but I'm not going to bring any boyfriends home to meet you." I certainly will have this conversation with my eventual spouse because they will be a core part of my sex life, but I don't feel that discussing my sexual preferences with family and friends would be at all liberating or fulfilling. 

EDIT because I forgot to include it: Fourth: The LGBTQ+ "scene" doesn't appeal to me at all. I will happily wear a rainbow shirt and go to a parade and I have many friends of all persuasions, but I'm not interested in putting a rainbow flag at my house or habitually hanging out at gay bars (though I'd have no problem going to one if a group of friends wanted to, and have done so before). Equal rights, preventing discrimination, AIDS research, and safe sex are all important issues to me, but not more so than i.e. climate change, criminal justice reform, or funding education. If I came out, there would be at least implicit pressure to participate in the LGBTQ+ community; I don't consider this a core part of my identity and so don't feel any desire to do so. 

While I'm fully aware that coming out or not is my own choice and prerogative, I am curious to hear your thoughts on this. Thanks all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37135315100.0" user="morfanis" delta="False">
    <text>I'm 50 and bi but have been married in a hetero relationship for the last 20 years. It didn't feel important to be out for a long time. There was no benefit to myself. I and my partner knew and accepted my identity (partner is bi too) and I felt comfortable with it.

A couple of things changed in the last few years.

1. I noticed some of discrimination that queer people still occassionally experience, and thought it was unfair that I could hide behind my straight relationship. I felt the need to out myself to do my small part to make queer sexuality more visible and normal.

2. A close friend was having issues about coming out. Also many of my nieces and nephew were reaching the high teens. I felt I needed to be more out to make it more comfotable for my friend and any of my family that wanted to be out themselves. 

Funny thing is, making myself visible I realised that I had been unconsciously avoiding situations before where I would make myself more visible. Becoming visible I now feel more true to and comfortable in myself

Viisibility is important. Mostly to help others who are struggling with their queer identities but also for expressing who you are and feeling comfortable with yourself.

Edit - sorry, just to add. I didn't out myself in everyones face all at once. I just notice opportunities every now and again when the conversation is about queer people, or pride month. I just randomly drop my identity into the conversation to support the ongoing discussion, not as the point of the discussion itself. You don't need to forcibly out yourself to family, just wait for an opportunity to push it into discussion when it fits.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
