<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1454822724.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/o25wec/cmv_there_is_no_compelling_reason_for_me_to_come/">
    <title>CMV: There is no compelling reason for me to come out as bisexual to my close friends and family</title>
    <original_poster>LexVeritas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Happy Pride month, all! This is something I've been thinking about for a while and I would love your input. 

I am a cisgender male who is bisexual (probably Kinsey 1-2, significant preference for women) and heteroromantic. While I occasionally enjoy sex with men, I have no interest in emotional or physical intimacy or romance with them--I don't even like kissing guys, basically I'm just into cock. I also enjoy sex with women, and have a strong urge towards intimacy and romance with female partners.

I've come out or mentioned my bisexuality to some acquaintances, mainly random internet strangers and sexual partners of both genders. However, I haven't brought it up with any of my close friends or family members, for the following reasons.

First: my sex life is my business. I haven't told any of my close friends or family members that I like feet either; it's irrelevant to those relationships. 

Second: I have no interest in dating men or i.e. making out with them at bars, and therefore don't feel that being closeted is at all restrictive or oppressive. I will never need to vent about the way a man I'm dating treats me, or about a man I'm crushing on, etc. like I sometimes do with women. 

Third: If I did come out, it would require explanation of all of the above. I really don't feel any need ever to say the words "Hi mom, I'm bisexual but heteroromantic, that means I sometimes like to suck cock but I'm not going to bring any boyfriends home to meet you." I certainly will have this conversation with my eventual spouse because they will be a core part of my sex life, but I don't feel that discussing my sexual preferences with family and friends would be at all liberating or fulfilling. 

EDIT because I forgot to include it: Fourth: The LGBTQ+ "scene" doesn't appeal to me at all. I will happily wear a rainbow shirt and go to a parade and I have many friends of all persuasions, but I'm not interested in putting a rainbow flag at my house or habitually hanging out at gay bars (though I'd have no problem going to one if a group of friends wanted to, and have done so before). Equal rights, preventing discrimination, AIDS research, and safe sex are all important issues to me, but not more so than i.e. climate change, criminal justice reform, or funding education. If I came out, there would be at least implicit pressure to participate in the LGBTQ+ community; I don't consider this a core part of my identity and so don't feel any desire to do so. 

While I'm fully aware that coming out or not is my own choice and prerogative, I am curious to hear your thoughts on this. Thanks all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37140833454.0" user="iamdimpho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I am a cisgender male who is bisexual (probably Kinsey 1-2, significant preference for women) and heteroromantic.

Samesies 🏳️‍🌈

Here's one reason why I would tell/come out to some of my friends:

Sometimes friends rely on each other to find potential partners (be it sexual and romantic). and while this is far from the primary way I meet my sexual partners, sometimes it's nice if someone practically delivers you a hottie because they know you two would probably have wild sex together. 

When going out sometimes, my more queer/bisexual friend group likes to 'challenge' each other to go up to and flirt with various people we think the challengee would find cute. If they only thought me straight, Id only be introduced to women, which is mostly fine. But would definitely miss on some awesome opportunities and hillarious situations (I don't often find 'conventionally attractive' men.. attractive, so it's mostly a miss for them, but sometimes)

Also, how's your experience on something like grindr etc? (I don't know how you meet men, but from my experience gay men on dating sites are just too aggressive and casual at crossing boundaries sometimes which made me abandon it altogether. So having my friend sus out potential partners can help.

The last reason would be representation, people don't often encounter bisexual men like us. I've met some (now bi-identifying) students who believed bisexuality meant they must like all the genders equally. Your existence is subverting that view.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
