<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="145491128.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2emdo8/cmvsegregated_by_gender_workplaces_would_lead_to/">
    <title>CMV:Segregated ( by gender) workplaces would lead to improved productivity.</title>
    <original_poster>hastyanon</original_poster>
    <original_post>I created this throwaway as I know this is a controversial and sexist opinion but it is one I have built up after 15 years of working in various environments. I would love someone to show me how I am wrong on this (preferably with some research to back it up) but in my experience, male-only (or almost male-only) work environments have been more on-task, have fewer issues of bitchyness and non-work related office disagreements, and generally more professionalism. I have worked in software development where teams/departments have frequently been 99% men and also worked in other office environments with a more equal mix. I see office politics in both situations but in offices with a greater number of women I have noticed a significantly greater quantity of personal issues becoming involved (relationships/friendships/personal disagreements etc). These frequently affect staff turnover and productivity. I can't comment on female-only environments as I have never worked in one, but would love to hear from those that have. I don't think women are any different to men in terms of productivity but from what I have seen the combination of men and women at work in an office is less than ideal. I'm looking forward to hearing your arguments and opinions. Please help me to change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27332483409.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>About 10 years ago there was a huge push for schools to try same-sex education. They had said there was overwhelming research to suggest that classrooms would be more productive if students were segregated by sex. 

This concept has definitely lost steam and has not caught on over the years. The field of education is so heavily scrutinized that it has become extremely results oriented. If the results were their, it would have been made mandatory already.

Back in February, the University of Wisconsin published a study that confirms that single-sex education offers not benefit. 

http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2014/02/single-sex-education.aspx</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27334700197.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's bad for social reasons.  How will a girl know how to date approach a guy without feeling even more awkward than she already would if guys were some sort of other?  I mean yeah, that still sort of happens.  But at least we see guys at school all the time.  I'd be nervous to ask one out, but I can talk to them as a friend or classmate just as easily as I can a girl.  Half the world is men!  I course I need to be accustomed to them!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
