<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="146826139.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fezrv/cmv_us_alcohol_taxes_should_be_higher/">
    <title>CMV: US Alcohol taxes should be higher.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Currently alcohol taxes in the US are not very high.  I think given the social costs of drinking, particularly drunk driving and alcoholism, we would be better off raising them to better compensate for those costs, as a [pigouvian tax](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigovian_tax).  We could lower other taxes to compensate, or not.  My view is not about the optimal level of overall taxation.

**The Numbers**

I'm going to just use hard liquor numbers because it's easier to get the tax rate per unit of ethanol.

Federally, a proof gallon is taxed [$13.50](http://www.ttb.gov/tax_audit/atftaxes.shtml), which equates to $27 per gallon of pure ethanol for human consumption.  At 0.6 fl oz per standard drink and 128 fl oz per gallon, that's about 12.6 cents per drink.  [State taxes](http://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxfacts/displayafact.cfm?Docid=349) vary, but  on the whole bring it up to maybe 16 to 20 cents per drink.

[This study](http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797\(11\)00538-1/fulltext) ascribes a very high economic cost to alcohol consumption, and particularly to rapid consumption.  I don't know if their economic cost numbers are fully accurate, but it seems to support the hypothesis that there is a large cost, and that the cost comes in particular from people who consume a lot of alcohol.

So why shouldn't the total tax on alcohol go up to something like $100 per gallon of ethanol?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27345233778.0" user="sardonic_drunkard" delta="False">
    <text>Several reasons,

(1)  If underground distilling was bad in the 1920s, you can't fathom how much worse it would be now. The homebrew scene has exploded in popularity, and learning to distill is substantially easier. The genie's out of the bottle (that's honestly not a pun). What underground distilling eliminates is the taxable market. The "it should be legalized and taxed" argument goes out the window. Nobody would buy the legally-produced stuff. Elasticity of demand at $100 per gallon would drive the market entirely underground. I'd be more than happy to switch from making beer to making whisky if it commanded a &amp;gt;300% premium in profitability given my input costs. 

So legal alcohol would be out there, but expensive; that's not good.

...Which leads us to...

(2) It's fiscally irresponsible to legislate this sort of tax. Considering how many people are capable of consuming alcohol, banning them due to the misgivings of the select few who can't consume responsibly is absurd. 

What's the market cap of [Brown-Foreman](http://brown-forman.com/brands/), you ask? [More than small countries; more than but a few university endowments](https://www.google.com/finance?q=NYSE%3ABF.A&amp;amp;ei=K9AHVLCiGdHqqAGp44CQCg). You're proposing to put hundreds of thousands of people out of work (whether directly or indirectly). You're proposing to ban companies where other remedies exist. Whatever your stance on alcohol, those who abuse should face the cost/criminal penalties. That's why the legal system exists. Those who are capable of consuming and producing alcohol responsibly shouldn't bear this cost. 

So it wouldn't even be taxed, or regulated! Even worse!

BTW,  It's irresponsible for an *economic* study to suggest that costs should be viewed without respect to benefits. Further, "72.2% from lost productivity" is outright bollocks, and laughable.

(3) $13.50 in tax per gallon is *absurdly* high...**absurdly**. The issue isn't $/drink—that's a red herring—it's % compared to production costs. Imagine a 100% sales tax (it would really be substantially more, since the basic distilled beverage would otherwise retail for less than $13.50/gal). 

Making booze is cheap. Mill corn, add water then yeast, let it sit, put heat to it &amp;amp; collect. The cost of distilled liquors is due to a base addition of tax and retailing cost. Pricing reflects consumers' willingness to spend more for what they deem to be a superior product. When the base price is high, the marginal cost to upgrade from Smirnov to Grey Goose is less significant. Subtract $13.50 from each, and elasticity of demand causes shifts. Make no mistake, booze is very cheap to produce. The only reason they're expensive is due to marketing &amp;amp; taxation.

So yes, the current taxation scheme *is* excessive. It's just excessive enough that beer seems reasonable in comparison, though beer is taxed at a much lower rate. 

N.b.: Suggesting that the federal government should do something because it "can" do something is naive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345246152.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>This is potentially persuasive, but I would ask if you have a response to some of the research I looked up elsewhere on the thread about international comparisons.  Ireland for example taxes spirits at approximately $150USD/US gallon of ethanol.  Specifically, they do 3133 EUR per hectoliter of ethanol.  Do we see these dire economic consequences and loss of freedom there?

See page 9 of this for my source http://www.drinksindustry.ie/easyedit/files/Alcohol%20Taxation%20EU%20Comparison%20JULY%202011.pdf</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345295062.0" user="sardonic_drunkard" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do we see these dire economic consequences and loss of freedom there?

Any time you have to ask whether or not there was economic loss from governmental imposition, the answer will be yes. Not only is this econ 101 theory, this is basic economic practice. Frankly, the degree of how "dire" something is, is irrelevant. Bad economic policy is bad economic policy. Externalities should be included, but "dire" connotes a necessity for action. I promise, as sure as alcohol was a problem 6000 years ago, it still causes problems.

You have to look at it from a very basic perspective. If a taxing lackey were to be standing at the interaction of two producers seeking to cooperate in a transaction, holding out their hand, and saying "ain't shit gunna happen unless my boss gets paid!!! You don't pay, you go to jail!!!" that is not beneficial to parties who cooperate in production of the item to be exchanged. 

But, to get to the base of your question, the answer is yes. There are dire consequences to prohibition of anything. Consequences are enormous for alcohol. Similarly, they're enormous for cannibus. Whenever a government attempts to enforce abstinence upon a population, bad things happen. Assuming that another de facto prohibition is beneficial to anyone is misguided.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345314644.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that there's no economic cost.  But is ~$8 in tax per 750ml bottle of liquor going to bankrupt Brown Foreman and result in hundreds of thousands of job losses?  You posited that this tax would collapse the legal alcohol market and bankrupt most businesses in it.  That's what I meant by dire.  

When I said $100 per gallon of ethanol, I meant pure ethanol.  A gallon of pure ethanol is equivalent to the alcohol in about 12.5 standard bottles of spirits (750ml at 80 proof), or about 215 standard bottles of beer (12 oz at 5% alc/vol).  Less than 50 cents a beer or $8 per bottle of hard liquor does not seem like it would kill the legal market. 

Is there a de facto alcohol prohibition in Ireland, where taxes are this high?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345377667.0" user="stevegcook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Any time you have to ask whether or not there was economic loss from governmental imposition, the answer will be yes. Not only is this econ 101 theory, this is basic economic practice. Frankly, the degree of how "dire" something is, is irrelevant. Bad economic policy is bad economic policy.

It sounds like your stance is "market gains no matter the social cost," which I have some issues with.  If something is profitable, but causes significant non-monetary harms to lots of people, it's worth considering regulating that thing, rather than just ignoring it because someone might not make as much money.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
