<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="146826139.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fezrv/cmv_us_alcohol_taxes_should_be_higher/">
    <title>CMV: US Alcohol taxes should be higher.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Currently alcohol taxes in the US are not very high.  I think given the social costs of drinking, particularly drunk driving and alcoholism, we would be better off raising them to better compensate for those costs, as a [pigouvian tax](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigovian_tax).  We could lower other taxes to compensate, or not.  My view is not about the optimal level of overall taxation.

**The Numbers**

I'm going to just use hard liquor numbers because it's easier to get the tax rate per unit of ethanol.

Federally, a proof gallon is taxed [$13.50](http://www.ttb.gov/tax_audit/atftaxes.shtml), which equates to $27 per gallon of pure ethanol for human consumption.  At 0.6 fl oz per standard drink and 128 fl oz per gallon, that's about 12.6 cents per drink.  [State taxes](http://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxfacts/displayafact.cfm?Docid=349) vary, but  on the whole bring it up to maybe 16 to 20 cents per drink.

[This study](http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797\(11\)00538-1/fulltext) ascribes a very high economic cost to alcohol consumption, and particularly to rapid consumption.  I don't know if their economic cost numbers are fully accurate, but it seems to support the hypothesis that there is a large cost, and that the cost comes in particular from people who consume a lot of alcohol.

So why shouldn't the total tax on alcohol go up to something like $100 per gallon of ethanol?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27357815146.0" user="TectonicWafer" delta="False">
    <text>There a practical reason for this current state of affairs:

Ethanol is tremendously useful for many things other than getting humans intoxicated.

Ethanol is an essential industrial chemical in the production of hundreds, if not thousands of organic compounds that you use every day, in products like aspirin, mouthwash, perfume, engine degreaser, you name it.

Ethyl alcohol is a common and cheap partially-polarized solvent.  This makes it really really useful, to the point where taxing it too highly would just be a general tax on economic activity.  This is the same reasoning, by the way, for why we no longer have taxes on salt (NaCl).  It's just too damn useful, and we need to use it in such massive quantities that the high levels of taxes that you are proposing would be a general disincentive to modern industrial processes.  

OK, you say, so what if we only tax alcohol intended to be sold for beverages?  Well, then, if you raised the tax level high enough, people would just substitute "industrial" sources for "luxury" sources.  The government of the USA tried this back in the 1920s.  It Did Not Work, by any measure.  

But, what if we wanted to raise the taxes on alcohols intended for ingestion by less than your proposed "$100 per gallon" number?

There might be a sensible economic case for a much much more modest increase on federal or state taxation on alcoholic beverages.  I don't know if there any decent studies on the effects of taxation on overall alcohol consumption -- my WAG would be that in a wealthy country like the United States, a increase to around $15 per proof gallon might be borne reasonably well by the consumer base without encouraging counterfeiting or smuggling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
