<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="146826139.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fezrv/cmv_us_alcohol_taxes_should_be_higher/">
    <title>CMV: US Alcohol taxes should be higher.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Currently alcohol taxes in the US are not very high.  I think given the social costs of drinking, particularly drunk driving and alcoholism, we would be better off raising them to better compensate for those costs, as a [pigouvian tax](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigovian_tax).  We could lower other taxes to compensate, or not.  My view is not about the optimal level of overall taxation.

**The Numbers**

I'm going to just use hard liquor numbers because it's easier to get the tax rate per unit of ethanol.

Federally, a proof gallon is taxed [$13.50](http://www.ttb.gov/tax_audit/atftaxes.shtml), which equates to $27 per gallon of pure ethanol for human consumption.  At 0.6 fl oz per standard drink and 128 fl oz per gallon, that's about 12.6 cents per drink.  [State taxes](http://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxfacts/displayafact.cfm?Docid=349) vary, but  on the whole bring it up to maybe 16 to 20 cents per drink.

[This study](http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797\(11\)00538-1/fulltext) ascribes a very high economic cost to alcohol consumption, and particularly to rapid consumption.  I don't know if their economic cost numbers are fully accurate, but it seems to support the hypothesis that there is a large cost, and that the cost comes in particular from people who consume a lot of alcohol.

So why shouldn't the total tax on alcohol go up to something like $100 per gallon of ethanol?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27345181774.0" user="Divinityfound" delta="False">
    <text>To change your mind, I can't tell if you are wanting a moral case as to not raise taxes or financial cost case as to not raise the taxes?

Please clarify.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345187577.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Either would possibly work.  Give me your best argument and I'll see!

Edit to add: I did mention in my original post that I would be open to lowering some other tax to get the same overall level of tax revenue.  E.g. raising alcohol taxes and lowering payroll taxes or boosting the EITC.  So an argument against higher taxes per se wouldn't be very persuasive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345212291.0" user="Divinityfound" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Note on Taxes

Most tax revenues are generally earmarked to go to a certain location. Property taxes for example strictly go into the education system and maintaining city infrastructure for example. So lowering taxes in one area only hurts another segment of society. Lowering payroll taxes hurts social security. Etc etc etc. It's a trade off when lowering one tax for another. One social ill vs another.

This is merely a case to suggest that one shouldn't be so quick about making certain taxes lower in favor of another.

&amp;gt; Moral Case against Taxes on Alcohol

Externalities is usually the case and reasoning to try and regulate with taxes.... but one can usually make the case that MOST bad things that happen to us aren't our fault.... but courtesy of other things that impact our lives.

BUT... a number of existing private solutions already exist to remedy alcohol drivers, such as insurance and property taxes that maintain the streets and the income taxes for law enforcement to take care of the drivers responsible for breaking the law.

&amp;gt; Financial Case against Taxes on Alcohol

EVEN if we were to raise it, how much could we reasonably raise alcohol prices? How do we equate costs that have not been accounted for? How do we know how much less people will drink with the price changes and how do we account for that?

Why not make a case for encouraging those who WISH to drink alcohol to purchase some kind of insurance to pay out in the EVENT that damages occur since private markets would be FAR more able to help in determining a REASONABLE cost as per a person's ability to drink?

Or, do what is already done, and move the costs onto the drinker themselves?

&amp;gt; Long story short....

There are already forces in place that invalidate the idea of increasing taxes on strictly alcohol, and other alternatives if we feel the externalities OUTWEIGH existing tax structures.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345235072.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Most tax revenues are generally earmarked to go to a certain location. Property taxes for example strictly go into the education system and maintaining city infrastructure for example. So lowering taxes in one area only hurts another segment of society. Lowering payroll taxes hurts social security. Etc etc etc. It's a trade off when lowering one tax for another. One social ill vs another.
This is merely a case to suggest that one shouldn't be so quick about making certain taxes lower in favor of another.

In the case of the Federal government, all tax revenue effectively flows to the general fund of the Treasury.  Even payroll taxes go there through a bit of a rube goldberg machine of special treasury bills.  Money is fungible, and apart from going to a different level of government, it doesn't really make a difference in my view.  But that's getting off topic.

---

As to the moral case, I'm not sure exactly what the point of this is.  There are other costs borne directly by heavy consumers of alcohol, or those who act irresponsibly.  But it still doesn't follow to me that it's not a good target for higher taxation.  Drinking seems like a better thing to disincentivize than working.  But I may be missing something here, so feel free to clarify/correct.

---

To your financial case, I'd say we can look at other countries with high alcohol taxes.  [Ireland for example](http://www.drinksindustry.ie/easyedit/files/Alcohol%20Taxation%20EU%20Comparison%20JULY%202011.pdf) taxes spirits at a bit over 3000 euros per hectoliter (Warning: PDF).  That converts to 113 Eur/US gallon or about $150USD per gallon.  

The insurance thing is clumsy.  A direct tax both compensates society for the costs, and disincentives the behavior without prohibiting it or subjecting it to invasive regulation, which would be a far greater impingement of freedom.  I would be for something like raising excise taxes, but greatly liberalizing the puritanical and often arbitrary regulations on the distribution and marketing of alcohol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345255089.0" user="Divinityfound" delta="False">
    <text>Ironically, I'm mildly intoxicated, so pardon me if I stumble over some phrasing....

&amp;gt; In the case of the Federal government, all tax revenue effectively flows to the general fund of the Treasury. Even payroll taxes go there through a bit of a rube goldberg machine of special treasury bills. Money is fungible, and apart from going to a different level of government, it doesn't really make a difference in my view. But that's getting off topic.

Doesn't get away from the earmarked problem. Unless if we want to cut out other programs to compensate this one..... that is my point. And to make it malleable would defeat the point of the democratic approach of our tax infrastructure.

&amp;gt; Drinking seems like a better thing to disincentivize than working. But I may be missing something here, so feel free to clarify/correct.

Nothing wrong to deter drinking all the same, but if that was the case, we'd make the taxes SO obscene it'll be for all intents and purposes illegal. And we saw how THAT played out when prohibition was in America. (Thanks Canadian exporters....).

Ergo.... social costs of taxation are HIGHER if you make the taxes so high drinking is impractical. But I may be misinterpreting your intention of making alcohol to expensive to purchase for poorer/middle class consumers.

&amp;gt; To your financial case, I'd say we can look at other countries with high alcohol taxes. Ireland for example[1] taxes spirits at a bit over 3000 euros per hectoliter (Warning: PDF). That converts to 113 Eur/US gallon or about $150USD per gallon.

Interestingly enough, even with high taxation.... 97% of their violence problems (so I read on reddit somewhere today) is related to alcohol. So making alcohol more expensive is OBVIOUSLY not a great solution in lowering social problem and violence.

&amp;gt; A direct tax both compensates society for the costs

Same way smoke taxes does? (Yes I know that the taxes are harsh enough that the system BENEFITS from smokers....)

&amp;gt; disincentives the behavior without prohibiting it or subjecting it to invasive regulation

You discourage the behaviors with taxes? Why not just illegalize it? Or just make it EVEN higher?  But I might be missing your objective.....

&amp;gt; which would be a far greater impingement of freedom

So you value social welfare over freedom as a whole? Yes or no?

&amp;gt; I would be for something like raising excise taxes, but greatly liberalizing the puritanical and often arbitrary regulations on the distribution and marketing of alcohol.

Doesn't that defeat your intention of eliminating alcohol consumption of society? Not trying to poke holes, I'm just looking for a consistent line of thought that I can personally follow.

&amp;gt; The insurance thing is clumsy

Health insurance is kinda crappy yet awesome if you have it. Same with auto insurance. And life insurance. And so on.... so I gotta ask on what basis do you suggest that it is clumsy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345287373.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Ergo.... social costs of taxation are HIGHER if you make the taxes so high drinking is impractical. But I may be misinterpreting your intention of making alcohol to expensive to purchase for poorer/middle class consumers.

You're misinterpreting my intention.  The people who would be substantially impacted by this are *very* heavy drinkers.  Someone who buys a 12 pack on the weekend for a football game with the guys will see that price go up by a few dollars.  That doesn't matter much if you buy 12 beers a week.  It matters quite a lot if you buy 24 beers a day.

I don't want to make drinking in general impractically expensive.  I do want to make extreme alcoholism impractically expensive, but you have to be consuming a really large amount of alcohol for $100 per gallon to be a budget buster - to the point where you need help.

&amp;gt;Interestingly enough, even with high taxation.... 97% of their violence problems (so I read on reddit somewhere today) is related to alcohol. So making alcohol more expensive is OBVIOUSLY not a great solution in lowering social problem and violence.

97% of anything being related to anything else is crazy high for something like criminality.  I'd wanna see a source to believe this.

&amp;gt;You discourage the behaviors with taxes? Why not just illegalize it? Or just make it EVEN higher? But I might be missing your objective.....

&amp;gt; &amp;gt;which would be a far greater impingement of freedom

&amp;gt;So you value social welfare over freedom as a whole? Yes or no?

Both are values.  I think ideally we want to minimize social harms while maximizing the sphere of choice for individuals.  By using a tax instead of outright prohibitions or detailed regulations, I think we can leave more room for personal choice while still ameliorating the harm to society.

My point about requiring "drinking insurance" being clumsy is that the people you really want to buy it (alcoholics) will just flout the law and not buy it, while inconveniencing the people who are responsible and do buy it without needing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345323595.0" user="Divinityfound" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to work backwards on this....

&amp;gt; My point about requiring "drinking insurance" being clumsy is that the people you really want to buy it (alcoholics) will just flout the law and not buy it, while inconveniencing the people who are responsible and do buy it without needing it.

Same way if we avoid car insurance.... we lose the right to ever drive a particular car. We can try to drive without it.... but the consequences of being caught are.... disastrous. Make the consequences equal to such behavior.

Ergo.... it'll be as flimsy as car insurance. Unless if you take issue with car insurance yourself? And if you do.... then I have to concede that this really isn't a compelling argument to you.

&amp;gt; Both are values. I think ideally we want to minimize social harms while maximizing the sphere of choice for individuals. By using a tax instead of outright prohibitions or detailed regulations, I think we can leave more room for personal choice while still ameliorating the harm to society.

There are social harms no matter what we do.... ranging from our impact on the environment by our average water consumption, to how much we drive, to how much land we utilize for pleasure.... the question comes down to why just pick this one social ill?

&amp;gt; 97% of anything being related to anything else is crazy high for something like criminality. I'd wanna see a source to believe this.

http://alcoholireland.ie/facts/case-studies-kids/

&amp;gt; I don't want to make drinking in general impractically expensive. I do want to make extreme alcoholism impractically expensive, but you have to be consuming a really large amount of alcohol for $100 per gallon to be a budget buster - to the point where you need help.

Question is if they'll just cut other life expenses out of their life in FAVOR of alcohol.... alcoholism is kind of a sickness.... where cost is less a consequence that they consider or think of.... Can't save those who don't want to be saved ya know?

&amp;gt; You're misinterpreting my intention. The people who would be substantially impacted by this are very heavy drinkers. Someone who buys a 12 pack on the weekend for a football game with the guys will see that price go up by a few dollars. That doesn't matter much if you buy 12 beers a week. It matters quite a lot if you buy 24 beers a day.

To be fair.... even a $1 difference can defer more casual drinkers (For example: my girlfriend), where as more serious drinkers they'll spend it the money irregardless of the consequences....

I guess I'm making the same case that gun advocates do.... the bad people will do it no matter what where you are just punishing the good people from taking care of themselves willingly or of their own volition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345772430.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Same way if we avoid car insurance.... we lose the right to ever drive a particular car. We can try to drive without it.... but the consequences of being caught are.... disastrous. Make the consequences equal to such behavior.
&amp;gt;Ergo.... it'll be as flimsy as car insurance. Unless if you take issue with car insurance yourself? And if you do.... then I have to concede that this really isn't a compelling argument to you.

I think car insurance is a good idea, but is also flimsy.  A lot of people drive without insurance.  Car insurance is also tied to a physical thing with a government issued license plate.  Regulating drinking like we regulate cars would be invasive and I think less effective than car insurance.

&amp;gt;There are social harms no matter what we do.... ranging from our impact on the environment by our average water consumption, to how much we drive, to how much land we utilize for pleasure.... the question comes down to why just pick this one social ill?

I'm not picking just this one social ill; it just happens to be the one I'm asking about.  Pigovian taxes can be used on carbon emissions for example.  

The link you gave says 97% of public order offenses were alcohol related.  That doesn't surprise me, since public order offenses is code for "drunk and disorderly."

&amp;gt;Question is if they'll just cut other life expenses out of their life in FAVOR of alcohol.... alcoholism is kind of a sickness.... where cost is less a consequence that they consider or think of.... Can't save those who don't want to be saved ya know?

Severe alcoholics often already have.  I don't think it can save every alcoholic, but it makes binging harder.

&amp;gt;To be fair.... even a $1 difference can defer more casual drinkers (For example: my girlfriend), where as more serious drinkers they'll spend it the money irregardless of the consequences....

&amp;gt;I guess I'm making the same case that gun advocates do.... the bad people will do it no matter what where you are just punishing the good people from taking care of themselves willingly or of their own volition.

This is fair.  Some casual and responsible drinkers will be deterred.  I still see that deterrance as better than the deterrance we get from taxing labor.  Your girlfriend, if she was a perfectly average drinker, might see the weekly cost of drinking go up by $5 or $10, but would ideally see her paycheck go up by $5 or $10 as well.  If she wanted, she could continue as before.  But if she wanted to spend the extra money elsewhere, she could.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
