<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="146826139.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fezrv/cmv_us_alcohol_taxes_should_be_higher/">
    <title>CMV: US Alcohol taxes should be higher.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Currently alcohol taxes in the US are not very high.  I think given the social costs of drinking, particularly drunk driving and alcoholism, we would be better off raising them to better compensate for those costs, as a [pigouvian tax](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigovian_tax).  We could lower other taxes to compensate, or not.  My view is not about the optimal level of overall taxation.

**The Numbers**

I'm going to just use hard liquor numbers because it's easier to get the tax rate per unit of ethanol.

Federally, a proof gallon is taxed [$13.50](http://www.ttb.gov/tax_audit/atftaxes.shtml), which equates to $27 per gallon of pure ethanol for human consumption.  At 0.6 fl oz per standard drink and 128 fl oz per gallon, that's about 12.6 cents per drink.  [State taxes](http://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxfacts/displayafact.cfm?Docid=349) vary, but  on the whole bring it up to maybe 16 to 20 cents per drink.

[This study](http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797\(11\)00538-1/fulltext) ascribes a very high economic cost to alcohol consumption, and particularly to rapid consumption.  I don't know if their economic cost numbers are fully accurate, but it seems to support the hypothesis that there is a large cost, and that the cost comes in particular from people who consume a lot of alcohol.

So why shouldn't the total tax on alcohol go up to something like $100 per gallon of ethanol?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27345192602.0" user="ShadowyTroll" delta="False">
    <text>So you are saying that because some people behave badly, everyone should be punished by paying more? I have always hated sin [sumptuary] taxes and believe they are wildly unfair.

The people give the government the power to tax in order to pay for public *services* we all need to share. Things like the military budgets and roads. They also help those citizens who are impoverished to have a higher standard of life.

Sin taxes are a punishment, not a valid raising of public revenues. If you wish to pass the costs of police action and other such things on to the culprits, that is what fines are for. The difference being a fine only targets the offending parties, not everyone.

The last problem I have is with the disproportionate effects of such a tax. Since it is a flat tax, it by definition hits some people harder. Why is it that a working class guy enjoying a beer or some whiskey should have to feel a noticeable hit to his wallet while a doctor or investment banker, lets say, doesn't even notice? Unless you are willing to blame the ills of drinking on the poor it seems unfair to burden them with additional taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345203761.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So you are saying that because some people behave badly, everyone should be punished by paying more? I have always hated sin [sumptuary] taxes and believe they are wildly unfair.

I am saying that when people engage in behavior that is likely to have social costs, that it is good policy to tax those behaviors at a relatively higher rate than other behaviors.

&amp;gt;The people give the government the power to tax in order to pay for public services we all need to share. Things like the military budgets and roads. They also help those citizens who are impoverished to have a higher standard of life.

&amp;gt;Sin taxes are a punishment, not a valid raising of public revenues. If you wish to pass the costs of police action and other such things on to the culprits, that is what fines are for. The difference being a fine only targets the offending parties, not everyone.

I disagree that excise taxes are a punishment.  In my view, they are a better tax than a tax on labor (the most common tax) which discourages something with positive social consequence.  Taxes create a disincentive to do whatever they tax.  I'd much rather disincentivize drinking than working.

&amp;gt;The last problem I have is with the disproportionate effects of such a tax. Since it is a flat tax, it by definition hits some people harder. Why is it that a working class guy enjoying a beer or some whiskey should have to feel a noticeable hit to his wallet while a doctor or investment banker, lets say, doesn't even notice? Unless you are willing to blame the ills of drinking on the poor it seems unfair to burden them with additional taxes.

The main people who would feel a noticeable effect on their wallets would be people who consume very large amounts of alcohol.  We're talking about something like 30 or 40 cents per drink.  You have to be consuming a lot of alcohol to have a significant impact from that. 

As I said in the original post, we could also lower some other tax to balance the revenue.  That could easily be a tax on the labor income of poor people, such as adding an exclusion to the low end of the payroll tax, or expanding the EITC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345374878.0" user="stevegcook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The main people who would feel a noticeable effect on their wallets would be people who consume very large amounts of alcohol. We're talking about something like 30 or 40 cents per drink. You have to be consuming a lot of alcohol to have a significant impact from that.

So... alcoholics.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27345541655.0" user="Raintee97" delta="False">
    <text>Are you counting that per shot? If you say that there are 22 pours in a 750 ml bottle that would come up to 7.70 cents per bottle. That would affect a lot more people than you think. I buy many bottle as I like to have a well stocked bar. I have to pay a 20 to 25 percent mark up just because of a study which was mainly based on lost productivity? 

It seems like you want to tax into some level of prohibition. I mean we tried that. It didn't work. You can't stop people from drinking. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
