<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1471022435.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/obt46b/cmv_in_breaking_bad_there_are_some_serious_meth/">
    <title>CMV: In Breaking Bad, there are some serious Meth Math problems with Walter and Jessie's 3 month job working for Gus</title>
    <original_poster>RedditExplorer89</original_poster>
    <original_post>1.) They are making 200 pounds of meth a week for 3 months.  (source: The show)

2.) The meth sells at $40 an ounce. (Source:

Jessie keeps saying, "He's selling at 40 a pound".  I see 3 possibilities for this:

A.) He mean $40 a pound.  For all the risk they are taking to make Meth, that seems like too small of revenue.

B.) Me meant $40,000 a pound.  This sounds like astronomically too high.  How could Meth junkies ever afford their meth if 1 pound sells for 1 years minimum wage salary?

C.) He mis-poke, and meant $40 an ounce.  This sounds most plausible to me, as it means they are making some decent money from their risk and Meth junkies can still afford to buy their meth.)

3.) There are 16 ounces in a pound. (Source: [Google](https://www.google.com/search?client=firefox-b-1-d&amp;amp;q=ounces+in+a+pound))

4.) They are working for 13 weeks.  (Source:

Assuming ~31 days in a month, ~31 x 3 = ~93 days in 3 months.  ~93/7 = ~13 weeks in 3 months)

5.)  Conclusion: The meth they make for Gus during the 3 months can sell for ~1.5 million dollars.  (Source:

$40 (per ounce) x 16 (ounces per pound) x 200 (pounds per week) x 13 (weeks in the job) = $1,664,000, or ~1.5 million dollars)

Now lets get down to the problems here:

**Gus is losing money**

Gus is paying 3 million dollars for these two guys to make product that he will sell for 1.5 million dollars.  That's 1.5 million dollars down the drain.

**Walter and Jessie are bad at Math**

Jessie and Walter both come to the conclusion that Gus is making 93 million off their 3 month job.  Given all the information we have, they should have come to 1.5 million.  Jessie I could understand making a mistake somewhere in this math.  But Walter is supposed to be the smart guy.  How could he also make this mistake?

**What would change my view**:

1.) Show me a way to interpret the information in the show in such a way that the job is profitable for Gus while still being based in reality.

2.) Explain why both Walter and Jessie made such bad math mistakes in their calculations.

Bonus points if you can do both.

**What wouldn't change my view**

*This was a mistake the show-writers made.*  If this is the case I apologize since it means there isn't really a view to be changed here.  However, I have hope that there is something I am missing that explains this mess.

Edits/deltas:

* Gus is doing this venture as a long term plan.  Once he has Walt's formula, he can start making money again.

* The math at $40k a pound checks out for Walter and Jessie's calculation if you assume 12 weeks instead of 13 weeks.  12 instead of 13 weeks seems like a simple enough mistake if you assume the 4 weeks per month as many people do.  $40k a pound for meth seems unrealistic to me, but at least that is a flaw in the world building rather than Walter or Jessie's character.

* Junkies buy in teenths (1/16 of an ounce), which makes selling Meth at $40k a pound more reasonable.  Also, $40k a pound checks out with how much money Walter and Jessie were making when they cooked in their RV.

* Real Meth sells at about the $40k per pound value.  Looks like the show was actually being very realistic after all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37230224070.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>  Hmm let me see if I remember correctly; 

One - Gus never planned or wanted to keep paying them at the same constant rate of compensation. (Either he didn't plan for a prolonger engagement or he was going to screw then over, so that payment can be reversed). This means the investment is cheaper in the long run.

Two - Gus made a mistake, instead of the showwriters. No person is actually perfect and the show was realistic in showing mistakes of characters (even if they were displayed with nuance). 

Realistically, these characters are humans. They simply could have overestimated or underestimated the length of engagement that would occur between eachother. This is still realistic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230295486.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>A long term investment plan from Gus makes sense to me (already gave a delta for this).

As for Gus making a mistake...I don't think so.  Sure, he can make mistakes, but this seems like such a huge one to make.  Also, as a business man, not the type of mistake I would think he would make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230306433.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I think that's under the assumption that businessman can't make big mistakes, when it is completely possible. For example, Warren Buffett had made huge mistakes regarding Disney. I think the showwriters can just be displaying this in a nuanced way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230417928.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>I think he could make the mistake, but I think at some point one of his lackey's would say, "Um hey boss, why are you paying 3 million to make 1.5 million?"  Also, he is paying Walt as the weeks go by, so I would also think he would have realized his mistake once the money starts coming in from the sales and he sees the money going out to Walter and Jessie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230448286.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Did he explain to his lackeys to complexity behind the economic portion of the deal? Also, isn't the compensation based of Walter's ability to make 200 a week?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230477838.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe "lackey" wasn't the right word.  One of his higher-ups perhaps.  Like, Saul Goodman, or Mike, or Gale, or the guy who hand-delivers the money to Walt.  

And yes, I think Walt is being compensated each week he is able to do the 200 pounds.  This is why I think Gus would realize after 1 or 2 weeks that he is losing money if he had made a mistake (from this CMV though I have learned that he is not losing money: he is selling at $40k a pound)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230503107.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Maybe "lackey" wasn't the right word. One of his higher-ups perhaps. Like, Saul Goodman, or Mike, or Gale, or the guy who hand-delivers the money to Walt. 

I ask this then; Is it stated within the show that he explains to the economic nuances of the deal in the shoe to these people? 

&amp;gt;And yes, I think Walt is being compensated each week he is able to do the 200 pounds. This is why I think Gus would realize after 1 or 2 weeks that he is losing money if he had made a mistake (from this CMV though I have learned that he is not losing money: he is selling at $40k a pound)

Did Gus have full watch over the exact flow of his cash? If he didn't, then this relies of him examining the specific economic nuances of the deal to people like Saul.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37230540420.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I ask this then; Is it stated within the show that he explains to the economic nuances of the deal in the shoe to these people? 

It isn't shown in the show, other than Saul.  Saul knows how much they are making since he gets a percent of everything they make.  

&amp;gt; Did Gus have full watch over the exact flow of his cash? If he didn't, then this relies of him examining the specific economic nuances of the deal to people like Saul.

I'm not sure, but seeing how calculated and meticulous of a person Gus is I wouldn't be surprised if he did.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
