<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1471022435.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/obt46b/cmv_in_breaking_bad_there_are_some_serious_meth/">
    <title>CMV: In Breaking Bad, there are some serious Meth Math problems with Walter and Jessie's 3 month job working for Gus</title>
    <original_poster>RedditExplorer89</original_poster>
    <original_post>1.) They are making 200 pounds of meth a week for 3 months.  (source: The show)

2.) The meth sells at $40 an ounce. (Source:

Jessie keeps saying, "He's selling at 40 a pound".  I see 3 possibilities for this:

A.) He mean $40 a pound.  For all the risk they are taking to make Meth, that seems like too small of revenue.

B.) Me meant $40,000 a pound.  This sounds like astronomically too high.  How could Meth junkies ever afford their meth if 1 pound sells for 1 years minimum wage salary?

C.) He mis-poke, and meant $40 an ounce.  This sounds most plausible to me, as it means they are making some decent money from their risk and Meth junkies can still afford to buy their meth.)

3.) There are 16 ounces in a pound. (Source: [Google](https://www.google.com/search?client=firefox-b-1-d&amp;amp;q=ounces+in+a+pound))

4.) They are working for 13 weeks.  (Source:

Assuming ~31 days in a month, ~31 x 3 = ~93 days in 3 months.  ~93/7 = ~13 weeks in 3 months)

5.)  Conclusion: The meth they make for Gus during the 3 months can sell for ~1.5 million dollars.  (Source:

$40 (per ounce) x 16 (ounces per pound) x 200 (pounds per week) x 13 (weeks in the job) = $1,664,000, or ~1.5 million dollars)

Now lets get down to the problems here:

**Gus is losing money**

Gus is paying 3 million dollars for these two guys to make product that he will sell for 1.5 million dollars.  That's 1.5 million dollars down the drain.

**Walter and Jessie are bad at Math**

Jessie and Walter both come to the conclusion that Gus is making 93 million off their 3 month job.  Given all the information we have, they should have come to 1.5 million.  Jessie I could understand making a mistake somewhere in this math.  But Walter is supposed to be the smart guy.  How could he also make this mistake?

**What would change my view**:

1.) Show me a way to interpret the information in the show in such a way that the job is profitable for Gus while still being based in reality.

2.) Explain why both Walter and Jessie made such bad math mistakes in their calculations.

Bonus points if you can do both.

**What wouldn't change my view**

*This was a mistake the show-writers made.*  If this is the case I apologize since it means there isn't really a view to be changed here.  However, I have hope that there is something I am missing that explains this mess.

Edits/deltas:

* Gus is doing this venture as a long term plan.  Once he has Walt's formula, he can start making money again.

* The math at $40k a pound checks out for Walter and Jessie's calculation if you assume 12 weeks instead of 13 weeks.  12 instead of 13 weeks seems like a simple enough mistake if you assume the 4 weeks per month as many people do.  $40k a pound for meth seems unrealistic to me, but at least that is a flaw in the world building rather than Walter or Jessie's character.

* Junkies buy in teenths (1/16 of an ounce), which makes selling Meth at $40k a pound more reasonable.  Also, $40k a pound checks out with how much money Walter and Jessie were making when they cooked in their RV.

* Real Meth sells at about the $40k per pound value.  Looks like the show was actually being very realistic after all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37233501736.0" user="EXGTACAMLS" delta="False">
    <text>It's definitely $40K per pound, for two reasons.

Firstly, they are selling a premium product. Walter's cook is literally the purest meth in the goddamn world, and he's the only one who can make it pretty much. That puts the price much higher already than other cook. Even better, not only is it more pure, it has a special look, the blue color, that makes it stand out almost like a name brand over a knock off brand.

Secondly, a pound of meth is a lot more than you think. It might not sound like a lot just per the weight, but that's enough for *many* people on its own. Remember how earlier in the show Jesse was hard-pressed, but proud, to sell just an ounce on the street? Well there's 16 ounces in a pound, and an ounce is enough for plenty of people too, so there ya go.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
