<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="147353546.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fqaq2/cmv_i_believe_that_there_should_be_no_penalty_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that there should be no penalty for Excessive Celebration in the NFL</title>
    <original_poster>mrspuff202</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have no idea why there are excessive celebration rules in the NFL rule book. If a player has done something exceptional, they should be allowed to celebrate as they wish as long as: A) they don't aggress upon a player on the other team (which is taunting) and B) the celebration doesn't run on for a ridiculous amount of time. These celebrations are fun bits of creativity and flair that allow the players to express their personality and ingenuity and make the game much more fun to watch.

A counterargument that I already foresee: What kind of example does that set for kids?

My answer: Actually a pretty good one. For one, there is a major difference between celebrating and taunting that even a child can understand: one is mean, and any four year old could make that distinction. But celebrations are a big part of why I played football, basketball, baseball, etc. as a kid. The batflip after a homerun, thumping my chest like Paul Pierce after nailing an improbable three: it teaches them to strive to be the best that they can be and to be happy when they succeed. Celebration of one's good deeds is a very good trait to have.

That's my view. Change my view, Reddit! Or else, Goodell will be getting a sternly worded letter from me.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27350429166.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>The thing with excessive celebration is that it takes time. Like a lot of time. You can actually delay the start of the next game or interfere with other programming with nothing running long except celebrations of each and every significant play. This is real bad for the process of televising these games. The NFL has a lot of very reasonable and very practical reasons for keeping players on task and under the time limits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27350587927.0" user="chevybow" delta="False">
    <text>There's delay of game if they don't get on with the next play. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27350594024.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Only after the ball is set, not if the player refuse to return the ball promptly and instead are using it for other purposes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27350624536.0" user="chevybow" delta="False">
    <text>Can't they get another ball? I mean what happens if a player theoretically just keeps a ball. They're not celebrating or anything- they just don't return the ball. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27350629895.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know, but I can't help but think that by varying the ball you're adding unnecessary risk of manipulation of the game. The NFL only supplies a limited number of certified balls, run through those and tampering becomes a threat. We see that happen in baseball fairly regularly, it's so common in fact that it often goes unremarked upon when discovered which simply contributes to that sport's fading popularity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27351751042.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>no one is making the refs stand around and wait. if a player wants to dance while the refs setup the PAT, let him. if he is still on the field when the ball is kiecked it will either be offsides of too many men on the field. having a specific penalty for it only calls more attention to it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
