<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="147353546.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2fqaq2/cmv_i_believe_that_there_should_be_no_penalty_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that there should be no penalty for Excessive Celebration in the NFL</title>
    <original_poster>mrspuff202</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have no idea why there are excessive celebration rules in the NFL rule book. If a player has done something exceptional, they should be allowed to celebrate as they wish as long as: A) they don't aggress upon a player on the other team (which is taunting) and B) the celebration doesn't run on for a ridiculous amount of time. These celebrations are fun bits of creativity and flair that allow the players to express their personality and ingenuity and make the game much more fun to watch.

A counterargument that I already foresee: What kind of example does that set for kids?

My answer: Actually a pretty good one. For one, there is a major difference between celebrating and taunting that even a child can understand: one is mean, and any four year old could make that distinction. But celebrations are a big part of why I played football, basketball, baseball, etc. as a kid. The batflip after a homerun, thumping my chest like Paul Pierce after nailing an improbable three: it teaches them to strive to be the best that they can be and to be happy when they succeed. Celebration of one's good deeds is a very good trait to have.

That's my view. Change my view, Reddit! Or else, Goodell will be getting a sternly worded letter from me.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27350748279.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>The key word is excessive. You're allowed to celebrate. You're even allowed to have a signature "move", as long as it's not deemed excessive per the NFL's guidelines. The issue is its very difficult to draw the line between celebrations and unsportsmanlike conduct. Consider it from the opposing team, who just got beat on a big play and is there on the field watching you. Even if you don't direct it at a specific person, at what point does it change from a harmless celebration to "rubbing it in". It's hard to say.

So there's a tricky distinction to make, but they key part is that the NFL is less interested in enforcing this distinction at exactly the right place as they are about enforcing it in as consistently and unbiased as they can. This is why the "excessive celebration" rules are a seemingly arbitrary list of extremely specific actions (using the ball as a prop, group celebrations, going to the ground, dunking the goalpost, etc...) It's not that they think that any of these actions is *necessarily* unsportsmanlike, its that to the extent possible, they don't want the referees in the business of making judgement calls about whether a celebration was unsportsmanlike or not. So they try to craft specific, enforceable rules that cover most of the historically unsportsmanlike acts, inform the players of these rules, and then try their best to enforce them consistently. It does err on the side of "no fun", but the *features* of the rules are legislating out unsportsmanlike conduct and ease/fairness of enforcement.

tl;dr It's not really about what is or isn't excessive and unsportsmanlike, its about crafting "sportsmanship" rules that are possible to enforce consistently.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
