<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360610717.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Not only would you actually earn the hatred and ire of every Muslim, whether radical or not, it just is simply not feasible. Secondly, we never colonized the Middle East, we may have had settlers of Greeks or Romans, but the West has never colonized the Middle East. Thirdly, you're ideas on dividing up the Middle East make no sense. Who gets what and why? How do you stamp out a belief as well? 

First let's say that an organized coalition of nations decided that the answer to a unstable armed conflict is to invade and occupy one of the most violent regions in the world? We would now face a real Jihad, not the bogus one ISIS or Al-Queada have called, but a real one. The one where Muslims *of every nation and background* is called upon to fight against the Invader. Take how many Muslims there are in the world and say 60-80% of them enter this conflict. London, DC, Paris, Moscow, Rome, Berlin, etc. would be the site of daily street fighting. The conflict would be even more global than the Second World War. And as a result you'd have an immense crackdown of Government on this conflict. This results in unhappy citizens who have more in common with the terrorists than they do their nation. Economies would be totaled as we tried to divert our national resources into occupying the region. Think, it took the US a few months to beat the Iraqis, but how long did it take for us to successfully occupy the nation? It never was, and the same story for Afghanistan. Beating the Army was easy, how about the Insurgents? Even with the world's most powerful army at them, how did that work out for us?

Secondly, most, if not all, attempts at holding or possessing land in the Middle East for the foreign forces, have not ended well. The Crusader Kingdoms were hit by numerous Jihads, and the British, French, and Ottomans had to fight numerous Wars over their territories to try to keep them in line. Think about the Middle East as well, you have high arid temperatures with numerous mountains and some of the most varying culture differences in one area. Turks are not Arabs, likewise Palestinians are not Egyptians. Persians have little in common with Arabs, save for religion, and the Pakistanis are almost entirely alienated with the rest of the Islamic world. How would we satisfy all of them? We'd have to build infrastructure, defend that infrastructure, supply the resources to build up this new area, erstwhile having to face the harsh geography of the region. Mountains, Deserts, Rivers, Valleys that have not yet been all conquered by man. 

It's simply not feasible and makes no sense. Solving conflict with conflict makes no sense as it simply propagates more conflict. Radical Islam is a large minority sect within Islamic Communities, and they gain traction because they are harsh and ruthless with what they do. They are simply responding to what they see as the Westernization of their World, and this is the problem: they don't want to be like us. We wouldn't improve the situation, we'd make it infinitely worse if we decided to occupy the Middle East. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
