<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360230598.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>How familiar are you with the history of the countries you are so swiftly dismissing as essentially "unfit to lead themselves?"

Many of the countries in the Middle East and Africa are former colonies, and have only had the "100 years" you mention to try and bounce back from colonial rule. Surely that isn't a fair starting point.

Also, your view tends to ignore the fact that the Western world plunged the globe into two horrendous wars within this last 100 years over equally childish reasons as current sectarian Arab conflicts.  You can't look at current extreme minorities and reclassify an entire region of the globe to their views while simultaneously putting on blinders to the war and genocide propagated by the "other" side.


The current regional trend of a more extreme version of Islam is also a recent advent. Read this summary of the Wahhabi movement (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wahhabi_movement) and you will see that the version of Islam we see today doesn't reflect the historical version very well. In 50 years we may very well be able to look back and say:
"Boy, isn't that crazy that from the 1970's to the 2040's a huge portion of the Arab world ascribed to that crazy version of Islam?"

Finally, your premise about us somehow  having the intrinsic authority to regulate people across the world bothers me. That we (I'm assuming you are from the US) get to decide that because the Middle East hasn't eliminated their violent minority we get to subjugate them all. This is exactly what ISIS is after. Their mission statement would be the same sentence except with the words "Middle East" and "eliminated their violent minority" replaced with "rest of the world" and "adopted strict Sharia Law."

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360256004.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>The intrinsic authority comes from being morally superior. How do you think people in the west would react if a violent Christian cult started beheading and crucifying Muslims and other Christians who did not practice the same faith? I don't propose we police the entire world, but when group after group rises up to state their intentions of destroying the western world, I kind of get fed up with being politically correct. I'm outraged that people would behead journalists and foreign aid workers and put them on the internet to cause terror in their enemies. I'm outraged that when capturing a city of new Iraqi army recruits, they promise to spare them and instead end up murdering over 3,000 of them. I'm outraged that this group trapped 30,000 people atop a mountain and crucified children. There is not an excuse that you can come up with to say that leaving this group/ideology to flourish is an acceptable course of action. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360285233.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>You can't claim moral superiority over an entire region simple because they have extremist elements. Should all Americans be compared to KKK members simply because we haven't eliminated their influence?

In fact, you can't simply assert a moral authority period. Even though I agree with you that most people on Earth are morally superior to members of ISIS, it still doesn't make moral superiority an objective value. The Spanish exterminated and enslaved millions of indigenous South Americans on the basis of moral superiority. It's ALWAYS relative. 


It seems that you are justifiably angry with Muslim extremists, but that doesn't provide justification to subjugate the entire Middle East. It merely provides some justification for military action against the extremists.

Even if you did find the authority to take over the region, all historical evidence points to the fact that occupation never works in the long run, and it would just make the problem worse. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
