<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360206013.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What do you do with all the people that are already there?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360217238.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>They become colonists and live under Western law, depending on whichever country has control. They basically become citizens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360225568.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So, when you say recolonizing, what are you saying? How many new people are going to live in the land?

EDIT: And furthermore, how in the hell do you plan on enforcing Western law?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360230674.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying we take over with military power, establish new colonial governments, use their oil and other resources to help us, and force peace for generations until the radicals die out of natural causes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360231999.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Do you really think this is possible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360239517.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think we have really committed to it. We have always gone after ideas instead of countries/regions. If we take away their ability to organize and escape to allied countries, how can they resist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360230528.0" user="tobynomates" delta="False">
    <text>And how will that fix the problems which lead to violent extremism? Wouldnt that make it infinitely worse by turning millions of them against us?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360241814.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>It won't the first few years. It's a long term view. If you take away their ability to practice violent extremism, take away their recruiting power, it will die out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360245187.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you take away their ability to practice violent extremism, take away their recruiting power, it will die out.

None of what you're proposing does this. Even if you're proposing making the entire middle east a police state... which is completely unfeasible. We don't have the resources to overthrow dozens of militaries, governments *and* radical groups, and if we did there'd be a huge cost *and* if you're going that far you might as well go after Russia too, because you're going to piss them off...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360260462.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I see that. But doesn't Russia see the problem of radical Islam as well? ISIS has already threatened Putin, not in a very real way of course, but still enough to know that they would attack them if they could. Russia invaded in the 70's of course and you know that they haven't forgotten. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360269504.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, Russia does. So do we.

It is a leap to go from ending problems with radical militants to *overthrowing multiple countries*, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360270461.0" user="tobynomates" delta="False">
    <text>How will you take away their ability to commit violent extremism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360265851.0" user="brownribbon" delta="False">
    <text>If they become citizens they get the right to move freely between borders of the colony and mother country. Terrorists, as well as those who simply don't want a foreign occupying force, would absolutely love this.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
