<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360261378.0" user="Bodoblock" delta="False">
    <text>It's absolutely not a healthy view, nor one that really solves anything.

&amp;gt;I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be.

The Middle East is not one monolithic block that decides to be one thing or the other. Additionally, it's not as if these last 100 years have been completely up to them.

Let's look at the Middle East countries, particularly the trouble regions.

Bahrain: A British Protectorate till 1971

Egypt: British until 1922, Suez Crisis invasion from Israel, Britain, and France in 1956

Iran: Briefly Russian occupied in 1911, Partly British occupied from WWI - 1921, Allied invasion of Iran in 1941, US overthrow of Mohammad Mosaddegh in 1953

Iraq: British until 1932, British invasion of Iraq in 1941, US invasion of Iraq in 2003

Lebanon: French until 1943

Palestine: This one is...complicated, to say the least

Syria: French rule (of one form or the other) until 1941

Simply put, the West has a pretty active history of involving itself in Middle Eastern affairs.

&amp;gt;I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there.

The overwhelming, vast majority of Arab Muslims both do not give a damn in the world about you but would still not like to see innocent people viciously beheaded.

Know that it's actually the Arabs who suffer the brunt of extremist violence and terrorism.

&amp;gt;I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east.

Ignoring the absurdly phenomenal cost of such a proposition, realize that doing so would simply validate the extremists in the region and exacerbate the terrorist threat to far new highs we've yet to see.

Our recent nearly a decade long foray into Iraq, while it wasn't an occupation, should be proof enough as to why a prolonged stay can't and won't bring out the results you're trying to seek.

&amp;gt;We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia

The US isn't oil-dependent on Russia. Other Western nations can, I am sure, figure out cheaper and more reasonable options than militarily engaging and invading 18 countries.

&amp;gt;Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully,

Yes, because militarily imposing peace and forcing two populations that hate each other to live amongst one another is so easy.

&amp;gt;"radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon

Or it becomes a banner for all those trying to regain the sovereignty of their countries. We saw in Iraq that our involvement can often strengthen extremism more than deter it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
