<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360490045.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Look, there's nothing in it for anyone. You're saying that that we should invade foreign countries, destroy their political structures (which are largely artificially created by the last round of colonialism), wipe out whatever cultural or religious practices you don't like, and the like to make you like them better?

Why does it matter if you like them? The whole ISIS thing is largely irrelevant to anyone not in the region, and the radical Islam is direct reaction against destabilizing steps taken by Europeans and Cold War Antagonists to destabilize the region. A Eurozone or US-led invasion is simply a continuation of the historical disaster. You wouldn't be *stabilizing* these countries but rather *further encouraging armed resistance*.  Ultimately, these countries need to stabilize themselves, because anything imposed from the outside will invariably be a bad fit and simply be a rinse-repeat of what happened the last few dozen times.

Besides, it's not like we need Gulf oil like we used to. Did you know that Persian Gulf sources accounted for [12.9% of US oil imports in 2012](http://www.npr.org/2012/04/11/150444802/where-does-america-get-oil-you-may-be-surprised)? Local US sources accounted for 33.8% and Canada accounts for 15.1%. Russia isn't even on the list. Additionally if Europe wants to be free of Russian Natural Gas then all they have to do is put in LNG ports and accept shipments from the Americas were the cost of Natural Gas is half that of Europe. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
