<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360444977.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one

More uninformed than anything else. Extremely dubious moral arguments aside, the US(the bulk of the West's military power) bankrupted itself with trying to 'stabilize' Iraq, you think it has resources or will to colonize the entire Middle East? This is a special kind of delusional.

&amp;gt; "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare

Naive thinking. Radical Islam is the symptom of the problem and not the problem itself. The true problem is that Middle Eastern peoples' grievances against the West are *mostly* legitimate - we're talking about a great civilization once upon a time utterly humiliated and decimated by foreign forces, military and cultural, for the last century. 

But our innate desire to swallow propaganda leave some people like you too uninformed to think critically. Let me try and help. 

Why is it that IS is able to expand so quickly? Are they superhuman monsters? Are they rabid cultists who just so happen to be sane enough to adopt smart battle tactics and organizational philosophies? Ask yourself how is it that such a primitively minded group like IS can *control* the territories they've gained. 

It is because the Islamic State actually has a great deal of *tacit support* from the arab population. It's because arab people really are sick and tired of being abused, exploited, and kicked around by the West and their client states. And they're tired of their national boundaries being artificially drawn (look it up Sykes-Picot).

I don't support the Islamic State, but it's clear that I have better reasons than you as for why. Maybe that fact alone should dissuade you from holding such sophomoric views. Sorry if I come across as a bit hostile. If you can believe it, I once thought like you regarding these sorts of things and a bit of self-loathing leaks through. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
