<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360263922.0" user="brownribbon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be.

They had 1000 years prior to the 20th century to do just that and they were doing okay until the discovery of massive oil reserves piqued the west's interests and we began sticking our noses in their affairs. 
Combine that with the fact that different western nations have backed different countries at different times (the US backed Iraq in the Iran-Iraq war and the Mujahideen in Afghanistan when the USSR invaded) and any attempts at deciding "who they as a culture are" will constantly be disrupted. Also...

&amp;gt;who they as a culture want to be

Depending on how you define it, the Middle East has ~20 countries, over 375,000,000 people speaking at least 12 languages, and comprising all of the three Abrahamic faiths (plus a small number of adherents to other religions). How can one reasonably expect this large and diverse a group to come to a consensus on something like a single uniform culture? Not even the eastern United States (which is smaller both geographically and in population) has a consistent culture. And we all speak the same language.

&amp;gt;e divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia

I don't understand this point. Dividing up the Middle East wouldn't suddenly make the oil fields disappear. And the majority US (I'm assuming you're American) oil imports come from the Western hemisphere--Canada, Mexico, and Venezuela being the primary sources.

&amp;gt;Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon

Neither of these things can be done without a very large ad long term military commitment. Which will cost a lot of money. And lives.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27360279558.0" user="ThrownOutToday" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about the rest of Western Europe who are reliant on Russia for their oil. Also, the US and Western Europe have well over 375,000,000 speaking more than 12 languages. How do you explain our mostly cohesive culture. If the atrocities that ISIS were committing happened in the West, then we as a culture would be morally outraged and committed to stopping it. It may not be economically feasible to occupy 20 countries, but really this rant is born of frustration at watching yet another innocent person lose their life to nonsense. I wish I had the answer to stomp this shit out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27363487660.0" user="Spot_the_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>There have been numerous civil  wars in European countries since world war 2.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
