<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="148359593.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gbuzt/cmv_the_west_should_recolonize_the_middle_east/">
    <title>CMV: The West should recolonize the Middle East.</title>
    <original_poster>ThrownOutToday</original_poster>
    <original_post>It's probably not a healthy view or a popular one, but with the rise of ISIS I find myself thinking that the middle east has had 100 years to decide who they as a culture want to be. Now we have sayings like "that will happen as soon as there is peace in the middle east" to say something is impossible. I'm struggling with racist tendencies. Racist might not be the right word, maybe its a combination of theologism(I don't think that's a word, but you know that I mean) and racism. I understand that not all Arabic Muslims want my head on a platter, but enough do to constantly have struggles over there. With the release of this newest beheading, I think we need to basically recolonize the middle east. We divide up the countries from Turkey to Iraq, which then means we have a solid oil source not dependent on Russia, Palestine and Israel are forced to share space and live peacefully, "radical Islam" is for the most part stamped out and frowned upon, and the young people of those states can now grow up in a stabilized home where they can develop other skills besides learning guerrilla warfare. The only downside I see with this is Russia stepping in, but I'm sure there is a solution to be found. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27360595330.0" user="forwhomisthe" delta="False">
    <text>First... world population is about 8 billion. Don't you feel a tiny bit silly that one beheading is making you consider occupying 1/4 of the globe? Fly on the window, meet brick. ISIS could execute a journalist a day for three years and they still wouldn't make a dent in anything important.

If you are feeling racist towards the Middle East, you should be avoiding colonialism like the plague. Tightly integrated colonial administration creates population transfers between the colonized periphery and the imperial homeland. The large, problematic immigrant populations in France and Britain date from a point when the immigrants' native lands were considered intimately linked with those countries. 

You endgame for the neo-colonial Middle East seems to be... oil. Why all this work for oil? If oil is all we want, it's as easy to buy it from ISIS as from Assad or Saudi. Oil is a simple problem. What you're proposing is like organizing an armed invasion of your local Walmart to make sure they continue to supply you with cheap t-shirts; the smart thing is to leave Walmart to their own devices, since they do a great job selling their wares without armed protection.

The reason why Middle East chaos bothers us is because we wants a democratic Iraq, we want the Yezidis to live in peace, we want the Palestinians out of refugeee camps, we want Iranians to be able to attend volleyball games, all that good stuff. You aren't even offering an iota of an argument for how re-colonization would solve any of that. In fact, it was the first wave of colonization that caused most of these problems to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
