<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149345306.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gwzkq/cmv_its_a_good_idea_for_bank_tellers_to_be_armed/">
    <title>CMV: It's a good idea for bank tellers to be armed.</title>
    <original_poster>ImAwesomeLMAO</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not entirely passionate about second amendment rights, but it just seems like a rational solution to the problem of an armed robber coming in every now and then. This won't help with any nonviolent thieves that use sneaking, hacking or bad checks, but mostly just to protect the customers and the employees themselves.

Assuming the employees are at least a little trustworthy, there's nothing to worry about. 

This isn't something I've done more than some Googling on, but it just occurred to me. Happy Friday guys.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27369935553.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather not do my banking where 4+ in the building are armed. The answer to the threat of violence shouldn't be the threat of violence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27369989159.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't answer a threat of violence with a threat of violence, how do you answer it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370001749.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You answer it with justice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370029787.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>so, what, police that carry guns? that's just a threat of violence if you don't do what they say.

a threat of violence is the only response to a threat of violence that isn't injury or violation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370247140.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Really, so security cameras, blue paint bombs on the money… those are threats of violence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370405469.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>Really, so security cameras, blue paint bombs on the money... those catch bank robbers and/or have stopped bank robberies from happening? No, they increase the chances of the robbers getting caught by cops, who will then use violence to apprehend them if they give resistance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370474903.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The threat of justice (getting caught) deters more crime than the threat of violence (being killed by a police officer). Arming more citizens doesn't make anyone safer, it just increases the chances of someone being shot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370487406.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, but the statistics don't back you up on that last point, not even a little. [Concealed carry coincides with a drop in crime rate in almost every city and state where it is allowed, and has never coincided with an increase in crime](http://www.gunfacts.info/gun-control-myths/concealed-carry/) so to say that arming citizens increases the chances of someone being shot is just wrong.

Further, the threat of "getting caught" is bullshit. What, they're gonna go to prison to learn how to become a better criminal? Oh no, what a nightmare for a career criminal. Deterrence is the best form of crime prevention for situations like this, and the idea that "if I try to rob a bank, I am likely going to die" is much more of a deterrent than "if I try to rob a bank, I might get sent to prison for 5 years"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370496714.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're right dude. I mean for 10.50/hour who wouldn't want to get into a gunfight over federally insured money? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370500515.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>Funnily, this hasn't been any of your other points, so interesting abandoning those to go for sarcasm. Further, there doesn't have to be a shootout; it's been proven dozens of times that putting more guns in secured facilities is more likely to result in less gunfights. Thirdly, I'd much rather be in a gunfight over federally insured money than be a victim of a shooting over federally insured money, given the two options.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370521433.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Whenever I go to the bank, risk of someone robbing the place is pretty far from my mind. I can't even think of the last time I've heard of a violent bank robbery happening in my state. Some problems don't need radical solutions. I'm cool with the inherent risk of going to the bank (basically 0% chance of anything happening). I would be more concerned about getting shot by a dumbass teller than getting robbed while at the bank. In fact I wouldn't mind if no guns existed the world. The idea of people wanting to carry around killing machines just seems weird to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370550434.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, this is a bunch of stuff to unravel:

Firstly [there are an average of about 14 bank robberies a day across the US;](http://www.fbi.gov/stats-services/publications/bank-crime-statistics-2011/bank-crime-statistics-2011) the statistics are a bit old, but I don't think they've taken a dramatic downward turn. Just because you haven't seen one doesn't mean anything; you spend relatively low amounts of time in a bank, compared to a teller or manager.

I also wouldn't mind if no guns existed. Or if there weren't bad people. But they do, and there are, and so reasonable people want to defend themselves with the best-available technology. I can understand someone who has never been in a life-threatening situation not understanding a law-abiding citizen's want or need to carry a firearm, but having a knife to your throat because you were out at night and might've been carrying money can change your perception really damn quickly.

To put it differently; sometimes people know that it isn't what an act *looks like* that matters, it's the *expected outcome* of the action that is important, and the utility that it gives. There is a pretty small chance, individually, that any one person will find themselves in a violent situation, but there are some hundreds of violent situations happening every day, and someone is going to be involved in those. Sometimes those people will be innocent, law-abiding people just going about their day. Listen to [this testimony](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DEJFAvA-ZUE) about this woman's inability to do anything when she was in a gun free zone and a crazy man came in and gunned down her parents. The fact is that guns exist, and we can't get rid of them. You can make one fairly simply out of piping and a nail and some rubber bands.

So, does the idea that cops want to carry around guns seem weird? I always find that disparity odd, and I think that this is the real reason that anti-gun people don't like me as much when they know that I own and occasionally carry a gun; you can't comprehend my reasoning, and I am culturally "other", and the tribal brain takes over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370570086.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Had I ever been in a life threatening situation, my opinion might be different but that's because fear clouds rational judgment. I think that a bank teller is much better off giving up the money (that will be replace by insurance) and letting the police (trained individuals who use their guns as a last resort) than brandishing a weapon and giving the criminal a good reason to use deadly force. Bank robbers usually don't want to be murderers, they simply want money. It might be true that concealed carry helps lower crime overall but in this specific scenario I'd rather not do my banking in a building full of armed individuals. More guns might equate to less crime, but I feel that's a rather short sighted solution. I think our focus should be on allowing police to isolate and diffuse these dangerous situations rather than encourage vigilante justice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370599737.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>Fear passes, realism is learned. It wasn't like I got mugged and then immediately got a gun; I spent time studying self-defense and researching these things. The world can be a dangerous place, and while it sounds all nice and noble to let the police handle it, my corpse doesn't care if its murderer gets caught; my living self cares about staying alive, regardless of whether or not there are any police around to hear me cry for help.

Depending on where you live, you likely already do your banking in a building full of armed individuals. I don't think that bank robbers want to be murderers, nor do I think they want to be dead. But until 13 years ago, we also didn't think hijackers wanted to be murderers, so assuming that right off the bat isn't always true. The statistics bear out that places with more guns attract less crime, and we shouldn't be letting our visceral reaction to guns influence how we react to the facts any more than we let our visceral reaction to dead bodies affect the fact that studying and operating on cadavers gives us a better understanding of biology and that surgeons benefit from practicing on corpses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27370045335.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>How does justice work?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
