<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149345306.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gwzkq/cmv_its_a_good_idea_for_bank_tellers_to_be_armed/">
    <title>CMV: It's a good idea for bank tellers to be armed.</title>
    <original_poster>ImAwesomeLMAO</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not entirely passionate about second amendment rights, but it just seems like a rational solution to the problem of an armed robber coming in every now and then. This won't help with any nonviolent thieves that use sneaking, hacking or bad checks, but mostly just to protect the customers and the employees themselves.

Assuming the employees are at least a little trustworthy, there's nothing to worry about. 

This isn't something I've done more than some Googling on, but it just occurred to me. Happy Friday guys.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27370059277.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>Here is why I don't think this is a great idea-

Training costs to make every teller smart around, and about guns would outweigh the cost that a bank would lose in the event of a robbery. Remember bank robbers make off with less than $15,000 the majority of the time- and this is if the haul is extremely successful, whereas training the staff in even a small bank would cost at least this much. It's just economically a bad idea.

It would elevate the chances of injury to the teller- Most bank robberies and armed robberies do not result in deaths or even serious injuries. People taking the risk don't want to needlessly turn a armed robbery conviction into a murder conviction. These people, in desperate times anyway, will essentially be given a choice between calling off the robbery altogether, or pulling the trigger when the teller draws.

In addition to the above, you are needlessly putting the teller in an even more stressful situation. Now, rather than simply handing over the cash, potentially adding a dye pack or pushing a silent alarm, they are expected based upon their training to meet the robber with potentially deadly force. This can contribute to the robbery going less smoothly, increasing the chances of injury or death on both sides.

Many tellers would be unable to complete the training, or fulfill their new job descriptions. Depending on the issued firearm, there are quite simply tellers who would be unable to use it. Tellers range from young and strong to old and frail, and everything in between. Giving a skin and bones grandmother a .38 special and expecting her to control it during a stressful situation is absurd. This would cost quite a few people their jobs.

Ask yourself, is it worth it to put a life at greater risk, spending thousands of dollers to put employees through weeks if not months of training, and purge the workforce for those unable to do something that has never been part of their job description, simply to potentially save a few thousand dollers?

source regarding bankrobbery averages http://crimeblog.dallasnews.com/2009/04/new-bank-robbery-stats-show-lu.html/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
