<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1493733763.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/opbwcj/cmv_vehicles_waiting_on_the_side_of_the_road/">
    <title>CMV: vehicles waiting on the side of the road (loading, unloading, breakdowns, buses etc) should use the pavement side indicators only, not hazard lights</title>
    <original_poster>physioworld</original_poster>
    <original_post>The idea here is that hazard warning lights on a vehicle only work when you can clearly see both side lights and there are many many times in city streets where you can only see one set. 

Basically I think it’s more dangerous to be stationary on the side of the road (excluding parked cars for obvious reasons) regardless of the reason and have your hazard lights on, than to just indicate to the side of the road you’re waiting on. 

My reasoning for this is that if you approach this vehicle from behind and one set of lights is blocked, you may think that the vehicle is about to pull out into traffic, which causes unnecessary uncertainty. 

On the other hand if you see a stationary vehicle on the side of the road and you see no lights, you simply steer around it, which is the intended point anyway. 

Overall I think this would help smooth the flow of traffic and reduce uncertainty about intended actions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37375278076.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>When a car is in a place where it would typically be moving but is not it is _really important_ that the location and color of _brake lights_ be represented.  

Ideally of course you steer around it, but outside of close range knowing a car is stationary vs. moving is oddly challenging.  The reason you have hazards where they are and in red is both to draw attention, but also to make it very clear that the car _is not moving_.  A car powered down without these lights is indistinguishable at a glance from a car that is driving forward.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
