<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1493733763.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/opbwcj/cmv_vehicles_waiting_on_the_side_of_the_road/">
    <title>CMV: vehicles waiting on the side of the road (loading, unloading, breakdowns, buses etc) should use the pavement side indicators only, not hazard lights</title>
    <original_poster>physioworld</original_poster>
    <original_post>The idea here is that hazard warning lights on a vehicle only work when you can clearly see both side lights and there are many many times in city streets where you can only see one set. 

Basically I think it’s more dangerous to be stationary on the side of the road (excluding parked cars for obvious reasons) regardless of the reason and have your hazard lights on, than to just indicate to the side of the road you’re waiting on. 

My reasoning for this is that if you approach this vehicle from behind and one set of lights is blocked, you may think that the vehicle is about to pull out into traffic, which causes unnecessary uncertainty. 

On the other hand if you see a stationary vehicle on the side of the road and you see no lights, you simply steer around it, which is the intended point anyway. 

Overall I think this would help smooth the flow of traffic and reduce uncertainty about intended actions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37375092229.0" user="Trevorjrt6" delta="False">
    <text>The ultimate goal of hazards is to get your attention. You thinking they are about to pull out is a success. That means it got your attention and now your driving more cautiously past them. You should never feel comfortable and complacent passing a stopped vehicle on the side of the road, that would lead to more accidents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37375206293.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>Very much this!  I would just like to add that the primary goals of hazards and turn signals are the same (drawing attention), which is why they blink.

A turn signal indicating the desired direction change is a secondary effect that you process *after* the blinking signal catches your attention.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
