<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27376240783.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>It teaches a child about the unconditional love of a parent and how even though a parent will keep giving it can cost them everything. That seems like a decent moral to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376939256.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that teaching kids about love is a good thing, but there should also be an aspect of accepting that love and appreciating or acknowledging its existence. The boy seems to exist in his own bubble, just taking what the tree has to offer without even saying thank you. I don't want to teach that moral.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
