<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375763931.0" user="Karissa36" delta="False">
    <text>Your problem here is thinking that there is only one truth.  The fact is as we proceed through life, there are many different truths and philosophies.  Sometimes one is more relevant and useful and sometimes another.  Sometimes charity is good.  Sometimes not.  So stop fighting with your wife about this book and instead add in your own book to read to your child.  I recommend The Little Red Hen.  You can read the story here.

http://www.enchantedlearning.com/stories/fairytale/littleredhen/story/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
