<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375887237.0" user="WeaselOvercome" delta="False">
    <text>It is not a story for children, it is a story for parents to read in front of their children. If it stuck out to you as a child it is because when your parents read it to you they got really solemn and quiet or even cried a little bit. You didn't understand anything, but you remember the book because it was important to your parents and it gained a solemnity in your household. 

Any cop-out to have the boy say "Well, I'll visit you on weekends!" or "Ill only use some of the branches!" would show parents' love as transactional or halfway, when it isn't. Parents' love is sacrificial, and utterly total. The book is shoving that right in your face. Of course the boy should say thank you or whatever, but the book isn't written for people to presently identify with the boy. They should only feel the tinge of regret of seeing their past selves in that boy.  The point is that parents' love is sacrificial and utterly total.  

So you read that damn book to your kids and cry a little.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375897643.0" user="dorky2" delta="False">
    <text>I remember that book so well from childhood, and I loved the story.  I always felt sad for the tree, but happy at the end that she could be happy and give the boy one last gift.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
