<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375803325.0" user="Ecator" delta="False">
    <text>I don't get entitlement from the boy in this story. Entitlement is the fact of having a right to something. The boy plays with the tree as a child, and then comes back later at various times. Each time it is the tree that asks something of the boy and he says no I don't want that I want this instead and the tree then provides that to the boy. At no point does the boy take anything that isn't offered by the tree. If anything the tree is the one who is entitled because each time upon seeing the boy again asks him to make her happy. It is like the tree feels like it has a right to happiness only the boy can bring so that is its entitlement. 

Why does the tree need the boy to be happy? Does the tree really need the boy or is it just the feeling the tree gets at being able to provide something for the boy. In chasing that feeling of happiness in providing for the boy the tree sacrifices everything of itself for that. Is that really what the tree wanted? To be a stump of a tree that props up and old dead man but is happy because it can be of use? 

I have never read that story before so I may just be reading more into it than is there but it seems deeper than just a tale about some entitled boy. I get more of a warning for moderation out of it than anything else. Had the tree got enjoyment out of providing for the child but instead of chasing down that happy feeling like an addict and instead went for contentment in being a tree in the forest it wouldn't have wound up a stump.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
