<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375580346.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think that just because the story contains characters who are immoral that the story is telling us to be like them? It could very well be saying, "your parents give so much for you, don't be like this horrible kid" in which case it would have great morals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375582629.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>I think its the last line "And the tree was happy". It seems to justify all of this by saying that its ok to abuse the tree if the tree is happy about it.

Edit: but I like the notion of teaching not to be like the kid. I can attempt to spin that when my little one has a better concept of morality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375589053.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>I think the story is meant to show unconditional love from the perspective of the one giving it, rather than receiving it (the perspective children are most used to). I don't personally believe that it necessarily has a moral, more that it presents something and leaves us to interpret it. What it presents is ultimately, what it's like to be a parent. It is rewarding to be a parent, there is no question that the tree should be happy. But a child reading the story might think, "wow, I never knew how much work went into dealing with me when I act like this."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375597155.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ultimately, what it's like to be a parent

I think this is what I am most opposed to. Unconditional love is an amazing feeling. But you can love someone, put them before yourself, and still seek acknowledgement for your actions. You want to know that you are appreciated or at least that your gifts have not been made in vain. 

Its cutting to see the child take, the parent give, and in the end the child winds up miserable. He doesn't share tales of his adventures, his joys or his sadness. He just comes to the tree to complain and to take. I would never want my child to think that is even an optional way to treat a parent. 

I wouldn't mind if my child read the book and thought "thank god I'm nothing like that little shit" but I also don't want her to think of me as a gullible tree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375718384.0" user="ablarga" delta="False">
    <text>I've always wondered - what does appreciation look like? Is it someone repeatedly saying "Thank you, thank you, thank you!" Is it someone prostrating themselves at your feet? Is it someone giving something to you in return?

I think the boy was appreciative. He asked the tree for help, and took that help and lived a good life with it. He grew up, he had a business, he raised a family, he traveled the world. He became his own man, he didn't harm others, and he didn't harm himself. He always asked. He never took more than the tree was willing to give. That, in my opinion, shows a deep respect for the things he was given. 

&amp;gt; He doesn't share tales of his adventures, his joys or his sadness.

You know, the tree never asks. The tree never asks about the boy's family, or the boy's travels. The tree doesn't ask why the boy is sad. The tree just wants the boy to play, like old times. The tree cares about the "idea" of the boy, not the man the boy has grown into. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376430209.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>This is a really good point. I didn't agree with OP to begin with, but if I had, this would probably have changed my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375590433.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>I've always believed that a person should do the right thing because it's the right thing, not because they'll get thanked for it. The tree genuinely cares about the boy, and does things for him. At the end of the boy's life, all he wants is companionship of the tree. I don't think thanks needs to be said there. He is thankful. The tree doesn't need to hear it. The moral is to be like the tree: do good with no expectation of reward other than knowing you've done a good thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375602418.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; all he wants is companionship of the tree.

I disagree with this sentiment. He doesn't care if the tree is there or not. In the end all he wants is a place to sit. The tree offers and once again the boy takes, but the tree could just as easily said "take my stump and make a chair" and the boy would have uprooted the tree and done so.

As for doing the right thing, I don't think that you need to desecrate yourself to do the right thing. The boy could have taken half of the tree and accomplished his goals, but the boy gives no thought to the tree and that notion of selfishness just bothers me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375695069.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>There's no reason to believe that he could have built the house using only half of the tree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375697276.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>There no reason to believe he could have built a complete house with the branches from one tree either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375709641.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>Correct, my whole point was that we don't know what resources exactly were available to him and what his actual needs were.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375701368.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>While I may have read it as a little kid, the first memory of this book was in 5th grade.  The teacher read it to the class.  We thought it was kind of sad because the tree was so nice but was taken advantage of.  Be like the tree, not the boy.  That's what we thought at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375764455.0" user="Uzerwhat" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I think it teaches empathy. I remember feeling pretty sad for the tree as well. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375782512.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>Well also we had to see the boy's point of view as well.  I don't think there's any part of the story where he realizes how much the tree sacrificed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375911602.0" user="aeschenkarnos" delta="False">
    <text>It reallly needs a sequel where he is turned into a tree. Kevin Smith could make it. Call it "Leaves".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376092720.0" user="goodolarchie" delta="False">
    <text>I believe so too.  I recall thinking in a child's words *This guy is a piece of shit.*  It's almost an allegory for an abusive relationship, or at least one where somebody is being taken for granted.  Ultimately, we feel sorry for the tree, and more thankful for the things that are given freely to us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375970023.0" user="crocodile_in_denial" delta="False">
    <text>allowing yourself to be taken advantage of it is not a great lesson either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375985794.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe that's part of the lesson as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375989176.0" user="crocodile_in_denial" delta="False">
    <text>that would go against your "be like the tree" lesson</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376004472.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>Meh.  My interpretation could he flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376156730.0" user="INDABUTTYEAH" delta="False">
    <text>I think you make a good point, in that the tree doesn't represent parents, it represents the worker. The boy of course is representative of corporations. The narrative is the description of how corporations exploit everything a worker has until he is worn down to a stump. At which point the corporation goes and finds another tree to stump.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27377113967.0" user="112-Cn" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think so: this analysis seems very modern, can you point to any indication showing the story was crafted with this in mind?

Additionally, the story (seems to) teach altruism &amp;amp; empathy, sacrificing yourself ( the tree) for the sake of the child. Are you saying that the story teaches the workers to sacrifice themselves for the good of corporations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376239972.0" user="fuchsiamatter" delta="False">
    <text>That's worse. It glorifies self-sacrifice and encourages martyr complexes. It would serve as a terrible guide upon embarking into adulthood, especially with regard to romantic relationships. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376819244.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't about romance.  It was a parent child relationship.  Even as 5th graders we saw that.  We didn't know if the tree was right to do what he did, but we did know the tree was kind and in the end the boy learned the most valuable thing from the tree was company.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
