<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375594572.0" user="convoces" delta="False">
    <text>Almost every story can be interpreted in multiple ways.

I felt exactly the same way as you about the boy when I read the story as a child. The story illustrates how the tree gives so much, and the boy gives nothing in return and it just felt wrong.

It's precisely how it's presented that was compelling to me as a child. I don't think the morality of the story is necessarily wrong. The story is *meant* to evoke a feeling of injustice about the relationship, to teach a lesson of gratitude by using an extreme example.

I think that's why the story is told from the tree's point of view. The key here is the perspective from which the story is told. You aren't told the story from the view of the boy: he's meant to be an example of a taker, so you don't empathize with his view. The story means to put you into the shoes of someone who gives a lot. 

Then, you learn the lesson by **empathizing with and seeing the point of view of someone who is generous.** You see what it costs them (in the case of the tree, almost everything) and it teaches gratitude.

EDIT: Words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375604215.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Almost every story can be interpreted in multiple ways.

I do agree with this. Your point is solid and maybe once my little gains a better understanding of morality I can try to provide her with the ideas of injustice and empathy with the tree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375615523.0" user="convoces" delta="False">
    <text>Cool! Yes, I definitely think there is at least a little bit of guidance or groundwork needed.

If I was able to help change your view in any way, do you mind awarding a delta? The instructions are on the sidebar. Or if not, is there anything else that I can help change your view about the topic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375617704.0" user="placebo_addicted" delta="False">
    <text>You could ask your wife to ad lib a "and the boy said, thank you!" when it's appropriate. It doesn't change the content, your little one won't know the difference and the story might stop irritating you so much. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375887711.0" user="jackpg98" delta="False">
    <text>Completely changes the whole point of the story, which is that the boy is exploiting the tree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375896567.0" user="placebo_addicted" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but we're talking about reading a story to a two year old. I think the story is a bit deeper than the boy's exploitation, more about the inherent value of the tree, and I don't see that changed by the boy expressing gratitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376830182.0" user="AShavedApe" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a huge fan of Shel Silverstein and this is a huge slap in his face to change the words. The message is there and it's great. Changing it isn't going to help the kid be moral and it's pretty upsetting to alter art so you're more happy to read it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376867019.0" user="placebo_addicted" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a fan as well, but I'm also a fan of familial harmony. I can't imagine that Mr Silverstein would really mind much if a parent of a toddler broke from the text to say "and this is when the little boy says thank you" or "this is when we should say thank you" in order to extend a lesson of gratitude to the poem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376899296.0" user="AShavedApe" delta="False">
    <text>Those are side-notes and separate lessons. Of course you can do that. But to add words directly into the story as if Shel wrote them is definitely not cool. I think reading the book as it is and then explaining afterwards is the best way to go about it. Shel Silverstein was very careful at writing kids books that were also very deep when broken down so even if kids could see that the kid was taking and taking, they might not see that it was the tree giving which is the focus (or vice versa). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376914952.0" user="placebo_addicted" delta="False">
    <text>I generally agree with you, but it's important to keep in mind we are talking about a two year old here. If you want to impress upon a two year old, it really has to happen at the exact appropriate moment to be effective. Trying to explain the secondary message after the conclusion of the story is an exercise in futility. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376925373.0" user="AShavedApe" delta="False">
    <text>I can't argue with you on that one haha </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376984234.0" user="TBFProgrammer" delta="False">
    <text>Depends where you put it. If it comes right before the statement that the tree was happy, it could be interpreted as saying "thank you" allows you to take whatever you want. This is a legitimate concern, to the extent that the original concern is legitimate, given that some children have to be reminded that "please" and "excuse me" are requests. Placed anywhere else, its a bit awkward but doesn't have a negative reading.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376408204.0" user="IAMARobotBeepBoop" delta="False">
    <text>My 5 year old is a bit short on empathy. I'm going to read this story to him and see what his interpretation is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
