<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375604039.0" user="vl99" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like there's a connection you're not making here. Sure the book ends with "and the tree was happy" but the message you're getting, that parents give and give, kids take and take, and parents are a-ok with that is only half the message.

The book teaches parents that the joy in parenting is being able to provide for your child, and that giving is better than receiving, etc. It also teaches you that while your child may not realize how important you are to them all the time, they will find comfort in your company once they grow older and wiser. This is shown by the old man not requiring anything physical from the tree at the end of the book, merely to find comfort in the presence of the tree.

To kids reading, the book delivers the message that if your parents love you, they'll keep providing for you in spite of it all, but this doesn't mean you should take advantage of them. Rather it shows you in a very physical metaphor the pain that your bullshit can cause your parents to go through and perhaps you should appreciate them for what they would do for you rather than just asking them to do it all the time.

Sure the tree was happy in spite of how much of its body was missing, but a kid reading might think "wow that tree looks really hurt, did he really need to hurt it? Why couldn't he just grow his own tree or buy a boat somewhere else? Did he need to take all the apples? Why is the tree happy when I feel so sad for it?"

Personally that's what I always got from it ever since I was old enough to interpret the serious message.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375629798.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is shown by the old man not requiring anything physical from the tree at the end of the book, merely to find comfort in the presence of the tree.

But again, the tree has nothing to do with it. The boy doesn't say I just want to sit here with you. He says I just want to sit. The tree could have just as easily said "come make a chair from my stump". The boy has no care at all for the tree or companionship (also shown by first trying to build a house for a family, then needing a boat to get away from that family).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375659870.0" user="vl99" delta="False">
    <text>The book could have ended with the boy taking the boat and that being the last we heard of him if he really had no connection to the tree. 

Hell why not sit in the boat if you really need a place to sit, on the ground, in the myriad other stumps in the forest, or in one of the chairs I'm sure he has bought over the course of his life?

When he came to the tree for apples to make money, it made sense. The tree was a quick and easy resource he could exploit when he was young and didn't have as many options. He may have also been young enough he wasn't conscious yet of the ramifications of his actions on the tree.

There are a million places he could go to sit. Hell, if he took a boat to get away from his family, it's pretty certain that he sailed that boat far away from his family, and thus the tree as well making it very inconvenient to come back, especially in his old age, but he did. What does that tell you? Even if it was subconscious, he desired to be near that particular tree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375665265.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>Or simply that if he ever needed anything, the tree would give it. The lack of mutual respect bothers me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375713198.0" user="vl99" delta="False">
    <text>Good, it should have bothered you. You should have been sad for the tree, and felt like the boy had some growing up to do. I believe that was what the author wanted. He wanted you to be upset at the lack of mutual respect so that you would hopefully endeavor to not let your relationship with your own parents degenerate as he did.

In reference to the sitting though, why did he do all the work to come back just so he could sit? To be with the tree is the only explanation that makes any sense.

Also old age is when the boy's interests finally realigned with the tree's. All the tree ever wanted was companionship, but the boy had other things to do, he had to live his life. And though the tree couldn't understand she still provided because she loved him that much. It is clearly stated that the boy loved the tree as well but as he grew older that love became more latent, he only came back when he had a need but this didn't necessarily mean he ever stopped loving the tree, just that he never took the time to express it, which was sad and frustrating from the perspective of an outsider looking in and should have been.

The tree is happy in the end that their interests have realigned and so is the boy else he would not have made the trip over, but the reader should still feel the pain of the tree in the gaps between visits. It even points out that one of the times the tree was not in fact happy because the boy wasn't there to drive home the fact that you should be feeling bad.

And to be honest it sounds like you do. It's not as if the book had some secret hidden message that only you were able to get. It's quite obvious to most readers that the tree is actually depressed and the kid is being a shit. The end of the book doesn't take that all away by saying the tree was happy as you clearly know since you still hate the kid. It just points out that in spite of all the shit the tree had to put up with, it was still happy to have the boy she loved, who ignored her most of his life, spend time with her, and to me that's even more tragic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27377609445.0" user="ImAwesomeLMAO" delta="False">
    <text>I never understood why he carried the branches so far away to build the house.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
