<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375760589.0" user="littleln" delta="False">
    <text>You know what I totally agree. But there are other ways to spin it and since I think it's a great book that's what I did. When I read this to my four year old at the end I say, "wow, this is such a sad story" and then we talk about it. I present it more as a story of self sacrifice on the part of the tree and how lovely it is that there are people like that who will give anything for other people... anything. You all know one. They'll give the clothes off their back. heck look at some of these people going off to fight Ebola. Self sacrifice. But the simple fact of life is... there are always people who will abuse this kindness like the boy. Both of my kids understand that the boy is selfish and the tree is kind and giving. 

Life can be ugly, but in the end we make our choices and maybe we end up happy.... it's pretty clear at the end that the tree was happy because the tree liked to give of itself... but the boy? Never do we see the text "and the boy was happy"... you know why? Because he isn't. The boy is never content with what he has and he always wants something else. Something more. And in the end... what happened to the house? The wife? The boat?  Where did it go and why is the boy old and lonely? He takes and takes from the tree and never really gets what he wants out of life. It's a commentary on life in general and the rat race of adult life. You want, you try and try, you want more- the house, the promotion, the fancy boat but in the end most of us end up lonely and miserable with wasted lives. Like the boy. Sure. The tree wasted its life too but at least it was happy, which the boy never was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375890718.0" user="jackpg98" delta="False">
    <text>Wow. That is a really interesting interpretation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27376282618.0" user="littleln" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. It's called "the giving tree" not "the taking boy" the tree is the moral protagonist of the story, not the boy. The boy is the antagonist. Look at it like that and the story is completely fine and has a great message.

First couple of times I read it to my kids I was like "jfc, this boy is a thankless, negative piece of shit" then I realize... That's the point. Gotta look at the tree, not the boy. The tree is a paragon of self sacrifice and kindness and finds happiness in her life despite a few questionable choices. We should try to be like the tree, not the boy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
