<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149946335.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2h9vbz/cmvthe_giving_tree_is_a_story_with_horrible_morals/">
    <title>CMV:The Giving Tree is a story with horrible morals.</title>
    <original_poster>Sinreborn</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am currently having this discussion with my wife. Both of us had the book read to us as children and my wife now reads it to our 2 year old. I can't stand this book. I believe it to be the personification of entitlement. For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair. 

I get the notions of self sacrifice that go into being a parent. I understand that I would probably do the same to make sure my own child lived a happy life. But I don't want to encourage this notion of desecration without though for stewardship or appreciation for the gifts being given.

Please change my mind so I can stop fighting with my wife.


Edit: For those unfamiliar with the story, [here is a link](https://archive.org/stream/TheGivingTree/The_Giving_Tree_djvu.txt) for the text only.
_____

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27375599065.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I am unfamiliar and surely there is a moral or change of heart at the end that you left out of your summary here...??

&amp;gt;For those unfamiliar, a tree (most likely signifying parents) provides a boy with anything he needs until he takes everything the tree can give leaving only the stump. The boy is absent when he doesn't want things and openly complains about what the tree offers. There is no thanks given by the boy at anytime and no acknowledgement that he is damaging the tree beyond repair.

Otherwise it's just about a boy taking all he can from the tree until the tree is gone... and no moral or point to it? Am I missing something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375610576.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>I added a link with the text. You can read it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375616486.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! Just read it... and I my through process was "aww... hmmm... uhg!... UGH!!!!... Ugh!!... ***Awww!!!***"

&amp;gt;-"I am sorry" sighed the tree. "I wish that I could give you something. . . but I have nothing left. I am just an old stump. I am sorry..." 

&amp;gt;-"I don't need very much now" said the boy. "just a quiet place to sit and rest. I am very tired" 

&amp;gt;-"Well" said the tree, straightening herself up as much as she could, "well, an old stump is good for sitting and resting. Come, Boy, sit down... and rest." 

&amp;gt;And the tree was happy.. 

The boy learned at the end that what mattered was spending time with each other. Sadly he only learned it after taking all he could from the tree for his entire life, but *eventually* once he was an old man he realized the good things in life are to sit in the shade with your loved on, which the tree knew all along.

That's my interpretation anyway. So I do think it has a good moral at the end. At the very very end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27375634257.0" user="Sinreborn" delta="False">
    <text>I've mentioned this elsewhere in the thread, but I disagree that the boy realized anything at the end. Also,

&amp;gt;sit in the shade with your loved one

There was no more shade, the boy took the shade...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
