<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1521278374.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/p5q9wm/cmv_ubers_should_not_be_able_to_use_air_fresheners/">
    <title>CMV: Ubers should not be able to use air fresheners.</title>
    <original_poster>Animedjinn</original_poster>
    <original_post>Especially those tree air fresheners should not be allowed. While some people are bothered by the smell, that is only one of many issues. Other issues:

1) They are highly toxic. The ones that get hung from the dashboard are largely unregulated and release concentrated doses of ingredients such as formaldehyde in a contained space. This is actually unsafe for both the drivers and passengers, similar to second hand smoke.

2) They can cause immediate breathing problems for people with asthma or other serious breathing problems.

3) We don't want to increase respiratory stress on people when we still haven't gotten control of an international respiratory illness.

4) Most don't get rid of smells, only add more smells. Anyone who thinks they are going to cover up old fast food or scented Juul or cigarettes or vomit is kidding themselves</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37562627850.0" user="Finch20" delta="False">
    <text>If you want a highly reglated safe form of transport, why don't you just take a cab?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562647201.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>Lol in what area are you living that cabs are safe? Plus they use these air fresheners too as should also be regulated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562684122.0" user="Finch20" delta="False">
    <text>Flanders, Belgium.  And I've never seen a cab here that uses air fresheners as those cars are not the personal vehicles of the drivers and are cleaned very regularly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562760939.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>I live on the US. Cabs are not safe and all of them have air fresheners.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
