<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1521278374.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/p5q9wm/cmv_ubers_should_not_be_able_to_use_air_fresheners/">
    <title>CMV: Ubers should not be able to use air fresheners.</title>
    <original_poster>Animedjinn</original_poster>
    <original_post>Especially those tree air fresheners should not be allowed. While some people are bothered by the smell, that is only one of many issues. Other issues:

1) They are highly toxic. The ones that get hung from the dashboard are largely unregulated and release concentrated doses of ingredients such as formaldehyde in a contained space. This is actually unsafe for both the drivers and passengers, similar to second hand smoke.

2) They can cause immediate breathing problems for people with asthma or other serious breathing problems.

3) We don't want to increase respiratory stress on people when we still haven't gotten control of an international respiratory illness.

4) Most don't get rid of smells, only add more smells. Anyone who thinks they are going to cover up old fast food or scented Juul or cigarettes or vomit is kidding themselves</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37562739156.0" user="The1TrueSteb" delta="False">
    <text>1. [I am using this link as reference](https://www.poison.org/articles/air-freshener-171). For passengers it does not seem like an issue, your probably should be more worried about a car crash than anything.

1. Does it? I don't know anyone with this issue, and I have not heard of anyone with this issue. I can not just take this statement as a fact.

1. Sounds like you are repeating yourself at this point.

1. So some don't get rid of all smells. So they should not try at all to make their car clean? Should we stop using seatbelts as well since they don't stop car crashes?

Also, I have an issue on what they "should do". They "should do" whatever they want and what their customers want. I think you mean that we should regulate the industry, yes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562940743.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>1. First of all, your article is mainly about kids eating air fresheners. Not adults breathing them. Second of all, as with cigarettes, it is about degree of exposure. Like with second hand smoke, cars are the worst place to breathe in toxic substances because they can stay in the air, or even be absorbed into the upholstery and then released again. This causes some risk for passengers and even more risk for drivers.

2. Do you know anyone with severe asthma? Ask them. The reason I brought this point up is because my roommate studies asthma and is always talking about things like this.

3. I am saying the risk is increased now with coronavirus.

4. Getting rid of smells would be making their car clean. Adding new smells wouldn't. Yes, I mean regulate the industry.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
