<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1521278374.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/p5q9wm/cmv_ubers_should_not_be_able_to_use_air_fresheners/">
    <title>CMV: Ubers should not be able to use air fresheners.</title>
    <original_poster>Animedjinn</original_poster>
    <original_post>Especially those tree air fresheners should not be allowed. While some people are bothered by the smell, that is only one of many issues. Other issues:

1) They are highly toxic. The ones that get hung from the dashboard are largely unregulated and release concentrated doses of ingredients such as formaldehyde in a contained space. This is actually unsafe for both the drivers and passengers, similar to second hand smoke.

2) They can cause immediate breathing problems for people with asthma or other serious breathing problems.

3) We don't want to increase respiratory stress on people when we still haven't gotten control of an international respiratory illness.

4) Most don't get rid of smells, only add more smells. Anyone who thinks they are going to cover up old fast food or scented Juul or cigarettes or vomit is kidding themselves</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37562620053.0" user="translucentgirl1" delta="False">
    <text>Like at all? I understand a complaint when it's such a strong air freshener that I can barely breathe in vehicle, but weaker air fresheners that aren't used excessively don't necessarily seem like too much of a conflict. Further, the main issue I see is that it is still their car; Uber has gone to great lengths recently to allow its customers to customize their rides, so in doing this, you go in direct conflcit for that ruling, which can open the door to even more regulations and limitations. 

Also, for you last point, depending on how strong the previous prescence of weed/vomit was, in comparison to the presence and application of the freshener, they can end up covering smells efficiently enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562641698.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>Even if the smell is weak, most are still carcinogenic.

The fact that it is their car doesn't matter if they make it a condition of hiding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562658220.0" user="translucentgirl1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The fact that it is their car doesn't matter if they make it a condition of hiding.

Hiding what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562944836.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>*hiring</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37563156977.0" user="translucentgirl1" delta="False">
    <text>Then wouldn't this ain't mean they would use air fresheners that are less harmful/ contact the creators of the fresheners themselves? Further, you can request for the individual to open their window or simply refuse to not get in their car. I don't necessarily understand the need to ban Uber drivers from putting fresheners into their car, especially if the ability to control their own environment is prioritized by Uber itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37563248289.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>Opening a window would only do so much and not be possible in winter or rain. However, Uber could create a scent free ride option to give passengers a choice. It would still endanger drivers however to use the fresheners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37563477588.0" user="translucentgirl1" delta="False">
    <text>Oh that would probably be good actually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562940612.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even if the smell is weak, most are still carcinogenic.

Based on what? This is an unsubstantiated claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37562974490.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>Most car air fresheners contain formaldehyde, which is a known carcinogen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37563000436.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>Are you sure about that? I don't see any trustworthy looking, scientific sources that talk about the dangers of the exposure level of an air freshener of any of the compounds commonly used.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37563235621.0" user="Animedjinn" delta="False">
    <text>The moist comprehensive academic summary of air freshener information is probably this: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132316304334</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37564632254.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
