<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397557787.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>Women's rooms for whatever reason get a different level of use and get dirtier than men's rooms. Also if there are two women in the restroom taking a longer time it could potentially hold up the men that would take a lot less time. Idk if i phrased that correctly though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397576010.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>On your second point, people shouldn't do that, doing that is a dick move. But if people are going to do that isn't it more fair to women to get to just share the other as opposed to wait an obscene amount of time, than it would be unfair to men who would just get to use the bathroom first come first serve as opposed to skipping most of the line?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397601266.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how it's more fair. Like to the man the logic is "I know I'm going to take at most 90 seconds in the bathroom why should I wait with the line of women that will probably take much longer?" Imagine that the men's line is the 10 items or fewer line and the women's line is just a regular checkout. And you have 14 items so you should just jump into the shorter express like because you don't feel like waiting. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397647493.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I mean if we want to talk about "fairness," *biology* isn't fair. It isn't "fair" that women *have* to take longer to deal with menstruation and men don't have to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397932500.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this is relevant. That's no one's fault. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398138617.0" user="pzlplz" delta="False">
    <text>I think that was kind of exactly their point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398448945.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>Oh obviously but I was saying that it's irrelevant to the question. What does that have to do with changing the gender assignments of bathrooms </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397739605.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>You know what's actually not fair? I'm a woman and I pee quickly, about the same speed as a man judging from when my boyfriend and I go to the restroom at the same time before a movie. Maybe roughly 10% of women using a restroom are on their period and I understand that taking longer, but besides that it doesn't make a whole lot of sense to me why women take a long time. It's not fair to me, a 90 second pee-er to stand in the line behind the three minute pee-ers because we share anatomy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397915715.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>It's not fair to me that people would have to wait in line because of the 3 minute pee-ers that could potentially occupy both bathrooms. 
Also I personally don't like waiting in line for the bathroom I'd rather hold it and stand somewhere else and just wait for the guy to finish. Women, I feel, are conditioned to waiting in line because that's what always happens. I don't want to have to start doing this because of the off chance that two menstrual/diarrheal women are in both bathrooms. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398149891.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, men never crap and equality is terrible when it means you lose some imagined advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398875522.0" user="Ulquiorra_Schiffer" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an actual argument? Seems like you just giving some very thinly veiled insults, masked under agreeing with a strawman. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398992723.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that:

1) Men aren't always fast in the bathroom, so it's not always a woman slowing the process. He could easily encounter a men's restroom occupied by a constipated man while the women's is totally empty, and then it would be advantageous for both to be unisex.

2) "I don't want to start waiting in line, women are used to doing it anyway" is a tremendously bad argument. It's just "I want things to be better for me, not good for everyone." "Black kids are used to going to shitty schools, I don't want to have to start sharing mine with them."

I pointed out the flaws in his argument using sarcasm, but that's not what a straw man is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398155968.0" user="pzlplz" delta="False">
    <text>So, to summarize your argument: Nobody likes waiting, but women have to do it all the time. I don't, and never want to. Therefore, maintain the status quo. Also, girls are gross.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397925299.0" user="SocialistMath" delta="False">
    <text>We should introduce fast-pee-lines. Once you have demonstrated an ability to pee quickly, you get a badge that allows you to go to the fast line. Fines are applied when you use the fast line when you're on your period or to take a dump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397933340.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>...I don't think so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398079905.0" user="SocialistMath" delta="False">
    <text>Damnit, tongue-in-cheek humor doesn't come across on the internet. I just re-read my comment, and I realize that it's not obvious that it's meant as a joke. I mean, if it were possible to organize them, fast-pee-lines would actually be awesome at big events like concerts, but it's just so ridiculous on the face of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398597987.0" user="contrailia" delta="False">
    <text>No, no. Your comment was obviously a joke. I read it as a joke. No worries. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398446802.0" user="hermithome" delta="False">
    <text>Goes excellently with your username.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398829178.0" user="SocialistMath" delta="False">
    <text>Heh. It was a joke. But I agree, fast-pee-lines make perfect sense from a mathematical point of view if you've ever heard of queueing theory.

Oh, you were referring to the "socialist" part? *roll eyes*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398921025.0" user="hermithome" delta="False">
    <text>No, the whole name. The math part and the socialist part. 

Seriously, a large part of this thread is basically just people arguing for different economics with regards to spending time cleaning and presumptive bathroom dirtyness. 

Most of the men are laissez-faire capitalists and most of the women are commies. You believe in a good strict meritocracy. I like it. Now, of course, we all fight to death. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399263286.0" user="SocialistMath" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, I never looked at it this way. Mind genuinely blown. Not sure whether "meritocracy" is really the right term, though - after all, this is not exactly about how we should decide who gets to wield power. It's just about we should decide who gets to use which bathroom and in which order.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399767536.0" user="hermithome" delta="False">
    <text>Well, yeah. It's the efficiency model that many others are espousing, only everyone else on this thread assumes peeing speed falls along gender lines, and you're making people earn their places. It's an accurate, meritocractic efficiency model, one based on actual skill and speed, not presumed skill and speed. 

Not sure whether I should be impressed or concerned that I managed to turn a bathroom debate into into bad econ / bad govt, but it's certainly fun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397992216.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Frankly it seems like a quality of service queue would make sense here.. Ladies can occupy a "mens" stall so long as there are no men in line. Its the same basic concept with ADA stalls. The point isn't that ONLY ADA compliant users can use them, its that they get first priority and if they are in use then they still have to wait. So if the women's room as a line just let them use stalls so long as no man is in the line.

Besides.. men can pee in 90 seconds due to a urinal which wouldn't exactly be occupied, even if there is a long line at the ladies room. =)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397754265.0" user="user_schmuser" delta="False">
    <text>Not really a good analogy. You're not told when you come into the shop that you have to go to the regular checkout regardless of what you buy. Lots of women take under 90 seconds and lots of men take over 90 seconds for other reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397883076.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>Okay that's fine but when if there's a men's line and a women's line there are certain expectations. You shouldn't expect or get to choose whatever line you want because you're impatient. It's not anyone's fault. Women inherently take longer in the bathroom than men on average. Is that not a fact? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397627561.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm. I think you're probably right, women's restrooms at least go through much more toilet paper. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour,  the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397917774.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this math holds up just based on the 8 to 10 thing. Maybe 10 to 5-6? And that to me just seems like it will cause the other bathroom to be cleaned more often. So still kinda wasting time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398027571.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather clean two bathrooms every 3 hours than one bathroom every two hours and one every three hours. Minimize my time touching bathroom stuff. Also minimizes the employee's time away from the counter or whatever, only one trip to the supply closet or whatever and one set of gloves/washing hands to go back to work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398439724.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but I don't think that justifies making the bathrooms unisex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398442348.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Why not as a manager?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398450497.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't take that long to clean bathrooms and realistically I don't think people clean bathrooms periodically throughout the day like you're claiming they do </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398465154.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>If they become as disgusting as some are claiming they should be</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398660181.0" user="freddieoh" delta="False">
    <text>Once every three hours though? I don't think anyone has said they will get that dirty. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
