<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397557043.0" user="tweetypi" delta="False">
    <text>The only reason I would see not to do this is that women's bathrooms also need sanitary disposals and often a machine to buy them, and businesses might not want to buy more than necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397570616.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>Those machines make money so it would pay for itself relatively quickly. Also both bathrooms already should have trashcans so they are both primed for disposal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397591704.0" user="Dickiedudeles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Those machines make money so it would pay for itself relatively quickly

They make more money if you only have to buy one but sell the same amount</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397876738.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>So, have one machine and mark one room as having said machine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398626244.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>At the moment you lose money from people who use the men's either because of lines or gender identity so don't have access to the first machine. When these machines are not available you also lose a lot of money in impromptu toilet paper substitutes which can get pretty massive. The products don't expire, so its only the one time cost of installation that you need to make up before its just profit. Also, hey, go for the good one with condoms, deodorant, chap stick and it could actually be a solid investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397607996.0" user="dekuscrub" delta="False">
    <text>A second machine probably wouldn't increase revenue though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397661171.0" user="adudeguyman" delta="False">
    <text>"Hey, another machine.  I am going to start my period now"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397663571.0" user="dekuscrub" delta="False">
    <text>As a man, I know I'd consider stocking up if only they placed those machines in bathrooms I used.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397869270.0" user="TheBatarang" delta="False">
    <text>Stocking up?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398627471.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>they're good for nose bleeds</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398631365.0" user="TheBatarang" delta="False">
    <text>I hope you don't get too many but just buying like, the OB brand (which are super compact and don't have an applicator) would be cheaper than buying from those darn things.  And they don't really look as much like tampons. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398735718.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>http://giphy.com/gifs/EIZZWh9DPHOmI</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398628368.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>reposting from different comment.

At the moment you lose money from people who use the men's either because of lines or gender identity so don't have access to the first machine. When these machines are not available you also lose a lot of money in impromptu toilet paper substitutes which can get pretty massive. The products don't expire, so its only the one time cost of installation that you need to make up before its just profit. Also, hey, go for the good one with condoms, deodorant, chap stick and it could actually be a solid investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397601354.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The sanitary disposal bin is small and the tampon buying thing could be placed on the wall outside of both rooms. Now why we still feel squeamish about periods is a whole other discussion but I think we should get over that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397663287.0" user="adudeguyman" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see that being something that someone wants to buy in the open despite there really isn't anything wrong with doing so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397611527.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>That would be covered by a regular trash can. The machines also are I believe typically stocked by a third party vendor so I don't see why having two of them would be an issue. And as a woman who's had to use them, they rarely work so the whole thing is a wash IMO. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397620441.0" user="Jaqqarhan" delta="False">
    <text>Washington DC already requires every establishment to have at least one unisex bathroom (for trans gender petiole). I've noticed that there are a lot of restaurants, bars, and coffee shops with 2 unisex bathrooms and no gender specific bathrooms. I think it makes sense since it reduces the chance of waiting in line. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397657803.0" user="dekuscrub" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Washington DC already requires every establishment to have at least one unisex bathroom 

This is most definitely not enforced.

Also, it decreases your chance of waiting in if you're female, but it has the opposite effect if you're not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397679292.0" user="Jaqqarhan" delta="False">
    <text>It's not enforced, but it seems like most businesses comply any way including all of the 60 or so Starbucks in the district. Sometimes 2 guys need to use the bathroom at the same time too. It's silly for one of them to wait while the women's bathroom sits empty. That is somewhat less common than a line for the women's bathroom while the men's bathroom is empty, but both situations happen frequently and are an unnecessary waste of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398193664.0" user="hefaestos" delta="False">
    <text>The enforcement lags a bit (compounded by a conflicting rule buried in a building code that took a while to root out), but they're trying to get better.

You can even help by [tweeting about non-compliant bathrooms](http://ohr.dc.gov/bathrooms) to #safebathroomsDC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397841169.0" user="thename226" delta="False">
    <text>Starbucks does this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398190139.0" user="hefaestos" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite correct. DC requires that all single stall bathrooms be designated unisex (i.e. exactly what OP is proposing). If there are only multi-stall bathrooms, no effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397669529.0" user="HellloYouu" delta="False">
    <text>Female here, those machines only exist in larger public bathrooms. Small places never bother, and most women only use those machines as a last resort. As far as sanitary disposal, there is no special container you are required to have, a lidded trash can is sufficient. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397677531.0" user="tweetypi" delta="False">
    <text>Also a female. Machines exist wherever they want them to exist, I have seen them in smaller bathrooms. Depending on how isolated the business is, it might be the only resort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397690158.0" user="SomeOldGoat" delta="False">
    <text>As long as there is toilet paper and/or paper towels in stock, it is never the only resort.

Just adding because I think it's a little weird that I got downvoted for this: I am a lady who has periods and so on. I don't use pads/tampons anymore (menstrual cup master race), but when I did if I had nothing with me I would pretty much always prefer to use some folded up toilet paper until I could get something more substantial from a friend or from home over using the little machines. This is not me being a callous dude saying "there's toilet paper, use that," this is me being a lady who actually did this on the regular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397871105.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>Then like OP mentions with the changing tables, mark one restroom as having said vending machine and the other as not having.

Whoever needs that one thing can queue up for it, but that is certainly not every female patron. Then also the males do not have to feel pressured against using that room when it is available, which is no less convenient to somebody who needs that machine than if another woman was using the room.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397884574.0" user="SJHillman" delta="False">
    <text>The downside I see with that is that if there's three women in line and the non-marked one is open, you know exactly why they're in line, which could lead to embarrassment (people are weird about their own bodies)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397912901.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>Then that's the business's fault for being cheap. If they get *so many* customers using that vendor that they queue up, then they need to install one in each room. Avoiding customer embarrassment protects revenue. However, I doubt that said vendors will wind up being *that* popular almost anywhere. ;3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398028379.0" user="lilbluehair" delta="False">
    <text>If that's the case, some saint would come by and give them all an extra tampon. We generally carry extras to "scratch each other's backs", even I do and I don't use them anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397935738.0" user="Yellow_Odd_Fellow" delta="False">
    <text>I view that the same as having a child. You know you are on your period, or prone to having it start. 

Don't leave home without the required materials.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397943009.0" user="Verybusyperson" delta="False">
    <text>Do those machines even work? I don't think I've ever seen people use them. Thought they were a relic of the past no one wanted to pay to have removed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398024355.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>They haven't worked the couple of times I've needed them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398630946.0" user="fizzycoke" delta="False">
    <text>I knew a coffee shop by my old university that would restock the thing every day, fucking life saver. Also seen ones with chap stick, deodorant, condoms, advil, just fucking everything, it was awesome.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
