<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397994914.0" user="toolatealreadyfapped" delta="False">
    <text>Last night, I ate spicy Tai food. Delicious, but this morning, things aren't sitting pretty. Eventually, urgency sets in and I run to the restroom. And I punish that fucker! We're talking 15 rounds with Ali, and that poor toilet never had a chance. 

Relieved, washed up, and eager to get away from the smell that is suffocating me, I open the door. To my horror, there's a cute girl next in line. She's about to be encompassed by my sins, and I can never look at her again. Ever. 

If it was a guy, he'd just gag and laugh, and think "glad it's not my asshole smuggling dead raccoons."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398261345.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>Everybody poops.  The fact that you can't look at her ever again is YOUR problem.  Should we force women to avoid a 10 foot bubble around you in case you accidentally pass a nasty smelling fart, just to prevent you from feeling embarrassed?

Also: why, as a straight person, do you get the benefit of not haing to share a restroom and your shit-odor with people you might be attracted with, and I as a gay person have to worry about what that cute lady waiting in line for a stall thinks of my stinky ass?  Making bathroom segregation about sexuality and sexual attraction is sort of a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398882481.0" user="Ulquiorra_Schiffer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sort of a problem

Only if you make it one. Everything in society is sexually based, on some level. Absolutely everything that involves interaction between men and women, and m&amp;amp;m/F&amp;amp;f for gay people, has some level of sexuality to it. It's ingrained in us through evolution. 

Also. He's clearly making a joke. No need to get so bent out of shape. Besides, it sounds like this 

&amp;gt;is YOUR problem.

and this 

&amp;gt;I as a gay person have to worry about what that cute lady waiting in line for a stall thinks of my stinky ass? 

Are incongruent. You can't bitch about him making his problem other peoples, then have the exact same complaint. That's not how things work, that's being a hypocrite or something. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398519994.0" user="NotKateBush" delta="False">
    <text>Every person in the world has had toilet issues. Scarlett Johansson, Emma Watson, the queen, and every woman you've ever had a crush on has had at least a couple horrendous shits in their lifetimes. Your embarrassment is all your problem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
