<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397750556.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>Personally I've heard about the poor hygiene and cleanliness of women bathrooms. As a male, I prefer not to have my bathrooms becoming dirtier. It seems like a common group characteristic for females to treat bathrooms very poorly. Urine everywhere and menstrual products everywhere. Seems like a zero sum where it gets better for women and worse for men. 

Selfishly, I'd prefer for my bathrooms to stay where they are. They're already not all that clean or comfortable. No argument for gender reasons; other places do this and it seems more of a culture hang up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397756570.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>People keep posting this, but as a woman why would that change my mind?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397768483.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>It shouldn't really, just no one wants to get hosed because some one else is. As a group, it's hard to see why you'd support your group losing something for another group to gain. There isn't some great logic to it, we just don't want our bathroom situation to worsen so your shitty situation improves. 

I'd reply with the same as a response to your original question. Why as a man would that change my mind? It's harsh but honest. It's hard to think why we'd want this change if things only get worse for us. This would be like a union supporting wage cuts so their member's companies can improve their situation.

The argument would be empathy and compassion; however, this goes both ways in maintaining or changing the current situation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397931217.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Sure but this is about my view and it so far hasn't been changed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397960694.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, then your quote

&amp;gt;People keep posting this, but as a woman why would that change my mind?

makes no sense. Why are you communicating on this subreddit if you don't care? No one is trying to say it might not be better for women, but why we should change it? As it stands, it's just a nice thought in your head that hasn't been made into practice. I assume your post is asking others to provide insight on why this should or shouldn't be done. 

Our response is males get screwed for no benefit, so they're unlikely to support this. Why one might change their view is because it's unrealistic. I'm struggling to see why having or changing your view is important to you if you don't care about the responses here. 

You said above that 

&amp;gt;I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

The responses have provided why others don't want this change, or why it's unlikely to change. Other reasons could be things like male dominance in managerial positions or business ownership. Maybe unisex is better financially in the short term, but customer complaints make it the poorer choice. 

I'm just really confused about this statement

&amp;gt;Sure but this is about my view and it so far hasn't been changed. 

It's fine not to be convinced or still feel like it's a reasonable view to have. Replies to the points made would be more productive towards the goal of discussion than saying sure but I still think hold my view. 

**Some more detail than that you haven't changed your mind would help foster more engaging and fruitful discussion.**

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397975121.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I've posted the benefits as I see them of the unisex system. I understand that men don't want this system and I understand that but I don't have any counterpoint to personal preference for shorter wait times. I think the benefits I laid out in OP and in other comments trump the preference for shorter wait times. I've seen this system in some stores so it makes me think there isn't a lot of outrage at the wait times.

Thanks for posting a more dynamic response than just the "I don't want it to happen," I don't have any particularly thoughtful response to that comment alone. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397985833.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really have a good reply other than it won't happen because the people in charge don't care and no one cares enough to change it atm. It's hard to rally support from apathetic groups and a large demographic (males) being against it or not caring. Probably a needs of the few vs many argument/trade off. I can't convince you it isn't good for you, but it won't happen because it isn't good for many which probably include those with the power to change it. 

A CMV can't really consist of arguing how it would be a bad thing for you, more that it's a fanciful or unrealistic hope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398001406.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Haha yeah wasting some time talking about it online is about as activist I'll get talking about this, definitely not an issue even worth signing a petition for. I just think it's the superior system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398023055.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>It's superior for some, that's kinda been my point. Can't really argue it's not good for you and there change your view. It's more of it's not happening and it sucks for others so change your view. Fairly subjective topic. An analogy might help I guess.

It'd be like someone posting "I should get 2% of every person's estate who makes more than 200k USD a year. CMV". I can't argue that it wouldn't be great for you. I can really only talk about the effects it has on others and why others wouldn't share the view or support it. This is a superior system for that individual, or maybe for a group of individuals, but the view changing comes in about feasibility. 

This is kind of subjective about whether people should have rational or realistic views. Or how you can even define realistic or rational in some useful way to communicate or apply it at a broader level. I suppose I'd categorize this topic as impossible to change view points on. It's more of a feeling/belief/hope than a prediction or truth. Can't really argue against feelings. 

I guess I'll end with I like the idea of gender being less of an identity issue for people and having less of a negative impact. Unisex bathrooms might help with that but pragmatically I can only think of my discomfort with the way women typically treat bathrooms. It's difficult to argue against self interest. Best for you and best for me can't coexist as a bathroom policy but as ideas they can. 

Enjoyable discussion at least, sorry about the lines. You can always just ignore the looks and enjoy the release of peeing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398066844.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah in reality this is not a particularly high stakes issue for me as a cis woman, the worst case scenario is I see a man with a surprised look on his face when I walk out. 

I think who really has a horse in this game is the trans community who face violence based on their restroom choice. To me that sort of trumps the "I don't want to wait an extra minute and maybe see a tampon" counterpoint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398134743.0" user="aghamenon" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, the sad reality is no one cares. Businesses won't feel pressured to change based on a fraction of the population. I imagine legal problems with entering the other gender's bathroom. Physical sex is more strongly enforced than mental gender identity. It's a fuzzy topic because the difference between someone who's trans wanting to go into their bathroom of choice and someone just feeling like it or for perversion is in their head. It's easier and lower cost just to divide by physical sex. 

A huge hurdle mental and identity issues face is questions of authenticity and validity. I'm not trying to be dismissive, they're very real for that involved person but legal differentiating is pretty impossible. It comes down to their feelings on their personal identity versus how we'll label them. 

I imagine wanting to use your gender identity's bathroom is a nice anchor or reassuring point if you're struggling with those issues. This again is probably only a problem for those transitioning and not post-op. 

It's not so much about trumping in terms of moral choices but costs in a general sense. There's probably less fuss this way which is unfortunate but a reality. Public spaces are a curious dilemma in terms of accessibility and control. 

Looking up statistics on the demographics, trans people make up .03% of the population which is 9.483 m. It sounds harsh but that's a well above acceptable "error" or group of dissatisfied users. 99.7% aren't trans so it's again harsh but you can dismiss them entirely from a business standpoint. That leaves you back with the male/female argument. It's a non-issue due to money than morality or ethics. No one cares enough to pay the required amount to change it. This is actually a kind of dangerous side of lobbying. Special interest groups affecting more people than their demographic negatively. It's not kind but one just has to dismiss them as at best a vocal minority. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
