<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27398046955.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Used a woman's single bathroom today.

Here are some differences you may not have though of:

1. Women expect the seat to be down. They could possibly fall in one gendered neutral.

2. Similarly, women need the seat down to pee, and with standard bathrooms (with the front of the seat missing), men can pee with the seat down, and get pee on the seat (or sometimes even get pee on the seat when it is up). This provides for an unsanitary situation when a girl goes to sit down to pee. Seperating the bathrooms by gender provides a place that men can pee without disturbing other men, and provides a place that women can pee without being disturbed by men.

3. It is more efficient for a business to pay for 1 tampon machine (or urinal, or condom machine, or baby changing station) rather than two.

4. People in general feel more comfortable with their bodily functions around people with their own gender, since they have those in common. To those of a different gender it can appear gross.

I don't think the bathrooms should be exclusive to one gender, but they should be oriented towards each. If there's a bathroom that's full, a woman could use the men's oriented bathroom. If there's a man that needs a baby-changing station, he could use the woman's oriented bathroom. If there's a man that needs to sit down to poop, he could use the women's oriented bathroom. If there's a woman that needs a condom, she could use the male-oriented bathroom. They shouldn't necessarily be seperated by gender, but by *functions* that are predominantly needed by one gender, and therefore labelled by gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398061646.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>1. Hahahaha. I'm a woman and that is ridiculous. I've fallen on an upturned toilet before but in my own apartment in the middle of the night. If you're not looking before you put your bare ass somewhere in a public restroom you're a fool.

2. I kick the upturned seat down with the toe of my shoe

3. Many businesses don't have these, they are usually operated by a third party vendor so it's not even the owner's thing. The baby table is actually superior in the two unisex setup because you can mark one as a family restroom. Only placing the table in the women's restroom is discriminating to men who have infants.

4. In the current system the hall in front of the door is not divided by gender, any sound or smell that would travel across the door doesn't change between the divided or unisex setup.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398077139.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hahahaha. I'm a woman and that is ridiculous. I've fallen on an upturned toilet before but in my own apartment in the middle of the night. If you're not looking before you put your bare ass somewhere in a public restroom you're a fool.

I don't think it's that ridiculous, especially since it happened to you. It has happened to others, and will continue to happen, and will happen more often in the future with more gendered bathrooms.

&amp;gt;I kick the upturned seat down with the toe of my shoe

There is pee on the seat because a male used it and it splashed. Now what do you do?

&amp;gt;Many businesses don't have these, they are usually operated by a third party vendor so it's not even the owner's thing. The baby table is actually superior in the two unisex setup because you can mark one as a family restroom. Only placing the table in the women's restroom is discriminating to men who have infants.

Marking it as a family restroom is seperating it into a category, yeah?

&amp;gt;In the current system the hall in front of the door is not divided by gender, any sound or smell that would travel across the door doesn't change between the divided or unisex setup.

I'm referring to stuff within the bathroom. Certain people may not feel comfortable sharing the same toilet seat with somebody of a different gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398098927.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>My bathroom plan relies on people having a basic awareness of what's around them. I behave differently in my own home.

I wipe the pee off like I do all the time in women's restrooms. Pee is gross regardless of gender

Yes family is a category.

There's never a guarantee a man's butt hasn't been on the toilet seat. If that makes you uncomfortable, that's a personal problem not a business one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398110986.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My bathroom plan relies on people having a basic awareness of what's around them. I behave differently in my own home.

Others may have a different plan.

&amp;gt;I wipe the pee off like I do all the time in women's restrooms. Pee is gross regardless of gender

I would assume pee getting on women's seats is less often than getting on a men's room seat.

&amp;gt;Yes family is a category.

So why is family being a category okay and gendered (but not exclusive) being a category not okay?

&amp;gt;There's never a guarantee a man's butt hasn't been on the toilet seat. If that makes you uncomfortable, that's a personal problem not a business one.

It may be comfortable for you, but not necessarily for others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398274464.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would assume pee getting on women's seats is less often than getting on a men's room seat.

I fucking wish...  I'm somewhat gender queer/don't care and sometimes use a men's restroom (because why not?).  While men may splash a little, women do this ridiculous thing where they hover over the toilet seat.  Some claim to do this because the seat is dirty.  It tends to result in them spraying pee all over the seat and not cleaning it up.  So the people who are so concerned with having a dirty ass are the ones making the mess for everyone else who would like to sit down.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398336683.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Some claim to do this because the seat is dirty. It tends to result in them spraying pee all over the seat and not cleaning it up.

Sounds like a self-fulfilling prophecy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398359336.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>An awful, awful self fulfilling prophecy.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
