<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397587611.0" user="bc2zb" delta="False">
    <text>I think the biggest issue with this would be accidental intrusions. If a patron doesn't lock the door for whatever reason, and there's no line, a man could accidentally walk in on a woman or vice versa. Some people shrug this off, but some people get really upset by this. At least with gendered bathrooms, you don't run the risk of one person accusing the other of being a pervert. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397603115.0" user="Amida0616" delta="False">
    <text>If you are the type of person who gets upset, lock the door.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397616934.0" user="bc2zb" delta="False">
    <text>Can you sit there and honestly say you do everything you mean to do in a public setting every time you do it? Do you always lock the door to the bathroom, what if the lock on the door is broken and you don't realize it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397627651.0" user="jbtuck" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I can say that I always lock the door.  In addition I also pull on the door to verify the latch... And I make sure the lock is functional with the door open to make sure I do not get stuck in a room with a broken lock.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397635130.0" user="Garden_head" delta="False">
    <text>I too do the paranoid door pull. My biggest fear is for someone to walk in on my going deuce. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397862319.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, your biggest fear? I mean, I'm sure you're using hyperbole here or something, but come on. Ebola is way scarier. Locked in syndrome, too. Being on a "zombie plane" - even if you're the only conscious person, it's still way scarier. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398046253.0" user="LesChampignonsVivent" delta="False">
    <text>This comment was unnecessary. You know they're using hyperbole; why does it matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398121096.0" user="ahruss" delta="False">
    <text>Ever heard of an *irrational* fear? People have phobias. They don't have to have reasons for them. My aunt's biggest fear is frogs. She literally will not go outside at night when she comes to visit my house in the summer because she can hear the frogs. Is it rational? No. She knows it's irrational. That doesn't change the fact that she's afraid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397864045.0" user="poopwithexcitement" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno, happened to a friend of mine once in a unisex bathroom at a bar and he managed to make the argument later in the night that she had to show the same amount of skin to him so they'd be even. Probably the strangest pickup line ever, but it worked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397654736.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>I get your point, but if I forget to lock the door I'm not going to blame the person who accidentally opens it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397663039.0" user="Seakawn" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't just about blame though, it's also about getting upset if it happens no matter whose fault it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397679723.0" user="KaptenBrunsylt" delta="False">
    <text>But whom the fault lies with is relevant. If you are the cause of your own upsetting feelings you can hardly blame the other for it, take the responsibility yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397866515.0" user="poopwithexcitement" delta="False">
    <text>I can also see it being possible that a woman walks in on a man who forgot to lock the door and gets mad at him for "exposing himself."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397876779.0" user="KaptenBrunsylt" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't change anything. Then she brought it upon herself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27400430924.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think she did. It was his responsibility to lock the door.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27400641525.0" user="KaptenBrunsylt" delta="False">
    <text>If the door is unable to be locked then you are taking a risk that someone might open, if they do open and then THEY feel offended it's their problem because there was ntohing you could do to change their mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27402040924.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>But the original comment was "a man who forgot to lock the door", not a door that is unable to be locked. And even if the door was unable to be locked, I think then that would be the management's fault, not the man or the woman's fault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397680797.0" user="Amida0616" delta="False">
    <text>I mean personally i dont care really. 

If i was really worried about someone seeing my dick or seeing me poop or something i would give it a double check.  

Unisex bathrooms exist all over and i dont see an epidemic of traumatized people from being accidentally walked in on. Also why is it worse for someone of the opposite gender to see you poop, then someone of the same gender? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398046556.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. All functional adults are conscientious about things that are important to them. If it's important that I not be barged-in on, then I lock the door - I notice immediately if it doesn't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397617212.0" user="kefkameta" delta="False">
    <text>Is this supposed to be some sort of clever reply?
Petite 30 y/o female walks in to one of the unisex bathrooms.
Drops shit the size of god damn burrito.
Forgets to lock the door and Jeff from Fucks co. walks in on her dropping this massive burrito out of her ass and they work together.

I feel like that would be very uncomfortable for her.
People forget.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397624730.0" user="notian" delta="False">
    <text>Why would that be more/less uncomfortable if it was Jennifer instead of Jeff? It would be just as bad for the person walking in, regardless of gender as for the person being walked in on, again, regardless of gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397660251.0" user="t_hab" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of people find it more uncomfortable to be seen naked by the opposite sex. Women change in front of each other all the time and they pee in front of each other all the time. Dropping a burrito is only a little worse.

Many women have big anxieties about being seen by a man. Sometimes it's religious reason, sometimes they've had a bad experience (sexual abuse), sometimes it's social anxiety, or whatever. 

Since we're specifically talking about businesses, they don't care why nor do they care whether or not the person is right to feel anxious. They simply want their customers and employees to feel comfortable as often as possible and this is one source of discomfort. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397782437.0" user="notian" delta="False">
    <text>So would these same people would *never* use a unisex bathroom if it's the only one available? Would they not frequent an establishment simply because they had 2 unisex bathrooms instead of 2 gender specific? Would these same people never use a bathroom in someone's home, or in their own if someone (of the opposite gender) is in the house?

The only real comfort that needs to be afforded by the business is a working lock on the door. Anyone who would be upset by being walked in on, will make sure the door locks, then no man, woman or other will walk in on them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397797126.0" user="t_hab" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So would these same people would never use a unisex bathroom if it's the only one available? Would they not frequent an establishment simply because they had 2 unisex bathrooms instead of 2 gender specific? Would these same people never use a bathroom in someone's home, or in their own if someone (of the opposite gender) is in the house?

Completely irrelevant. These people would pee in a forest if they had to go and it were the only place they could go. If they are on a 10 hour flight with turbulence they might even pee in their pants. 

&amp;gt;The only real comfort that needs to be afforded by the business is a working lock on the door.

Obviously you've never run a business or perhaps you've never even worked in one. Customers and employees will complain about lots of things and will sue over ridiculous things. Gender-specific bathrooms are commonplace and most companies will not want to stick their heads out to force societal change on this issue. It's simply not worth it for them. If 1% of women would rather have sex-specific bathrooms, the company is better off having sex-specific bathrooms. 

&amp;gt;Anyone who would be upset by being walked in on, will make sure the door locks

Right, because nobody ever forgets to do something basic when they have to use the toilet really badly. I guess nobody has ever started to poop before checking for toilet paper either. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397891335.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Gender-specific bathrooms are commonplace and most companies will not want to stick their heads out to force societal change on this issue. It's simply not worth it for them.

OP is not asking businesses to stick their necks out to make this change, OP is simply asking to discuss whether or not this change is right to be made via any avenue; one potential avenue being change in regulation.

If your business increases liability due to *deciding* to go unisex, then I'm fine with them following the coward's route. But if the regulations change so that you *have to* make all single-person bathrooms unisex then their liability does not change so there's no problem on that front.

So far as door locks, that is occupant's responsibility and no other person's fault if they neglect it. Broken lock can be proprietor's fault, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397998216.0" user="t_hab" delta="False">
    <text>OP says that he can't think of any reason why it isn't more frequently seen. OP is asking businesses to make these changes. OP does not talk about making this change through other avenues, such as a change in regulation.

The idea of the government telling businesses that they have to make changes that will make some of their clients uncomfortable without any increase in safety is your suggestion and ai think can be rejected for pretty obvious reasons, bringing us back to the discussion of whether businesses should make the changes of their own accord.

Some indeed have made that change, but it hasn't been universally welcomed by customers and most businesses won't.

Remember, we're talking about businesses that lose money if a proprtion of their client base or employee base is uncomfortable and it isn't up to the business to tell them they are wrong for being uncomfortable. You might think that a person should never forget to lock the bathroom door and you might think a person should always notice if the toilet seat is up or down, and the individual business owner might agree with you, but if it makes some of his customers less happy he would have to be an idiot to do it, unless he only had the space for one bathroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398084983.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; OP does not talk about making this change through other avenues, such as a change in regulation.

Unfortunately this is implicit given that many jurisdictions *do* require separate men's and women's facilities, even when they only admit one person at a time. This dates back from a much more binary era where it was popular for each gender to believe that the other one had cooties.

&amp;gt; but if it makes some of his customers less happy he would have to be an idiot to do it

.. unless it makes a greater percentage of the clientele *more* happy or comfortable in return. For example: Fathers now having access to that one room with the changing table installed in it, trans people having less anxiety about using either room, nobody having to queue up when one room is either empty or disgusting, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397877641.0" user="poopwithexcitement" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, i can testify to the reverse. If I go to a bar and they have two sex specific bathrooms with just a toilet each, I will never become a regular. Lines for the restroom while drunk may be my least favorite thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397645395.0" user="AptCasaNova" delta="False">
    <text>I've been walked in on by both genders - it's equally uncomfortable.

Mind you, this was at a hospital where no locks are allowed..  but the concept is the same.  Small, unisex bathroom that opens directly into corridor.

People walking by can possibly see you, Jeff or Janice or whomever the hell..  maybe with their kid(s) in tow.

All I ask is that the loo be in kicking distance of the door so I can hide my apparently shameful lady shits from the men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397653564.0" user="vicefox" delta="False">
    <text>What if it was Stacy, the admin, who walked in on her pinching the burrito? Stacy catches a big whiff and slams the door shut. Petite 30 yr old starts crying out of embarrassment as she pushes out a couple little enchiladas.

Does gender really change anything in this story? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397678754.0" user="Amida0616" delta="False">
    <text>Its not clever, just common sense. 

If you are super concerned with someone seeing you in the bathroom double check. I dont understand why the gender, petiteness or size of the poop matter.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397632261.0" user="LinguaManiac" delta="False">
    <text>And if they are the type of people to get upset, they already lock the door. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397860410.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, there are places that don't have working locks, but that's not a good argument against this; use the buddy system, get an employee to watch the door, or find another bathroom if it freaks you out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397656217.0" user="d3pd" delta="False">
    <text>... and hope they don't have blasters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397702404.0" user="LucasBlueCat" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it will be the same crazy lady who forgets to lock the bathroom door,  also blames her car for the keys locked inside. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398043386.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>Now you're blaming the victims of barging from doing the bare minimum to protect themselves? For shame, victim-blamer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398052582.0" user="Amida0616" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry i should check my "functional door lock" privilege. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398304945.0" user="tkrex" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously. Privacy is up to whoever is in the bathroom. I don't want ANYONE accidentally walking I on me, regardless of gender, sexual orientation, or any other variable. It wouldn't be a huge deal, but I lock the door either way because it's my own responsibility to do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397620820.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>That's an interesting issue I hadn't thought about, but I don't see how someone could be accused of being a pervert for opening a unisex bathroom door by mistake (well I guess the accusation I understand, but I don't think there would be any consequences beyond that). I see it as a potential issue, but if you're going to be extremely bothered by it then I think the responsibility lies entirely in your hands to make sure the door is locked, not to ask someone to change the system for your comfort. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397667812.0" user="bc2zb" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the responsibility lies entirely in the hands of the person using the bathroom, but accidents happen. The point isn't adults should accept responsibilities for their actions, but should single occupancy public restrooms be unisex. The issue of an accidental intrusion is not likely to be a huge issue, but what if a child were on either side of the door? I was going to public restrooms by myself before I was introduced to the subtleties of sexual dimorphism. A child doesn't always think to lock the door, nor do they always think to knock. Most children also aren't taught how to handle such a situation. I would think that while the child would react unfavorably to any intrusion by a stranger, an intrusion involving a stranger of the opposite sex could be a very public and embarrassing event for all parties involved. Likewise, an adult could lash out at a child and their parents for being intruded upon by a young child. Either situation could lead to a lost customer for the proprietor and would not be in their best interest to maintain single occupancy unisex restrooms.    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397720235.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>The extremely unlikely scenario you've laid out of slight embarrassment doesn't trump the issues I laid out in my OP. I also can't imagine a person so irrational that they stop going to a business after accidentally being seen peeing there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397865043.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I also can't imagine a person so irrational that they stop going to a business after accidentally being seen peeing there.

I've been embarrassed enough in some businesses to quit going there, but that's hardly anyone's fault but my own. It's also embarrassing to pee yourself waiting in a queue for the toilet, so I'd call that issue a wash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398786558.0" user="CharlieChuu" delta="False">
    <text>Did this while pregnant.  :( had an older mom (been there done that veteran) actually trying to rush me into the next available stall in front of the whole line when it happened. So embarrassing. I was glad to have my bladder control back after childbirth. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397738004.0" user="Shorkan" delta="False">
    <text>I think we are taking the story too far. A child can also possibly mistake the women's bathroom with the men's taking us to this same situation and we are not concerned about that. Thing is, accidents happen and we can't account for all of them. We could strictly prohibit children to go to the bathroom alone, but one could still do it if their parents are distracted. We could put security personal next to the doors for that matter.

Thing is, women (and, less commonly, men) have to wait in line while one of the bathrooms is empty every day, while the cases we are discussing are bound to happen way less often. We have to find a balance, or otherwise the Mongolian army should be defending every bathroom in the world in case an extremely sensitive child runs away from their parents and enters an unlocked bathroom being used by a young couple to alleviate their sexual needs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398784314.0" user="CharlieChuu" delta="False">
    <text>When I was pregnant I seriously forgot to lock the door constantly. It was like a pregnancy trope or something for me. Thankfully I only had two people walk in on me and both were women in the women's room but this actually made me think from a different perspective on this issue. My derpy forgetfulness could have REALLY embarrassed me if a man walked in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397651171.0" user="warpus" delta="False">
    <text>I once used a woman's bathroom, but did a crappy job locking the door.  A woman walked in on me and was outraged that I was not a woman.  I shrugged it off.  Who cares?  I mean, I should be more careful next time when I lock the door, but the men's was busy.  Women's was free, so..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397713839.0" user="entropydecreaser" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, you should have made sure the door was locked...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397718967.0" user="warpus" delta="False">
    <text>Right you are, but that's not what her outrage was about.  I was on my way out when she walked in anyway, so she didn't see any unnecssary bits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397737085.0" user="entropydecreaser" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, never mind then!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397723235.0" user="nbsdfk" delta="False">
    <text>I always just go where there's free. I mean they got stalls for a reason, whats got gender got to do with it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398776282.0" user="FluffySharkBird" delta="False">
    <text>The other day ila guy accidentally walked into the girls room st school.  It's the kind with a sharp turn in the little help so there isn't a door, so we didn't notice him until he peered from the hall thing. "Oh." And he left.  There were two other girls chatting while I was putting on lipstick.  Mistakes happen.  He didn't try and do anything mean so we didn't report it </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397675873.0" user="SuperRusso" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but if I'm some kind of peeping tom, I could just as easily deliberately walk into the women's room and claim that I made that mistake.  This is why the onus of preventing this kind of intrusion is on the person in the bathroom, not on the outside of it.  All the person in the bathroom has to do is lock the door.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397740097.0" user="scribbling_des" delta="False">
    <text>The bar I frequent has one single bathroom.  I find that a ridiculous number of people don't lock the door and I end up walking in on them.  Every single one of them has been male.  I just don't get it.  Why wouldn't you lock the door?

And I'm sure someone will say that I should knock.  One, it is usually to loud to hear a response.  And two, that's what the damn lock is for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397866340.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Every single one of them has been male. I just don't get it. Why wouldn't you lock the door?

Maybe they're hoping for someone to glimpse their goods whilst walking in on them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398209748.0" user="scribbling_des" delta="False">
    <text>It is setup so that their backs are to the door.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398134914.0" user="Asynonymous" delta="False">
    <text>Were they taking a whizz? Sometimes you think "eh, this isn't a big job there's no reason setting everything up like I'll be here for a while."

Of course that's more something for at home or a multi-stall men's room, not for a single-stall.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398878582.0" user="Ulquiorra_Schiffer" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that the intended reason for going to a bar is the cause of this. 

Intoxication impairs brain functions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397783908.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>This is just silly, honestly, but you're completely right of course.  Why should I be more horrified if a woman walks in on me wiping my ass than I should be if a man does it?  It's equally embarrassing.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397834652.0" user="jMyles" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's a pretty brazenly heteronormative view right there.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398230273.0" user="Jimmyfinder" delta="False">
    <text>The world is heteronormative. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397917132.0" user="mulch17" delta="False">
    <text>What about places with only one unisex restroom? This exact scenario you described could happen there, but that doesn't stop unisex single restrooms from existing. They're still quite common, even with that risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398085925.0" user="TheGeorge" delta="False">
    <text>Well you do, they can claim you're a pervert if they know you're LGBTQ and are also are terrible people that think that equals pervert.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
