<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397793552.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think I can change your view the reddit way... with a technicality rather than actually addressing the real issue you are pointing out. =)

Most states actually have laws requiring that an office provide seperate male/female bathrooms. For example, in California: *The California Labor Code requires separate facilities whenever there are more than four employees. Where separate facilities are provided for nondisabled persons of each sex, separate facilities shall be provided for persons with disabilities of each sex also. Where unisex facilities are provided for persons without disabilities, at least one unisex facility shall be provided for persons with disabilities within close proximity to the non-accessible facility.*

So businesses have to follow this regardless of what makes sense. Often times this leads to employees being banned from either restroom for fear of a employee originated lawsuit. Does it make sense? not really.. but its still the law which is why you have not seen it more often.

[1] http://www.dgs.ca.gov/dsa/Programs/progAccess/accessfaqs.aspx#faq20

**edit: fine, I will fix the tapeo if you just stop messaging me! =)**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397903185.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; mail/female bathrooms

I wasn't aware that letters and packages needed to pee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397970632.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Deoh! Thats what I get for posting quickly and not double checking. =)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397910743.0" user="SocialistMath" delta="False">
    <text>I feel really weird about your comment. I feel it should be downvoted, because it so obviously misses the point and you are most likely aware of it (given the smiley and all). On the other hand, maybe OP really *was* naive about the existence of such codes...

Anyway, the reason why your comment misses the point (if it's not obvious after all) is that what is *right* and what is *legal* is often not the same thing, and it seems reasonable to assume that OP intended to discuss what is *right*. As an aside, this discrepancy is why a mechanism for changing laws is necessary ;-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397982798.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I was addressing the comment: "I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!" only, not really intending to change his view directly (especially since I more or less agree with him). But pointing out the legality can help explain why its not common. Sometimes things seem unpopular until you realize that most people actually disagree with the law but not enough to speak up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397927768.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but I think the law should change. Sorry doesn't change my view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397977831.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yea I didn't actually expect this to change your view, I was specifically addressing this comment: "I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!" Most places basically can't do this due to laws.. If the laws were taken away we would see much, much smarter layouts. In Europe I saw places where they had full privacy stalls and the whole bathroom was unisex. I loved this layout which basically means that I agree with your initial concept. =)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398049694.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>You're right. OP didn't ask the question he meant to ask. He wanted a reason why it's right, not a reason why it exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398603536.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>She. I understand the assumption I'm a male on reddit but come on it's a post where half of what I talk about is peeing in a women's restroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398990110.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>When I'm criticizing someone I make sure to use the male pronoun to head-off any claims of sexism in my criticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399055135.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I... what? Just don't be sexist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399104553.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>That's not enough.

If you say "this man's an emotional, irrational, unstable crybaby" then you might be accused of being an asshole, but nobody will accuse you of being sexist.

If you say "this woman's an emotional, irrational, unstable crybaby" then you'll probably be accused of being a misogynist, even if gender had nothing to do with it.

People love to point out biases and explain away expressions that they don't like as if they are primarily a product of those biases. The only way to avoid those unproductive conversations without introducing new biases (e.g. by changing your vocabulary depending on what biases you need to avoid) is to treat everybody as if they are a member of a group for which the major biases are unlikely to be addressed.

e.g. because of female and asian driving stereotypes, in all conversations about poor drivers you assume all actors are not female or asian. Because of biases against female competence, whenever you criticize someone's competence you assume they aren't female. Because of stereotypes of black criminality, you assume that all criminals aren't black, etc.

The online world is just easier that way</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399132049.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Why is your answer to default to a male gender? That doesn't make any sense. You made a non-emotional, non-insulting criticism of me why would you think anyone would accuse you of being sexist?

Switching an obviously female poster's gender to male to avoid sexism just makes you look dumb for ignoring the many references to my gender in this post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399137518.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why is your answer to default to a male gender?

&amp;gt;Because of biases against female competence...

Believe me I wouldn't do this if it wasn't the best way to avoid grief. Also I like applying good reasoning to terrible premises and watching the chaos.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399146156.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>So you're half trolling to get people worked up in a different way while avoiding sexism accusations? That just doesn't make any sense. Calling me a man is worst than a sexist comment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399194806.0" user="jianadaren1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So you're half trolling to get people worked up in a different way while avoiding sexism accusations? That just doesn't make any sense.

What do you mean it doesn't make sense? It just is.

&amp;gt;Calling me a man is worst than a sexist comment.

Now we're getting somewhere. Denial of identity is worse than suffering the stereotypes of the identity - is this universally true? To what extent are stereotypes a part of an identity? Do they impair or enrich the identity? Does combating the stereotypes reduce the associated identity burden or benefit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398378017.0" user="Mollyu" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't know that mail needed to use the bathroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398445396.0" user="hermithome" delta="False">
    <text>tapeo?

Also, do the separate facilities specifically have to be gendered? Or would two unisex facilities suffice?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
