<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27399076116.0" user="sun_tzuber" delta="False">
    <text>Church traditions become culture traditions. It's hard to change a tradition. 

Leviticus 15:19-30:

&amp;gt;“When a woman has a discharge, and the discharge in her body is blood, she shall be in her menstrual impurity for seven days, and whoever touches her shall be unclean until the evening. And everything on which she lies during her menstrual impurity shall be unclean. Everything also on which she sits shall be unclean. And whoever touches her bed shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening. And whoever touches anything on which she sits shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening. Whether it is the bed or anything on which she sits, when he touches it he shall be unclean until the evening.

So you can't sit in the same chair as a woman who's on her period. 

Apparently [this guy](http://ajjacobs.com/resources/book-club-guide/) tried to live the bible literally for a year: 

&amp;gt;But if you take it really strictly, it says you cannot even sit on a seat on which a menstruating woman has sat. My wife thought this was offensive, and sat on every seat in our apartment. So I ended up standing for much of the year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399089553.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Businesses offer unisex restrooms quite frequently. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
