<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397665021.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Wait wait... people actually care about the gender of a person using a *single-person* washroom? 

As a man I use the women's bathroom all the time without any issues. And I've seen women use the men's too without anyone so much as looking twice. How can a single-person restroom even have a gender assigned to it?

Where I live, most of them are labelled with no gender sign, or have a man/woman/wheelchair/baby sign on the door.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397722469.0" user="borgosanjacopo" delta="False">
    <text>I work in engineering. My company is about 98% male, yet they still have gendered single person restrooms. The ladies' room (which is nearly always empty) has a sign on the front advising disciplinary action will be taken against men using it. Load of bullshit if you ask me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397736048.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>See that's absurd! What's the horribleness of a man using a bathroom with a sign saying it's a women's room? There's nobody else in there! Although I wonder if there was a "sneaking into the ladies bathroom to sit on reddit all day" problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398138347.0" user="Avien" delta="False">
    <text>FYI OP, *Ally McBeal* experimented with unisex bathrooms and it quickly degraded into a place for hot sexy lawyers to have spontaneous intercourse in, while on the clock.

I'd argue that gender-specific bathrooms are better for employee productivity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398162148.0" user="IlllIlllIll" delta="False">
    <text>Life is exactly like Ally Mcbeal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398399442.0" user="Direpants" delta="False">
    <text>I honestly can't tell if you're merely stating a fact or if you're being sarcastic.

^^^^^^^^/s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398577604.0" user="bluescape" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Life is exactly like Ally Mcbeal.

It all happened 15 years ago?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398577229.0" user="2Weird2Live2Rare2Die" delta="False">
    <text>Except we're specifically, clearly talking about unisex single-occupancy restrooms as opposed to gender-segregated single occupancy restrooms.  Having enough people present to do more than masturbate would be against the rules in *either* situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398623108.0" user="willrandship" delta="False">
    <text>Having them distinguished gender-wise makes it impractical, even if they enter at different times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398637476.0" user="2Weird2Live2Rare2Die" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not parsing that.  Care to rephrase or elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398647513.0" user="willrandship" delta="False">
    <text>Let's go with an example.

Man A, Woman B, want "spontaneous intercourse" at the office.

Given single bathrooms with no gender signs: A enters first, B enters 10 min later, engage in hot sexy lawyer sex.

Given single bathrooms with gender signs: A enters first, B has trouble sneaking by everyone.

That extra effort makes it just a little bit more difficult to pull off, and in the heat of the moment that's sometimes all it takes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398655857.0" user="2Weird2Live2Rare2Die" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, but is that faint hint of a deterrent worth creating a hostile and even dangerous environment for non-binary individuals in that workplace?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398669634.0" user="willrandship" delta="False">
    <text>Hey, I'm on the side that wants non-gendered bathrooms, if only for queuing efficiency. I was just laying down a sensible justification for their views.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398672002.0" user="2Weird2Live2Rare2Die" delta="False">
    <text>Which I appreciate. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398872364.0" user="sensitivePornGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Thank god same gender sex is impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27400155090.0" user="willrandship" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure you're well-educated on that, /u/sensitivePornGuy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398794823.0" user="Atario" delta="False">
    <text>We had unisex multiperson bathrooms at my dorms in college (including shower stalls).  People were weirded out the first day, but by the second we all wondered why they are ever segregated in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397769965.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like compliance with legal relations, if you have more than a certain number of employees you are required by law to have separate bathrooms for both genders.

The number is low too, like 8 to 15</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397845512.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source for this? it just seems weird to me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397873589.0" user="SteelTheWolf" delta="False">
    <text>If it is accurate, then that law should change. I once suggested this at a pet store I worked at with gendered one person bathrooms and I got some weird looks. At the time, my only reason for suggesting it was a logical, legistical one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397907689.0" user="Yellow_Odd_Fellow" delta="False">
    <text>logistical (not being a douche, just trying to help)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397955768.0" user="SteelTheWolf" delta="False">
    <text>Ah. You are correct. The editing capabilities on mobile are frustratingly limited.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397970816.0" user="Yellow_Odd_Fellow" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. They are. I just didn't want to seem like a douche, so I had to disclaimer myself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398571200.0" user="sohcgt96" delta="False">
    <text>The tricky thing is, building codes tend to be more of a city/county thing as opposed to a state/national thing, so while you might have one area that changes, it would take a long time to become a nationwide trend. That's not to say I'm opposed to the change, just saying it would take a while to get traction in enough areas to effect a significant slice of the population. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397877175.0" user="MagillaGorillasHat" delta="False">
    <text>Generally, those are city codes, so a source would apply only to one city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397902795.0" user="brettj72" delta="False">
    <text>[here you go](http://reason.com/archives/2014/04/11/gender-neutral-bathrooms-building-codes)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398092994.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>~~Yes I do, I've edited it into my first post.~~

Sorry, I don't. I thought this was a different thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398246754.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398251533.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I thought this was in response to a different thread (I was answering from my messages page)

I do not have a source on this particular fact as its only something I heard a previous employer complain about.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398133058.0" user="cal_student37" delta="False">
    <text>Is that actually a law? I know that many progressive institutions in California are moving to unisex bathrooms (not for efficiency concerns, but because gender-is-a-social-construct-transpeople-patriarchy concerns).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398147180.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but.

Its state law afaik, so its probably different in California than where I live, but I know it was a law here around 2011 because my employer was getting into a legal mess because he wanted to hire more employees, but his facilities didn't meet the legal regulations in terms of bathrooms. (he had a single unisex bathroom and he needed to have one for each gender)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398176281.0" user="cal_student37" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like bathrooms could an equality thing (like ADA which is federal) or it could be state, county, or municipal building codes. Who the fuck really knows?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399128209.0" user="hippiekyle" delta="False">
    <text>If that's true, it's not often enforced. I worked at an elementary school that had about 90% women and the teacher's lounge only had one bathroom for all to share.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399273465.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>I'm certain schools have their own set of regulations, being government entities instead of private businesses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397896369.0" user="orbitalnerds" delta="False">
    <text>I am the lone female engineer in my office.  We have gendered single person restrooms and everyone use whatever one is open.  THE SMELL.  There are no words to explain the smell.  And the mountain of newspapers and magazines.  Are they really necessary??  

One day I will work for a company with gendered restrooms!  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397994398.0" user="Gentlemoth" delta="False">
    <text>Why would mens bathrooms smell worse than womens? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398078813.0" user="baddox" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's used more, because there's only one female in the office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397996586.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>I hope you aren't suggesting that women's bathrooms are somehow clean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398071262.0" user="Shubeyash" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if the women's restroom is only used by one person, it would probably be a lot cleaner than the other one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398787044.0" user="Phononix" delta="False">
    <text>You have clearly never been into the women's restroom. I dare to say that women's restrooms are often dirtier then men's. 

I was a restaurant busser for some time and was often called upon to take car of messes in the restrooms. 

The men's usually saw vomit, dirty seats, etc. 

The women's usually had to do with blood on the seats, toilet paper on the floor, clogged toilets from pads, paper towels in the sink. 

Things were the opposite you expect. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399250947.0" user="Shubeyash" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstand. If there's one (1) single woman at a company with a women's restroom and multiple men, I have a very hard time imagining that the women's restroom would be dirtier than the men's, given that it would be used by one (1) person, and the men's would be used by many people.

Also, I suspect it's a cultural thing, because one of my family members has worked as a cleaner for years and insists that the women's are cleaner than the men's because men will frequently do their business outside of the toilet and sometimes leave underwear full of shit, plus spit [snus](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snus) on the walls/floor/ceiling, while the women's mostly tend to have a problem with overflowing garbage cans.

Being a woman, I have been into many women's restrooms (and I've never seen one in the state you describe, worst I've seen had a few drops of urine on the seat and another one with unflushed shit). Never been to USA though. I'm Swedish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399288591.0" user="Phononix" delta="False">
    <text>1.) I only said often for that reason, I understand that this is not always the case. 

2.) The US is pretty unique as far as culture goes. Glad to hear the ladies are more tasteful in the Swedes. 

3.) I have not experienced the whole, cannot hit the pot with my turd scenario... and I really don't plan on seeing that in my agenda. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399964910.0" user="Shubeyash" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I can't understand number 3 either. Surely you must be doing it on purpose if it ends up outside? Eww.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398012499.0" user="warmshower" delta="False">
    <text>There's a restaurant in my town that has two bathrooms, one women's, and one UNISEX!!!

The fuck is that???

Reminds me of a tongue in cheek remark my now-father-in-law made about marriage: we split everything 50-50... half his, half hers -- and half of his, is hers too!  (i kid of course... sort of)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398051919.0" user="leeeeebs" delta="False">
    <text>That's probably against building code...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398070184.0" user="warmshower" delta="False">
    <text>This is a restaurant I didn't eat at for a while because I had witnessed the owner basically calling his (all attractive and female) waitresses "sweetheart" and the like and treating them like his personal assistants.  So it wouldn't surprise me if he's not afraid to break a few rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398050326.0" user="Tyrien" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Load of bullshit if you ask me

Doing everything they can to avoid even the *idea* of a lawsuit. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398217393.0" user="Tahns" delta="False">
    <text>Could be non-discriminatory laws. I work in construction and while finishing off buildings I have hung up gender signs for bathrooms like OP described. Why? Building codes. Wouldn't pass inspection without 'em. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398395078.0" user="DownOnTheUpside" delta="False">
    <text>That's hilarious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398428209.0" user="CervixProbe" delta="False">
    <text>I work in EMS. Male dominated field as well. The amount of times I've taken a shit in the woman's single bathroom is easily in the 40s or 50s. Plus you get a little rush out of "I shouldn't be doing this hehehe." On the flip side some straight up awful stuff flops of of girl butt so using the men's room after them is horrible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398440633.0" user="Gr1pp717" delta="False">
    <text>Get some co-workers to form a line outside of the mens room, right next to the woman's room, and just wait for a manager to walk by and see all of that lost productivity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398818293.0" user="Klutztheduck" delta="False">
    <text>What if the men identify as a woman? Would be pretty sweet to have my own executive bathroom. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399081973.0" user="bluetrench" delta="False">
    <text>My engineering company is also majority male and they have single-person bathrooms with gender signs. Or so I thought... Turns out only the ladies' bathroom is single-person (I'm female), but the men's bathroom is multi-person (I know because I saw multiple gentlemen enter at once). I thought that was quite interesting, and provided the logic behind the single-gender signs that I thought were silly at first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398010429.0" user="Corrupt_Reverend" delta="False">
    <text>But every now and then, you get the multi-person women's restroom that has a deadbolt on the door right next to a single-person men's restroom....

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398122006.0" user="ihateyouguys" delta="False">
    <text>Attack of the ManWomanWheechairBaby!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27591485185.0" user="GreenVoltage" delta="False">
    <text>I was thinking this too, I immediately pictured a man in a typical lady washroom sign dress in a wheelchair with baby arms. where are my photoshop inclined friends?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398896145.0" user="Oneinchwalrus" delta="False">
    <text>My old work, had a girl's bathroom, which was well looked after, always nice handwash, mirror, clock etc. The boys', had no handwash, mirror etc, it even had a freaking ladder and misc stuff in it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
