<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397687416.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Since we're talking about a *business*, the business should do whatever their customers request/desire, in such a way that it will maximize their profits. 

I would argue that they are in a better position to decide what that is than you are.

Luckily, OSHA regulations, while requiring gender segregated bathrooms for employees (in certain numbers depending on number of employees), allow for single person unisex toilets, so the businesses that are choosing to have segregated single sex bathrooms are not doing so because they are forced to by law. 

Also, cultural expectations may be causing this in some cases. There are cultures, especially in Asia and the middle east, where the concept of unisex bathrooms is anethema.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397712802.0" user="rosekm" delta="False">
    <text>OSHA and federal law may not require gendered bathrooms, but many localities do. My business, with no other employees at the time, was required by the county to not only have two bathrooms, but to mark them as male and female.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397741514.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I believe most businesses are operating this way based on convention and perhaps local ordinance, not a hard crunching of the numbers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397756879.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Most business decisions by a small business aren't based on hard number crunching, and yet they seem to make them relatively effectively anyway. 

What makes you think that your impression of what would be good for their business is more accurate than theirs?

And, of course, if it's due to local ordinance, then they really don't have a choice, and "should" follow the ordinance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397760926.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I think I've put a medium amount of thought into it, and I haven't ever seen any evidence of a business weighing this decision. If you have something besides your counter hypothetical, I'd love to see it.

I think the local ordinances should be changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397774029.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>If your view were that "it would be better if society didn't expect to have separate bathrooms for men and women" that would be one thing. Society, however, *does* have this expectation, and it's only rational for businesses to conform to this expectation unless there's an extremely good reason to do otherwise. 

I would say that, while you point out some minor practical reasons that it might be *slightly* more optimal some of the time, that's not a good enough reason for a business to override this convention. 

And there are some good reasons why society expects this, given the other (perhaps not productive) societal expectations and people's behavior. People generally simply want to be told which bathroom to use. They don't want to walk up and have to think "hmmm... what if someone of the opposite sex is in there and forgot to lock the door and gets upset". They just want to be able to open a door and even if there's a mistake, it will simply be laughed off and no one will think there's much harm. People don't want to be nervous approaching a public bathroom.

But those reasons aren't really relevant. People *do* expect separate bathrooms, therefore it's practically by definition in businesses' best interests to cater to that expectation.

This isn't true in all countries, and in those countries you find that businesses *do* change this convention regularly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398029478.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Many unisex bathrooms exist in this country, and I haven't ever seen a complaint about them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397899838.0" user="poopwithexcitement" delta="False">
    <text>I have seen nothing in this thread that prevents me from thinking "that's a stupid law - we oughta change it."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
