<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397561549.0" user="moun7" delta="False">
    <text>From my experience cleaning bathrooms, women's public washrooms tend to be grosser (toilet paper everywhere, the whole hover piss thing), and while this may not be as much of a problem in individual style bathrooms, coming from a guy's perspective, I still say screw that. Sure, it may benefit women, but it would rarely benefit men as our bathroom lines are already almost non existent. I know this isn't exactly a solid argument, but I'm just saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397616946.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I've heard this before, though I guess neither of us have seen a large enough number of the "other bathroom" to confirm or deny the phenomenon. But I think the benefits to the line waiting for both genders and to trans individuals trump the mild discomfort of a dirty bathroom. 

Edit: Copying my management of restroom cleaning hypothesis from another comment below:

From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397678505.0" user="Tift" delta="False">
    <text>I love the idea of dirt units.

One thing I have noticed is that there seems to be more care by patrons (generally) when I have been to establishments that have clearly marked unisex bathrooms.  Which is a nice, though perhaps temporary side effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398078375.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>That's kind of funny. It almost implies that women try to keep things a little cleaner when they believe men will see the mess they make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398084442.0" user="Tift" delta="False">
    <text>And the reverse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398087391.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>If men know women will see how little of a mess they make, then they will purposely make a bigger mess?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398107531.0" user="Tift" delta="False">
    <text>not what i meant but clearly what i said, well played.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398351036.0" user="JasonDJ" delta="False">
    <text>It's how you assert your Alpha status.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397701854.0" user="critically_damped" delta="False">
    <text>Plus, to save money, you can just close one of the bathrooms!

Which happens immediately upon implementation of this policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397733215.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. I've seen plenty of places with two unisex restrooms. Having people wait around in lines to use the one bathroom could also be costly to your business. It also can't be that much in savings, if 100 people are using the bathroom every day it doesn't really matter if there's one or two you're buying the same amount of toilet paper and soap. You're probably paying an hourly employee to clean them, it's not like their shift would be 20 minutes shorter and you'd save on wages with one restroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397758642.0" user="critically_damped" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine the other restroom would be closed by an asshole manager with a stick up his ass and a tendency towards retaliation.

Or, in shorter terms, a "manager".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397762755.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. Unless you have some sort of evidence of that being a phenomenon, I simply disagree with you on this hypothetical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397988039.0" user="manwithfaceofbird" delta="False">
    <text>Ever worked in a restaurant buddy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398018241.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Yes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398183809.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have evidence yourself then?

You must have only worked in one restaurant owned by your parents or something...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398441758.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Three restaurants not managed by my parents. Never seen a restroom shut down out of spite for rules. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398762692.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>The question was have you never met a manager who might?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399056059.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>No.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398483665.0" user="Dhalphir" delta="False">
    <text>Why would it be closed? Its still taking up space and already cost the money to exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398495057.0" user="critically_damped" delta="False">
    <text>I've worked in several establishments that had locked empty rooms that were "already paid for" because it cost money to clean them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397766813.0" user="FOX_DADDY_SUPREME" delta="False">
    <text>On the contrary, if this was the new norm and I was creating a new store/restaurant, I would only bother getting one bathroom built.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397932649.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>That's fine if you want to take that action. Probably short sighted but whatever. still thousands of businesses with two restrooms so it doesn't change my view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397952304.0" user="jonscotch" delta="False">
    <text>Why would it be short sighted? Would people really say "This place only has one bathroom! I am never shopping here again!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397959413.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>There are plenty of times the one restroom would be occupied for 15 minutes and prevent customers from using it. If I had a small child or an infant, I would definitely avoid your business. Let's say your a gas station, not having an open restroom might send customers to your competition. Let's say the bathroom becomes disgusting but there's a busy period and you're short staffed. Customers might become irritated and leave. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398000936.0" user="Banana_bee" delta="False">
    <text>And managers wont often hear of this. It's half the working time, plumbing costs and resources for a few isolated lost customers. It's hardly a loss.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398110902.0" user="FormalPants" delta="False">
    <text>Almost all gas stations have one unisex room.

Only stations with mor than 8 pumps tend to have more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398857375.0" user="red_nick" delta="False">
    <text>There are petrol stations with less than 8 pumps? :P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399554004.0" user="FormalPants" delta="False">
    <text>Most of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399584548.0" user="red_nick" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly not here (UK) they aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398128962.0" user="Asynonymous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Let's say your a gas station, not having an open restroom might send customers to your competition.

All the service station bathrooms I've been to were single stall unisex rooms that you had to get a key from the attendant to use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398198650.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The majority of Starbucks are like this...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397931473.0" user="See-9" delta="False">
    <text>If the men's bathroom is occupied I just use the women's...be an adult and clean up after yourself (hell I replace TP, soap, and paper towels in the women's while I'm there if it needs it) and go on your merry way. No one should have a reason to bitch at that point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397702160.0" user="arsevolcano" delta="False">
    <text>The reason there is a queue is because women take ages in the bathroom, what are they doing in there? Do women ever go a bit quicker if there is a queue behind them? Not that I can see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397715616.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Sitting down to pee and changing pads and tampons. It just takes more time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397715840.0" user="BabyBoyDoe" delta="False">
    <text>This is why the true benefit comes from having the toilet separate from the sink and mirror.  I say, put the sink and mirror outside the bathroom, and it not only makes the line go faster, it also forces disgusting people to wash their hands.  I call that a win-win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397870739.0" user="TeslaIsAdorable" delta="False">
    <text>Plus, there's no nasty door handle to touch going out. I hate the paper-towel-less bathrooms (or those that don't have a trashcan near the door), because it essentially negates hand washing.

Most of the time, I skip the sink step and use hand sanitizer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397727337.0" user="Tartra" delta="False">
    <text>1) Go in. 

2) Last person didn't flush. 

3) Go in different stall. 

4) Dribbles on seat. 

5) Wipe seat (if not hovering). 

6) Juggle purse.

7) Juggle coat. 

8) Coat and purse won't fit on the same hook. 

9) Make them. 

10) Lower bottoms. 

11) Race horse (pee). 

12) Change liner. 

13-17) Manage shark week.

18) Wipe. 

19) Wipe (if two-ply). 

20) Wipe (if one-ply). 

21) Raise bottoms. 

22) Flush. 

23) Flush again (if toilet fails). 

24) Regather belongings. 

25) Squeeze out with belongings. 

26) Juggle belongings when approaching sink. 

27) Try miserably to wash hands while squeezing coat and purse under armpits (wet counter). 

28) Horse walk to drying mechanism because belongings are now between legs. 

29) Dodge every other fucking woman doing the same thing or - God forbid - touching up their make-up and hogging the fucking mirrors (i.e., sinks). 

30) Leave. 

If wearing high heels, add five minutes. 

For the guys,  I hear it's:

1)Walk in. 

2) Piss. 

3) Wash hands (optional lol). 

4) Leave. 

So 'hurrying', based on what you might think women do (e.g., four steps, like men), is comparing apples to orange sorbets. They both involve fruit, but they're different experiences from head to toe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397741696.0" user="Grammatical_Aneurysm" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather flush for someone else than wipe piss off of a seat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397752498.0" user="Tartra" delta="False">
    <text>Well, most times, people get stuck doing both. There's like one wild pissing woman who puts little drops on a few of the seats, but the most are just splashes from the toilet flushing last time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397764644.0" user="Grammatical_Aneurysm" delta="False">
    <text>Icky. But I recently started working at a place where I have to use a public bathroom. It was like a light switch, the realization that if someone hadn't flushed the toilet, I *could just flush the toilet*! It was like magic. So many new stalls opened up to me. Where I would move on in disgust before, I now could overcome. And it was *easy*. Now I see women peek into stalls ahead of me and scoff. Not me! "I'll take it!" I say, and I stride in confidently. 

Pee dribbles? No thank you! Toilet full of crap? No problem!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397848495.0" user="poopwithexcitement" delta="False">
    <text>Someday one of those toilets will flood.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399026004.0" user="Grammatical_Aneurysm" delta="False">
    <text>I prefer to look on [the bright side](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SJUhlRoBL8M). Don't be a downer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397836296.0" user="Fermit" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like I almost understand your struggle now. I never can because I'll never go through it, but I'm so sorry for whatever it's worth. Stay strong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397889819.0" user="Tartra" delta="False">
    <text>Try to arrange some beaver fever in a late-fall, early-winter North Canadian cabin with twenty other guys on a trip. This has happened to my first-year class once: winter boots, winter coats, crowded bathroom, distinct need to sit and use the stall, and the sinks were taken by everyone trying to ditch or retrieve their soggy gloves. Perfect analog for the really far end of the scale. 

Reddit: we help each other reach their dreams. :) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398069250.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>You forgot "dodge child who is terrified of the hand dryer"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398592847.0" user="grimoiregirl" delta="False">
    <text>What the fuck kind of Neurotic bitch are you?

Last person didn't flush

Flush because someone else's piss is not going to leap out of the toilet and kill me.

Lift coat so that it is not touching toilet when you sit down, like you would when wearing a skirt and bunch it up 
over your butt so that it will not get in toilet.

lower underwear, pants, nylons, etc/lift skirts

Keep purse in lap or set on stall floor, where it will not magically catch cooties

Piss

Remove menstrual cup

Dump shark week into toilet

Wipe cup with toilet paper or sanitary wipe from purse, if in single use bathroom, rinse in sink.

wipe

replace cup

flush

flush for a second time because toilets at work suck

Put clothing back into place

pick up purse if needed

Apply hand sanitizer or wash hands

This AND the walk to the bathroom at my work takes 3.5 minutes according to my call center software that tracks how long I am not at my desk. Never taken longer than 5, not with heels, social anxiety, spanx, etc.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398626019.0" user="Tartra" delta="False">
    <text>The rage... Can't tell if it's being equally sarcastic or real...! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398747901.0" user="grimoiregirl" delta="False">
    <text>Ditto.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398160696.0" user="jackiekeracky" delta="False">
    <text>Some women do. I hate them. 

/notallwomen  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397833022.0" user="Fermit" delta="False">
    <text>The dirt units thing is a cool way to look at it, but it assumes that men and women go to the bathroom with the same frequency, which everybody knows they don't. After extensive armchair research, I found out that this is due to the position of the bladder in men and in women. Women have more pressure placed on their bladder by their internal organs than men do, causing them to make peepeerooni more. So it'd be more weighted toward the 10 dirt units and have an overall negative  effect for men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397919446.0" user="moun7" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest I don't actually care either way, I'm just taking a side for the sake of argument.

Anyway, you could perhaps look at it from an equality or fairness point of view. This change would benefit women only. Women would have shorter wait whereas men would have a longer wait, and in this day and age where equality is such a huge deal, the managerial headache, such a change may cause, may not be worth it. If it started as unisex bathrooms then, yes, it's already equal and fair.

One bathroom each is equal on the surface and the fact that women inherently take longer can be argued to be not applicable. For example take this, admittedly, weak analogy. Say you have a car and a truck that both get the same mileage out of a single tank of gas (so I'm making the assumption that men and woman have to pee about the same amount in a day). You pay the same amount for gas (you have the same number of bathrooms) but the truck still costs more to fill up (women take longer in t he bathroom) and you would never argue otherwise. I know there are flaws to that analogy, like you can choose to buy a truck but you didn't choose to be a woman, but damn, I didn't expect to actually have to think about this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398135488.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Eliminating inequality cannot be called inequality just because one group loses an unfair advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398190319.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>Biology is unfair? 

Let me just fix that for ya. Shouldn't take but a few million years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398270186.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're misunderstanding my position. Of course biology can't be made equal. But you said:

&amp;gt;Anyway, you could perhaps look at it from an equality or fairness point of view. This change would benefit women only. Women would have shorter wait whereas men would have a longer wait,

which is a backward argument to make. Their waits would become equal.

Someone nearby in this thread likened it to school integration, which is a fantastic analogy. You can't argue that integration was an act of inequality just because non-whites got the primary benefit. Things were made equal, and unfair advantages were lost, but the loss of those unfair advantages is not itself a new inequality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398291115.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>I just got here, the other guy said that. Easy mistake to make though as I jumped into the conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398342771.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, but the argument still stands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398039197.0" user="GreenStrong" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;though I guess neither of us have seen a large enough number of the "other bathroom" to confirm or deny the phenomenon.

Anyone who has cleaned public restrooms can confirm that the women's room is dirtier- there are millions of people who have seen both sides, five days a week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398057067.0" user="MissRepresentation" delta="False">
    <text>Cannot confirm. Used to clean bathrooms, the men's bathroom had a scent of piss that just would not leave even though we cleaned the bathrooms every day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398077329.0" user="adelaideanne" delta="False">
    <text>I was going to say this. Women's rooms may got dirtier, but they almost always smell better. That nasty stale-piss smell lasts forever. I've nearly thrown up from it in some places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398077495.0" user="adelaideanne" delta="False">
    <text>I was going to say this. Women's rooms may got dirtier, but they almost always smell better. That nasty stale-piss smell lasts forever. I've nearly thrown up from it in some places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398743279.0" user="relaci" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously!  Why do all guys' public bathrooms smell like piss?  Do they just not even try to aim it when they're not at their own home?  Do they feel the need to mark or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398181724.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>I have worked as a janitor for my mothers boyfriends company all through my youth, I feel I am an expert on the quality of bathrooms.

Women's are worse, by far. 

Until you *all* get rid of the hover to pee shit, I will take a firm stand against sharing public bathrooms with you.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398477234.0" user="lipsticklady" delta="False">
    <text>I try to not to pee shit EVER.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398762094.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>Try?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398939309.0" user="lipsticklady" delta="False">
    <text>Every once in awhile, poop soup, amirite?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398578970.0" user="grimoiregirl" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, sharing bathrooms with men might help, because it might reduce the number of women who are terrified that someone knows that they piss and shit like everyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398248727.0" user="ImMrAllStar" delta="False">
    <text>I have seen a large number of both types of bathrooms designated to women and men and overall women bathrooms are indeed much worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398482165.0" user="Dhalphir" delta="False">
    <text>There is no advantage to men. There is never any line at the mens room, anywhere. Not that your idea isnt good, but if women want to be using the mens room, you girls need to stop fucking hoverpissing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398615099.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah hover piss is egregious behavior. Not exactly like we can take a vote on that one, people do what they want. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397690176.0" user="TAEHSAEN" delta="False">
    <text>I think its VITAL for unisex bathrooms to have Urinals because sometimes the toilet water splashes onto the upper sides of the toilet when men take a piss while standing. And many of us (*cough ~~my roommate~~ cough*) don't have the decency to clean it up afterwards.

I know you can easily put the seat down before sitting, but its still really disgusting knowing that you have residual droplets of piss sitting right underneath your seat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397708519.0" user="KinglyWeevil" delta="False">
    <text>Urine is sterile, anyway. It just smells bad. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397720869.0" user="quinn_drummer" delta="False">
    <text>Only on leaving the body, after that it picks up all other kinds of germs and becomes filthy as fuck

Edit: spelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397755144.0" user="KinglyWeevil" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. It picks up the already present germs. Exactly the same as water would. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397775335.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>Water isn't full of nitrogen compounds that bacteria love to eat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397770885.0" user="thewhitelocust" delta="False">
    <text>It only smellz?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397818690.0" user="DallasTruther" delta="False">
    <text>Urine is sterile, your urethra isn't though.  It can come out dirty.

Anyway, are you into watersports?  Not everyone else is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397835199.0" user="KinglyWeevil" delta="False">
    <text>No...I just think people make too big a deal over things like that. It isn't their fault, it's genetically advantageous to avoid contact with such things and to find them disgusting, regardless of whether or not it serves a purpose in this specific case.

The point I'd really like to make is this: If you're freaked out about the urine splashes on the toilet rim under the seat, you probably shouldn't touch anything else in the bathroom, or your phone, or any other frequently contacted surfaces like door knobs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397717204.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Why do residue droplets of pee bother you more than the filty toilet bowl? I only care about what's on the seat itself, the whole area underneath is a damp grossness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398193367.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>What would /u/TAEHSAEN  do in the age of outhouses? Or in a country like India?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398110940.0" user="NCPereira" delta="False">
    <text>As a male that is 204 cm (6'8") tall I can confirm this x200</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397754758.0" user="MoreHeadState" delta="False">
    <text>It was actually the men that work for me who asked for separate bathrooms, because "the women are so goddamn disgusting" and "we don't like seeing bloody tampons in the trash". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398575078.0" user="grimoiregirl" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, okay, so women who are hoverpeeing are clearly insane.

But... where are women supposed to put bloody menstrual items? If you flush them, they clog the toilet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398591580.0" user="MoreHeadState" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I know, I just finally gave in and had two restrooms put in. I never really took notice of the problems, because I have my own washroom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398856278.0" user="red_nick" delta="False">
    <text>I'm guessing they were using bins, rather than the medical waste disposal type</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398926454.0" user="mysanityisrelative" delta="False">
    <text>I mean...what do you think we do at home?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399064833.0" user="PatrickBearman" delta="False">
    <text>I think the assumption is that you wrap up the item.  From my days of cleaning female bathrooms, I will tell you that women seem to do everything BUT wrap them up and place them in the garbage.  I have seen them in toilets, on toilets, on the toilet paper holder, on the sink, and even stuck to walls.  

Sometimes I do not understand people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397808826.0" user="cbnyc" delta="False">
    <text>To add to who this would benefit, I want to add something from the perspective bar management. We have consciously made the decision in the past to make the bathrooms into male/female from a revenue perspective. Men spend more money in drinks at our places and also tend to buy drinks for other people more often than females. It makes sense to minimize their time away from bar activities (being stuck in a like for the bathroom) and instead drinking and buying more drinks. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397922862.0" user="moun7" delta="False">
    <text>Good point. I would have never thought of that as I'm just a chemistry student with no business experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398873359.0" user="sensitivePornGuy" delta="False">
    <text>That's the worst argument possible. Maybe women would spend more money at the bar if they weren't stuck in line for the loo!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399051012.0" user="tumbleweed42" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. Sometimes when I go out drinking, I purposefully sip on my drink slower (and thus spend less money on refills) only because I want to limit the number of visits to the ladies room. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399192122.0" user="cbnyc" delta="False">
    <text>How? The bar is there to make money, and men spend more money at bars than women do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397874116.0" user="Ish_the_Stomach" delta="False">
    <text>My favorite bar, in a particularly small city has two of the bathrooms described **by OP** (also the "top secret one" that only regulars tend to use) The two main bathrooms have signs that divide them by gender. I have seen women use the men's and men use the women's. No one seems to mind either way. They are also basically equal in cleanliness. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397936047.0" user="CringeBinger" delta="False">
    <text>Work at a restaurant and mostly do bathrooms. Girls' restroom is rarely cleaner than the men's. Little scraps of toilet paper everywhere, tampon wrappers on the floor even though we have little trash cans specifically for them, and water and soap all over the sink. 

It's probably because men use a urinal wash their hands quickly and get out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397974315.0" user="Alex549us3" delta="False">
    <text>Eh at small breweries with single person bathrooms I've been waiting behind 3+ men with the women's restroom completely empty the whole time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397983314.0" user="Jeffffffff" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so your argument is that this shouldn't be done because it would be beneficial to women but detrimental to men, because currently men have it better for using public toilets. 

Fyi, this is like arguing that schools should have remained segregated because schools for black children were shitty and integrating wouldn't have any advantage for white children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398198647.0" user="Bascome" delta="False">
    <text>It is not like arguing that at all. Women already get bigger bathrooms and more stalls, now they want our bathrooms as well. 

Entirely different than segregated schools that lacked proper funding.

No this is like the white children lobbying to go to the black schools and the black kids saying "um can't we have anything to ourselves in this life without you white kids coming along and asking for more?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398253072.0" user="Prof_Acorn" delta="False">
    <text>Can you ensure that women who use the bathroom will only urinate and leave, and not take extra time to do makeup, chat with friends, read magazines, and whatever else it is that makes the women's line so much longer than the men's line? 

The guy's line is shorter for restrooms, not because we have more stalls (women do) or because less men use it, but because we zip, piss, zip and leave.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398336095.0" user="Jeffffffff" delta="False">
    <text>Can you ensure that men will do that? You just asked if I can guarantee women will be quick, told me that I can't, then told me you can somehow guarantee men will. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398354488.0" user="Prof_Acorn" delta="False">
    <text>I think the line after every movie, every play, every music venue, every event throughout the United States speaks to how much faster men use the restroom. Why should we wait around for twenty minutes to take a piss when all it takes is 15 seconds for us to go? 

Make even more stalls in the women's room if it need be, but gendered bathrooms are fair when men use bathrooms so much quicker. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399104358.0" user="Jeffffffff" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think there aren't women who are annoyed at the long bathroom lines because they just want to get in, pee and get out? Do you think every man is quick in the bathroom every time? If you don't, this is discriminatory. If you do believe that, you're going to have to argue that. 

Your argument is for an express bathroom line for people who just want to get in and get out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398012336.0" user="angrypandarage" delta="False">
    <text>If you work somewhere where there's more men than women, it's better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398169634.0" user="man_w_plan" delta="False">
    <text>When I was a teenager, I worked many jobs in restaurants and retail which involved cleaning bathrooms. I've seen a ton from both genders, and on average I would say the women's does tend to be nastier. That said, they are all nasty if they aren't cleaned often enough. I don't know what people do in there, but they make a huge fucking mess a lot of the time. I agree with you though that this would mostly benefit women. Not always, but most of the time men don't have a line unless someone is taking a shit. I don't really know how I feel about it. I've debated this a lot myself. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398328844.0" user="b0x0fawes0me" delta="False">
    <text>I worked at a business for about a year that had two individual gender-separated bathrooms and had to clean them every night I worked. The mens bathroom was almost always dirtier (eg piss on the seat from bad aim, soap smudged all over the sink, etc). This is just my own personal experience, but the women's room was almost never that bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398844560.0" user="cptspiffy" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. The situation mentioned by OP is actually advantageous to men, since *most* women won't go into the men's and skeeze it up. This is especially true if you are a man willing to use the women's if it is unoccupied. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
