<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27397786247.0" user="funchy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. 

The division may make many women feel safer.

Sadly we live in a world where women fear sexual assault from men.  I don't know how you feel, but i think many women worry about being cornered or confronted by a strange guy.

The solo bathrooms may not necessarily be at a busy hallway.  If you don't sex segregate them, Peter Pervert can stand in front of the one you just went into and he can't be accused of doing anything wrong.   You're in a little room with no way out.   You open the door and Peter Pervert is blocking the opening.   Mr Pervert makes a comment about your appearance.   Now you have to assertively tell Mr Pervert to please step aside.  He'll fake apologize and say he was just waiting his turn.  For a brief second,  as you look down the hall and don't see anyone else, the thought of sexual assault crosses your mind.  He takes a step into the room and you are forced to take a step back.   In a split second,  he shuts and locks the door.  You're trapped in the corner.  He says he will hurt you if you scream.  You are now a sexual assault statistic.

 If only the building has separate bath rooms: Then a creep couldn't get away with standing in front of the door.  Then you're not faced confronting a man to get out of that small room.   And maybe the odds sexual assault would happen are small but the *fear* that it could happen is always there. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397823135.0" user="ShouldersofGiants100" delta="False">
    <text>Your scenario is kind of absurd in that nothing at all about gendered washrooms stop it. "Peter pervert" as you label him could stand in front of the mens washroom, which are typically adjacent or right across the hall. In fact, I don't think I've ever seen a hall with only one door, especially one door that leads to a bathroom... he could stand in front of any other door and look completely nonchalant, then walk over in a couple steps. Or he could stand there and if anyone asks say he is waiting for someone. Further, most of these bathrooms are in public areas, like rest stops. Labelling them does not make them even the slightest bit safer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398035192.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Funchy's view of rapist thoughts: "Let's go rape somebody today! Look, a bathroom. Oh no, there's a sign on the door. I can't defy social convention that would be unsightly!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27397930210.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure a rapist could think of another excuse to stand by a bathroom. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398280569.0" user="whatdyasay" delta="False">
    <text>What about people who's gender does not appear to perfectly match the bathroom they use?  They risk assault every time they use the restroom, and not just one in a dark or isolated hallway.  They have to worry about people seeing their non-perfectly-gender-conforming body and deciding to comment on it, block the door, assault them (sexually or otherwise).  Gender neutral or unisex bathrooms help to avoid this situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
