<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="38" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27398578642.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>I cant say with 100% certainty that this would be a issue where you live but where i am at 95% easily of the male bathrooms have a urinal. By making the bathrooms unisex to save money when building urinals likely would no longer be put in.

My issue with this from experience is a mens bathroom lacking a urinal the sit down toilet now has piss on the seat. Some people seem to be to lazy to put the seat up or down for themselves to not inconvenience others with their bio waste.

Personally my view is the exact opposite of yours. I dont think unisex bathrooms should exist at all. Due to many of the reasons stated in this thread already.

But the urinal is important to me and probably a lot of other guys. Urinals are what make male restrooms move faster and not have lines. Local bar near me has individual bathrooms but the guys bathroom doesnt lock because it has a single stall and a urinal, if someone is taking a shit the urinal can still be used easily without any problems. Should that place go unisex you wont have any guys using the urinal while a woman is in the bathroom cause it would likely cause a hell of a lot of legal problems for establishments. Not sure how many male bathrooms you have been in but urinals are usually close together and a significant chunk of the time there is no dividers between them so anyone really wanting to can get a look at your johnson. Guys pretty much have established bathroom etiquette for this. We dont look down while peeing at urinals like this or to the sides, we look at the wall above the urinal to avoid looking at some other guys dick for the most part (some guys are lookers but its rare that it happens and if it does and eye contact is made it turns into a awkward fast look away kinda deal).

You turn bathrooms unisex though and you eliminate the speedyness of the males bathroom. Thus forming two lines. Not to mention you now have more people wiping off the toilet seat also adding more time to lines. Im gonna assume im not the only person who when using a public toilet lines the seat with toilet paper to sit on if it doesnt have the toilet seat covers (surprisingly not many places do).

So it defeats the whole point of your view since now instead of only one gender having a line going on now you have two bathrooms with lines, your not saving much for time and opening things up to a large variety of issues that having gendered bathrooms removes. In some cases having unisex makes sense. Gas station near me has one bathroom, its unisex. But they dont have a ton of people trying to use the bathroom since its a gas station way out in the middle of nowhere and isnt very high traffic. But only a few miles down the road the restaurant i was talking about earlier only has two small bathrooms and a ton of activity at times, the place has a bar in it and is on a golf course so now instead of a short wait for one bathroom you have two short waits for the two bathrooms which disrupts the already established flow of the place. Its more men there than women and the mens room operates fairly quickly due to basically having two toilets. The womens rarely has a line and the mens never does. If both are unisex now its only two toilets because the current mens room likely wouldnt have a urinal anymore and even if it did if a woman was in there using the stall its likely a man isnt gonna be in there as well using the urinal.

TL:DR - combining bathrooms like this just causes more chaos for some places, your view should be changed to venues having enough bathrooms or more stalls opposed to them being unisex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398588648.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>My post is only talking about single use bathrooms, not multi stall or urinal ones. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398596011.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>Like i said may vary by location but where im at almost all mens restrooms have a urinal, even single use bathrooms, though some of the single use bathrooms have evolved into 2 people bathrooms due to the stall and urinal. I can think of one i was in recently this hasnt happened at but a large percent of them have a stall and a urinal. Grocery store i go to most the time the sit down toilet isnt in a stall and the door has a lock but the bathroom still has a urinal which as i said makes the mens bathroom move faster even in this way due to there not being pee on the toilet seat of the sit down stall so it saves the wiping it off time.

Would be more efficient to have multiple stalls put in to move a bathrooms lines along faster and remove the locks if lines are a issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398597941.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>There are many places with no stalls or urinals, only two identical rooms with one toilet. That is the topic of the post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398617508.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>Okay in that situation then what does it matter what the sign on the door says? Place my wife used to work at had 2 bathrooms like that one male and one female, it also on the other side of the building had two large bathrooms with stalls and urinals. I preferred to go into the individual ones cause they smelt better and were less likely to have anyone coming in and out of them. I used the womens on all the time because apparently some old lady complained about the toilet paper being shitty so they had nice tp in it. The door had a lock on it and if no one was in it id use it. No one ever gave me crap about it but if they would have i would have said i prefer the nicer tp so i used this one.

It must just be a location thing cause where i live if a single use bathroom has a lock on it and the other is busy its not unusual to see someone of the opposite gender on the door to use the other bathroom if its free and most people dont really give a crap probably cause they know what its like to have to go and not want to wait or not be able to hold it any longer.

Basically what your asking is should we force places to change the signs on doors if they have two individual bathrooms. Either that or you lived in a pretty shitty place were people are just dicks who like to complain about small stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398620230.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>This whole thing is very low stakes. I've gotten a surprised look and a snarky comment when I've used the men's room. I don't think we should really force anybody to do anything. I just think the unisex system is superior, and if a friend were opening a gas station or coffee shop or whatever I'd suggest doing it this way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398635160.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>Ive noticed some of the newer gas stations near me bathrooms are unisex so maybe this is whats up with that. One of the newest ones only has one bathroom. What i thought was unusual about it was there is a shower in it and the bathroom is huge, could easily fit 4 stalls and 4 sinks in it, but its one toilet, baby changing station, sink, and one shower. In a fairly busy gas station at that. Its right on the highway (though to be fair the highway near me is just a two lane road basically). Seemed odd to me that even though this gas station is on the highway and set up for truckers it only has one bathroom and the shower is in it as well so if someone is showering the bathroom is likely gonna get a line going.

Personally if i was gonna open a place up id make two bathrooms somewhat bigger for potential expansion room if needed, and probably do the same until i needed to add stalls then segregate them again. Make both bathrooms big enough for say 3 stalls but start out just two rooms with toilet and a sink. Add stalls as needed later and if its never needed at least the bathrooms are roomy instead of cramped. Though i could see this being a problem in certain areas like NYC due to room.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
