<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="152278353.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2inuq9/cmv_if_a_business_has_two_individual_bathrooms/">
    <title>CMV: If a business has two individual bathrooms, both should be unisex bathrooms</title>
    <original_poster>ricebasket</original_poster>
    <original_post>The bathrooms I'm describing are the ones where there's a single door and a small room with a toilet, sink, and trashcan that are used by one person at a time. I don't think there's any reason to divide them by gender. By equipment, they're identical I believe it's pretty uncommon for them to have urinals. Frequently the women's restroom will have a short line I have to wait in, while the men's stall is completely unoccupied. Occasionally I'll jump the line and use the men's restroom anyway, but people will give you strange looks. I've had men point out that they could not so easily do the same thing if there were a line at the men's room, and I think that's a really good point. If a business wants to provide a baby changing table, they could simply install one and mark it on the door avoiding the issue of either paying for two or only installing one in the women's room and leaving dads with infants out of luck. It's also beneficial to trans individuals who may feel uncomfortable using a gendered restroom.

I really can't think of any reason why this isn't more frequently seen. CMV!

Edit: Two counterpoints in response to common arguments:

1. From a management bathroom cleaning point of view, a unisex bathroom could be an advantage. Let's say a women's bathroom dirties by 10 dirt units every hour, the men's restroom by 8 dirt units every hour, and the restrooms are cleaned every 4 hours. That means you're more likely to get a customer complaint and have an employee need to go clean the women's room in hour 3, wasting some time. If you have unisex bathrooms it would even out and they each dirty at 9 units per hour, so it's easier to keep them both equally clean.

2. It doesn't make good business sense to have anyone tied up in a line. If there are 3 women waiting to pee and the men's stall is free, I don't want those women waiting around I want them browsing my store, paying the bill and freeing up a table, getting to their movie, etc. This argument also only favors men.

Edit 2: For all the talk of how terrifying women's bathrooms apparently are, I now feel like a hardened bad ass for using them all these years.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27398132508.0" user="gstring_jihad" delta="False">
    <text>If the goal is to minimize average wait time for all persons, and the bathrooms are sufficiently busy, then segregating them makes sense.

To see why this is so, exaggerate the numbers so that one sex takes a million years and the other takes a millisecond. If the bathrooms are unisex, they'll almost invariably be occupied, and both sexes will have to wait millions of years. Segregating the bathrooms increases the rate at which the millisecond sex passes through the queue vastly more than it decreases the rate at which the slower sex moves through the queue.

If your goal is to equalize the time taken by both sexes to use the bathroom even if this results in longer average wait times overall, then unisex bathrooms make sense. If this is your preference, then you might consider whether you would allow the same criterion to apply in other cases. For example, should women, or shorter people in general, automatically get assigned seats with less legroom on airline flights? On average women have shorter legs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398136294.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I want universal wait times reduced.

I don't think your airline analogy makes a lot of sense, in the restroom case you still get the same result/product. In the airline example someone gets an inferior product (although sidebar, I have short legs and don't give a damn about leg space and would love a discount on a short legroom seat).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398150627.0" user="gstring_jihad" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think your airline analogy makes a lot of sense

The quality of the product depends on the distance between the passengers knees and the seat ahead. This is determined by the difference between the amount of legroom and the length of the passengers legs. Equalizing the comfort between the sexes would mean adjusting the legroom to compensate for leg length variation.

Women (or shorter people in general) would not get a discount on the seat with less legroom. On average women would pay the same amount for the same comfort as men (say, 3 inches of space between knee and seat). Their comfort would be decreased to match men's current comfort, just as in the bathroom scenario, men's wait times would be increased to match women's.

I'm not suggesting this is a good idea, but I can't see how one would support your bathroom position without accepting it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398444322.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I'm proposing a measure to make the sexes equal, you're proposing one to make them have different experiences. I don't see them as equivalent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398476912.0" user="gstring_jihad" delta="False">
    <text>You're proposing men and women wait equal times for a bathroom, I'm proposing that men and women have equal space between their knees and the seat in front of them.

In one case equalizing the experience means men wait additional time to match women's, in the other, it means women sacrifice leg room to match men's.

Unless you can explain specifically why the cases differ or why you believe equal experience important in one case but not the other, you might find people question the logical consistency of your position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398595762.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>I can't stop you from questioning it. I think you're taking an exaggerated example to try and trap me in some logic consistency run around. You know the airline legroom is a dumb idea, I know it's a dumb idea. If you want to talk about bathrooms I'm game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27398625270.0" user="gstring_jihad" delta="False">
    <text>That's three times you've said the analogy's wrong, and zero times you've explained why you think so. If you think it's an equal experience sitting in the same economy seat at 5'9" and 6'3" (taller woman versus taller man) on a cross-country flight you might want to ask someone that tall about the experience.

I suggest you consider whether you can really expect other people to take your issues seriously if you can't give them the same courtesy. Imagine if someone said to you "obviously this complaint about bathrooms is a dumb idea, and we both know that," but didn't explain why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399058157.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>From my first comment where I explained the difference in the situations: "I don't think your airline analogy makes a lot of sense, in the restroom case you still get the same result/product. In the airline example someone gets an inferior product"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399102213.0" user="gstring_jihad" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that you have not yet provided a reason why you believe the product to be inferior.

Men on average presently receive an inferior product: in any given airline seat, they will find the distance between their knees and the next seat considerably less than is the situation for the average woman. This makes a seat which might be comfortable for even a taller woman uncomfortably cramped for a taller man.

Portioning out seats to take account of the height difference between the sexes so that both sexes on average experience the same comfort (same average distance between knees and the next seat) would provide an equal experience, which appears to be your priority.

If you mean that women would receive an experience inferior to that which they experience now, you're correct. In your bathroom example, men would receive an experience inferior to what they experience now.

I would have trouble defending your position from the claim that you appear to believe men ought to make sacrifices for the sake of equality, but women need not do so. That seems like the *opposite* of equality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27399113156.0" user="ricebasket" delta="False">
    <text>Less leg room is an inferior product. It is also a purchased product. You're also proposing dividing the sexes which creates problems at the outliers of gender norms, namely tall women, short men, and trans individuals. I'm proposing a system where a divide is broken down and everyone shares wait times and restrooms regardless of gender.

I simply do not think these are comparable situations and I don't understand why you've chosen to argue against me in such a silly hypothetical. This is my final word in this discussion and I won't respond to you any longer. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
