<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37620175390.0" user="AlfalfaFlimsy8483" delta="False">
    <text>If your wife had COVID recently, she might be okay without it, but the studies on the length of protection offered by natural immunity have mixed results. 

My wife got the vaccine even while we were trying, and she could have been pregnant. Our main reason was because fever during pregnancy can have serious negative effects on the unborn baby. There is always a chance that getting any vaccine could turn out poorly for you, but I’m convinced pretty much everyone will get COVID eventually, and we would rather take the risk of an extremely unlikely adverse reaction than to risk the possibility of having a destructive fever during pregnancy.

I’m seeing some people mention passing on antibodies to the baby, but the danger to children, even with the delta variant, is still so low that that factor doesn’t really matter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
