<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613953508.0" user="Forthwrong" delta="False">
    <text>As of 11 August, the CDC recommends it for everyone, [including pregnant people](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/recommendations/pregnancy.html). It has always recommended it [for people who had Covid in the past.](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/faq.html)

Notably: "pregnant and recently pregnant people are at an increased risk for severe illness from COVID-19 when compared with non-pregnant people."

I applaud your commitment to making an informed decision, and it seems like your hesitancy is based on the lack of studies providing certainty. The lack of long-term studies is not a concern because effects that take months to come to light are profoundly rare in all vaccines, and the Covid vaccines are no exception to this. 

It's worth noting that vaccines are among the safest of all medical interventions (despite both the known _and_ unknown adverse effects, both short-term _and_ long-term), safer than antibiotics and high blood pressure medications, and far safer than blood transfusions and routine surgeries.

---

As for scientific certainty, true, vaccine hesitancy would still be reasonable on the basis that this is a nascent technology, because we should wait until things play out a bit. One of the most influential vaccinologists ever, Dr. Maurice Hilleman, said: "I never breathe a sigh of relief until the first 3 million doses are out there."

Things _have_ played out. We're past three, thirty, or even three hundred million doses; we're past three _billion_ doses. Major components of the vaccine have been studied heavily for the past 30 years. Public and scientific scrutiny on the vaccines continues to be intense.

These things can give a strong sense of certainty.

---

In terms of the mRNA vaccines, the material doesn't stay around long in the body, making the possibility of such delayed effects [mechanistically unlikely](https://www.amjmed.com/article/S0002-9343\(21\)00153-4/fulltext).

From the decades of research on mRNA vaccines, [mRNA vaccine](https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28754494/) [safety studies](https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31079849/) give further evidence to the rarity of delayed effects.

Using the precautionary principle here is self-defeating – the tiny chance of a delayed side-effect should not be compared with the dream of a vaccine with no delayed side-effects; it should be compared with the reality of a virus with deadly known effects – the chance of spreading Covid, even in your region's best case scenario, is far more likely.

While lowering exposure to others is great and reduces transmission, no one measure is foolproof. There's a chance you might catch Covid (because the vaccines are not 100% effective) and spread it to her when she's in her vulnerable state. The risk of this is small, yes, but the risk of a delayed side-effect is even smaller.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614312419.0" user="Morasain" delta="False">
    <text>Well, contradicting that, the German Robert Koch Institute recommend pregnant women *don't* get the vaccine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614361255.0" user="GadgetGamer" delta="False">
    <text>And contradicting your contradiction, the UK's Royal College of Obstetricians &amp;amp; Gynaecologists advise that [pregnant women should have the vaccine](https://www.rcog.org.uk/en/guidelines-research-services/coronavirus-covid-19-pregnancy-and-womens-health/covid-19-vaccines-and-pregnancy/covid-19-vaccines-pregnancy-and-breastfeeding/).

My personal feeling is that even if COVID does not kill you, it can restrict the oxygen supply in a woman's body that leads to the baby dying. If you want to protect the unborn child, then vaccines are a good idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37624021167.0" user="betweentwosuns" delta="False">
    <text>If they both work from home, have groceries delivered etc. it's almost mechanically impossible to contract covid. I'd agree with getting vaccinated if she was out in the world, but even if the risk associated with vaccinating while pregnant is quite low that's still more than the covid risk faced by someone permanently home with natural immunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37624287883.0" user="GadgetGamer" delta="False">
    <text>I did a quick search and found [this page](https://www.marchofdimes.org/pregnancy/prenatal-care-checkups.aspx) that said:

&amp;gt; How often do you go for prenatal care checkups?
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; * Weeks 4 to 28 of pregnancy. Go for one checkup every 4 weeks (once a month).
&amp;gt; * Weeks 28 to 36 of pregnancy. Go for one checkup every 2 weeks (twice a month).
&amp;gt; * Weeks 36 to 41 of pregnancy. Go for one checkup every week (once a week).

That's a lot of going out into the community including close contact with other people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37624624071.0" user="betweentwosuns" delta="False">
    <text>Good point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614407353.0" user="Forthwrong" delta="False">
    <text>I did some searching and found [this article](https://www.dw.com/en/covid-is-it-safe-to-get-vaccinated-in-pregnancy/a-57438440) presumably about what you mentioned.

An excerpt:

&amp;gt; In April 2021, STIKO recommended against vaccinating people during pregnancy.  [....]

&amp;gt; STIKO said it lacked sufficient data to make a general recommendation in favor of vaccinating pregnant people because they only rarely take part in clinical trials.

&amp;gt; So, it's not necessarily that the committee has spoken out against vaccinations for mothers-to-be, it just says it can't recommend it for everyone who is pregnant.

&amp;gt; It's a case of not for and not against. But it's precisely that stance that expectant mothers find confusing.

The FDA didn't make a conclusion on its guidance for pregnant people until 11 August. This is clearly a field where emerging data can influence the positions of regulatory authorities, and the FDA changed its position from "not sure" to "yes" in the light of emerging evidence.

Please correct me if you meant something else.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
