<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613908267.0" user="YourMom_Infinity" delta="False">
    <text>Any one who remains unvaccinated is giving the Covid 19 virus a chance to spread and mutate. If given enough of an opportunity by unvaccinated people, the Covid 19 virus will mutate into something the current vaccine does not recognize or protect against. It is not "her body, her choice" if her choice impacts everyone around her.

Parents often think they're being "selfless" and making a decision or choosing an action that benefits others when all they're doing is being selfish for their kid/s. You do not care about every other woman or child on the planet (kids under 12 can not get vaccinated currently), you only care about the woman in *your* house and the child *you* helped create.

When all is said and done, no one can force anyone to get vaccinated. But your situation is not unassailable from a moral standpoint. Your wife is not a biological island, and her vaccination status does impact other people. Moreover, you and your wife choose to put many many more children at risk by protecting your one from negligible risks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613966418.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point, what we don’t yet believe is if the risks are negligible. There have been (thankfully few) vaccination programs here in the past that have ended up being harmful to unborn babies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614572226.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>The risks are negligible.  

I am neonatal health care provider.  The *only* issues I see related to covid in infants are mothers who are unvaccinated and either have to deliver a severely premature child because they are dying, chronic hypoxia (low blood oxygen) in the mother that affects the baby's brain development, and health issues with the *mother* forcing delivery.  

The risks of covid during pregnancy are ***far*** higher than any possible risk of the vaccine.  

We have the majority of our moms here who have been vaccinated. No effects in the baby.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614974788.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>Wrote above in favor of vax but will sound anti here.     IMO the mutation argument is weak and coercive.  If she gets the shot while pregnant it should be for her health.  It’s despicable to Blame a pregnant woman  for fueling mutations if she has concerns on a pharmaceutical that no prior generation of babies has gotten.  Pregnancy is intense- women stop some of their favorite things like drinking coffee and sushi just to make sure things go ok.  Many OTC drugs are scheduled as “no long term data”. And therefore not given to pregnant women.  Even if this is recommended its glaring that there’s no long term data.      Her duty is to herself and her baby.   As for who can make Mutations -   Our breakthrough infections are rampant.   We can make mutations while vaxed.  not to mention your cat can get COVID.  Your cat can make mutations.   Not to mention  The more than 80 percent of humans on earth not vaxed ,,.. we are all a petri dish.  We already knew of  dozensw of mutations before this vax rolled out and at least 12 of them are mutant variants that can resist vax and in turn make new mutations ..   given that CDC dropped the ball on tracking our breakthrough cases,  we are very reliant on Israel data  at this point. I would look there for good info - fwiw i think its more reassuring</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37618735443.0" user="YourMom_Infinity" delta="False">
    <text>Breakthrough infections are 1%. You have a vastly lower chance of contracting COVID *or spreading the virus to others* when you are vaccinated. 

*Her duty is to herself and her baby.* Meanwhile, while she’s catering to *herself* and *her offspring*, she is putting others at risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619268175.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>No they are not one percent on Delta the new strain.  If you are vaxxed and go to an indoor event of only vaxed people right now  where cases are spiking you are  quite likely to encounter a breakthrough case and also likely get one yourself in 5 days.   These products were never tested on Delta.   This is the test .   On the plus side, it’s like we are getting inoculated by natural immunity because cases are so rampant,  and the vax are very good at keeping us home from the hospital</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619315873.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.propublica.org/article/the-cdc-only-tracks-a-fraction-of-breakthrough-covid-19-infections-even-as-cases-surge          “The CDC tracked all breakthrough cases until the end of April, then abruptly stopped without making a formal announcement. A reference to the policy switch appeared on the agency’s website in May about halfway down the homepage.....”I was shocked,” said Dr. Leana Wen, a physician and visiting professor of health policy and management at George Washington University. “I have yet to hear a coherent explanation of why they stopped tracking this information”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37622647713.0" user="RevolutionaryHeron1" delta="False">
    <text>Eh the idea that the unvaxxed cause mutations is actually a hypothesis considered less likely than the idea that mutations are actually caused by mass vaccination programs. Virologists actually warned of this at the start of the vaccine rollout - as long as we vaccinate in stages, the virus will learn. Be wary of pinning this on the unvaxxed community. It’s an unfortunate side effect of vaccines.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
