<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613933657.0" user="nnaughtydogg" delta="False">
    <text>You guys should do whatever you feel is best, but particularly whatever she feels is best. But an IRL cautionary tale for you. My friend is a doing her residency in DC. They had a pregnant patient this past week who got covid at 32 weeks. She was on the max dose of O2, and still had oxygen saturation levels that were below 90 (dangerous for the baby). She needed to be intubated it got so bad, but if they intubate then they run the risk of needing to do an emergency non sterile C-section in the ICU. Her and her husband opted to do an early C-section, which was successful, baby is ok thankfully. Now however, due to complications from the intubation/c section it is likely she will not pull through. On top of that they had to get a non infected family member to be with the baby because the rest of her family is sick. All this to say I understand your trepidation about vaccinating your pregnant wife, but there are serious risks to not vaccinating as well. And I will reiterate that you guys should do what you think is best and I am sure it will work out either way. Best of luck</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
