<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613898549.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, she should be vaccinated. 

[American College of Obstetricians guidance ](https://www.acog.org/covid-19/covid-19-vaccines-and-pregnancy-conversation-guide-for-clinicians)

[CDC guidance ](https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2021/s0811-vaccine-safe-pregnant.html)

Is her doctor recommending different? If so, why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613951559.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>Some healthcare professionals are currently advising for, and some are saying to wait until after baby is born.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613962957.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Source?

Edit: to say GTFO with down voting me, and provide a source.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614220134.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>They honestly don’t know the risks. There has been no studies for this vaccine on pregnant women</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614238398.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>You are honestly grossly misinformed. 

" In  the largest study of its kind to date, researchers at Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH), Brigham and Women’s Hospital and the Ragon Institute of MGH, MIT and Harvard have found the new mRNA COVID-19 vaccines to be highly effective in producing antibodies against the SARS-CoV-2 virus in pregnant and lactating women."

[Source ](https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2021/03/study-shows-covid-19-vaccinated-mothers-pass-antibodies-to-newborns/#:~:text=In%20the%20largest%20study%20of,virus%20in%20pregnant%20and%20lactating)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614330047.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn’t say if the babies will have long term defects from the mother having the vaccine. It’s literally impossible to know that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614382632.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>True, because we don't have time travel yet. 

But, we have been specifically studying pregnant women during this entire time and nothing points to any longterm effects. 

Fact: Live vaccines are not recommended for pregnant women because of adverse side effects. 

Question: Can you point me to a study showing proliferation of longterm side effects from a vaccine that is/was recommended to pregnant women?

I've been alive a long time, and can't remember that time we all stopped taking a specific vaccine due to manifestation of longterm effects. 

Please let me know, I'm genuinely interested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614446114.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thalidomide_scandal

Mistakes happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614448461.0" user="WikiMobileLinkBot" delta="False">
    <text>Desktop version of /u/saltycranberrysauce's link: &amp;lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thalidomide_scandal&amp;gt;

 --- 

 ^([)[^(opt out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiMobileLinkBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^(]) ^(Beep Boop.  Downvote to delete)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614483874.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed they do. But this isn't referring to a vaccine and was not a longterm effect.

So, I'm not seeing how it's relevant to establishing there were longterm effects (your concern) with birth defects or development in children, associated with a vaccine. 

I am actively searching for this now, but coming up empty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614496352.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>I’m simply stating we don’t know if the fetuses will be harmed. So perhaps it’s better to wait until after the pregnancy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614628281.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>It could be, but it's pure speculation not based in facts or evidence. 

The same could be said of any number of newer drugs that pregnant women are advised to take. For example biologics.

Personal perspective questions:

How long should it be studied before recommending? I mean it could possibly have side effects 10 years out? 

Do you see no benefit to the current approval and monitoring system we have to vet drugs? Do you feel that it's inadequate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614716984.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>In my personal opinion you have to weigh the risks vs the benefits. I might feel comfortable taking a vaccine that has no track record. But then you are making that decision for your unborn fetus. I think I wouldn’t risk it. Probably around 10 years of studies would convince me.

Perhaps I can give you another example I was on a drug. This drug was a miracle. It helped many people and was FDA approved. After 3 years they found that it was killing peoples livers and was pulled from the shelves. So yeah you could say I’m not convinced by our current approval system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614857890.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the reply, it helps me in understanding your views better.

Ugh, it seems like any thing you take longterm affects the liver. I know many people with similar experiences. 

Personal anecdote:

I know first hand about OP's struggle. My wife was on a biologic when she found out she was pregnant. She had to decide whether or not to continue during pregnancy. She's actively involved in  pharmaceutical research, so knew where to find relevant information. Like the Covid vaccine, she couldn't find any information that it could be bad, so followed the physicians advise and continued. So far, so good.

You can only hope to make an informed decision, based on available facts and associated risks involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614891225.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>So true, we can only make the best decision with what we know at the time and keep moving forward</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37616563131.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>That sort of liver reaction can happen with any drug. The only way to find out if it is going to happen more frequently than acceptable is to give it to a large number of people. 

I had that same kind of reaction to green tea extract - not in overdose amounts by far</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37616623691.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>we know that COVID-19 can harm pregnant mothers and their unborn, and is more likely to harm them than someone who is not pregnant.

We have good reason to believe that the COVID-19 vaccine won't cause long term harm.  The vaccine gets the body to produce some proteins.  Both the proteins and the vaccine are quickly destroyed in the body.  Nothing sticks around to cause harm.  Any negative effects one would expect to see fairly soon after vaccination.

Why take the option to risk what we know can cause serious harm (infection) and that we don't know the full ramifications of long term for those infected, over the vaccine that appears to be very safe?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614582428.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Which the FDA wisely did not approve, and unlike the covid vaccine, they did no studies on pregnant women.

What studies would you find persuasive? What does it mean to "know" if there's harm or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614602304.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>A study of pregnant women and how there babies develop over the years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614611683.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Ballpark for how many years? People have already posted various studies on pregnant women, and if you'd say something like, 10-15 years, then basically any vaccine or "new" medication would be off the table.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614653459.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I wouldn’t give pregnant women not fully tested drugs. They could just get the vaccine once they’ve given birth</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614665946.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yeah I wouldn’t give pregnant women not fully tested drugs.

I don't know why you're dodging the question. The FDA just approved one of the vaccines so I don't know what your standards for "fully tested" are here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614742169.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>Long term studies on the long term effects of the drug. As I mentioned in another comment I was on a drug that was FDA approved. It was a miracle drug. It was on the shelves for a whole 3 years before they had to pull it because they figured out it was killing peoples livers.

You can choose to take the vaccine but don’t tell me we know do a fact that there won’t be long term repercussions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614749881.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Long term studies on the long term effects of the drug.

Ok... like I keep asking, what is "long term" to you? I don't know why you're refusing to give me a straight answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614799549.0" user="saltycranberrysauce" delta="False">
    <text>O, I thought your 10-15 years was a reasonable timeline</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614818989.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Ah ok. Seems like it's rolling the dice to never take a vaccine when you're pregnant. I just looked up the numbers on [Indiana and it's something like 1 in 14](https://www.indystar.com/story/news/health/2021/07/30/covid-indiana-your-odds-getting-infected-if-not-vaccinated/5432010001/), with a 1 in 297 change of hospitalization. Even if you take all the precautions, like you said, mistakes happen. 

AFAIK there hasn't been a vaccine that's ever caused a birth defect, and even when there are complications of a vaccine the odds are like 1 in a million, 1 in one-hundred thousand maybe. Doesn't seem great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619164551.0" user="sgtm7" delta="False">
    <text>How could anyone say there are no longterm effects, when the covid mRNA vaccine hasn't been around "longterm"?   Longterm would be the 130 years of data regarding inactivated virus vaccines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619528299.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>So, if you don't trust the mRna science, take one of the 2 inactivated Covid vaccines.

Though it hasn't been proven yet that their efficacy is as good as the other available vaccines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619612045.0" user="sgtm7" delta="False">
    <text>I took the vaccine in October and November last year, and had a booster shot in July.  I was only commenting on the lack of actual longterm data on mRNA vaccines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619667647.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>I understand. My comment wasn't directed at you specifically. Just noting that there are alternatives where the base concepts/implementations have been around &amp;amp; studied longer. 

The mRna science  has been around for over 30 years, and this (1st real world) application seems to be proving its effectiveness and safety. Evidenced by this being one of, if not the largest trial ever conducted by people.

Speaking to OP's concerns, all available data, trials, and anecdotal evidence points to taking the vaccine being the best way to protect yourself and your unborn child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614262326.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>So we have seen around 10 different healthcare professionals in the last few months. Some have explained that the policy is to advise for vaccination but they wouldn’t do it personally. Some have unequivocally recommended she get the vaccine</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620101548.0" user="beestingers" delta="False">
    <text>How do you link a source from your own doctor? That is why you are being downvoted. It's a dumb question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620335335.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you could link to any OB/GYN practices website showing the recommendation to forego vaccination. Surely if doctors felt this way, they wouldn't hide it for no reason. 

You could link to any OB/GYN Healthcare providers public letter or email or sentiment with the same.

You could link to a news article showing the same. I.e. "Some doctors not recommending Covid vaccines for pregnant women "

That's just off the top of my head.

The simple fact is that you're probably not going to find any, because it goes against everything we know at this point.

You also could answer one of my first questions to OP; Why did a doctor advise against the vaccine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37621758995.0" user="ExtraDebit" delta="False">
    <text>Their doctors?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
