<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613867518.0" user="Discoinfernwow" delta="False">
    <text>I think the opinion you have is a valid one. Why do you want your view changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613881814.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>Because if someone can put forward an argument that it is, on balance better for her and baby, i might change my view</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613891825.0" user="Discoinfernwow" delta="False">
    <text>Might be better for her, but I don't know if the effects on babies are known atm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614581517.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>No effects on the baby.  Except possibly a mild passive immunity to covid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37630926050.0" user="AcanthopterygiiFar65" delta="False">
    <text>Source.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37632235617.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/coronavirus/the-covid19-vaccine-and-pregnancy-what-you-need-to-know%3famp=true

Rasmussen SA, Watson AK, Kennedy ED, Broder KR, Jamieson DJ. Vaccines and pregnancy: past, present, and future. Semin Fetal Neonatal Med. 2014 Jun;19(3):161-9. doi: 10.1016/j.siny.2013.11.014. Epub 2013 Dec 17. PMID: 24355683.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613923424.0" user="iamonlyoneman" delta="False">
    <text>What's better is to NOT do things that carry risk but don't have benefit.  It looks like people who have recovered don't take additional protection from a vaccine after they were ill with covid and recovered 

https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.06.01.21258176v2</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614011068.0" user="Forthwrong" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What's better is to NOT do things that carry risk but don't have benefit

This is an excellent heuristic, and it doesn't support vaccine hesitancy – it supports getting vaccinated.

It's worth noting that there's a reason there's a great overlap between vaccine side-effects and effects of Covid infection. This is no coincidence – it's because they're caused by the immune response, and the effects occur with more frequency and severity in people infected with Covid than in people who were vaccinated.

We're all taking a risk either way, whether vaccinated or unvaccinated. However, the risk is far lower for vaccinated people. That's how not being vaccinated is a greater risk.

As for prior infection, [unvaccinated people who already had COVID-19 are more than 2 times as likely than fully vaccinated people to get COVID-19 again.](https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7032e1.htm?s_cid=mm7032e1_e&amp;amp;ACSTrackingID=USCDC_921-DM63289&amp;amp;ACSTrackingLabel=MMWR%20Early%20Release%20-%20Vol.%2070%2C%20August%206%2C%202021&amp;amp;deliveryName=USCDC_921-DM63289)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614156633.0" user="Okney1lz" delta="False">
    <text>Looks like maybe that's not entirely correct at this point.

"Based on those findings, researchers suggested that immunity might last for years, possibly a lifetime, in people who were infected with the coronavirus and later vaccinated. But it was unclear whether vaccination alone might have a similarly long-lasting effect."

[Sauce ](https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/28/health/coronavirus-vaccines-immunity.html)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
