<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37614580684.0" user="ItsMyView" delta="False">
    <text>**"I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself"**

You both decided to have this baby. You both will raise this baby and you both will make medical decisions for the baby in the future. This is not a 'her body her choice' situation. Ultimately, she will make the final decision but your input should be considered in what she ultimately ends up doing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37615014433.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t the handmaids tale so yes it’s her pregnancy in her body FFS</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37615056927.0" user="ItsMyView" delta="False">
    <text>Did you even read what I wrote? They mutually decided to have a baby and therefore his input should be considered. I already said that she will ultimately have the final say because she is the one that would have to get the shot. Are you seriously saying that her husband, the father of the child, should have no input?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37616442279.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text> “this not a ‘her body her choice’ situation.”

Yes it quite literally is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37618845850.0" user="ItsMyView" delta="False">
    <text>I like how you dodged my question. Well done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619296835.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not a question.  Just a sort of oinking noise people make when they invoke pregnancy as a real estate claim by men</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37619430137.0" user="ItsMyView" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, you really are a man eater. My comments had NOTHING to do with pregnancy. The point that you are unable to grasp is should a husband and wife have a respectful conversation in a situation like this before the wife makes a final decision about getting vaccinated. I honestly can't tell if you have a reading comprehension problem or if you are just an arrogant woman with a huge chip on your shoulder. Thanks for this wonderful conversation but I think it's time you go on to your next man hating post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620325859.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text> by using terms like “man eater” and “man hating”  you reveal yourself.   Thanks :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620510463.0" user="ItsMyView" delta="False">
    <text>Karen, you are too funny! I dedicate this song to you:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yRYFKcMa\_Ek&amp;amp;ab\_channel=hallandoatesVEVO</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620751040.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>Love that song.  Thanks</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
