<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613859241.0" user="acquavaa" delta="False">
    <text>What did her doctor say about it?

Congrats on 18 years of no herpes btw</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613873825.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>So doctors here are all advising to get it. Previously they were advising against it so we feel it’s a bit of an unknown</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613906800.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>You know how ridiculous this sounds?

"Scientists are now following the heliocentric model of the solar system.  Before, they followed the geocentric model of the solar system, so it feels a bit unknown."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37618846560.0" user="NeedCheatsheet" delta="False">
    <text>Please explan why does it sound ridiculous?

It shows that scientists have been wrong for this whole time and just now changed their mind. What if they change their mind again?

What you are seemingly suggesting is to blindly believe science which itself is unscientific.

Ideally you would read the research and make your own conclusions but that is unrealistic, so OP is obviously unsure of what to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620389823.0" user="No-Transportation635" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It shows that scientists have been wrong for this whole time and just now changed their mind. What if they change their mind again?

Holding off on a recommendation due to lack of evidence, then making the recommendation when better evidence becomes available is hardly "being wrong the whole time".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37620480817.0" user="NeedCheatsheet" delta="False">
    <text>I was talking about the model of solar system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613971497.0" user="Prickly_Pear1" delta="False">
    <text>Doctors weren't sure if it was safe so they advised against it until they got more information. They now have more information and now they are saying you should get it.

Why does it feel like an unknown?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37617103125.0" user="kollectivist" delta="False">
    <text>As more information emerges, the advice inevitably changes to reflect that. More information - lots of it - is emerging to say it's safe. Caution was the wisest approach when no information existed, but now that it does, it'd be foolish to continue to advise delaying in a situation where you have a rampant variant with an R0 of around 6, and a demographic which is already in a state of immunolgical flux because of pregancy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37621693675.0" user="PassionVoid" delta="False">
    <text>So you choose to go on the recommendation they made when they had less information rather than the one they made after they gathered more? That's kind of weird. If you won't listen to your doctors, why are you seemingly ready and willing to listen to anonymous Redditors? What information are you hoping to get from this thread that you anticipate could supersede the advice of your actual doctors?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
