<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613889028.0" user="Kingalthor" delta="False">
    <text>I'd google for news articles about pregnant women that aren't vaccinated and get covid. There are some terrifying examples of very severe outcomes for pregnant women.

It made sense to be skeptical of the vaccine in the early days, but now pfizer has full approval and every medical organization is recommending pregnant women to be vaxxed.

You are comparing potential unknown side effects of a vaccine that has full approval, to known severe risks from covid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613915204.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>So we have both been doing a lot of research about the benefits of both online, but both pro and anti vaccine believers put forward very convincing arguments. 

It’s fair to say that when she had it late last year she didn’t have a very bad time. And the antibody test shows she still has some immunity. Although I know diff variants can have worse impact and she wasn’t pregnant at the time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613946615.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>How many anti vax arguments are coming from medical professionals? 

 Would you rather take legal advice from a licensed attorney or from a sovereign citizen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37613972501.0" user="Kingalthor" delta="False">
    <text>It might be helpful to add some of those arguments into your post. We can't change your position if we don't know what it is and why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614008545.0" user="Herpes_free_5ince_03" delta="False">
    <text>Done. Thank you</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
