<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37614071846.0" user="Away-Reading" delta="False">
    <text>I got vaccinated while I was pregnant, and I don’t regret it *at all.* The best protection for your baby after he or she is born will be antibodies. Obviously no one wants their baby to get infected, and there are only 2 other ways to ensure your baby has antibody protection: mom gets vaccinated, or mom gets COVID. 

Unfortunately for both your wife and unborn baby, COVID during pregnancy can be really dangerous. Mom has a higher chance of severe illness, and any severe illness during pregnancy can have a very negative impact on the fetus. Of course, your wife may be otherwise young and healthy, so the risk of serious illness might still be low.

That’s what I figured too...until I learned that COVID can mess with the placenta big time. Studies have shown that the placentas in pregnant women with COVID are smaller and full of freaking blood clots. This happened in something like 1/3+ of COVID pregnancies, regardless of how sick the mom got. **Asymptomatic COVID was just as likely to cause damage to the placenta.** Since the placenta is literally keeping the fetus alive, serious damage to that organ is a *terrifying* prospect. 

The vaccine, however, doesn’t effect the placenta at all. In fact, the baby doesn’t actually get any of the vaccine directly...they only get the antibodies that mom’s body makes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37617707517.0" user="ChamberedEcho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The best protection for your baby after he or she is born will be antibodies.

Do the antibodies last longer than 6 months for infants?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37617740906.0" user="Away-Reading" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure. But having antibodies will definitely be most important when the baby is a newborn. Newborns not only have weaker immune systems - they also spend way more time in high-risk places like the hospital or visiting the pediatrician.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37621511189.0" user="heavenstarlight" delta="False">
    <text>agreed. my cousin’s newborn has antibodies through breastmilk !!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37677921510.0" user="MultPathways" delta="False">
    <text>Did u have your baby yet? Any abnormalities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678113618.0" user="Away-Reading" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I did. She’s absolutely perfect! She’s super chill and her weight gain is right on target... which I cannot say for her two older brothers when they were babies. 


Actually, the vaccine was kind of tested. we were exposed to COVID (for several hours) by a family member who didn’t know they were positive. This happened when my baby was just 2 weeks old, but neither of us were infected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678286483.0" user="MultPathways" delta="False">
    <text>That’s awesome to hear ! I am very nervous about it but am going to take it. Which vaccine did you get?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678444522.0" user="Away-Reading" delta="False">
    <text>I got Moderna

And don’t be too nervous!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678788977.0" user="MultPathways" delta="False">
    <text>Ok thank u😅😅I am getting the Pfizer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37679090531.0" user="Away-Reading" delta="False">
    <text>I hear that the Pfizer vaccine has less severe side effects, so that’s probably a good thing!

Edit: By “side effects” I mean the achy arm and annoying flu-like symptoms some people get.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
