<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37617930001.0" user="SnooApples9411" delta="False">
    <text>I'm 31 weeks pregnant and have been fully vaccinated for months. No side effects outside of the expect feeling poorly for a day after the second. My sister is a pharmacist that works vaccine clinics. I discussed it with her before deciding to get it. Everything has its risks but the risk of serious infection when pregnant is much higher then risk of serious side effects due to the vaccine. The reason doctors have changed what they're recommending to you is because studies for the vaccine in pregnant women have only recently been finished and have shown safe, so guidelines for for pregnancy and the vaccine have changed. I understand the hesitancy it's hard wanting to do the best for your baby and not always being sure what that is. I would get vaccinated again and feel I've made the best decision I can with the information that is available. One other thing to consider is studies are showing that getting vaccinated while pregnant can give the baby protection against COVID after birth just like the Tdap does (which I got today and have had with every pregnancy).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37677936709.0" user="MultPathways" delta="False">
    <text>Did you get tested for down syndrome or birth defects?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678165613.0" user="SnooApples9411" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. I've had multiple miscarriages years ago and a family history of congenital heart defects, so I have had extra tests with each pregnancy. For this one I've had genetic testing, 2 extra ultrasounds, and an echocardiogram and have still found no issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37678277197.0" user="MultPathways" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you so much! I’m very nervous about it. Which vaccine did u get?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37679259795.0" user="SnooApples9411" delta="False">
    <text>Completely understandable! I got the Moderna. It's really really hard wanting to do right by your baby and not being sure what that is. It's a huge responsibility. For me the data showing the risk of vaccine side affects being much lower then the risk of severe covid is what made me feel comfortable with my decision. I know at the end of the day I've made the best decision I can with what information is available and literally can't do any more then that. No matter what you do congratulations on your baby. For me my kids are the best thing I've ever done and I never knew it was possible to love somebody so so much.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
