<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37613924331.0" user="nicecorduroy" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not too sure of how a vaccine affects a fetus but I do know that the CDC has given pregnant woman the clear. 

That said, I can understand your concern and that of your wife’s. If she’s truly isolated and you are severely limiting your outside interaction it might be just fine. However there’s a level of assumed and implied risk that you could end up contracting one of the newer variants and become a breakthrough case thereby endangering your wife.

Antibodies from acquiring covid organically are not well understood, they might not last more than a few months and may not be protective against delta in the most robust way. 

I’d consult with your OB/GYN and maybe even an infectious disease specialist if it’s affordable and accessible, however just wanted to provide some points of consideration not necessarily push my own views onto you. 

Personally if I was outside of the house a lot and my wife was in your wife’s situation we’d probably get vaccinated assuming the CDC guidance states it’s appropriate. Moreover, as of this morning Pfizer got full FDA approval. 

What are the concerns (if any) about fetuses and the vaccine? Off the top of my head I can’t think of any major contraindications, although my knowledge is more scientific and I am not a clinician.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37614588626.0" user="sapphireminds" delta="False">
    <text>The only vaccines that can affect the fetus are live virus vaccines and those are not recommended during pregnancy. 

All other types of vaccine are *highly* encouraged for pregnant people and have been for years with no ill effects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37615165466.0" user="nicecorduroy" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting makes complete sense, mRNA vaccines wouldn’t really even interact so to speak with the fetus</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
