<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1528730433.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pa5zy9/cmv_my_pregnant_wife_shouldnt_seek_the_covid/">
    <title>CMV: My pregnant wife shouldn’t seek the COVID vaccine</title>
    <original_poster>Herpes_free_5ince_03</original_poster>
    <original_post>So my wife and I have both had COVID in the past and both tested positive for antibodies. I am double vaccinated but my wife has not yet received any. She is approx. halfway through pregnancy and we can’t decide if she should get the vaccine or not, mostly due to unknown impact on the baby and a lack of long-term studies. She works from home permanently so her exposure to others is significantly decreased.

We are not against a vaccine, just feel like we need more info to make an informed decision. She is undecided, I am leaning towards no.

* I firmly believe it is her body and her choice and this post is for info only. She will ultimately make the decision herself

Edit: 

When she contracted COVID before her health was not significantly impacted and she has made a full recovery with no long-term noticeable effects.

Different healthcare professionals have advised different things. Some say to get the vaccine now, some say to wait until the baby is born, one has said to wait until after breastfeeding. The lack of coherent advice is one reason for her (and my) reluctance.

She is permanent work from home with very limited contact with others, when outside we follow all guidelines, wear masks, sanitise and are otherwise very aware of the risk of transmission.

We are not in the US and the vaccine offered is Pfizer.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37614867397.0" user="pezzyn" delta="False">
    <text>Anecdotally ive seen fine outcomes from women who got vaxxed while pregnant.  Ive also seen fine outcomes for women who remained unvaccinated.  And then there are some horror stories of women dying right after birth.    She has natural immunity which offfers good protection but Delta is such a game changer thats not a given -   I don’t begrudge anyone hesitant about any optional new interventions while gestating .  but if you Are in an area of high transmissions and birthing in a hospital then it weighs more in favor of vax.   

Something to ask doctor about is whether the FDA approval gives them some discretion as to dosing, maybe your partner could get comfortable with fractional dosing ?  If you explain to the MD that she is otherwise unwilling to get vaxxed then a partial dose regimen is better than nothing (most doctors aside from some dedicated allergists do not have time or energy for this but maybe worth a try to get her partially vaxed)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
