<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27424029830.0" user="longlivedp" delta="False">
    <text>I think that the Swiss model is better than the Nordic model. 

Switzerland has relatively low taxes AND a good social safety net. 

The difference between Switzerland and Scandinavia is that in Switzerland fewer services are free. You have to pay for daycare, for private health insurance, for school meals. There is less social housing and you have to pay a bigger contribution towards your pension.  The advantage  is that the government can afford to charge low taxes, and low taxes also means most people are able to afford those things.

The government expects most adults to be capable of supporting themselves 100%, and the education system prepares people well for this. There is no excess of university graduates. People with poor academic skills are encouraged to go into vocational training. 

Still, the government will help people financially if and **only if** they get into difficulties. It will not help a large number of people **by default** like it happens in Nordic countries.  But since the number of people requiring this help is small, and since help is temporary, the government can still afford to charge low taxes.

&amp;gt;Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution.

Switzerland has all these things AND it has low taxes. What's not to like?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424078461.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>The Swiss do have a neat banking system and gold exports however. Low taxes is something you can allow for if that much money is coursing through your country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424106132.0" user="longlivedp" delta="False">
    <text>Norway has oil wealth.

The UK has oil wealth AND a banking sector just as big as Switzerland's, proportionally.

Yet both Norway and the UK have much higher taxes.

Switzerland must be doing something right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424149538.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Size of banking sector isn't the thing; the fact that the Swiss is a tax haven means a lot of countries' rich people go to Switzerland to evade their countries' taxes and store it in Switzerland instead.  
It's easy to do as much as a scandinavian country if most of the tax comes from tax evaders.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
