<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422209561.0" user="road_laya" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a Swede and here's why I think the "Nordic Model" (a fairly recent invention) is a bad idea for me and probably for you too:

* The "safety net" is mostly given to those who already have money. Poor people don't qualify. It's much like the pyramid scheme of Social Security in USA - poor young people are forced to pay for the benefits of the old rich.
* The reason that it "works" (i.e. not everyone leaves or stop working) is mostly cultural - Swedes are raised to have pride in their profession. They would even pay to have a job even if there was less money in it than being on the dole. This is why Swedes that migrated to USA show a similar work ethic and happiness score to those who stayed in Sweden.
* The redistribution hasn't removed the class differences - in fact, social mobility is smaller than in countries with lower overall tax like USA. If the Nordic Model didn't remove class differences in Sweden, why would it remove class differences in places like USA?
* The tax doesn't go to the intended purposes, but are instead wasted. When my first child was born, we had to call every second hour to see if there was any free rooms in the hospitals. "Wait, wait", they kept telling us. The contractions started to get really close, so finally they let us go to the hospital. But the hospital in our city was full, so we had to go to the second closest city. That hospital was *also* full. So my wife did most of the birthing on a sofa in the TV room/rec room.
* The reason that there are still some old corporations left in Sweden is that the governments have traditionally pampered to a small number of industrials to keep some sort of economy going here. Basically high taxes for regular people, not so much for the richest. Just look at how they treated the Wallenberg family. This has cemented the old class structures and makes it impossible for new people to rise to the same heights as those families who got rich before the taxes on income were raised considerably. Now they gave Facebook a hundred million kr. It's crony capitalism.

I'm thinking of moving to Estonia to start a business there. I don't really like the place, but I don't see how I have any opportunity here in Sweden.

Also, take the "happiness report" with a grain of salt. The conditions are set up by people who like to describe Scandinavian national democractic socialism as an Utopia, just like you do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422262682.0" user="sgc033" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The "safety net" is mostly given to those who already have money. **Poor people don't qualify.** It's much like the pyramid scheme of Social Security in USA - poor young people are forced to pay for the benefits of the old rich.

Could you explain the bolded text? If poor people are not getting redistributed money through the tax system, then this is new news regarding the *Nordic Model*.

&amp;gt;The reason that it "works" (i.e. not everyone leaves or stop working) is mostly cultural - Swedes are raised to have pride in their profession. They would even pay to have a job even if there was less money in it than being on the dole. This is why Swedes that migrated to USA show a similar work ethic and happiness score to those who stayed in Sweden.

I think you are missing the point. Strong work ethic is not absent in the US or other places, it is just hard to sustain in a system that has evolved to make it increasingly difficult for those at the bottom to move up the ladder, so then you get generational poverty and welfare dependency, which works as a positive feedback system leading to an increasingly large divide between classes. Consider the economic advantages in the US from being able to afford to go to an Ivy league university.

&amp;gt; The redistribution hasn't removed the class differences - in fact, **social mobility is smaller than in countries with lower overall tax like USA.** If the Nordic Model didn't remove class differences in Sweden, why would it remove class differences in places like USA?

Could you provide your sources for this claim? Perhaps you are not familiar with the saying ["If you want to live the American dream, move to Denmark [or other Scandinavian countries]".](http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/cifamerica/2012/jan/17/want-to-get-ahead-move-to-denmark) Also, class differences are most likely inevitable, however, the source of class distinctions would likely change. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422306467.0" user="TNine227" delta="False">
    <text>I thought ivy league colleges covers financial need? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422352060.0" user="sgc033" delta="False">
    <text>There are a lot of bursaries and they take quotas from different social classes etc... so perhaps my point is somewhat lost. My point is, in the US money factors into your education more so than most places on the planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422701602.0" user="perpetual_motion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Take quotas from different social classes

Do you have a source for this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422369257.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Generally those with family income &amp;lt;$75k don't pay tuition. The average cost for a student to attend MIT is about a third of what it costs an average student to attend UMass.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422739051.0" user="HoMaster" delta="False">
    <text>The Ivies or any top tier school is need-based, meaning they will subsidize whatever amount you need to attend the school, based on the parents' income.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423146907.0" user="Thamanizer" delta="False">
    <text>Some other colleges might not, and if you don't qualify for an Ivy (relatively few do), that's what you'll probably get unless you want to go to a public college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422268926.0" user="Solenstaarop" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The redistribution hasn't removed the class differences - in fact, social mobility is smaller than in countries with lower overall tax like USA. If the Nordic Model didn't remove class differences in Sweden, why would it remove class differences in places like USA?

I have only seen statistics that contradics this statement and as a scandinavian who have spend a few years of my life in other countries I have to say that scandinavians don't know what real class difference and ghettos are. 

We might say we have ghettos in scandinavia, but one wouldn't call it a ghetto if he had seen or visited an american ghetto. The same when it comes to class difference. 

Tbh my worries when it comes to our system is that we have it so good that we don't quiet understand some of the problems they are struggeling with in other countries</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422268952.0" user="toresbe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's much like the pyramid scheme of Social Security in USA - poor young people are forced to pay for the benefits of the old rich.

It's not a pyramid scheme, it's an insurance system; spreading the risk. The old rich people have paid their share through taxes.

&amp;gt; They would even pay to have a job even if there was less money in it than being on the dole.

I'm not going to dispute the Swedish work ethic. Us Norwegians have had plenty of opportunities to be impressed with the recent wave of Swedish work immigrants.

But I do believe that the argument of the pay difference is somewhat bogus, because the examples raised to hilight it will usually be completely extraordinary and unrepresentative, like a single parent working the worst imaginable job and having three children, something like that.

As a whole, the pay difference between being on welfare and working a job is substantial. Not to mention that work experience is probably the most important factor for advancement in the future, so judging only on one annual income is totally disingenuous.


&amp;gt; The redistribution hasn't removed the class differences - in fact, social mobility is smaller than in countries with lower overall tax like USA. 

Whaaaaaat? Nonsense. Social mobility in the Scandinavian countries is *way* higher than in the US.

&amp;gt;If the Nordic Model didn't remove class differences in Sweden, why would it remove class differences in places like USA?

You're aware that Sweden did use to have people starving in slums and dying of poor sanitary conditions, right?

&amp;gt; The tax doesn't go to the intended purposes, but are instead wasted. *(a bad experience with a government service)*

This illusion that the grass is greener on the other side unaccompanied by the willingness to actually check if it might not be, really permeates a lot of the criticism of the Nordic model. 

Your story is bad, but what does it illustrate? That organizations are fallible? Of course they are, and they are most certainly fallible in the private sector too. But by most analyses, public health care systems are consistently superior in effectiveness and efficiency over private systems.

And unlike with the private sector, the administration of such a system is subject to democratic institutions and thus public debate. Public health is a true common good, one better supplied by collaboration than competition - and one that can only adequately be ensured in an organizational form which can pool resources to work for the common good. The private sector can never supply this.

&amp;gt; I'm thinking of moving to Estonia to start a business there. I don't really like the place, but I don't see how I have any opportunity here in Sweden.

Leaving aside your claim that it is impossible to start a company in Sweden, with which I disagree - I think you should look a little deeper at what opportunities you might already have been guaranteed because of your membership in the welfare state, such as having grown up in a society relatively free of poverty (and therefore safer surroundings and more trust), being guaranteed a good education and good health care?

I wish you wouldn't have so little regard for the sheer amount of opportunities a person must have have enjoyed before they can start considering starting a business - and how effectively the Nordic model supplies that nurture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422301473.0" user="Garrotxa" delta="False">
    <text>The old people haven't paid their share if they are taking out far more than they put in, which is the case for the US Social Security system. I don't know if it is the case in Nordic countries or not, though; I'm just pointing out paying into something doesn't necessarily mean that it is 'fair'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422309697.0" user="Schoffleine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's not a pyramid scheme, it's an insurance system; spreading the risk. The old rich people have paid their share through taxes.

The concern is that the young are paying into the system with no benefit once they reach the same age, basically being siphoned for no return. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423376189.0" user="guy_from_sweden" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for this. As it almost always is (or at least feels like it almost is) when it comes to Swedes talking about politics, they are very biased and are letting that overshadow the facts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422763488.0" user="Novamonk1" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting post, but one thing did catch my eye.
  
&amp;gt; Now they gave Facebook a hundred million kr. It's crony capitalism.
  
So would they be Kroner Cronies? Heh? Heh? .... er ... sorry, I'll head out now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423081865.0" user="VoodooWHAT" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is, many of the bigger companies have been sold to China now, like SAAB, Volvo, SKF to name a few, the one area that is still making a progress is IT. Mostly because you're more free to start up things on the Internet. 

People think that Sweden got big companies like IKEA, volvo etc in the system we have today. That is not true, Sweden were once one of the poorest countries in Europe. But when the monarchy got less power and more free market came into the picture(because of the libertarian opposition at that time, that wanted more freedom when it came to opinions and more free enterprise ) things started moving forward.(this is around ~1870's. The country had very low taxes around 10% and people were much more free in creating things and from 1870's to 1970's Sweden had one of the fastest growing economy in the world. After that the more "socialistic" side of Sweden started.

I don't think a poor country should try it out. If you're rich or on your way(China/Hongkong) then yes it can work. But I wonder for how long.

I'm really tired at the moment, so forgive me if anything seem strange in my writing or if my english seem crappy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423234925.0" user="Vartib" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm thinking of moving to Estonia to start a business there. I don't really like the place, but I don't see how I have any opportunity here in Sweden.

I'm considering doing the same and I'm interested in what you personally don't like about the country. Just seeing if there are things I haven't considered yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423583157.0" user="road_laya" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know the language and my relatives will probably stay in Sweden.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
