<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422868642.0" user="Daimai" delta="False">
    <text>The only reason Scandinavic countries are well off economically, is because of the fact that they have had several lucky moments in history allowing them to profit immensely. Simply put, their wealth is not the result of their economic policies, but because of luck.

The obvious example being Norway, they have their oil reserves, meaning they can keep injecting money into their country, no matter the economic policy. It would take an idiot to fuck it up.

Another example is Sweden, a country which was relatively poor until World War 2 happened, and Sweden was one of the few untouched countries in Europe. Combined with their steel and forestry exports, they were able to skyrocket economically. Once again, a result of sheer luck.

There are other, way more efficient economic systems which have to be used if the country doesn't have the luxury of natural resources bestowed upon them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423110563.0" user="VoodooWHAT" delta="False">
    <text>What made Sweden get it's wealth is because of of the libertarian opposition that managed to change the views of the monarch, to get sweden to become more free when it came to free enterprise around 1870. But yes it's also thanks to not being in war. It's just a part of it though. Vulcan AB match factory, IKEA, Volvo, SAAB, H&amp;amp;M, Astra Zeneca are some of the few that helped Sweden skyrocket economically.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
