<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422323882.0" user="GreenStrong" delta="False">
    <text>The Nordic nations do a fine job taking care of their citizens, but they do so in an environment of geopolitical security and open trade maintained by a very expensive military hegemony they don't have to pay for.  [All of these nations spend less than 1.5% of their GDP on defense, the United States spends between 3.8 and 4.6%.](http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/MS.MIL.XPND.GD.ZS) The US also spends huge amounts on global security that is outside the defense budget- intelligence and nuclear weapon production are multi-trillion dollar projects handled by the Dept. of Energy and various shadowy three letter agencies.

Many in the US argue that we should spend less on a globe- spanning military, but there is no question that the Nordic nations, and many others, benefit tremendously from the secure environment, especially with regards to Russia.  In the immediate aftermath of WWII, the Nordic nations would have had to spend vast amounts of money to turn their nations into fortresses to avoid being swallowed by the Soviet Union, instead they were able to invest in education and infrastructure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422397153.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>In geopolitical context that's true, the Nordic nations had the  however I don't feel 2% GDP is a very decisive factor not to take steps towards it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422468154.0" user="thelastdeskontheleft" delta="False">
    <text>Weird [this](http://www.usgovernmentspending.com/percent_gdp) site gives a much different breakdown for 2015

Spoiler : 13.5% for defense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422724726.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>As an aside, why doesn't the US demand that our allies spend more on their own defense, rather than just free-riding ours? I understand that they don't all have the capability to maintain a fleet of nuclear powered sheeps, or ICBMs and stuff, but surely they could share some of the burden, especially in Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422915755.0" user="Amitron89" delta="False">
    <text>My thoughts: it comes down to power. At the end of the day, the biggest military wins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423154345.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>I would think that the biggest justification for demanding a larger military presence of its allies would be to allow the U.S. to spend less on defense.  The problem is that the U.S. does not *want* to spend less on defense.  The military has repeatedly told Congress that it needs to be able to spend money in a more intelligent way (like not buying more tanks because we don't need more tanks) and Congress ignores them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423156611.0" user="Frandaman760" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't seem to me that there are any real economic considerations given to how much the US spends on military. According to some mainstream economists that's a good thing, but that's another issue.(Broken Window fallacy and what not)

 I guess they consider the influence and control of precious natural resources to be priceless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423168699.0" user="pushme2" delta="False">
    <text>On one hand, I do want the US to withdraw everything from everywhere except in the Atlantic and Pacific oceans, but on the other other hand, there is value in having the worlds largest and strongest military.

Having bases around the world allows quick and decisive responses to threats and keeps all the other countries from doing anything to radical that is against US interests. By having a presence everywhere, the US has a bargaining chip in anything that can or will affect it.

Also is the factor of terrorism and entities causing instability and suffering. The current one, ISIS. Is it right for the US to get involved in that? The suffering and instability of those people and countries doesn't really have anything to do with the security of the US, yet many people do not object to "getting involved". If it were not for the US's capabilities, would anyone even have the capabilities and will to stop it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423148416.0" user="Thamanizer" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think about the fact that Finland and Sweden are not parts of NATO, and that especially Finland did just fine balancing between the West and the Soviet Union?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
