<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422158374.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>Your last part is right:

None of this works on larger scales, for the same reason that all the differences you listed could be said as the differences between a large and small company, even if both are well run.

The largest Nordic country is Sweden, with a population of 9.5 million.

To put that into perspective, Sweden is about population of New Jersey, and wouldn't even be in the to 10 most populous states.

It's much more simple for small governments to work efficiently and to have highly effective legislature, because the line between voter and final decision is fairly short.

Differently, when you have a nation with a population 35x larger, it becomes much more difficult to efficiently represent the population - leading to lower satisfaction rates among the populace.

As /u/garnteller pointed out, the Nordic countries are notoriously anti immigration, and while that in itself is bad, it also means that their society can easily relate to itself, and charitable "empathy" is much easier to foster.

Differently, the US is has the highest immigrant population in the world (there are more first generation immigrants in the US than the population of all the Nordic countries combined, twice over).

So, with a nation that doesn't relate easily to itself, it becomes much more impractical to expect the same levels of camaraderie.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422168962.0" user="GarrWC" delta="False">
    <text>Is there any reason that it couldn't be applied to somewhere like Ireland?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422176179.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>Other than highly entrenched social network already in place, it probably could.

It must also be accounted for that the Nordic nations have high access to natural resources, which make it much more economically robust compared to places like Ireland.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422180431.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>/u/citation_included 's post proves that high access to natural resources is merely the case with Norway(12% of GDP). The other nordic countries' are 2% or below.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422185685.0" user="GarrWC" delta="False">
    <text>Do you happen to know what the social welfare system for unemployed people is like in Norway?

Sorry for all the questions. I just find it very interesting and always find it easier to understand when I get it from someone else than to read articles/wikipedia pages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422184151.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I was at the impression that Ireland is on its way to implement a similar system, does it not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422193867.0" user="GarrWC" delta="False">
    <text>Everything in Ireland is a little bit all over the place at the moment. To say there is a system of any description is a bit of a stretch. There's been a lot of changes over the past 5 or 6 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422172210.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Extending the same question to you as I did to /u/garnteller - is it merely a challenge of administration and integration? Or do you find it beyond the possibility of implementing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422187334.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>It's part logistics, and part homogeneous population.

You're never going to get the people of Kansas to empathize with the people of Miami </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422343650.0" user="WinterSon" delta="False">
    <text>so implement on a state level? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422398695.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>State level nordic system is definitely something to be considered; especially with the less populous states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422536604.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>It's not long term viable.

You see the same thing you're seeing in the US now.

Business and people naturally migrate away from the higher restriction areas, and the states essentially compete against each other and undercutting any kind of advantage to that system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
