<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422115575.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>One problem is that it leads to some serious [anti-immigrant sentiment](http://harvardpolitics.com/world/political-economy/immigration-and-the-nordic-welfare-state-model/).  Not that there isn't resentment of immigrants elsewhere as well, but it's something that could really break the system.

Of course, you could just not allow immigrants, but that isn't feasible for other countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422117889.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I feel that requires a high level of integration; just any newcomer should not be able receive all the benefits the rest of the country paid a lot of money and effectively worked for over the years. That would just be unfair to the rest, imo. 

There's no ideal solution to this. I believe besides some sort of native-only(ie live 5~ years in the given country to start receiving local benefits) or workfare(ie be a full-time employee to start receiving local benefits) measures could reduce it, but I don't find that flaw so glaring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422151564.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>But it gets to the basic point- what you can do in a homogeneous society is different than what you can do in a more diverse one (such as the US or the UK).

Norway is 94.4% Norwegian (and 2% non-European) ethnically. Finland is 93.4% Finn - when you roll in Finnish Swedes, you get 99% of the population.  Certainly Denmark and Sweden are more diverse (it looks like 15% or so, but I couldn't find their statistics).

Sadly, I think people are more likely to want to support those who are ethnically closer to them, which limits the applicability of the model to other countries.  It doesn't make it bad economically, but unworkable politically in most places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422157100.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>I think it just makes the transition from US to Nordic model more complex and longer, or in need of a variant, but I don't think the modelis based on xenophobia. Having been there with latin americans I don't see segration as *part* of the model.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422173495.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>No, I didn't mean to imply that it's based on xenophobia, but that for many people paying higher taxes to help take care of 'our own' is much more agreeable when those people are very similar to yourself.  In a diverse country, it becomes easy to think of other groups as "them", not us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422174717.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>In understood your point, I just disagree with it as the basis of the system.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422183619.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, then I don't think I understand your point.  That many the US don't resent paying to take care of immigrants or minorities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422197608.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>No, that the nordic system isn't possible just because of a homogenous population.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422163953.0" user="citation_included" delta="False">
    <text>There are [15 US states](http://www.indexmundi.com/facts/united-states/quick-facts/all-states/white-population-percentage#chart) which are more than 85% white. The [UK is 87% white](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethnic_groups_in_the_United_Kingdom#Ethnic_Groups_-_2011_Census_data), and [Ireland is 88%](http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/293754/Ireland/234218/Ethnic-groups-language-and-religion).

If you are talking about economic or educational homogeneous, then its a catch 22: Countries that haven't benefited from the Nordic models creation of equality can't benefit from it because they are too unequal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422179287.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just about race - most Nords are, well, Nordic.  Even if you factor out white Hispanics, there isn't the same level of similarities between American whites.

I think it's pretty hard to look at the massive backlash against Obamacare, which is the most Republican implementation of semi-Universal healthcare imaginable and think that the US is ready to move to a Nordic model.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422241610.0" user="citation_included" delta="False">
    <text>The view being argued here isn't necessarily about adoptability, it is about effectiveness. Therefore, unless the you are asserting that "most Americans aren't, well American" and that that prevents the Nordic model from being effective, I'm not sure its relevant that parts of the US are currently opposed to Obamacare.

That said, individual states have the power to independently adopt the Nordic model for government ([Massachusetts had healthcare before the rest](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massachusetts_health_care_reform)) and some very much resemble the Nordic countries in demographics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422249201.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>How can something that couldn't be adopted be effective?  Yes, if you were founding "Citation_includedstan" and had to pick a social welfare system, the Nordic Model would be a great choice.  But the implication was that other countries should switch, which isn't based on effectiveness but on politics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422275242.0" user="citation_included" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How can something that couldn't be adopted be effective?

About 40 years ago [Regan proposed mandatory health insurance](http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/10/02/1243318/-Meet-the-Grandfather-of-Obamacare-Ronald-Reagan). About 20 years ago [Clinton proposed health care reform](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinton_health_care_plan_of_1993). Neither was politically possible at the time (they didn't happen). Yet the advocates kept working toward that goal and now we have, just barely, health care reform. At any point in that span the argument of "we can't switch to it, so we shouldn't try to switch to it" could have been made.

The fact that we can't adopt it right now, or even in the near future, is not an argument against it being a good idea to work toward in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422318107.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, we should work toward it, but it's not a near-term solution</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423148495.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>The practical reasons for not adopting the examples you gave were largely political in nature.  The issue of whether the Nordic model would work in an heterogeneous culture is a systematic problem.  The question comes down to whether the Nordic model could EVER work universally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422828934.0" user="cal_student37" delta="False">
    <text>Calling Obamacare "semi-Universal healthcare" is like calling the Invasion of Iraq a "semi-diplomatic assistance action".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422357277.0" user="nenyim" delta="False">
    <text>I'm very doubtful about using skin color to check if a population is homogeneous or not. I feel much closer to black people born and raised in the same socio-economic environment as much than some people in American reality shows.

Foreign born and 1st/2nd generations would probably be a much better statistic when considering that most black people had ancestors in the US for a good long while. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423263664.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>White is not homogenous. 

Are those states 85% German-American or noregwian-American? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422165478.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Do You feel a diverse country could not apply such a measure, then?  
Admittedly, being Polish(Poland's like 98% Polish) I did not look from this angle.  
That definitely makes applying the Nordic model more challenging in a more culturally diversified country, but is it merely a challenge of integration and reconciling differences to prevent segmentation, or is it straight up impossible? What's your take on this?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422181565.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Another poster suggested Canada, which seems like a place were it could work.  But looking at countries like the US and UK, where groups like the Tea Party and UKIP vehemently oppose progressive politics (arguably based on xenophobia/racism), it's hard to imagine a path to get there .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422190858.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I always thought Canada is the american nordic equivalent. Although I did not want to call up on it due to the large swaths of terrain at its disposal.  
I suppose cultural diversity creates more - due to lack of better term - personal interest political fronts. I feel like it's still possible to implement in US once politics notice Canada has it noticably better with its pro-nordic policies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422202299.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>The US has been observing the superiority of the Canadian health care system for decades and still hasn't caught on... I think you give Americans too much credit, unfortunately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422212461.0" user="shorta92" delta="False">
    <text>Except when Canadians cross the boarder for surgery</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422223170.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>From [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_the_health_care_systems_in_Canada_and_the_United_States#Health_care_outcomes)

&amp;gt;n 2007, Gordon H. Guyatt et al. conducted a meta-analysis, or systematic review, of all studies that compared health outcomes for similar conditions in Canada and the U.S., in Open Medicine, an open-access peer-reviewed Canadian medical journal. They concluded, "Available studies suggest that health outcomes may be superior in patients cared for in Canada versus the United States, but differences are not consistent." Guyatt identified 38 studies addressing conditions including cancer, coronary artery disease, chronic medical illnesses and surgical procedures. Of 10 studies with the strongest statistical validity, 5 favoured Canada, 2 favoured the United States, and 3 were equivalent or mixed. Of 28 weaker studies, 9 favoured Canada, 3 favoured the United States, and 16 were equivalent or mixed. Overall, results for mortality favoured Canada with a 5% advantage, but the results were weak and varied. The only consistent pattern was that Canadian patients fared better in kidney failure

The US also pays more per-person, and twice the overhead rate for administration

The Canadian lifespan is 2.4 years longer than for Americans.

So, yeah, I'd trade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422239568.0" user="KerSan" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I'm Canadian and I have to tell you Americans that Canadian health care really isn't all that. It's OK if you have an immediate and easily treatable issue, and it is free, but the minute you need something complicated and/or elective, you're facing ridiculous wait times and an overworked, underpaid, and snarky staff.

It's also hard to actually find a good family doctor. In some cities, there are shortages of family doctors. You are expected to keep your appointment quick and to the point. I'm OK, but there are a lot of people who aren't. We're a lot better than America, but I'm personally jealous of the Australian system. It looks a ton better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422266349.0" user="aDAMNPATRIOT" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for being honest. Ours sucks too though </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422340429.0" user="Goatkin" delta="False">
    <text>Australia's system is basically the same as what you describe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422349564.0" user="KerSan" delta="False">
    <text>Well, thanks for tearing down my idealism. Jerk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423280225.0" user="Goatkin" delta="False">
    <text>On the other hand, we don't have snow and we have nice beaches. A big difference is that we probably have a lot more dermatologists than Canada, y'know, because of all the dermatological cancer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422211875.0" user="JohnnyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>I get a kick out of people who tell me that the USA is too diverse for this sort of thing.  

Put me on an airplane and drop me with a parachute over any populated area of the USA and I will guarantee that in a matter of minutes I can walk to a Home Depot, McDonalds, Staples, Gap, and so on.  Or, I'll walk into any grocery store and be able to find bread, milk, eggs, meat, and so on in a matter of seconds without any assistance.  

Based on the obvious success of the business model, treating the USA as a homogeneous population works well.     </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422247726.0" user="vinnl" delta="False">
    <text>Couldn't you use that argument to argue that the whole world is a homogenous population, considering the spread of McDonald's and Coca Cola? It might work for their specific business purpose, but that doesn't necessarily mean socio-economic models also apply without modifications.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422256738.0" user="JohnnyBeagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Couldn't you use that argument to argue that the whole world is a homogenous population, considering the spread of McDonald's and Coca Cola?

To a point, sure.  Maybe someday in full.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423156024.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>Under this definition, the US, Russia, France, and Japan have no diversity among them. Yet clearly this isn't the case. Cultural diversity means more than what brands you buy from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422198423.0" user="Xanthilamide" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think about Australia?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422205178.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Um, that's it's a big place where they talk funny?

Honestly, I don't know enough about their politics to comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422221076.0" user="HaemophiliacHedgehog" delta="False">
    <text>I'll sum it up for you. We had a government that created clean energy targets, kept the country from going into recession while the US and Europe saw catastrophic levels of unemployment, apologised to the native Aborigines for crimes committed against them and left the population marginally better off despite a carbon tax, through tax cuts and supplements.

We then took all that, and replaced it with a government that wanted to ban under 30s from accessing welfare for six months, made us become the only country in the world to repeal a carbon tax, created draconian Orwellian surveillance legislation that they can't even explain, aim to deregulate university fees to shift to an American style model, and don't even get me started on their torment of people coming here by boat.

And the best part? The PM is currently still preferred PM over the opposition leader. We're a country not worth saving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422231158.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you can get some Vikings to reband, invade and institute a Nordic model in Oz?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422241256.0" user="HaemophiliacHedgehog" delta="False">
    <text>They can't fuck the place any worse than it's already being fucked mate, we'd better get on this Viking idea quick sticks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422353928.0" user="Goatkin" delta="False">
    <text>This is all nonsense and cherry-picking. The Carbon Tax was unpopular, and while I don't necessarily agree with the repeal, electricity prices are coming down. 

The Orwellian surveillance state claim is absolute nonsense.

The "American style system" is not at all an accurate claim nor the intention of the government. While the education minister said something that could be misinterpreted to that effect, it is just not the case if you look at the details of the proposed reforms. 

I could go on and on about why your post is nonsense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422459060.0" user="zoidberg1339" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; apologised to the native Aborigines 

You, uh, want a medal for that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422808713.0" user="Gulvplanke" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Norway is 94.4% Norwegian

Source? Wikipedia claims it's 86,2% which sounds far more likely to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423199996.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>[The CIA World Factbook](https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/geos/no.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423504941.0" user="Gulvplanke" delta="False">
    <text>[The official Norwegian bureau of statistics disagree](http://www.ssb.no/befolkning/artikler-og-publikasjoner/oversikt-over-personer-med-ulik-grad-av-innvandringsbakgrunn)

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27425692766.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Careful - the CIA might try to fix the situation so as not to be wrong (again).  

My bad - thanks for the clarification.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422231171.0" user="lotu" delta="False">
    <text>Why should newcomers not be able to receive full benefits?  From a moral standpoint many immigrants are in far worse shape then the people who have been living in the country for generations.  It's not like the poor have been paying into the system and the immigrants haven't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422290110.0" user="brberg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;just any newcomer should not be able receive all the benefits the rest of the country paid a lot of money and effectively worked for over the years.

What about natives who haven't worked and paid benefits in? If you want to exclude foreigners because they haven't paid in, why have a welfare system at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422450574.0" user="thelastdeskontheleft" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you mean. That's the problem though. 

The US has to deal with this a LOT because of all the immigrants. No one wants to figure out a better situation for immigration reform but we have people (especially in the south from mexico) that are extremely poor coming in and using up a lot of the healthcare (huge burdens on hospitals in the south when 25% of your patients are broke and don't have insurance) and burden the school systems with free lunches and burden just about everything with a huge influx of poor people (most of which are illegal and not paying taxes). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423646516.0" user="brberg" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I was arguing in the opposite direction: If you oppose giving welfare benefits to people who haven't paid in, you might as well abolish the welfare state entirely and replace it with forced savings plus compulsory disability insurance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27426646760.0" user="thelastdeskontheleft" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone taking from the wellfare pool hasn't paid in. That's literally how they work. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422290694.0" user="Edhorn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's no ideal solution to this. I believe besides some sort of native-only(ie live 5~ years in the given country to start receiving local benefits) or workfare(ie be a full-time employee to start receiving local benefits) measures could reduce it, but I don't find that flaw so glaring.

No, this is a terrible idea, in a country there should be only citizens and non-citizens, any sort of rules that demotes a group of people to second-class citizens encourages xenophobic sentiments about what it means to be a true countryman. If you want it to take about 5 years to become a citizen in the first place fine, but please do not segregate the citizens of the same country.

&amp;gt; I feel that requires a high level of integration; just any newcomer should not be able receive all the benefits the rest of the country paid a lot of money and effectively worked for over the years. That would just be unfair to the rest, imo. 

You do not pay taxes in the Nordic model because you, yourself, will necessarily get something back. You pay taxes to help those who need the support, not supporting or kicking out a certain group of people who are living in the country is counter-productive as the purpose of the support is not only to help the receiver but also society as a whole and will keep people from resorting to crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423408683.0" user="patrickmhb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; should not be able receive all the benefits the rest of the country paid a lot of money and effectively worked for over the years. That would just be unfair to the rest, imo.
    
If there are to be exceptions for people who, in your opinion, have not worked and paid for the benefits of this model, surely this applies equally to the long-term unemployed and the disabled? This strikes me as a contradiction in your argument.
    
In your original post you point to factors such as natural resources and social cohesion being conducive to a high standard of living. If this is indeed the case, surely credit cannot be given to the "Nordic model", but to environmental factors? Otherwise, countries with similar models but fewer resources and less social cohesion (such as the UK) would be equally well-off. This is not the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422163380.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How about Canada?

The only thing they seem to fuck up afaik is the balance between intervening and abstaining from native / rural politics as well as treatment of natives / rural people. But I think Swedes make fun of the Saami, so maybe it's not too different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422175068.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, Canadians pretty much rock, and I suspect it would work there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423471138.0" user="randomguy506" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly I think Canada system is a better system than in Scandinavia, but that's just my opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422947203.0" user="fuzzycuff" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is that racial diversity is ingrained within Canadian culture. Especially with the urban areas, there is large number of different ethnic groups and most just end up accepting that people are different. However, I do not believe that the same could be said about other countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422220417.0" user="Crushinated" delta="False">
    <text>So you think that social systems should be degraded and stripped down to make immigrants more comfortable?  Maybe the immigrants wouldn't come in the first place if there were no benefits to mooch off of...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422229072.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>You know, you're right.  Immigrants have never contributed a thing to America.  All of the benefits should be for Native Americans alone, lets kick out all of the land stealing moochers!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422231658.0" user="Crushinated" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that Europeans to America were conquerors, not really immigrants in the traditional sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422240049.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>So when do you start the clock for when immigrants stopped being "good"?  1787?  1880?  1930?  2013?  What makes them different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422252815.0" user="Crushinated" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say immigrants are basically fine, but asylum seekers are the real problem.  At least here in Norway, they typically do not integrate and are content to exploit the social welfare system, and it throws everything out of balance.  Immigrants America or anywhere else typically work hard and don't put the same kind of strain on the system or cause the same sociological problems.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422259835.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I don't know enough about the Norwegian immigrant situation to comment, sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422251949.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>Explain to me why is this a bad thing. Not the sentiment or the slippery slope to discrimination, but the fact that you put your own citizens before non-citizens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422258606.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>It depends.  Nordic countries aren't dependent on immigration, and so if they want to restrict immigration, it might make sense.

In a country like the US, which is a country of immigrants, it is not in their best interest.  Immigrants (and their children) have contributed immeasurably to the economy and culture.  Besides the irony of people whose family are one or two generations off the boat railing against immigrants, it's self destructive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422262699.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>What if you pose strict immigration but be welcoming to those that succeed, like the Swiss do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422317930.0" user="TNine227" delta="False">
    <text>We have a 3000 mile long border with a third world county. The strength of immigration laws won't stop immigrants. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422364135.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't mean Swiss is lack of refugees or illegal immigrants. It won't stop people from getting paid under the table either. But as a policy alone I don't see anything wrong with the idea of protect your own before getting involved to other things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422589121.0" user="Vox_Imperatoris" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the fact that you put your own citizens before non-citizens.

Well, if your justification for the welfare state is to care for the poor, it seems pretty damned unjust to leave the vast majority of the world's population to live in much poorer conditions—not because you wouldn't give them a handout—but because you won't let them move to a country where people are willing to rent them an apartment and employ them.

And it's not just the foreigners who are harmed, but also the native citizens. What if I'm Danish, but I want to invite my Russian friend to live in my house? I'm not allowed. What if I want to employ a worker from China? I can't (at least in the vast majority of cases). Don't you think that, if Danish employers were allowed, they would prefer to hire Chinese (or Russian, etc.) workers at half the wage of Danish workers—which would still be far more than they make in their home countries?

But, of course, the Nordic system doesn't work if you let in a really large number of immigrants or—heaven forbid—have open borders. It depends on homogeneity and everyone living there already being rich by world standards. It's perversely saying to those in the world who are genuinely poor: sorry, but since we can't afford to give you boatloads of welfare that would improve your living standards to 10 times their current status, we won't let you come here without welfare and improve your living standards to 2 or 3 times their current status (and those numbers are conservative).

It's essentially a huge gated community where everyone inside is taken care of—but fuck you if you were born in Haiti or something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422640536.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well, if your justification for the welfare state is to care for the poor, it seems pretty damned unjust to leave the vast majority of the world's population to live in much poorer conditions—not because you wouldn't give them a handout—but because you won't let them move to a country where people are willing to rent them an apartment and employ them.

If we can bring the world up to par to say, Scandinavian countries, then great. However currently it is not possible. As a country, since you only have sovereignty on your own soil, you only have obligation to your own citizens, then why should you use your own resources, your own citizen's resources for that matter to perform interventions in other countries when your own country not without problems?

I guess *citizen* was a bad word use from me. What I had in mind is the people that currently residing in your country. That would include immigrants.

I personally is very much in favor of protectionist policies that favors your own country's businesses over others, and I think free-trade agreements between multinationals are not a good thing and needs to be tightly controlled to your own people's benefit. But that is just my opinion anyways.

You know what, there will always be "shithole" of countries that are used for their natural resources, cheap labor etc.. This is hard to avoid. Regardless, a country's priority should be making sure that your country is not that shithole, not so that no country is a shithole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422720051.0" user="Vox_Imperatoris" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If we can bring the world up to par to say, Scandinavian countries, then great. However currently it is not possible. As a country, since you only have sovereignty on your own soil, you only have obligation to your own citizens, then why should you use your own resources, your own citizen's resources for that matter to perform interventions in other countries when your own country not without problems?

I'm not saying they should. I don't think they need to spend a dime in foreign aid. It would be much more helpful simply to open up one's own country to foreign trade and immigration.

&amp;gt; I guess citizen was a bad word use from me. What I had in mind is the people that currently residing in your country. That would include immigrants.

The problem is that the number of immigrants is highly limited, and necessarily must be so for the Nordic welfare state to function.

&amp;gt; I personally is very much in favor of protectionist policies that favors your own country's businesses over others, and I think free-trade agreements between multinationals are not a good thing and needs to be tightly controlled to your own people's benefit. But that is just my opinion anyways.

Protectionism never benefits any country, on balance. It benefits certain special interests, sure. But only by causing a greater harm to the consumers who buy products from those industries. Protectionism is, as one economist said, the attempt to do to one's own country in peacetime what enemies seek to do to it in wartime: to cut it off from the benefits of imported goods.

This applies even if one country is subsidizing its exports. Unilateral free trade on the part of the non-subsidizing country means that country A (which subsidizes) is taking money from its own taxpayers and giving it to the consumers in country B (which does not subsidize).

&amp;gt; You know what, there will always be "shithole" of countries that are used for their natural resources, cheap labor etc.. This is hard to avoid. Regardless, a country's priority should be making sure that your country is not that shithole, not so that no country is a shithole.

It is not written anywhere that there will "always" be such countries. Global poverty has been [massively reduced](http://www.stephenhicks.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/world-poverty-reduction.jpg) in the last few decades, almost entirely due to liberalization in countries such as China and India. (However, most people remain [unaware](http://www.stephenhicks.org/2014/01/14/poverty-reduction-and-public-awareness/) of this fact.)

But yes, some countries remain mired in poverty. This is principally due to low productivity of labor, caused by lack of capital. Why is there less capital investment in Zimbabwe than in South Korea? It is chiefly due to bad government policies: the economy of Zimbabwe is far less free, and there is no guarantee of the rule of law.

As a result of the low productivity of labor, workers' talents are largely wasted in Zimbabwe (or Haiti, etc.). Not just the Einsteins of the world are left to rot but also the Joe Blows of average ability. Zimbabwe's dysfunctional economy makes their work virtually useless. To solve this and allow these people to realize their potential to benefit the world economy, there is no need to invade Zimbabwe and try to "build democracy" there (or colonize it, if you want the old-school way).

All that is needed is for the developed countries to *let more of those people in*. Even with no form of handouts at all they would be *vastly* better off simply in a *free* (-er) country.

Again, it's not a case of whether you are obligated to give a starving man in Africa a piece of bread. You're not: let him starve, it's not your problem to fix everyone else's issues. But if the starving man wants to move to a place where someone is willing to give him food and money in return for honest work, you *are* obligated not to have men with guns tell him he's not allowed and had better starve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422731380.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The problem is that the number of immigrants is highly limited, and necessarily must be so for the Nordic welfare state to function.

It means the country reached a nice equilibrium, I see no problem with this.


&amp;gt;Protectionism

I argue against this, it shields your own businesses from problems of circumstance, allowing them to compete fairly. Again, I'm not advocating hard protectionism like the past, but enough so that it incentives employment in your own country, as opposed to being say, outsourced.

I merely argue that there is a lot of differences between hard, hard protectionism vs. complete and absolute free-trade. I argue for something in the middle. But the key ideas is that in any case, your own people benefit. It is a selfish view and I was never a believer of utopia.

&amp;gt;It is not written anywhere that there will "always" be such countries.

True, this is just what I think, what I have concluded. There will always be jobs that nobody willing to do but needs to be done. This applies on a larger scale as well. Not everyone can find that niche service sector market or high-tech exports. Somebody has to trade their own natural resources for money which is at the expense of their natural resource reserve as well as the environment. Japan went through this, China going through this. India is going through this. Africa is at the start of this.





</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422763569.0" user="Vox_Imperatoris" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it incentives employment in your own country, as opposed to being say, outsourced.

But outsourcing is *good* for countries that practice it! It means that, instead of paying someone $10 an hour to make a product, they can make it in India for less and import it. As a result, they get the same product for less. And then the people who were employed in making that product in the developed country can do some other job that the Indians are not able to do.

Of course, outsourcing is not the *most* efficient or beneficial thing that could happen. Far more efficient would be to import the Indians instead of exporting the factory. But because of the immigration restrictions which I have repeatedly mentioned, this is exactly what they can't do.

&amp;gt; There will always be jobs that nobody willing to do but needs to be done.

Perhaps nobody is willing to do them for the same amount of money as a glamorous job, but they are willing to do them for *some* amount of money. That's why you get paid more to work on an oil rig in the middle of the ocean than in a cushy job (holding the quantity of people *able* to do both jobs equal).

&amp;gt; Somebody has to trade their own natural resources for money which is at the expense of their natural resource reserve as well as the environment.

The reason these extractive economies don't develop beyond that level is that their governments' policies are too dysfunction to allow economic progress and investment beyond the most basic level. Resource extraction is certainly not a *necessary* stage in development, just the lowest-hanging fruit. Take Hong Kong, for example. What resources do they have? None. Yet simply because they had a free economy and lots of immigration, they were able to prosper.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422792091.0" user="vegetablestew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But outsourcing is good for countries that practice it!

Which unless is your country, you don't want it. If it benefit your people, sure. Do it. Again, you are arguing about details, but I am more interested in the idea of "your people benefit before others"


&amp;gt;Perhaps nobody is willing to do them for the same amount of money as a glamorous job, but they are willing to do them for some amount of money. 

Is a race to the bottom, a race for the lowest bid. Wellbeing is not guaranteed even when there is a job. You need job as well as an adequate benefit.
Hong Kong is an interesting example, but this is because of its unique geographic location. Not every country can be like this. Also, recent years Hong Kong has been less important than it used to be and the government is scrambling to find ways to reignite that economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422275935.0" user="Edhorn" delta="False">
    <text>This post is about the economic model which I personally fail to see how it leads to anti-immigrant sentiment. The OP did not say that the model requires a homogeneous population, which a lot of people believe, and I personally agree that it isn't a requirement and should stay out of the discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422320932.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Because, as some of the people who have responded to me, having a high level of services for those in trouble means you are paying for (in there term) "moochers".  Immigrants obviously fall into that category.  

I'm not arguing about the economic model (which I agree with), I'm arguing about the applicability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422304264.0" user="sgc033" delta="False">
    <text>The *Nordic Model* doesn't inherently lead to anti-immigrant sentiment, it just happens to currently exist in those countries. Presumably, one the main drivers of that sentiment is immigrants' disproportional use of state resources upon arrival. This could be mitigated in many ways. Fast-tracking foreign credential assessments, allocating resources to programs that help immigrants train and successfully transition, to name a few. Also, part of the sentiment is likely motivated by fears of the unknown ("them") and preferences for their own kind ("us"). This also can be mitigated over time through exposure and education. In Canada, we are by no means a multicultural utopia, but our experience with a diverse population   has definitely reduced anti-immigrant sentiment. Another reason for anti-immigrant sentiment could be a perceived lack of contribution by immigrants and those utilizing state resources. This is prevalent virtually everywhere and is usually justified by beliefs that the poor and immigrants are lazy and have poor work ethic. Again, this is not inherent to the model. Beliefs can change and policies can be designed to improve the transition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422322876.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>I've actually responded about this, and particularly Canada, in a number of other posts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
