<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422240092.0" user="mstrdsastr" delta="False">
    <text>Two points:
 
* Norway and Sweden have huge energy deposits that basically float their economies and social government without overburdening their population.
* Their population is a fraction of the USA, which helps control cost.

In the US, our population is huge, which would make having social programs like they have next to impossible to fund (we can't even fund what we currently have) and still provide basic services like roads and schools without taxing the public at unsustainable levels.  Also, we have a huge immigrant influx which makes these social programs that much more difficult to manage.  

Lastly, while we have great resource deposits, they are expensive to access and extract mainly due to logistical and geographic problems (the US is huge, and most of the resources are in remote areas), and again the income generated from them pales in comparison to our budgeted expenditure needs.  

Really, when you come down to it, the vast size of the US makes a social democracy like the Scandinavians practice next to impossible to implement.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422405926.0" user="nenyim" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Norway and Sweden have huge energy deposits that basically float their economies and social government without overburdening their population.

[Source](http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.TOTL.RT.ZS?order=wbapi_data_value_2012+wbapi_data_value+wbapi_data_value-last&amp;amp;sort=desc). Nautral resources represented 1.1% of the GDP for Sweden in 2012 compared to 1.3% for the US and a whopping 0.2% for France (which I will use an example later).

&amp;gt; Their population is a fraction of the USA, which helps control cost.

Yes sure but it also control the income. What matter isn't the cost but the cost per capita and this tend to goes down when you scale up things (otherwise Walmart wouldn't exist).

&amp;gt; In the US, our population is huge

True. but states populations aren't that big. France has a similar system in place and has around a fifth of the US population which is around twice the population of California. People keep saying it's impossible to scale up without exactly saying why past it's impossible so even assuming they are right we still have perfectly functioning models that would allow to do it on a state level.

&amp;gt; Also, we have a huge immigrant influx which makes these social programs that much more difficult to manage. 

Again per capita is probably what matter the most. So let's compare Immigrant as a percentage of population [source](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_foreign-born_population) Sweden:15.9%, US:14.3%, France being a little lower at 11.6%. So this argument doesn't really hold either.

&amp;gt; Lastly, while we have great resource deposits, they are expensive to access and extract mainly due to logistical and geographic problems (the US is huge, and most of the resources are in remote areas), and again the income generated from them pales in comparison to our budgeted expenditure needs. 

As shown earlier it's simply not true. The US is making more money from natural resources than either Sweden or France, even more so as it's a percentage of GDP and the US GDP is higher per capita.

&amp;gt; and still provide basic services like roads and schools without taxing the public at unsustainable levels

This is the only argument I can agree with. The US tax burden is around 27% compare to 40 up to nearly 50% of the GDP for countries with system describe by OP. I believe it's more than worth the cost but the cost is definitely high and I see why people would think it's simply not worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
