<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422192129.0" user="HilariousEconomist" delta="False">
    <text>I think most people would agree with you that the Nordic countries have been successful, but why do you limit your prospects to only these small countries? Many other countries in Europe have similar levels of health, education, and measure close to Scandinavia in terms of both their quality of life and economic health such as Switzerland. New Zealand, Canada, Australia are all neck and neck with Scandinavia in terms of healthcare, education, economy (NZ being probably the best country to live in the world according to SPI). Why can't the Anglosphere be a perfect example of society as well?

Second I'd challenge your beliefs on feasibility. Not only must a country or autonomous region be small enough for local government to be smart and deliberate with their planning (which I fully support) they must also have the proper culture of anti-corruption, public spirit, and pragmatism. This kind of culture is conducive to an efficient and trusted state but doesn't happen everywhere (for example Chinese local government are very corrupt, inefficient with their money, and downright irresponsible, but Swiss local governments are the exact opposite). These countries also have the history of democracy, moderation, and pragmatism that many others do not (or at least not yet such as African, Asian, an d Latin American countries). Institutions, culture, and history matter a lot, so while the Nordics may give us good policy ideas, their countries are too different to export everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422411946.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Well, Nordic model is an ideology other countries more or less share. Naturally there will be differences even in the nordic countries, but it all comes down to "free market economy with a social safety net" with stress on a few factors. Other countries had similar success with similar policies(Canada, New Zealand among them), Nordic countries are just the best example of the sort due to the ideal environment to develop such a system.  

It's true that we cannot just copy-paste all the policies, however if no challenges exist, it could be implemented as an example - again, it's a general direction a country could take, not a definite solution.  
Just thought I'd clarify.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
