<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422862418.0" user="JoeDonJackson" delta="False">
    <text>It is not a fair comparison to any other country... Norway lucked out in finding HUGE amounts of oil reserves compared to the size of their population.

They can afford a lot more infrastructure (social safety net) per person than any other country in the world.

But yeah, a modern developed democracy + practically free oil, makes for a pretty good country </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423157234.0" user="Thamanizer" delta="False">
    <text>But what about Sweden and Denmark? They have even more developed systems, while Norway has been able to afford some inefficiencies thanks to the oil income. As an anecdote, Sweden even has a far better road network than Norway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423167199.0" user="JoeDonJackson" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what you mean by "more developed systems"  -- Their systems are much more bulky -- Denmark has much more problems with balancing taxation  -- Sweden is doing well because it has a good start-up culture and industry (such as Bofors, worlds forth biggest weapons manufacturer)... but Norway is especially lucky with their oil.

I think Sweden is closer to Norway in prosperity.  Denmark is lagging behind. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
