<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422182678.0" user="DickWitman" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's an ok idea if you're Sweden or Norway and your population is 5 million or below. The basic rule with the Nordic model is: don't try this at home. Those countries are small, homogenous, and largely agree politically. The same can't be said of the United States for instance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422230519.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention that from what I've gathered, most of the Nordic countries have a togetherness mentality. There is less abuse of government systems because with such a small population you feel like you're a part of something. Most people can relate to one another.

In countries with hundreds of millions of people, a lot more people have the "take what you can get" way of thinking. A person from New York City doesn't have much in common with a cattle rancher from Texas. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422326056.0" user="toresbe" delta="False">
    <text>Trust me, the US has every country in the world beat in terms of having a strong common national identity.

Yes, there is a greater amount of interpersonal trust, but - here's the thing - that trust more than anything *comes from* the income equality and the social safety which the welfare systems are a major aspect of protecting.

Economic equality means that you can relate to more peoples' lives. Nevermind a cattle rancher from Texas - a Wall Street investment banker has nothing in common with a bartender in the same city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422348662.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Uh...have you ever even been to the United States?

The US is probably the most culturally diverse nation in the world. It's not because we're special or anything, it's because we're the 4th biggest country by size, and 2 of those above us don't really apply because a majority of the land is uninhabited. Not to mention we took immigrants from every corner of the earth. The income equality in the US isn't super horrible on a grand scale. Yes, there is a disparity and it does cause tension, I'm not arguing that. But the US is more diverse than any country I can think of. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422379318.0" user="PolarisDiB" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The US is probably the most culturally diverse nation in the world.

[Queens county, New York, is the most culturally diverse urban area in the world.](http://www.newyork.com/articles/neighborhoods/queens-72876/) Residents in Queens represent people from over 100 countries speaking over 130 languages. 

Queens isn't necessarily 'New York', much less the rest of the United States, but what's also worth pointing out is that many* Americans don't really notice the difference, except where they've come from a mostly homogenous small or rural area. For anyone else that's grown up in a US city, Queens is pretty much par on course of their expectations for what being around other people is like, except with a larger and denser population.

So far in my various travels to other cities, the only non-American city I saw that had a familiar amount of diversity was London. Other places like Tokyo, Dubai, and even Paris, were a lot more homogenous , except that it's worth pointing out that European cities it's a lot more common to hear multiple languages because all those countries are so close together, whereas in New York people default to English in many cases even when they're from a non-English speaking country. 

* Qualification: I'm willing to say many, I'm much less certain about 'most'. There are huge swaths of the United States geography that are smaller, more homogenous communities. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422391215.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Eh, you're not wrong but that's not what I was going for. 

Take South Korea for example - the entire country is pretty much the same thing, from Seoul to Busan you can find sticky rice and kimchi at every restaurant. 

Now put a New Yorker and a Chicago resident in a room and ask them what real pizza is. I've lived all over the US, and places are *very* different. Bring up hockey in Minnesota and you fit right in. Bring it up in Georgia and get blank stares. And the opposite with NASCAR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422614517.0" user="toresbe" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think Koreans disagree about the proper way to make kimchi? There are tons of variants.

Yes, there are cultural differences. But my point is, you don't need cultural similarity, you just need to feel attached to the nation - I think Americans are that more than any other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423214611.0" user="snipawolf" delta="False">
    <text>You'd find that level in Toronto, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422326537.0" user="AirMoons" delta="False">
    <text>Does this mean that this is a cultural issue rather than a population size one ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422337878.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Er...sort of.

A population size of a few million can still easily have the same culture throughout. A population of 320M isn't going to have to. It's a difference in cultures that matters, but it's the population size that fuels the culture differences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422576284.0" user="Maslo59" delta="False">
    <text>Its a diversity issue. Less diversity = more societal cohesion.

Nordic model is incompatible with multiculturalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422331200.0" user="Brosama220" delta="False">
    <text>The homogeneous population plays a huge role. Everyone in Denmark, or other Scandinavia countries for that matter, have pretty similar lives. Of course there is a difference between a  fisherman and a CEO. But compared to other countries, it is negligible. The two still watch the same news, have a similar religious background,  and usually value the same things. It's also fun to note that everyone usually has some relation to everyone else. Yesterday I met a girl from the other end of the country, living in a city of less than 5 thousand. We had two mutual friends, both of them rather close to both of us. And this is a very common experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422418167.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that there is any quantifiable empirical evidence that culture makes this system any less viable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422430131.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>There's not quantifiable empirical evidence that anarchy doesn't work, but a little common sense goes a long way. 

People inn the United States take from the government whatever they can get because they don't see it as taking from their neighbors. People in smaller, more homogenous countries have generally had a more empathy on both sides - those who have don't mind helping those who are in need because they have so much in common, and those who are in need don't take excessively because of the same reasons.

A puerto rican immigrant living in Miami probably doesn't have that much in common with me. We have a different setting, and his views probably don't match very many of mine. If I were to apply for social programs, I would be less likely to see myself taking from him, but rather see myself taking from the faceless government that has unlimited money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422435311.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>You have no quantifiable statistical evidence to support this claim. You're just basing this off of hasty generalizations and speculation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422442058.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, whatever makes you feel right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422514313.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, but you actually need evidence for a claim to be considered valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423487901.0" user="sachalamp" delta="False">
    <text>In situations where evidence is difficult to produce, reason is the next best thing you get. 

Should you choose to ignore/discredit it, that's your prerogative i guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423761223.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;“That which can be asserted without evidence, can be dismissed without evidence.” 

– Christopher Hitchens.

His "reasoning" is little more than generalizations and speculation, with no facts or statistical evidence to back it up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423983918.0" user="sachalamp" delta="False">
    <text>For many topics the theory came first, then the results followed to confirm/infirm. If you can't/don't want to think abstract, feel free not to.

I guess he/she was right after all, whatever makes you feel right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423992635.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>Its pretty much what makes him feel right. There's no evidence to support a claim, thus he made a claim that "feels right" to him. Again, if he makes a claim, then he is obligated to have evidence to defend that claim for it to be even considered. The burden of proof is on him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424004583.0" user="sachalamp" delta="False">
    <text>He proposed and ideea. You can agree or disagree on the same terms.

If he would've presented it as an irefutable fact, your comment would've made sense. He/she **literally** began his/her post with

"There's not quantifiable empirical evidence that anarchy doesn't work, but a little common sense goes a long way."

And after that, you come in and call for "burden of proof" lynching. I mean, dude, it really makes no sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424014833.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>No, he made hasty generalizations about entire countries and cultures that may or may not be true, and then tried to pass that off as "common sense" (which is pretty much presenting it as irrefutable fact). His claim was that the Nordic model would not work in the US because of our culture, and I asked him to provide solid factual evidence, links to research done on this, statistics etc. He had none, and therefore I dismissed his claim as anecdotal and invalid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424019944.0" user="sachalamp" delta="False">
    <text>My advice is to take a step back now and read again the whole parent some other day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424116500.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>I did, and it was basically him claiming something baseless as "common sense," and then refusing to provide evidence for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422306402.0" user="Edhorn" delta="False">
    <text>People keep saying this, yet I personally have never seen any real proof of it other than 'this sounds good'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422313072.0" user="toresbe" delta="False">
    <text>Homogenous? Before the Labour Party gained real power in Parliament, faith in our national democracy among workers was so dim that although the bourgeoisie marched on the 17th of May - constitution day - flying Norwegian flags - the working people would march on May 1st, saying "strike the Christian cross off the flag and raise it pure and red".

There were bloody confrontations between workers on strike and police forces, resulting in deaths. 

Yes, we were ethnically homogeneous, but society was not homogeneous in any political sense. 

Yes, we are small, but I don't see the relevance. Every time I say I don't, someone will fault me for not seeing the obvious relevance which they stubbornly refuse to explain to me, but I don't see why this wouldn't scale. 

Agree politically? No, we don't. We have a far greater selection of political parties in Europe than an American ever will, and a far wider selection. Norway has climate denialists in government right now. You can vote Communist or Libertarian, and you don't need more than a few thousand votes to actually get a seat in the national parliament.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422325062.0" user="AirMoons" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you should elaborate on why this is only applicable to small countries, I am not convinced at all that this is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422421426.0" user="TEmpTom" delta="False">
    <text>Many states in they US have comparable populations compared to Scandinavian countries. The system can be adopted at a state level, while slowly integrated at a federal level later on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423381149.0" user="guy_from_sweden" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, but *5 million and below*? Sweden is closing up at 10 million people. And I can't say the we largely agree politically either. You might be onto something here, but these armchair assumptions that aren't even true in some cases makes me want to distrust you instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423617032.0" user="MrStrange15" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sweden or Norway and your population is 5 million or below.

Sweden is closer to 10 million, but Norway, Denmark and Finland have a population from 5-6 million. But I agree with the rest of your points.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
