<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422638111.0" user="UrbanZenMonk" delta="False">
    <text>Can Denmark do what they do in Canada, on our land mass and population? 5.6 million people compared to 30+ million people stretched over, well, I'm not sure outside Canada is much more larger than Denmark. Much larger.

In fact, it would stretch and take up multiple countries in the European Union. This is important for things like road construction (infinitely more cost in Canada), railway construction (a lot more land to cover = more costs), etc. etc. etc.

So, can that model work in Canada? 

Take Alberta. Alberta has a ton of oil and delivers transfer payments to every other province to the tune of billions.

Does Denmark or anyone have to pay massive hand outs to other countries surrounding them?

What of Norway, for example. Do they give any of the oil revenue to neighboring countries and if they did, could they do what they do while forfeiting billions upon billions, like Alberta does for the rest of Canada? 

I'm sure, taking just Alberta, that the model would work but the resources and immigration just allow those models to work in Europe.

In essence, is that not selfish to the rest of the planet? They have theirs and have shut the door to their country.

Canada has ours but we haven't shut the door to other immigrants. We are open. So is the U.S. 

I often find that the only fair comparison to these little countries and their models is to expand what they do to all of the European union which would now be closer to the geography and size of the U.S. while considering different states have different economies.

Now, is Denmark and all them sitting so well with Greece requiring assistance? This is like Quebec, in Canada, needing hand outs from Alberta's oil. 

I find the geographical size, immigration, resources, etc. of countries are ignored in these. 

EDIT: changed a word "not" to now</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
