<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154930043.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k8osb/cmv_i_believe_that_cannabis_is_an_objectively/">
    <title>CMV: I believe that cannabis is an objectively better substance for recreational use than alcohol</title>
    <original_poster>ProjectGO</original_poster>
    <original_post>*(Note: I will be using the term cannabis instead of marijuana, weed, or pot, since that is the proper name for the plant and does not carry slang or propaganda connotations like the other common terms do. Also, for the purposes of the CMV cannabis consumption refers to the inhalation of smoke from burning cannabis buds, as opposed to more exotic methods of consumption.)*

As an adult of legal age in Washington state, I am allowed to purchase cannabis from a government-licensed store and consume it in my own house. For the purpose of this CMV, let's assume others have similar rights such that legality is not a concern.

The known effect (and implicit goal) of drinking alcohol or smoking cannabis is to temporarily alter the brain's chemistry to produce enjoyable sensations. By almost every metric I can think of, cannabis is a superior substance to use to achieve this goal.

* **Safety:** Alcohol poisoning, alcohol related organ failures, and intoxicated accidents kill hundreds of thousands of people a year. Very drunk people are known to become violent, emotional, and dangerous to themselves and others. Cannabis's effects are caused by THC, which is very nontoxic to ingest. The amount of THC required to overdose and die from cannabis use is literally impossible to consume quickly enough to maintain a fatal saturation. Studies have shown that [cannabis use does not lead to more driving accidents](http://norml.org/library/item/marijuana-and-driving-a-review-of-the-scientific-evidence) and the most common effect of driving high in simulator tests is reduced speed. (Still, don't drive impaired, regardless of what you're using). I can only speak from anecdotal evidence, but I have never seen cannabis cause an aggressive or violent reaction in the user.

* **Controlled intoxication:** Consuming alcohol with a specific level of intoxication in mind (other than blackout drunk) is a challenging task. Variations in drink strength and methods of consumption can make it harder to judge one's level of intoxication, and the timing and order of consumption plays a significant role in how the alcohol affects the body and how enjoyable the experience is. The duration of alcohol intoxication is usually many hours, which generally means that by consuming alcohol the drinker has implicitly accepted that they will not be safely able to do certain tasks or make certain decisions for the remainder of the day/night. Cannabis, especially state regulated cannabis, comes with detailed information regarding THC content and the heredity of the specific plant being consumed. This allows the user to tailor their cannabis experience to achieve or avoid specific effects, and with some planning (although no more than counting your drinks) accurately control the length and intensity of their cannabis intoxication. The duration of intoxication from smoking cannabis is typically shorter than that of consuming alcohol, and leaves the user capable of functioning normally with few ill effect after use.

* **Effects:** Alcohol generally lowers the inhibitions, impairs the judgement, and increases the volume of the person consuming it. Heavy consumption can lead to loss of motor control, disorientation, blackouts, and alcohol poisoning. The effects of cannabis depend largely on the genetics of the plant in question, and can be carefully tailored by growers to induce a specific intoxicating effect. Plants from the species *Cannabis Indica* tend to cause feelings of calm, drowsiness, and relaxation. Plants from the species *Cannabis Sativa* tend to cause uplifting, energetic, or cerebral effects. Excessive consumption of cannabis may lead to dizziness, paranoia, or 'couch-lock', but there are no chemically harmful effects (such as alcohol poisoning).

* **Aftermath:** Hangovers suck. Waking up and feeling like you just want to trow up and die is no fun at all. Cannabis has negligible aftereffects, and (anecdotally again) cannabis use after heavy alcohol consumption significantly reduces the pain of the next morning's hangover. Alcohol and alcohol byproducts remain in the body for 1-2 days at most after intoxicating effects have ceased. Cannabis byproducts remain in the bloodstream and urine for 2-6 weeks depending on frequency of use and body type, and can be detected in hair samples far beyond that.

* **Price:** In Washington, lower-end state-regulated liquor sells for around $35 per 1.75 liters. This converts to about $1 per shot, which is on par with roughly $1 a beer when buying from a grocery store. Assuming consumption of 6 drinks in a night, the at-home cost is $6. At a bar, event, or stadium, drink prices are significantly more expensive, and 6 drinks (including tips) can quickly surpass $50. At current prices (which are expected to fall as supply and demand balance out) you can purchase 2 grams of high-potency cannabis from a regulated store for $60. Calculating an equivalent scale of grams of cannabis per drink is a difficult task, but by my math (2g can make 4 0.5g bowls which can each get 3 people to the equivalent intoxication of 5 drinks) it still comes out to roughly $1 per drink equivalent. Bulk cannabis from a medical co-op is much less expensive ($250 per oz = 28g), and lowers the price to $0.30 per drink equivalent.

* **Social acceptance:** Alcohol wins this one hands down. In adulthood, someone who doesn't consume alcohol occasionally is considered the exception rather than the norm. Cannabis is still widely seen in the connotations of "dope for hippies and stoners", and cannabis use is not considered a suitable topic for discussion the way alcohol use is. Much of modern nightlife is centered around going out and consuming alcohol socially, and there is no equivalent cannabis culture yet. For younger audiences there are a wide range of drinking games played socially with alcohol, but few (if any) social games revolving around cannabis consumption.

In short, I believe that cannabis is objectively superior to alcohol in terms of achieving a state of recreational intoxication. By the metrics I have stated, I feel that cannabis is the superior substance in all cases except social acceptance, and that is a nebulous metric that is subject to change and unrelated to the effects that either substance has on the user. 

The best way to CMV would be to point out one or more metrics I have not considered where alcohol is preferable to cannabis, or show that my logic in assessing the metrics I have used is incorrect. The goal of this CMV is not to start an argument between 'stoners' and 'teetotalers', but rather to objectively compare two intoxicating substances on their merits and drawbacks.

**TL;DR:** All things considered, I'd rather get intoxicated on cannabis than on alcohol.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27423096145.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What about the "lingering after-effects." I suspect that if you smoke marijuana daily, it can slow you down for months afterwards, and reduce your motivation. The same is true for alcohol, but perhaps to a lesser extent. The effects of alcohol don't seem to stick around for quite as long. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423159189.0" user="princessbynature" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with your suspicions and would say with much confidence that the lingering-after-effects are much more severe with the consumption of alcohol than the consumption of marijuana.  Hangovers are experienced by nearly anyone who has ever gotten drunk while the report of a hangover after getting high on marijuana is extremely rare.  

You can die from drinking too much alcohol in a short period of time.  Not a single person has ever been recorded as dying from an overdose of marijuana.

Long term alcohol consumption will damage your liver.
There is no evidence that there is any equivalent damage from consuming marijuana regularly.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423203908.0" user="TheWingnutSquid" delta="False">
    <text>Anyone can die from anything, to me that argument doesn't really matter, no one rgularly dies from just drinking at the bar so that one kinda annoys me. 

They both have similar effects depending on how often you use. Alcaholics tend to have more severe issues while people who smoke every day tend to have severe issues as well, it might not be to the point of internal dammage but at the same time people can drink all their life and have no problems as well. Like I said, the magnitude of use is what matters most when comparing them like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423496613.0" user="BlackRobedMage" delta="False">
    <text>While there is, mathematically, an LD50 for marijuana, it's not really physically possible to have that much in your body at one time. From the [Institute for Cannabis Therapeutics](http://www.oregon.gov/pharmacy/Imports/Marijuana/StaffReview/ReschedulingCannabis-NOTES_3-10.pdf)

*The non-fatal consumption of 3000 mg/kg A THC by the dog and monkey 
would be comparable to a 154-pound human eating approximately 46 pounds 
(21 kilograms) of 1%-marihuana or 10 pounds of 5% hashish at one time. In 
addition, 92 mg/kg THC intravenously produced no fatalities in monkeys. 
These doses would be comparable to a 154-pound human smoking at one time 
almost three pounds (1.28 kg) of 1%-marihuana or 250,000 times the usual 
smoked dose and over a million times the minimal effective dose assuming 
50% destruction of the THC by smoking.*

On the same page, both the LD50 of alcohol and tobacco are listed, are far lower, and are within the reach of a human during habitual consumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423640312.0" user="celticguy08" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Anyone can die from anything

That's simply not true. You can't die from cuddling puppies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423667753.0" user="bob000000005555" delta="False">
    <text>What if there were thousands of puppies and you are crushed to death? Or perhaps you startle them and they, in the thousands, behead you? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27423720696.0" user="Windshield_Wiper" delta="False">
    <text>you would die, but you would die happy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424064175.0" user="bob000000005555" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and they, in the thousands, behead you?


-
&amp;gt; you would die happy

You're crazier than I am. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424079522.0" user="celticguy08" delta="False">
    <text>If you are crushed to death from puppies you are crushed to death, not cuddled to death.

Any object can kill you, but not any action. We don't judge illegality of an object based on actions that are uncommon to be done with that object, otherwise everything would be illegal because enough of everything can crush you to death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424771506.0" user="bob000000005555" delta="False">
    <text>This was implicitly understood by everything. But in the spirit of poor humor it was ignored. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27424785799.0" user="celticguy08" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you making jokes on /r/changemyview?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27425018282.0" user="bob000000005555" delta="False">
    <text>A joke isn't orthogonal to a rebuke. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
