<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1561033788.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pteddo/cmv_pregnant_women_should_be_automatically/">
    <title>CMV: Pregnant women should be automatically registered to donate their afterbirths for stem cell research (with an opt-out option).</title>
    <original_poster>Ragdoll_Proletariat</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a Catholic and my father received stem cell treatment a few years ago. It massively improved his quality of life. I learned shortly beforehand that a woman's afterbirth and its core blood contains a lot of stem cells which can be used, to the point that women can actually donate them. I think this should be made an automatic process because of the following reasons:

1. There's no religious debate about harming an embryo because the baby has already been born, meaning that Christian women could help move this forward.
2. Afterbirths normally go in the bin which is a waste of stem cells.
3. Most women don't know this is an option so wouldn't opt into it.

I believe this would hasten research opportunities and consequently medical developments.

I write this with the caveat that women who want to eat it/frame it/etc can opt out in the same way as with UK organ donation. I'm not a doctor of course so I'm wondering if there's anything I'm missing here. I'm interested in seeing people's thoughts on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37844559676.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845088859.0" user="Ragdoll_Proletariat" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't something I'd considered, thank you for contributing this point of view. Do I still give a delta if the view was expanded or given a new nuance but not fundamentally changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845218669.0" user="Old_Sheepherder_630" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t care about the delta, I just wanted to throw it out there that is can be an option for other situations as well, where it can be a source of comfort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37846207178.0" user="mogadichu" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it's worthy of a delta, since it doesn't change your original stance in any way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845268831.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>The concern with using miscarriages / aborted tissue is that miscarriages can be induced, and abortions are a choice. Which means there can be incentives for increasing the numbers of either. The worry is that it becomes less of a "getting a positive from a traumatic situation" and more of an industry.

I am generally for such things, but such donations need to be strictly regulated, and research with the products donated needs to be strictly and without exception kept 100% separate from facilities and professionals which offer direct patient services to pregnant people. There can be no incentive for the hospital or doctor collecting the donation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845722180.0" user="Old_Sheepherder_630" delta="False">
    <text>I agree there shouldn’t be a financial incentive, and I see your point.  I was strictly referring to miscarriages so at least something good can come out of a painful situation.

An induced miscarriage is an abortion.  What most people call a miscarriage is called a “spontaneous abortion” in the medical files and paper work so the verbiage can be confusing for some.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845888241.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>You added a word that I didn't use.  "Financial". I left incentive broad deliberately.  There should be no incentive at all.  No research, financial, social, or any other incentive. The people providing pregnant people their options should have 0 dogs in that fight.  They need to 110% unbiased, and free from any motivators except the best interest of their patient. To prevent any pressure for a pregnant patient to make a choice regarding abortion. That decision is for a pregnant person, and them alone. 

When doctors have insufficient oversight and are incentivized in a direction, you get occasional situations like Dr. Mahindra Amin, dubbed by many as the "Uterus collector" for his deceptive practices in performing more than a few unwanted hystorectomies.

There can be no incentives at all. None. People who advise and treat the pregnant need to have absolutely no link to the research.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845922966.0" user="Old_Sheepherder_630" delta="False">
    <text>I was thinking of the research or donation is the incentive to the medical community overall to offer donation as an option, but absolutely no one involved with the mother should have any motivation besides the well being of the mother.  No coercion, no guilt, no opinion.  Offer options and care compassionately regardless of decision.

I can see I'm not communicating terribly well today and you brought up important points I missed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845752849.0" user="SalamanderSylph" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with OP's view that donating placentas (placentae?) should be opt-out.

I think that donating miscarriages should be opt-in, however. 

My reasoning is that a miscarriage is far more emotionally traumatic and the "default" option should have the least chance of causing further distress given that, in the situation, the mother has a hell of a lot going on in their head and might just nod through various questions.

If they are highly religious, they might be further destroyed by not being able to have a funeral or similar, or have beliefs that the soul of their child is harmed by further damage to the body that research entails.

Even if they do choose to opt-out, they may be made to feel that they are having to take a broadly harmful choice in order to grieve the way they believe in.

That said, I firmly believe that informing the mother of the possibility to donate and allowing them to choose to do so is excellent. In fact, opt-in could increase the emotional benefit of doing so. Obviously, the whole situation is absolutely awful, but making a decision to do something good with it would allow some feeling of control of a positive rather than  it being a default.

Thank you for sharing your experience. Honestly, it is something that had never even crossed my mind was a possibility!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845838743.0" user="Old_Sheepherder_630" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree because in that case it's not just the afterbirth, it's the child's remains.  I was asked if I wanted to arrange for burial, donate, or disposal.  Honestly it had never once occurred to me that donating was a thing for miscarriages.  So I was glad to be told it was an option.   As you said in the trauma of the moment who is going to be in the state of mind to inquire about it.

With a live birth just dealing with the placenta and cord I am for opting out, but when it's actual remains of course it should be a deliberate choice to donate and I didn't think that through when I first responded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37848839003.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Old_Sheepherder_630 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Old_Sheepherder_630&amp;amp;message=Old_Sheepherder_630%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20commen\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/pteddo/-/hdvo94s/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
