<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1561033788.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pteddo/cmv_pregnant_women_should_be_automatically/">
    <title>CMV: Pregnant women should be automatically registered to donate their afterbirths for stem cell research (with an opt-out option).</title>
    <original_poster>Ragdoll_Proletariat</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a Catholic and my father received stem cell treatment a few years ago. It massively improved his quality of life. I learned shortly beforehand that a woman's afterbirth and its core blood contains a lot of stem cells which can be used, to the point that women can actually donate them. I think this should be made an automatic process because of the following reasons:

1. There's no religious debate about harming an embryo because the baby has already been born, meaning that Christian women could help move this forward.
2. Afterbirths normally go in the bin which is a waste of stem cells.
3. Most women don't know this is an option so wouldn't opt into it.

I believe this would hasten research opportunities and consequently medical developments.

I write this with the caveat that women who want to eat it/frame it/etc can opt out in the same way as with UK organ donation. I'm not a doctor of course so I'm wondering if there's anything I'm missing here. I'm interested in seeing people's thoughts on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37845211220.0" user="Putin_Yerdix" delta="False">
    <text>I know most people are harping on the importance of bodily autonomy and I agree but OP I want to raise a slightly less abstract consequence of this view. I would happily donate my stem cells to help sick people like your Dad or for a non-profit research lab. Even in the event that I wasn't properly informed of an opt-out option if my leftover babysack was going to a good cause I would be mildly irked my doctors didn't tell me, but I wouldn't overall have a problem with it. The problem is that with donations like stem cells or other genetic material is I wouldn't have any knowledge or control about where my donation was going. There is a chance it could go to people in need or be used for the advancement of human kind. There is also a chance it could be sold to a giant pharmaceutical company and turned into a profit. There is a chance it could be used for military research or some rich ladies skincare routine. Stem cells are valuable and I agree that there should be wider spread donation especially since it does not cause any physical harm. However, having women donate as a default, without informed consent could lead to both violating their bodily autonomy and causing them to inadvertently donate to causes they don't support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845225171.0" user="Putin_Yerdix" delta="False">
    <text>Also I accidentally deleted my other comment thank you for the delta OP. Your heart is in directly the right place the core of the problem is transparency in medicine and with donations.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
