<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1561033788.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pteddo/cmv_pregnant_women_should_be_automatically/">
    <title>CMV: Pregnant women should be automatically registered to donate their afterbirths for stem cell research (with an opt-out option).</title>
    <original_poster>Ragdoll_Proletariat</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a Catholic and my father received stem cell treatment a few years ago. It massively improved his quality of life. I learned shortly beforehand that a woman's afterbirth and its core blood contains a lot of stem cells which can be used, to the point that women can actually donate them. I think this should be made an automatic process because of the following reasons:

1. There's no religious debate about harming an embryo because the baby has already been born, meaning that Christian women could help move this forward.
2. Afterbirths normally go in the bin which is a waste of stem cells.
3. Most women don't know this is an option so wouldn't opt into it.

I believe this would hasten research opportunities and consequently medical developments.

I write this with the caveat that women who want to eat it/frame it/etc can opt out in the same way as with UK organ donation. I'm not a doctor of course so I'm wondering if there's anything I'm missing here. I'm interested in seeing people's thoughts on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37844903039.0" user="MsWeed4Now" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. Not your body, not your choice. 

Also, why wouldn’t you just ask? Make it an option? Why jump straight to force? Sheesh… something something flies and honey.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845122172.0" user="Ragdoll_Proletariat" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not advocating taking it forcibly - the woman will still be able to say no for any reason and would be given that opportunity well before time. It's only something that I stumbled across because I was actively looking and I kind of feel like someone about to give birth has enough faffing about to do without having to think about whether the redundant blood sac goes in the bin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850170728.0" user="KOMRADE_ANDREY" delta="False">
    <text>Making it opt out instead of opt in gives off those vibes. Being an organ donor is opt in, not opt out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850726178.0" user="etrytjlnk" delta="False">
    <text>In the US it is, in other countries it is opt out and in those countries there are far higher rates of organ donation, meaning more saved lives, and the people there are perfectly happy with their system because they can easily opt out if it really means anything to them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850796846.0" user="Ragdoll_Proletariat" delta="False">
    <text>My country is opt-out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850821968.0" user="KOMRADE_ANDREY" delta="False">
    <text>The in that case fair enough. In both cases I am of the opinion it should be opt in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37853673331.0" user="No-Bewt" delta="False">
    <text>the problem is that this is a specifically gendered thing. Men will never have to deal with this or make that choice, they have nothing the equivalent to this, and to make a law that primarily puts a burden on one half of the population for a biological function outside of their control is not ethical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865275455.0" user="Holiday_Calendar_777" delta="False">
    <text>One word..transmen..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37883053890.0" user="No-Bewt" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, and? you think trans men are going to be against abortion and women's rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37883186467.0" user="Holiday_Calendar_777" delta="False">
    <text>But you cant say its only a women issue...cuz it includes men..and some transmen dont have a uterus anymore..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37883309140.0" user="No-Bewt" delta="False">
    <text>sure, there are transmen who could be impacted by this ruling, nobody said otherwise, but this is about subjugating women, for whom they think having sex and not being married makes them useless. If you're a man, regardless of if you can get pregnant or if this impacts or could impact you, this was made with subjugating women in mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845213110.0" user="Old_Sheepherder_630" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean it’s not her body?  We’re talking about the placenta and cord, whose would it be if not the mothers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845337018.0" user="Ragdoll_Proletariat" delta="False">
    <text>I'm guessing you might be referring to the comment further down. What I meant is that it's not equivalent to an organ but more like a gallstone, spit or shed menstrual blood. Those things belong to her more than anyone else but they aren't her body in the way that a person's eyes or liver are their body. The afterbirth is something the body gets rid of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37846146648.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>You could also argue that it stops being yours once it goes in the trash though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37846366393.0" user="MsWeed4Now" delta="False">
    <text>As long as you’ve consented to trash it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37846526736.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>It’s implied since that’s the default</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37847879307.0" user="TheRealRJLupin" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly what OP is saying. It shouldn't be the default, the default should be to use it for something helpful, with the option to put it in the bin if one should so choose</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37848723943.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I get it. This person just said they need consent to trash it, and I’m saying they don’t need consent because it’s implied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37848994178.0" user="Spare-View2498" delta="False">
    <text>Things shouldn't ever be just implied, they should be rationalised in a positive way, implying consent is a form of coercion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849419538.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>I’m sorry, but that’s just not how life works. Implied consent is a major faucet of every aspect of life. When you have a medical procedure, you do expressly consent to certain things- the procedure, the risks, etc. You also impliedly consent to some things like the disposal of waste tissue or emergency treatment. You could argue that some things for which we accept implied consent require express consent, but you can’t say that “things shouldn’t ever be implied” because it simply isn’t practical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849462640.0" user="Spare-View2498" delta="False">
    <text>No I did not say it shouldn't be implied at all, it is how it is implied that matters</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849474523.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>Okay well, one, you did say that. “Implying consent is a form of coercion.” And two, we haven’t been discussing the form that implied consent should take, so if that’s what you meant, it’s coming a bit out of left field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849509484.0" user="Spare-View2498" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, implied consent without it being coercion is impossible because we have different views on what we think is right and wrong, if ever the world was united in body mind and spirit perhaps it wouldn't be a form of coercion. But because even as a parent you wish the best for your baby, because of that strong feeling of protection we take precautions for bad things that happened to us and in a lesser extent to our loved ones and the one we come in contact with. That we can take decisions that we may consider correct but are not. And if we as the parent do something bad to our kid while thinking we were helping creates guilt in moral people, because we become aware we imposed our will over anothers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849794618.0" user="igna92ts" delta="False">
    <text>Well in this case both options imply consent, one it's consent to use it for medical research or whatever, the other consent to throw it away. And in both cases you have the choice to opt for the other option. Considering that most people don't even think about the fact that it's being thrown away it would be much better to have the implied consent option that helps advances in the medical field and if someone doesn't like that they can opt out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849869218.0" user="Spare-View2498" delta="False">
    <text>As long as it's informed consent yes but if you're doing it with the presumption people don't think about it,it doesn't in any way help the whole point. Its not whether  you do it or not, as the idea is beneficial , it is how you do it that is important to make sure this beneficial thing is not used in non beneficial ways towards humanity</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850667765.0" user="uglylizards" delta="False">
    <text>Based on this comment, I don’t think you understand what implied consent is. Nothing you wrote is at all relevant to this topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849948453.0" user="Salt_Winter5888" delta="False">
    <text>Placenta and umbilical cord are normally wasted and go to trash or in the sewer. Unless she is planing to eat it (yes, there is people that eat it, it is gross but also natural) it will end up as organic waste. So it will be like donating your poop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37849966859.0" user="MsWeed4Now" delta="False">
    <text>Which you can also do, but I bet it’s illegal to take without consent. Like breast milk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37850225387.0" user="Salt_Winter5888" delta="False">
    <text>That will depend on the country, I don't really know about the UK. But for example, in my country the first articule of the constitution says that the state must protect the people and the family, and his supreme goal is to achive a common benefit for everyone. So in my country they can force you to do almost anything for a greater good. Also my country doesn't recognize body autonomy in the constitution so this law will be on top of that.

So yeah it will depend on the country.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
