<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854963719.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>I, in general, agree with, "when rights conflict, the answer becomes much more complicated and people may often disagree on the best outcome", but I wouldn't say that when body autonomy goes against another right, it automatically loses.

For example, there is a classic ["Violinist" thought experiment](https://philosophicaldisquisitions.blogspot.com/2017/03/the-ethics-of-abortion-and-violinist.html):

&amp;gt; You wake up in the morning and find yourself back to back in bed with an unconscious violinist. A famous unconscious violinist. He has been found to have a fatal kidney ailment, and the Society of Music Lovers has canvassed all the available medical records and found that you alone have the right blood type to help. They have therefore kidnapped you, and last night the violinist’s circulatory system was plugged into yours, so that your kidneys can be used to extract poisons from his blood as well as your own. The director of the hospital now tells you, “Look, we’re sorry the Society of Music Lovers did this to you — we would never have permitted it if we had known. But still, they did it, and the violinist is now plugged into you. To unplug you would be to kill him. But never mind, it’s only for nine months. By then he will have recovered from his ailment, and can safely be unplugged from you.

So your body autonomy conflicts with the violinist's right to life.  Regardless of which way you think this thought experiment should be resolved, I don't think the answer is an automatic obvious one.  Even if you agree that you SHOULD have the right to unplug the violinist and kill him doesn't mean you won't be a bad-guy for doing so.

&amp;gt; But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason.

Because of the impulsive nature, I think it helps avoid the issue since present you and future you aren't going to agree.  It muddies the concept of "self-determinization" when you have multiple selves that don't agree.
So isn't exactly the best example to use in terms of comparing suicide to other kinds of body autonomy.  I think you could certainly argue that body autonomy supports allowing people to commit that impulsive decision, but I don't think it is a clear cut answer.

&amp;gt; To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.

Exercising your rights can often make you a bad guy, one that is completely within their rights, but still a bad guy.  Like I could hurl some insults at you right now for no reason to try to make you feel like crap.  It may be within my free speech rights, but doesn't make me a good guy even if you support the idea that I shouldn't be charged with a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855396603.0" user="SeThJoCh" delta="False">
    <text>The automatic obvious answer is that the violinist 
”thought” experiment falls on its own premiss and is very poorly thought out and extreme in its assumptions that all pregnancy is forced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859087811.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>I think you fail to understand the purpose of a thought experiments.  It is not meant to be an exact analogy of every aspect of pregnancy.  It very purposefully changes some of the assumptions (like the violinist being an adult instead of a fetus, and as you pointed out, the situation being forced), to help us examine which assumptions are important and why.  A perfectly reasonable response to this thought experiment is, "It would be wrong to disconnect in this case because the violinist is an adult, but wouldn't be wrong in the case of a fetus because that isn't a person yet", a detail they very intentionally changed.

But I wasn't even using it as analogy to pregnancy *at all*.  Just a random hypothetical that pits body autonomy against someone else's rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37872221371.0" user="SeThJoCh" delta="False">
    <text>It has no need to be any kind of a direct one to one for my complaint to hold true.

If one actually were to wake up in the scenario of the thought experiment in question, the thing to do would be to just say no and unplug.
There is no logical inconsistansy, no flaw.
The answer is clear as day, the person waking has zero responsibility and the people who connected the violinist do.

Actually i do understand thought experiments perfectly well enough, they are supposed to not fail on their own premiss

”So your body autonomy conflicts with the violinist's right to life.  Regardless of which way you think this thought experiment should be resolved, I don't think the answer is an automatic obvious one.  Even if you agree that you SHOULD have the right to unplug the violinist and kill him doesn't mean you won't be a bad-guy for doing so.”
The answer to it is automatic and obvious though, and unplugging is wholly unproblematic.
The people who plugged the violinist in are the badguys and actually unplugging is ethically preferable and morally good in the scenario of this thought exercise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
