<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37858236007.0" user="Kerostasis" delta="False">
    <text>Roe vs Wade was bad law, yes…but my understanding is that it was mostly replaced by Casey vs Planned Parenthood anyway. The opinion in that second case had a lot more thought put into it than the original Roe vs Wade opinion. Roe is just more famous for some reason- probably just because it was first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858456932.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I can get behind that. But I’d still think either legislation or constitutional amendment is a better way to allow abortions to happen.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
