<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856436420.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>The 14th Amendment doesn't create the right to privacy.  The 14th Amendment says that the right to privacy (which the 4th Amendment hints at) applies not only to the Federal government but also the States.  Without the 14th, State police can establish State religions, perform unreasonable searches and seizures, quarter troops in your house in peacetime, etf.  Just the Feds can't.  The 14th protects Federal rights from the States.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856470255.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>That’s incorrect. The Roe decision is founded upon ‘Fourteenth Amendment's concept of personal liberty and restrictions upon state action’.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856473971.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and the restriction on State action relates to the privacy right which is a penumbra of other guaranteed rights no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856477993.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The restriction on state action is enumerated in the constitution. There is no such restriction as broad as ‘privacy’</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856516938.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>There's no restriction as broad as "expression" in the First Amendment.  It guarantees freedom of speaking, printing on a printing press, etc.  Nowhere does it specify that email is protected.  But we extrapolate.

Likewise extrapolation from the rights against searches and seizures, quartering troops, etc we can extrapolate a broader right to privacy that wasn't spelled out just as expression wasn't spelled out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858523197.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>You can do such a thing, probably, maybe. But I’d say it’s not the courts’ role to make these inferences and expand existing rights. I think legislation and constitutional amendments are far superior methods of addressing the issue of changing ethics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858576854.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Disagree, rights should be interpreted broadly rather than narrowly.  And it's not a matter of changing eyhics.  When the Constitution was written nobody would have dreamed that it would be okay to restrict expression if it was done by smoke signals, it just want spelled out.  And nobody would have dreamed Congress would have tried to limit what a doctor could do for a patient.  These just weren't written explicitly.  It's absolutely the Supreme Court's job to protect these rights more broadly then the minimum written.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858609838.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t really matter what the founders intended. They made an amendment mechanism to take into account of the changing times. I’d much rather it be used (as it’s far more democratic), then let 9 unelected judges pontificate on what rights people should and shouldn’t have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858677435.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>They also made a court system to interpret the words.  And yes of course rights are antidemocratic.  The whole point of rights are to constrain the People when we want to be wicked.  It's crucial that the wise folks enforcing those rights are not beholden to the People, do not have any worries about reelection, do not have any incentive to give the howling mob what it wants.  Democracy is, as Franklin noted, two wolves and a lamb voting on what to have for lunch.  We need undemocratic elements like Rights to protect us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858732750.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The whole notion of judicial review was a power grab in Marbury v Madison. The founders most definitely did not intend to grant the courts the power to strike down laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858812653.0" user="texashokies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The founders most definitely did not intend to grant the courts the power to strike down laws.

Federalist 78 talks about judicial review as being an intended part of the constitution.

Assuming this Wikipedia article is accurate: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judicial_review_in_the_United_States#Statements_by_the_framers_of_the_Constitution_regarding_judicial_review

It seems like the framers supported judicial review</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863675011.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The power to declare laws unconstitutional is different from the power to strike those laws down. English judges have the power to declare laws unconstitutional (declaration of incompatibility), but cannot strike legislation down outright.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858826206.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>If that were true (and I'm not sure it is) we'd need to build some mechanism into *some* branch that would protect rights without having to worry about reelection or popular opinion, or else just not have rights.  People feel like genocide, guess we get genocide.


Do you want that extra democracy/no human rights?  Or did you have a plan to put rights interpretation into another branch?  Maybe into the executive, some shadowy NSA branch?  Into the legislative, some unelected permanent "rules committee"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863621844.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The UK’s system seems to be working fine. There’s no genocide there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864316607.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>UK courts "can't" strike down laws, but they can interpret them very differently than the plain meaning if that is necessary to bring the law into accordance with guaranteed rights.  The Queen can also strike down any laws as necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866699996.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The courts can interpret laws in very contrived ways, but if it really cannot be reconciled, they issue a declaration of incompatibility and punt it back to parliament.  

The Queen may or may not strike those laws down herself. It is unclear whether exercising those powers can only be with the advice of her ministers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866734249.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but if it really cannot be reconciled, they issue a declaration of incompatibility and punt it back to parliament.

In other words they don't go into effect as is, the Courts have the undemocratic power to block the laws.

&amp;gt;The Queen may or may not strike those laws down herself. 

Which means she may, when it comes down to it.  Just not too many times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866746360.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>No, the law goes into effect as is. They cannot block the legislation from going through.  

She may not have that power it is unclear and thus far it is untested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866830214.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>The Courts can issue a Declaration of Incompatibility with human rights.  As you say, this does not block the *legislation*.  It does however block the police or other authorities from actually violating the human rights as the law may demand they do.

"It is untested" means she can in practice, if she's in the right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866887534.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>No, the courts must still apply the legislation as is. Meaning that the police and authorities must act in compliance of the law.  

If it’s untested, in practice, if a case came up where she struck down legislation, it will inevitably go to court, where they will rule on the lawfulness of that (or they might squirrel away and say they aren’t competent to rule on actions of the crown). Either way, whether she actually can is unknown.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866918564.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>No, police are not permitted to violate human rights legally in the UK</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866926450.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The police must act in accordance with law in the UK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867093543.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>And a crucial law is the human rights act which forbids them to violate European-defined rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871776095.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The Human Rights Act makes it unlawful for any public body to act in a way which is incompatible with the convention, *unless the wording of any other primary legislation provides no other choice*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
