<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37855822767.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of body autonomy as a core human right.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

I agree with yyzjertl in that it doesn't really concern the right to bodily autonomy. The main reason the anti-vax crowd uses the argument is that forcing them to undergo a vaccination (enforced by state violence if they don't comply) would indeed be a violation.

Imposing restrictions on what the unvaccinated can do socially isn't a bodily autonomy violation any more than compelling all motorists to wear seat belts or safety helmets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856368290.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>The Harvey Weinstein defense is not a valid argument. Piling up technically-not-murder hardships until they reach the level of aggression that you feel will coerce someone into doing your will is still blackmail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856397902.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Except that it's done to protect a multitude of other people from someone's harmful decision, and not for personal sexual gratification.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856410982.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>No, how would that make it valid?  If raping someone with Coronavirus kept them from going out and spreading it, would that suddenly be ok?  The end doesn’t justify the means especially when the means are systemic cruelty</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856461421.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>This can't be decided based on some black and white principle. It's all about weighing the impact on everyone against everyone's personal rights. Obviously the impact of rape would weigh very heavily in the other direction. It has to be proportional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856466673.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>But the impact of rape would only impact one person, while that same person could have otherwise gone out and infected a theoretically limitless number of innocent people. So isn’t that a net positive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856586924.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>How does your suggestion even work? How would raping someone prevent them from spreading covid?

A crucial difference here is that instead of major harm, we'd only be imposing inconveniences on persons in order to save lives. That is the kind of proportionality I'm talking about.

When seat belts were introduced, people also made all kinds arguments about losing personal freedoms etc. And seat belts aren't even that much about protecting others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856594756.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>I’m sure if you raped someone enough or made it a consequence of going outside they could be heavily encouraged to stay home.  “Imposing inconveniences” is weasel wording. Isn’t rape an inconvenience?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856649581.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>I would count rape as a major harm, and it would be highly disproportionate, when compared to the alternative of only imposing inconveniences.

By inconveniences I mean making life *a little* less comfortable, or *a little* more difficult than usual, such as not being able to visit big events, public indoor dining, etc. Compared to people dying because of that person's decision not to vaccinate, these are acceptable *inconveniences*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857065871.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>You are positing “it is ok to bully someone into unwillingly putting something in their body if it will save lives”.

But where does bullying stop?  The bullies are powerful people who won’t accept “well it didn’t work but it sure inconvenienced them”.  It’s already gone much beyond “inconvenience” and clearly the bullies are willing to escalate until it has the desired effect.  We’re at the “or you’ll lose your job and not be able to get a job” stage and everyone knows what comes next.

Once you are ok with blackmail to override bodily autonomy, “for the greater good” (or “it saves lives”) will be used to excuse anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857209956.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But where does bullying stop? The bullies are powerful people who won’t accept “well it didn’t work but it sure inconvenienced them”. It’s already gone much beyond “inconvenience” and clearly the bullies are willing to escalate until it has the desired effect.

What it comes down to is restricting one kind of freedom in order to protect the freedom of others to go about their business safely.

&amp;gt; Once you are ok with blackmail to override bodily autonomy, “for the greater good” (or “it saves lives”) will be used to excuse anything.

Sorry, I'm not interested in slippery slope arguments. They also made those during the introduction of mandatory seat belts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857224492.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t consider this to be a slope?  Not at all?  We went from voluntary to masks enforced to meager bribery to social shaming to restriction from sporting events to restriction from almost *everywhere* in the case of NYC, to threats of dishonorable discharge from the president to a mandate saying we lose our jobs.  In under a year.

That’s not a slope to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857265467.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>A slippery slope is a claim that something is inevitably going to happen in the future. 

You said they will use it to *"excuse anything"*, which is a typical slippery slope expression. What do you even mean by anything? What do you think they're going to try to excuse, that inevitably follows from previous steps on the slope?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857281915.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not what a slippery slope fallacy is but even if so, can you tell me *why* it is a fallacy?  Why is predicting some behavior something to be ignored?  If you publicly want to reach Point D, and we began at Point A then moved to Point B, and Point C is the only way to Point D, it’s foolish to say “you can’t predict the future. Stop saying they’ll go to Point C”

What inevitably follows is prison and violence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857353356.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That’s not what a slippery slope fallacy is but even if so, can you tell me why it is a fallacy? Why is predicting some behavior something to be ignored?

I'm going by this definition:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; The fallacy is that of supposing that a single step in a particular direction must inevitably and irresistibly lead to the whole distance being covered. There are cases in which one step leads to another, and cases where it does not. It is not a fallacy to suppose that after the first stride, further steps might be taken towards unpleasant consequences, but it is usually an error to suppose that they must.

([Source](https://books.google.ie/books?id=Gh5UjNNc0v4C&amp;amp;pg=PA151&amp;amp;dq=%22The+fallacy+is+that+of+supposing+that+a+single+step+in+a+particular+direction%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22The%20fallacy%20is%20that%20of%20supposing%20that%20a%20single%20step%20in%20a%20particular%20direction%22&amp;amp;f=false))

&amp;gt; What inevitably follows is prison and violence

Merely for refusing the vaccine, or for violating laws requiring vaccine passports by entering places without permission?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857372855.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>Yes that is the definition, but it does not say why it is a fallacy. How does the author guarantee the word “usually”? How could that possibly be proven?  And also it limits to “a single step” thus it is not valid as I have detailed a multitude of steps already taken in the same direction with the same goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857411361.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes that is the definition, but it does not say why it is a fallacy.

It does; it even explicitly says so twice. It's about claiming that the projected future step is inevitable. The non-fallacious version would be to acknowledge merely that the future step could happen.

&amp;gt; And also it limits to “a single step” thus it is not valid as I have detailed a multitude of steps already taken in the same direction with the same goal.

And you're postulating a goal now, also without justification.

Perhaps it will be better to examine the specifics of your claim. So what is it, that you believe will inevitably follow? 

Prison and violence for merely refusing the vaccine, or something else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858336140.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>You seriously are claiming the “goal” isn’t “everyone in America is vaccinated”?  That’s the goal. They’ve said it’s the goal and called it “the goal” in multiple places. 

&amp;gt;	It's about claiming that the projected future step is inevitable. The non-fallacious version would be to acknowledge merely that the future step could happen.

But WHY is that fallacious? Of course no one is saying anything is literally inevitable. There is no need for a fallacy to remind us we can’t know the future. But if we know the goal and the steps they are willing to take to reach it, we are operating in a model where the goal is reached by any means. Obviously that might not happen.  That’s why they will do anything to make it happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864681064.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You seriously are claiming the “goal” isn’t “everyone in America is vaccinated”?

Well sure, and that's a goal more in the sense of an ambition/aspiration. The goal you were postulating is prison and violence, for which I see no evidence.

&amp;gt; But WHY is that fallacious? Of course no one is saying anything is literally inevitable. 

That's indeed what makes it a fallacy: an unsupported assumption of certainty by extrapolating from previous cases. 

So again, what precisely did you mean by "*What inevitably follows is prison and violence*". Are you claiming that the state will enact violence against people or imprison them for the mere fact that they're not getting vaccinated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37868057184.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>A fallacy is not an unsupported assumption.  One example of a fallacy might be to say “my assumption is true *because* it seems unsupported by facts”. A fallacy is a specific reproducible flaw that can apply to the method of reaching any logical conclusion.  It can be identified inside an argument but it is not a problem with the argument, rather it is a problem with how the argument was reached.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37868098651.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't defining what a fallacy is, but what a slippery slope fallacy is - it involves claiming certainty that some future thing will happen, despite no evidence other than similar things having happened before.

In any case, I won't continue until you become more specific about your claim of what precisely you believe is going to happen, and what your justification is for this belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37868150369.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that the government strives for a monopoly of violence.  The stage before violence for extended government power is incarceration.  The state will use as much power as it needs to enforce the vaxx.  Many people will not ever willingly take the vaxx.  Therefore, the end result is either the government gives up, or they begin “lawfully” using incarceration and then violence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37872451584.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>You're still not answering the question directly. Are you definitively  claiming that the government will use violence to enforce vaccination? I.e. vaccination at gunpoint or something like that? Holding people down?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874142207.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>Is this some sort of a trap?  Is the goal here for me to say “I can read the future by using the Slippery Slope Method, the logic of which tells me-“ 

“Ah ha!” you then suddenly swoop in to j’accuse.  “A fallacy has taken place!”

I clearly said that all indication appears that the government will use any and all powers they have to force the vaccine upon any and all Americans.  They have the power to imprison and to assassinate, individually or en masse.  Yes, they will not hesitate to use violence. Whether or not they actually use this violence is dependent on whether the involved parties are still empowered by the time that violence is the only remaining option.  They would likely use it sooner but it has traditionally been the most politically unpopular option in almost every case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874560976.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Is this some sort of a trap? Is the goal here for me to say “I can read the future by using the Slippery Slope Method, the logic of which tells me-“
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; “Ah ha!” you then suddenly swoop in to j’accuse. “A fallacy has taken place!”

You made some very vague claims about future events (that *anything* will be excused, and that violence and that violence will happen) and you also added that they couldn't possibly be a slippery slope. 

Even without discussing whether it's a slippery slope, it's difficult to determine the validity of such vague claims.


&amp;gt; I clearly said that all indication appears that the government will use any and all powers they have to force the vaccine upon any and all Americans. They have the power to imprison and to assassinate, individually or en masse. Yes, they will not hesitate to use violence. Whether or not they actually use this violence is dependent on whether the involved parties are still empowered by the time that violence is the only remaining option. They would likely use it sooner but it has traditionally been the most politically unpopular option in almost every case.

I'm not going to take the position that no violence will ever be used, because that will clearly be the case. *All laws* are backed up by violence, in pretty much the same way: if you do something that is sufficiently illegal, you can be locked up, and if you resist being locked up, the state has a legal monopoly to use violence against you to restrain you if necessary.

For example, if people refuse to get vaccinated, and they then enter into a business where vaccine passes are required, they will be there illegally. If they then refuse to leave, they may eventually be threatened with lockup and potentially even violence if they don't comply. That would be an entirely legitimate use of violence, as it is necessary to enforce any justice system. 

Is this the kind of violence you are thinking about? Or are you claiming that they will actually use violence to go out to vaccinate people against their will? I definitely don't believe that such predictions are justified.

So, which is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874874671.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>The first one I can guarantee, the second is speculation but not as speculative as you might think.  Because Biden knows he cannot legislate this through congress he chooses an executive order. Because he knows he cannot even by executive order mobilize the states to force needles in arms, he has chosen a weaselly extortionate scheme to bully Americans into getting the jab on their own.  That jump so soon to guerrilla psychological warfare is why I believe the jump to actual proactive violence will be equally sudden.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37875140776.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  That jump so soon to guerrilla psychological warfare is why I believe the jump to actual proactive violence will be equally sudden.

And do you believe this will be done in some global conspiracy with the rest of the world? After all, this is also how it's done in many other countries, e.g. in Europe - they all have vaccine passports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37875184989.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>If the situation requires it, certainly.  And the number of countries with such passports is much smaller than you’d think. There’s no reason I can think of that the U.S. would need this alliance you describe though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864725854.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>there is a key difference.  

if they wanted to, say, make having the vaccine required to get your tax refunds, or to buy a computer, or some other unrelated thing, **then** you would be right.

it's an entirely different matter to restrict people from situations where they may endanger others by being in close proximity without safeguards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37861576458.0" user="Walleyabcde" delta="False">
    <text>Where the lines blur is that by imposing enough social restrictions you begin to force them to get vaccinated against their wishes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864741472.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>if the restrictions were unrelated to safety, you would be right.  if they tried to make it required to vote, or to get your tax refund, or to exercise fundamental freedoms, you would have a point.

look at it this way, if the law said restaurants could not serve the unvaccinated, not by delivery, not on a patio, not a curbside pickup, not with masks, under no circumstances, that would be harassment, yes.

but the actual policy around would still let you do all of those things, the only thing you can't do is refuse a vaccination and a mask and still dine indoors.  hardly a collosal imposition with so many other options available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37868866666.0" user="Walleyabcde" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the reasoning. It's not clear to me that the consequences are necessarily as harmless as you think though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37869158110.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>that's fair.  I think fundamentally it's a matter of the fact other people have the same rights you do

people have a right to refuse the vaccine, but I also have the right of free association, meaning I should be able to avoid them if I want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37869237006.0" user="Walleyabcde" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that.

At the risk of going off topic. A lot of my own hesitation doesn't come from the measures themselves - it comes from the narrative.

The clear spin and biases in the media. The shared narratives and catch phrases being used by the politicians, which suggest a centralised control. Stories, some of which seem legitimate, of fudged statistics. The lab leak saga and Fauci links. And the sheer pushiness of it all. "Get the vaccine NOW and if you have doubts you're a selfish anti-vaxxer".

Some of these may be red herrings, but until I know that they raise questions, specifically of whether there are bad actors involved in this.

It makes me feel like something is not quite right. Whether we're being gas lighted. Or I'm just paranoid; for now I don't know which, and because of that I don't want to be forced into these things. It will take time for me to feel I see this situation clearly enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37870175660.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>That is fair, a lot of people have given fully in to their anxiety, despite chanting "follow the science" they want to freeze things forever at the most extreme, restrictive measures for their own anxiety's sake, and then inventing almost ritualistic non-science-based precautions (like leaving their groceries for 30 minutes in the car before bringing them inside, or putting on vinyl gloves to remove their mask) despite the fact that the science now says they are relatively safe.

That attitude, with people calling for outright persecution is frightening. The examples I gave are real suggestions I've seen made-- withholding owed tax refunds contingent on proof of vaccine, making it required to vote (presumably in hopes that it would mean republican politicians are swept out of government entirely as a result), tying it to other rights they feel would force people to get the vaccine (I've seen people suggest 'well republicans like guns, you should have to be vaccinated to own a firearm!' which is just bonkers)

On the other hand, for people in high-risk groups, and I'm in that group, it is an existential threat that so many people refuse to be vaccinated and this is giving rise to an endless series of variants which mean even the vaccinated aren't safe.  Their choices are resulting in people, even vaccinated people (especially in high-risk groups) dying.  I can't entirely blame them for a certain degree of exasperation because they think "I did everything right and I still have to worry about dying young, because of other people's choices".

At the end of the day it's a matter of yes, you have a right, but other people, in turn, have the right to judge you for how you choose to conduct yourself.  If that means they think you're cavallier with their safety, dangerous, selfish or sociopathic, well that's their right.  I don't go as far as some of my friends despite being high-risk (see what I said above about 'freezing in time at the most absurd and then inventing pointless rituals') and they have decided not to have contact with me as a result-- that's their right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
