<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856144843.0" user="Schmurby" delta="False">
    <text>So are arguing that due process does not include a right to privacy?

If so, do you think that any right to privacy is outside the bounds of constitutionality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856178141.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Due process does not, in itself, include a right to privacy yes. I don’t really understand you other question, can you clarify?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856186444.0" user="Schmurby" delta="False">
    <text>Do you reject the notion of the constitution protecting privacy at all? 

That was the ruling in roe v wade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856197432.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The constitution *can* protect privacy if there is an amendment. But as it stands, I don’t see how it protects it at all. There are specific instances where there exists a right to privacy (such as protection from unreasonable searches and seizures, and from having soldiers quartered in your home), but there is no such general right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856216477.0" user="Schmurby" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct that it is never specifically stated but courts have been ruling as though it is implied by the 4th and 14th amendments going back to the 1890s. 

I recognize your right and merit to disagree but jurisprudence would disagree with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856227872.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The fourth amendment yes, because going into someone’s bedroom to search for contraceptives is unreasonable search and seizure. But not the fourteenth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856239714.0" user="Schmurby" delta="False">
    <text>So how is telling someone they have to carry a baby to term not a violation of their privacy?

How does what’s going on in a woman’s body involve the government any more than what’s in her sock drawer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856365531.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how abortion is a privacy issue anyway. It is a question of whether a doctor can legally perform the procedure. I'm sure we could think of any number of things that a doctor is simply not allowed to do to someone or prescribed to them whether they consent or not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856455871.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The issue then was Texas wrote a very restrictive law banning abortions. One way to strike that law down is to show that it’s unconstitutional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856475558.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Unless abortion is not a constitutionally protected right at the federal level, which is the reading being questioned, in which case it is a state issue</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856480596.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The ruling made it constitutionally protected at the federal level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856496322.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't you questioning the validity of the ruling? You got it right in the OP. Abortion isn't even tangentially in the constitution and should properly require going through the amendment process if the power to outlaw it is to be denied to the states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856499884.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not questioning the validity—it most certainly was valid. I’m questioning the legal merit of the decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856523028.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Legal merit is the validity. If it has no legal merit, it has no validity. It isn't a question of whether abortion should or should not be a right. Either the states have the authority to decide the matter themselves or they do not. The tenth amendment makes clear that states can do pretty much whatever they like so long as the constitution doesn't expressly forbid it, or if it is an explicitly granted federal power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858507544.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well no. They’re different questions. To not be valid, a judgement must either be faulty in some procedural, way or that the deciding of the case was so biased that it isn’t worth anything. In this case, the judgement can be vacated. In the case of the Supreme Court, an invalid judgement would be one where, say, one party wasn’t allowed to state their case at all. This is a matter of legal force, and the Supreme Court is the final arbiter of that.  

Legal merit, on the other hand, discusses whether a case has been decided ‘correctly’. One can hold the position that a case had been decided ‘wrongly’, but still abide by the result, and accept the consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860275386.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>A legal case made without sound legal reasoning will be invalid by the common usage of the word invalid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863602570.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The common meaning of invalid in this context would be ‘without legal force’.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858007660.0" user="chaching65" delta="False">
    <text>​In Griswold, the Supreme Court found a right to privacy, derived from penumbras of other explicitly stated constitutional protections. The Court used the personal protections expressly stated in the First, Third, Fourth, Fifth, and Ninth Amendments to find that there is an implied right to privacy in the Constitution. The Court found that when one takes the penumbras together, the Constitution creates a "zone of privacy." [source](https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/privacy)

You are correct in that the constitution does not explicitly say the right to privacy is protected under the 14th amendment.  What Griswold did was determined that a combination of amendments would create a "zone of privacy" which is then a fundamental right protected under the 14th amendment.  Roe V Wade affirmed that there is this "zone of privacy" AND abortions are part of it.  

So if you said Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly because abortions could NOT be protected under this "zone of privacy" then you could be right but to say our constitution does not protect rights to this "zone of privacy" would overturn many cases like gay sex, use of contraception, gay marriage, watching porn at home, because all of these cases reaffirmed Griswold in its decision.

Roe V Wade will not be defeated by justices claiming that the constitution doesn't protect one's rights to privacy.  If anything it would be defeated by stating abortion is not under this "zone of privacy" which would return the rights to states like TX to ban abortions (unlikely) OR the court had no jurisdiction in creating the trimester rule since that goes beyond what the court is supposed to do which is to interpret the constitution and then rule whether a state law violates it but never to legislate.  The latter would possibly give TX the right to regulate abortions before viability like the heartbeat bill or the 15 weeks bill in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization.  That would be the more likely situation at hand instead of allowing states to outright ban abortions BUT it could also have the opposite effect by giving women the absolute right to abortions beyond viability if states like NY allows it.  It's a double-edge sword.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858595481.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I believe this penumbra reading of the constitution gives far too much latitude to the Supreme Court. In essence, the Supreme Court could take the role of congress in making new law. I believe that’s undesirable. I’d much rather congress and the states pass a new amendment affirming the right to privacy, or pass legislation legalizing gay sex, contraception, etc. It’s almost as bad as Marbury v Madison where the Supreme Court blatantly took power for itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37862825840.0" user="chaching65" delta="False">
    <text>Marbury v Madison claimed a congressional law was unconstitutional no? What is so bad about that?  That's their job.

We shouldn't need Congress to legislate fundamental rights like gay sex, or use of contraception.  That's like legalizing masturbation and pre-marital sex.  What if right wing extremist has a trifecta in Congress?   They can just make all of those things illegal.  The constitution protects us specifically from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863616762.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The power of courts to strike down legislation passed by congress isn’t granted to the courts in the constitution. This power was seized by the Supreme Court in Marbury v Madison. In many parliamentary systems, courts do not have the power to strike down legislation (see parliamentary supremacy in the UK).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864762037.0" user="chaching65" delta="False">
    <text>They have the power to strike down any law that is unconstitutional.  That is the check and balance the founding fathers intended.  If Congress disagrees with the Supreme court they have the power to amend the constitution.  So in the case of Marbury v Madison congress could've amended the constitution to extend the jurisdiction of the supreme court if they wanted to.  Plus Marbury v Madison was decided on 1803 which is only 14 years since the constitution went into operation.  So our founding fathers was present when the "judicial review" doctrine went in effect and could've done something about it.  However only Mercer and Dickinson have expressed opposition to the doctrine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866733853.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not opposed to judicial review. I’m merely stating that, given how it was established in a blatant power grab, all subsequent decisions made using this as precedent is the court acting ultra vires. One does not have to oppose something in order for it to be wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37868218555.0" user="chaching65" delta="False">
    <text>There is precedence for "Judicial Review" in courts before Marbury v Madison where a judge voided legislation by ruling it unconstitutional.  This suggests Judicial review wasn't a Supreme Court power grab but rather exercising the power courts had all along.  Here are sources for two.  [bayard v singleton](https://www.ncpedia.org/bayard-v-singleton) and [ten pound act cases](https://www.encyclopedia.com/politics/encyclopedias-almanacs-transcripts-and-maps/ten-pound-act-cases-nh-1786-1787)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871810977.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>English courts didn’t have the power to do so. So it definitely want a power that courts always had. But my point is that the various branches of the US government derive their powers from the constitution. Given that the power to strike down laws wasn’t in it, doing so anyways is acting ultra vires. That said, I think strong judicial review is a good think. But I think an amendment granting courts that right is needed to legitimize it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
