<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854414029.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>I think bodily autonomy is a critical and important right.  No one should be forced to take the vaccine.

However, refusing to take it can then justify restricting other things we don't consider rights - e.g. entering certain physical places, participating in certain activities and so on.  You can still vote, you still have the right to a fair trial if you are suspected of a crime and so on.

I don't know any proposal that actually requires vaccination, or forces it with threat of punishment if not taken.  I would be against any law that actually required someone to have something injected into them by force, or at threat of punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855024759.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't laws that you lose your job or have to pay significant amounts of money on testing punishments?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856443261.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>No more than a gazillion other safety requirements that must be followed for all sorts of jobs. And...no employee is paying for testing in any mandate program.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859203810.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No more than a gazillion other safety requirements that must be followed for all sorts of jobs

The existence of other workplace safety rules is not relevant to the question of whether or not the vaccine policy punishes people for not vaccinating

&amp;gt;And...no employee is paying for testing in any mandate program

This is false [https://www.wesa.fm/health-science-tech/2021-09-15/bidens-mandate-requires-weekly-covid-19-testing-for-unvaccinated-employees-that-will-get-expensive](https://www.wesa.fm/health-science-tech/2021-09-15/bidens-mandate-requires-weekly-covid-19-testing-for-unvaccinated-employees-that-will-get-expensive)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859320324.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>It will get expensive, it is not being paid for by the employees.  That is not the proposal nor the mandate.  There is nothing in the article you state that says otherwise - it's about whether insurance carriers or the employer will pay.  At least read your own references please.

Workplace safety _absolutely_ has to do with this.  That's why we have regulations around everything from blood borne pathogens in the workplace.  And...again, not punishment to have eligibility requirements for employment that align when ensuring that you're protecting your workforce's health.  Tons and tons of precedence.

The degree to which you shoot and miss here, using made-up information is getting pretty absurd.  You just keep leaving behind an idea then moving on to the next false idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859343625.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The employer does NOT have to pay for this [https://www.nytimes.com/article/unvaccinated-covid-tests.html](https://www.nytimes.com/article/unvaccinated-covid-tests.html), the cost will ultimately fall on the employee</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859416438.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Undecided and unknown as the article states. And...many states have stepped in.  Further, the vaccine is paid for universally.

Calling anything one must do to be employed "punishment" is silly.  Certification cost is punishment?  Cost of  proper work attire is punishment?   Come now.  You're 9 layers deep into this and only one thing you've said being even possibly true depending on how it plays it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
