<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854301292.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>In the situations you describe where bodily autonomy supposedly conflicts with other human rights, there is actually no conflict. This is because the right to bodily autonomy is not a right to do whatever you want with your body. Rather, it's about self-ownership and self-determination of people over their own bodies. It's about the protection of the integrity of people's bodies, their rights to access medical care, etc. It does not purport to give you the right to unilaterally act as you please just because those actions (as all actions) inherently involve your body.

In the case of the arm-swinging, the right to bodily autonomy is not really relevant: it doesn't give you a right to swing your arm in the first place.

In the case of vaccination mandates, the right to bodily autonomy _does_ purport to give people the right to refuse vaccination—because this is inherently about their control over the processes of their own body. However, it does not purport to give them the right to then go into public places while unvaccinated (because this is just a thing people do with their bodies, not about the body itself). As such there's no conflict between present vaccine mandate policies and the right to bodily autonomy.

The right to bodily autonomy is an inalienable right, and as such can't be used to justify suicide (which would constitute an alienation of that right).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854338186.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>It kind of sounds like you're just vacillating between different definitions for the same words. 

You're trying to separate the *inalienable right* of body autonomy from the consequences of acting according to that right in a way that harms other people.

In terms of suicide, what you're saying still implies that if I want to put enough heroin in my arm to kill myself, that is a right that cannot be taken away from me, and the consequences of exercising my rights are immaterial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854354688.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It kind of sounds like you're just vacillating between different definitions for the same words.

Which definitions are those?

&amp;gt; In terms of suicide, what you're saying still implies that if I want to put enough heroin in my arm to kill myself, that is a right that cannot be taken away from me, and the consequences of exercising my rights are immaterial.

This is exactly the type of thing I'm saying has nothing to do with the right to bodily autonomy. The government can make heroin illegal to possess and use, and this doesn't violate your right to bodily autonomy because it really has nothing to do with your body—except in the general way that all our actions involve our bodies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854374945.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>So if you see someone eating a fatal dose of a (legal) drug, you're saying that their right to do that supercedes your right to what might be called good samaritanism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854780759.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm saying that they _don't_ have a right to do that under bodily autonomy. The situation you describe has nothing to do with bodily autonomy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859311211.0" user="Runs_With_Sciences" delta="False">
    <text>Then what does bodily autonomy mean to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855017234.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, it does not purport to give them the right to then go into public places while unvaccinated

This is not true, isolating someone from society is a harsh enough punishment to count as coercing medical teratment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855025571.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>They aren't being isolated from society, though. They are being barred from specific social situations in which Covid is likely to spread, not from society generally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855043551.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What about policies where many people lose their job if not vaccinated? https://www1.nyc.gov/site/doh/covid/covid-19-vaccines-keytonyc.page</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855050553.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>What about them? Job sites are often places where Covid is likely to spread, so it is natural that many of them would be covered.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855075280.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Making someone unemployed is sufficient punishment (possible financial ruin) to count as coercing medical treatment

I was responding to your claim that people aren't being coerced into vaccination, not disputing covid's ability to spread on job sites</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855089196.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Making someone unemployed is sufficient punishment (possible financial ruin) to count as coercing medical treatment

Not really. Requiring vaccination as a condition of employment isn't coercing anything. You always have the choice to _not_ be employed there. Nobody is forced to employ you. Plus, requiring medical treatments (vaccines, drug tests) as a condition of employment is a pretty standard setup—this isn't some sort of crazy new thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855100765.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The NYC policy I linked is a government requirement that no employer in certain industries is allowed to employ any unvaccinated person, If that is the industry you have skills for, you may not be able to support yourself financially if you do not get vaccinated</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855114493.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Then your recourse is to get a job in one of the many other fields and job types which this order does not cover.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855124198.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think that you can simply go get a job sufficient to support yourself in an industry that you have no experience in? That's just not how jobs work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855139827.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty much all employed people have done this. Like, how do you think people get jobs? You get a job first, and then afterward, while on the job, you get the experience. But you have to get a job while having no experience in order to start getting job experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855195940.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;you have to get a job while having no experience in order to start getting job experience

Yes, but you don't usually make enough to support yourself when you have no experience

Usually you only get a job that pays reasonably after first working lower paying jobs in that industry or going to school for years to learn a skill

People cannot rely on the ability to immediately find a new job that pays reasonably in an industry they have no experience in</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855295822.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>New York's minimum wage is $15/hr. If that's not enough for people to support themselves, then that's a separate problem unrelated to the vaccine mandate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855318272.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Good catch, I had not thought of that, where I am it is $7.25

Even so $15 is below a living wage in NYC [https://livingwage.mit.edu/counties/36061](https://livingwage.mit.edu/counties/36061) and the ability to get hired quickly in an industry you have no experience in is highly uncertain to start with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855326259.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>That's a risk the people in question choose to expose themselves to. But they are no worse off than people who are presently unemployed and unskilled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859144293.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You are ignoring the fact that there will be a very harsh financial punishment for some of those who choose not to vaccinate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860263917.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like they should get vaccinated then...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860442588.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The discussion was over whether certain policies coerce vaccination, not over wheather anyone should or shouldn't get vaccinated</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
