<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37857981894.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>The 9th amendment exists. 

So long as it continues to exist, the constitution cannot be used to construe that rights don't exist, unless directly specified. 

Therefore, even if the constitution doesn't specifically say you have a right, you may well have that right anyway, unless it specifically says that you don't. 

In other words, SCOTUS can simply pull rights out of thin air. Unless the construction specifically says that a right doesn't exist, then there are no other limits on SCOTUS ability to ass pull any rights that it wants too. 

You don't need the fourth or the fourteenth. You just need control F, and see that the word privacy isn't in the constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858467710.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The 9th amendment isn’t worth anything in Supreme Court jurisprudence. In practice, any right that isn’t enumerated can be taken away on a whim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860721740.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Precedence exists. 

Use the 9th to bring it into being. Use precedent to keep it there. 

It's worked for Roe for 40 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863608054.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The 9th amendment doesn’t confer any substantive rights. To use it to do such a thing is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867703012.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Why? 

It seems to be that the 9th exists specifically because we have rights that aren't specifically listed. When the court identifies those rights, it acts. 

That's the whole point.

Take a famous example - the separation of church and state. Not actually in the constitution. Not actually in the declaration of independence either. Jefferson spoke it plenty, but it doesn't actually appear in the founding documents. 

The first amendment only recognizes that there should not be an established state religion. (Such as the Anglican church being the official church of England at the time). 

If you want anything to do with public schools, whether God can be on the money or in the pledge, or anything like that, the first does little to no actual work. 

If you want to squirrel "separation of church and state" into the constitution, you need the 9th, or it just isn't there.

Similarly, the first only protects speech, print media and assembly. If you want to dress how you like, or do your hair how you like or otherwise have "free expression" in a manner that isn't verbal or text based, you need the 9th.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871800623.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>If I want separation of church and state I’d support a constitutional amendment saying so. Having courts invent rights is a very dangerous game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37873972625.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>"that's a dangerous game" is pretty different than "roe was decided incorrectly". 

You might not like the ninth, but that doesn't mean that SCOTUS decided roe wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874774671.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not like I don’t like the 9th. I don’t think it’s useful for deciding cases.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
