<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854269783.0" user="CruelSun2" delta="False">
    <text>Explain how this isn't simply "Body autonomy is not a human right if I don't like it"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854359411.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>It's called [syllogism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syllogism).

I'm not saying I don't like it. I'm not passing judgement either way. I'm just showing that, based on the assumption that it *is* a human right, you end up in weird places logically.

By assuming that body autonomy supercedes the rights of other humans not to catch what you are not vaccinated against, you also have to concede that a pilot, hypothetically, overdosing on heroin while flying a passenger jet, was completely within his rights, and the consequences of his actions matter less than the consequences of his losing that right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854521246.0" user="CruelSun2" delta="False">
    <text>Where does anything say we have a right to bodily autonomy? Must've missed that one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37854857428.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>Antivax people say it’s a human right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856522569.0" user="CruelSun2" delta="False">
    <text>Good thing I think they're wrong too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864712875.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>if argue almost everyone says it is, or acts as if they believe it is on a fundamental level.  it's the foundation of medical ethics as well as basically the entire concept of "human rights"-- if you believe people have rights then you must, necessarily believe they should be able to exercise those rights without permission from someone above them.

the alternative is to believe people should have no right to make their own decisions and should not be able to live their life as they wish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864689713.0" user="dWintermut3" delta="False">
    <text>it's widely considered a fundamental human right, in fact many would argue it is **the most** fundamental human right.  its also the core basis for things like medical ethics.

it's a fundamental value of most worldviews that absent a compelling harm, people should be able to live as they wish.

in addition, most other rights spring forth from autonomy.  the right to express oneself (aka free speech) the right to live by one's conscience (aka freedom of religion as well as political freedoms), the right to privacy is rooted in non-interference with the private lives of individuals as well.

Rights of due process and criminals' rights are rooted in the fact that while sometimes abridging someone's freedom (by imprisoning or by forcing them to do something or not to do something) us necessary society feels it's such a grave matter it should have massive procedural safeguards and a defined process that gives the individual every benefit of the doubt.

and beyond that, autonomy, in the form of the right to refuse treatment, to have all the information presented to you when making medical decisions, and to participate in the decision-making of your medical care are foundational to medical ethics.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
