<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37855246928.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855577584.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>Well, logical ends are like that.

Reductio ad absurdum</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858296213.0" user="Angdrambor" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Throwaway-242424 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Throwaway-242424&amp;amp;message=Throwaway-242424%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20commen\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/-/he21bgw/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
