<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37857891089.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text

The Court has also found a right to privacy exists from the Ninth Amendment. From the decision:

&amp;gt;This right of privacy, whether it be founded in the Fourteenth Amendment's concept of personal liberty and restrictions upon state action, as we feel it is, or ... in the Ninth Amendment's reservation of rights to the people, is broad enough to encompass a woman's decision whether or not to terminate her pregnancy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858473420.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>You could make just the same judgement that it isn’t broad enough. Two out of the 9 justices dissented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858668820.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like you've changed your view twice in this comment.

Your view states that the decision is problematic because it derives the right to privacy from the 14th Amendment. Now you also hold the view that the 9th is as well. You secondly change your view by arguing the number of assenting justices determines the correctness of a decision, which is absent from your view.

&amp;gt;You could make just the same judgement that it isn’t broad enough.

But you offer no rationale for that judgement.

&amp;gt;Two out of the 9 justices dissented.

How many justices need to assent for a decision to be correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858707297.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The rationale for that is given in the two dissenting opinions. Clearly they felt it isn’t broad enough otherwise they would’ve concurred.  

The number of justices assenting has no bearing to the ‘correctness’ of the decision. Korematsu v United States was clearly decided wrongly by a margin of 6-3.  

My underlying theme tying all this together, is that it is not the courts’ place to create new law, but rather Congress’ as well as the states’.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858779335.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>So your view has changed from the decision was incorrectly decided as derived from the 14th Amendment to it was incorrectly decided as derived from both the 14th and 9th?

&amp;gt;The rationale for that is given in the two dissenting opinions. Clearly they felt it isn’t broad enough otherwise they would’ve concurred.

So why is the minority right and the majority wrong? You are making a claim of fact that they majority is wrong on this question. Why are they wrong and not the minority? Are you saying you have no rationale for your view on this point?

&amp;gt;My underlying theme tying all this together, is that it is not the courts’ place to create new law, but rather Congress’ as well as the states’.

If the decision was decided correctly, then they didn't. They affirmed a right under the Constitution and rendered laws in violation of that null. Unless you are saying judicial review itself is bad which would render the Constitution meaningless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858792361.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>My reasons for why the majority got it wrong is written above.  

Judicial review itself isn’t bad, but that power wasn’t granted to the Supreme Court, it was a power grab in Marbury v Madison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858855904.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My reasons for why the majority got it wrong is written above.

You only give reasoning for why reliance on the 14th Amendment is wrong, not the 9th. You give zero reasoning for why the right to an abortion isn't derived from the 9th Amendment. You don't even mention the 9th in your view. You have to change your view just to acknowledge this flaw.

&amp;gt;Judicial review itself isn’t bad, but that power wasn’t granted to the Supreme Court, it was a power grab in Marbury v Madison.

Article 3 of the Constitution grants the judicial power to the SCOTUS. Congress only has the authority to define the power of inferior courts. Congress has no authority to dictate the judicial power of the SCOTUS. The Constitution is meaningless without judicial review. The judicial power is the power to determine what the law says and to pronounce and implement judgments based on that interpretation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858944588.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>You can easily account for the 9th using the same Rehnquist logic. If the 9th really protected abortion rights, then abortion laws should never have been allowed. They were allowed, so obviously it wasn’t intended to protect abortion rights.  

Judicial power does not necessarily entail judicial review. Look at the UK’s court system for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858973752.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can easily account for the 9th using the same Rehnquist logic. If the 9th really protected abortion rights, then abortion laws should never have been allowed.

Then do you also subscribe to the logic that the 2nd amendment doesn't cover handguns otherwise the handgun bans would have never been allowed?

Or that the 14th Amendment didn't apply to segregation, otherwise "separate but equal" would never have been allowed?

If a legislature can pass a law, that means the law isn't unconstitutional? That means Constitutionality is just a matter of democratic outcomes, not the text of Constitution? The actual text is meaningless and unenforceable? A majority of Congress could pass a law stripping the Executive Branch of all powers? A majority of Congress could ban all firearms and we could just ignore the 2A?

&amp;gt;Judicial power does not necessarily entail judicial review. Look at the UK’s court system for example.

That would be meaningful if the USA was a monarchy and the UK had a Constitution imbued with checks and balances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863569167.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I’m generally of the opinion that, if one were to take a far narrower view of rights, you’d force the population to make constitutional amendments more often and then the outcomes would generally be more democratic. I think that’s worth something.  

Parliamentary supremacy doesn’t derive itself from the monarchy. Further, as is common practice in the UK, when there’s a law in breach of a right in the ECHR, courts would seek to read the law in such a way to comply with the ECHR, rather than the American practice of striking it down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865157354.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I’m generally of the opinion that, if one were to take a far narrower view of rights, you’d force the population to make constitutional amendments more often and then the outcomes would generally be more democratic.

Seems like that is your actual view.

But Constitutional Amendments are meaningless if laws passed by Congress aren't subject to them.

&amp;gt;as is common practice in the UK, when there’s a law in breach of a right in the ECHR, courts would seek to read the law in such a way to comply with the ECHR, rather than the American practice of striking it down.

Well that isn't how the law works in the USA. Ultimately your reason for why these decisions are wrong is that you think we should have a different legal system.

Of course every court decision is going to be wrong when you view the Constitution as optional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866755782.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not arguing judicial review is bad. I’m suggesting how it was added to the legal framework (via a case that the Supreme Court decided) was bad.  

I’m not suggesting it’s better. I’m just suggesting it’s possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867072482.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>But when you really get down to it, you have no reasoning why the 9th amendment doesn't confer the right to an abortion. You only have reasoning why the Constitution doesn't confer any rights at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871765597.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well no, but the 9th doesn’t confer any rights. It only states that the enumeration in the constitution doesn’t affect rights that people already have. *But what would those be?*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37872603872.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>As the court said, a right to privacy or an abortion. Your only argument here is that a law being passed that violates a right means there was no right. But that has all sorts of other implications.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874770172.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well the court said that. But what basis does it have for saying that. Nothing in the constitution explicitly grants such a right to privacy. They justices essentially made this part up, and then justified how you can draw this conclusion using the penumbra argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37875111156.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But what basis does it have for saying that

The text of the 9th Amendment. It has to mean something. It wouldn't be there if it didn't mean anything.

&amp;gt;Nothing in the constitution explicitly grants such a right to privacy.

Nothing in the Constitution limits rights to the explicit text of the Constitution. In fact, it explicitly says in the 9th that rights are not all explicitly enumerated.

&amp;gt;They justices essentially made this part up

No, the Founder's made up the 9th Amendment and the SCOTUS just recognized this was where it should be applied if it meant anything at all.

All rights are made up by the SCOTUS. The Constitution doesn't explicitly define any rights to any extent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37878519038.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The constitution explicitly defines rights in 1A-8A. Some of them are incredibly precise like the $20 in the 7th amendment.  

I’m saying that the rights shouldn’t be made up by SCOTUS, but rather created via constitutional amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880073194.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>The Constitution doesn't define any rights, it merely and briefly states rights sounding words. The SCOTUS defines those rights. What freedom of speech entails isn't described anywhere in the Constitution. 

&amp;gt;I’m saying that the rights shouldn’t be made up by SCOTUS, but rather created via constitutional amendment.

All rights are made up by the SCOTUS and these rights are enshrined in the 9th Amendment. Why is there a 9th amendment at all if not for this exact situation?

You've also changed your view. You aren't arguing this particular case was wrongly decided, but that how we make legal decisions is entirely wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880088619.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Because the 9th amendment is used as a catch all to make rights appear where none have been created. If you want a right to privacy, then make one via amendment, but don’t claim the 9th does because I can just as well claim the 9th amendment gives me the right to sovereign citizenship or whatever flavor of the month crazy idea that people have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880126596.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because the 9th amendment is used as a catch all to make rights appear where none have been created.

A. That's why it's there.

B. They've been created by the 9th Amendment. They've been as created as any other right.

&amp;gt;If you want a right to privacy, then make one via amendment, but don’t claim the 9th does because I can just as well claim the 9th amendment gives me the right to sovereign citizenship or whatever flavor of the month crazy idea that people have.

Then you just want us to ignore entire portions of the Constitution?

If the 9th gives you some crazy right, why haven't those rights been affirmed? Why should we have to go through a burdensome amendment process when we have an existing amendment that addresses the issue? 

The Constitution isn't a set of laws or rights. It is a framework for debate about laws and rights.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
