<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37863590958.0" user="Ralife55" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are kind of missing a point here. The supreme court has the power of legislative review, but that power is effectively meaningless.

 At any point, Congress or the executive branch could simply ignore the supreme court. 

Congress could vote to remove the supreme court as an entity or that it's rulings only means something if notorized by a vote by congress, or, as has become talked about recently, stack the court with like minded judges.

The executive branch on the other hand can just ignore the courts rulings since they enforce all laws they rule on. As they did famously in the lead up to the trail of tears. Unless Congress interjects with an impeachment of the president, the courts ruling is effectively made moot.

The courts power comes from the other two branches accepting it's rulings, and the other two branches power (ideally) comes from the people, so, any ruling the court makes that is not overruled by congress or ignore by the executive branch, or both, is accepted by the state as the law of the land, and by extension, the people.

The courts arguments being consistent and thoughtful are literally meaningless. If they say something is law now, and the other two branches say ok, it's now the law 

This idea that the courts are this untouchable entity with to much reach is silly. They are actually extremely weak. If the court ever passed a ruling that the vast majority of the people were against, the court would be checked immediately.

On the topic of abortion, it's a contentious issue, and as such neither of the two branches can gain enough support to ignore the court. Atleast not for any real length of time. 

Republicans for example could have basically ignored roe from 2016 to 2020 when they controlled Congress and the white house. Trump could have said "I allow states to ignore Supreme court rulings on abortion", and so long as Congress agreed, and the people did not revolt, it would happen , but it would have gotten overturned in 2020 once they lost that control and those states would be forced back In line.

Our government is just accepted norms, every single rule can be ignored or changed so long as the people support it or are atleast apathetic. 

Our three branches are only better than a monarchy or totalitarian state because power is spread out. It makes it harder for a single ideology or idea to gather enough power to force things through without a vast majority of support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863658598.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, I get that. But this isn’t what the post is about. It’s about the narrow question of whether, from a legal perspective, the Supreme Court got it right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863763653.0" user="Ralife55" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and the arguments I've seen from you towards others who have answered is effectively that the court's decision was based on interpretations of the constitution made possible by the process of legislative review. You argued that the court should not have the power of legislative review at all and that the constitution should be taken at face value, or as close to face value as possible.

 Essentially, your saying that any change of rules or interpretation of the constitution must go through Congress. Therefore, the ruling of roe v Wade is a bad ruling because it relies on interpretations of the constitution via legislative review, a power that should not exist.

My initial statement was to show that legislative view is a moot power and has no real meaning without support from the other two branches of government, and therefore, the people. If you need congressional support in order for the roe v Wade ruling to make sense you already have it in congresses inaction to force the court to change the ruling, something it can easily do.

Congresses inaction shows it believes the ruling is popular enough to not be worth attempting to overrule, so it accepts it. Same can be said of the executive branch as well. If they both accepts it, it's law.

The courts argument is moot in this case, they literally could have said "abortion is legal cuz fuck you" and left it at that. If Congress and the executive branch accept it, it effectively becomes law. The court has no real power, it's power comes from the other two branches and by extension, the people.

Arguing whether or not the argument the court made was good or not is pointless when they don't need to make a good argument. Congress and the executive branch just need to say "sounds good enough to me" and boom, it's law.

Going off the assumption that Congress and the executive get their power from the people, any accepted court ruling is effectively the country accepting a new law.

To surmise, your argument is effectively pointless because the only thing that matters in a democracy is the will of the people. Not enough people want roe v Wade struck down, so it remains law.

Really, the only thing you need to worry about in the case of roe v Wade is whether you want it to stay or be struck down. Then make sure the government knows your opinion so it can act accordingly to yours and your fellow citizens will. If they don't listen to the vast majority, well, that's why we have the second amendment. Anything else is a waste of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864561106.0" user="Sreyes150" delta="False">
    <text>Your refute is off topic and should be removed. You didn’t engage on the topic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866671587.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well, broadly speaking, my view is that Roe is wrong because Griswold is wrong. Griswold is wrong because (a) it created rights from thin air and (b) Marbury v Madison was wrong. Marbury v Madison was wrong because nothing in the constitution or congressional legislation gave the Supreme Court the power of striking down statute. The Supreme Court is therefore ultra vires in all its decisions striking down statute.  

Is judicial review striking down unconstitutional legislation a good idea? Yeah, and I think it should’ve been explicitly granted to the courts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866869078.0" user="Ralife55" delta="False">
    <text>See, my argument is that, in reality, none of that matters. I understand your argument is that Griswold made a bad case, but my argument is that that literally has no meaning.

Every court ruling only means something if the other two branches of government (and by extension, the people) say it does due to their ability to either manipulate, abolish or just ignore the court.

Every ruling the court makes, no matter how shaky or firm the ground it sits on, only matters if the rest of the government says it matters.

So my argument is that debating whether or not Griswold's argument was sound is a waste of time. Griswold could have literally said "abortion is legal cuz fuck you" and so long as the other two branches went along with it (and by extension, the people) it would effectively be law.

The only reason roe v Wade, or any other ruling for that matter in recent history, has not been over turned is because neither Congress or the white house can gather enough popular support to get rid of it.

Abortion is a contentious issue, and as such rulings on it cannot be over turned easily, and even if it were, it could simply be reinstated once another faction gains control of the government.

Really the courts are just an express lane towards passing laws. They can say whatever they want, and so long as Congress or the white house allow it and enforce it, it's law.

Sure they have to make it sound good with legal jargon to convince the public, but in reality it all comes down to public support, or atleast public apathy. If the people don't care about the laws you pass you can pass whatever you want after all.

At the end of the day, the constitution is just a piece of paper. It only means something if people give it meaning. If the people are ok with the court having the ability to strike down statuette then they have that power regardless what the constitution says or is interpreted to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866923419.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>This is a very cynical view of law and I don’t totally disagree. However this CMV is a post on the legal merits of the decision and surrounding factors. Telling me it doesn’t matter doesn’t really change my mind on my view that it was decided wrongly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866989759.0" user="Ralife55" delta="False">
    <text>Ehh, I mean, that's fair. My goal was more to show the futility of the argument rather than to change your mind on the argument itself. It's like having two neighbors arguing over who's responsibility it is to trim the tree limbs of a tree that sits on the line between their properties, but they both pay the local HOA fee's which include a tree limb trimming service that comes out and trims the tree limbs regardless of which one of them is right.

Sure, they can argue, and maybe their is a correct, logical conclusion to which of them should trim that tree, but it's not like that argument will change the actually reality that neither of them ever will have to and that their argument is a waste of time.

Unless the system around them fundamentally changes, the argument is moot.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
