<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856123213.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't it seem more likely that your interpretation is incorrect than that of some of the most experienced judges in the country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856129632.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>There was criticism when the decision was handed down that it was ‘judicial activism’.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856137515.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>There are tons of pro-abortion lawyers and people in general who believe the right to an abortion should be available, and also recognize that Roe V Wade was not decided correctly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856241170.0" user="IcedAndCorrected" delta="False">
    <text>Would this same logic have applied to *Plessy v. Ferguson* and *Korematsu* at the time those were decided?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856387868.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the judges interpretation of the law was more likely correct than if I or some other layman tries to interpret it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856489104.0" user="mslindqu" delta="False">
    <text>Seems dangerously close to 'they're the expert so just accept everything they say'.   

No, experience and stature do not automatically make what you do golden.  Everybody poops and experts are just as full of shit as anybody else, given the opportunity.

The peer review that is built into the court is really whats important here as one 'experts' opinion is just that, an opinion.. because these matters are gray and literally many interpretations can be valid..  however I think a lot of times the peer review is not whole hearted and decisions often left to politics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856501414.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;'experts' opinion is just that, an opinion

It is just an opinion, but not all opinions are equal, and expert opinions are far more likely to be correct than a layman's opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856570991.0" user="mslindqu" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm.. interesting.  I think opinions are opinions.  They're subjective by nature and thus cannot be ranked.  This is a position a friend of mine turned me around on.

For example, I eat a lot of apples.  Let's say I'm an apple expert.  I say honey crisp is the *best* apple for just plain eating.  Ok, now prove it.  You can't.  Your stance would be that I eat a lot of apples so I must know how they compare and am better situated to rank this qualitative measure.  But my taste buds aren't your taste buds, and my brain isn't your brain.  

I think with opinions/qualitative measures.. the best we can do is statistics '60% of people prefer honey crisp therefore you're most likely to prefer it too'.  If your point is that an expert is more likely to know that statistic, then I might concede that, however there's nothing stopping anyone from knowing it too.

Intuitively I understand what you're saying.  When you apply definitions and logic to it however, I end up here.

Deciding an ambiguous law might be deemed better done by an expert because they have a more thorough understanding of how that decision will interact with other law..but that's not really part of forming an opinion of what an ambiguous law means.  That's more about gaming the system - politics. 
(I recommend honeycrisp because most people can get it, even though there's much better varieties you'll never see in your life).  

Interesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856603526.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>Opinions aren't always about subjective things though.

For example, I'm in the forest hunting deer and think I should go west to find them, an experienced hunter from that forest thinks we should go north.

They're both opinions and either might be correct, but the experienced hunter is more likely to be correct.

Forming opinions based on incomplete information is almost always more likely to end up with a correct opinion when done by experts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856763864.0" user="mslindqu" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting point. 

&amp;gt;Opinions aren't always about subjective things though.

But in the case of this thread, it is subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857848619.0" user="abqguardian" delta="False">
    <text>This argument doesn't work. Precedent being overturned isn't new</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857863079.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>That's irrelevant, balance of probabilities is that the experts who looked at it were right.

Just because doctors sometimes diagnose things incorrectly doesn't mean you should trust my uninformed guess instead.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
