<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856152920.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court.

Shouldn't this just be about Griswold? That's where the right to privacy was first established, I don't see what Roe adds to the discussion.

And saying that, it feels like you have to deal with the fact that SCOTUS has routinely upheld the right (and expanded it) since then

&amp;gt;(As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’)

From what i can find, there was often a right to privacy under the 1st/3rd/4th/5th/9th, as well, prior to Griswold.

&amp;gt; The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient

Why?

You don't give much reasoning, and it's been upheld, reaffirmed, and expanded, since. I'm not sure "no reasonable person would read it that way" really suffices, given that level of scrutiny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856175310.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>It could be mostly about Griswold, but way more people know about Roe.  

There are bits and pieces which could piece together something resembling a ‘right to privacy’, but no enumerated right as such (unlike the right to bear arms or to vote if you’re over 18, or the right to private life as found in the ECHR).  

It’s insufficient because a plain reading of the 14th amendment doesn’t make any mention to the concepts of ‘privacy’, the 14th amendment is about as simple as constitutional amendments get.  

Edit: I just saw your edit. I think that’s sufficient reasoning because I believe the law should be accessible. The law should mean what it says. If due process can somehow mean privacy, then using similar reasoning all our statutes can be twisted beyond recognition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856238713.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are bits and pieces which could piece together something resembling a ‘right to privacy’, but no enumerated right 

Hardly the first time SCOTUS has done so. And that seems to get to a much deeper question on how to read the Constitution

&amp;gt; It’s insufficient because a plain reading of the 14th amendment doesn’t make any mention to the concepts of ‘privacy’, the 14th amendment is about as simple as constitutional amendments get.

But why is a plain reading the correct one? 

And even if that's correct- why can't one get that from 'liberty/due process'? It's a rather vague/broad term, it doesn't seem insane to read a right to privacy downstream from liberty

And if it's so obvious, why has it been upheld/expanded by several different SCOTUS? This isn't just Roe- Casey, Lawrence, and probably a half dozen other cases have upheld it and expanded it. They've had room to adjust it if need be, even without the constraint of worrying about accidentally upsetting Roe.

In another comment you mentioned people accused Roe of being activism, but I don't know if you can apply that to so many cases over such a long period, with different courts. Roe is but one branch of that.

(And this gets potentially quite deep. Even supposed textualists and the like tend to end up supporting things like strict scrutiny- despite not even being hinted at in the Constitution)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857236861.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>Just because it isn't enumerated doesn't mean it isn't a right.  Something can still be a right even if it wasn't specified.

What if privacy is simply an unenumerated right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857604521.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but no enumerated right as such (unlike the right to bear arms or to vote if you’re over 18

The enumeration in the Constitution, of certain rights, shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people.  


It's right there in the constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857851871.0" user="texashokies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There are bits and pieces which could piece together something resembling a ‘right to privacy’, but no enumerated right as such 

Good thing there is a part of the constitution that explicitly covers rights not enumerated. It's called the 9th amendment which reads: 

"The enumeration in the Constitution, of certain rights, shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858479467.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>In Supreme Court jurisprudence, the 9th amendment isn’t really worth anything. In practice, any right which isn’t explicitly granted, can be taken away in a whim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858716508.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Then your argument is completely circular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858736126.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>My main argument is that it isn’t the court’s place to make new law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858755085.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Specifying a right that is in accordance with our traditions and history is different from making law. I don’t think the government should be allowed into the bedrooms of its citizens to decide who they sleep with, do you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858763660.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t. But if there’s no statute saying so, or a constitutional amendment granting a privacy right. I don’t think a court can safely decide that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858781960.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Then you’d rather the ninth amendment didn’t exist, which is fine, but not really an argument that Roe was wrong. 9A pretty clearly says there are rights not listed below, and the court saw fit to enunciate one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859159587.0" user="eldryanyy" delta="False">
    <text>The 9th amendment doesn’t mean that the court can create new rights at will by interpreting them to be included in the 9A.

Rather, the ninth amendment was added to the Bill of Rights to ensure that the maxim expression unique est exclusion alterius would not be used at a later time to deny fundamental rights merely because they were not specifically enumerated in the Constitution.

This opens the door to LEGISLATION adding amendments to further rights, and not being struck down. It doesn’t give the supreme court the right to interpret all cases and say it’s right/wrong as they see fit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864234646.0" user="sight_ful" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don’t think that’s correct. If rights are added in by amendments, then they are in the constitution at that point. You wouldn’t need an amendment to tell you that other amendments are valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865870022.0" user="eldryanyy" delta="False">
    <text>You need an amendment that tells you that adding amendments is allowed in the constitution... and that those amendments aren’t the sun total of all rights.

That’s literally why the founders included it, and the argument of many supreme court justices. You can disagree with how it’s applied, but that was the intent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867688540.0" user="sight_ful" delta="False">
    <text>How is that the intent when there were already 8 other amendments made before it? Precedent already showed that congress could make amendments, plus it is addressed in article 5 of the constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867953111.0" user="eldryanyy" delta="False">
    <text>Article 5 discusses amending existing articles, not adding articles... those aren’t the same thing.

There weren’t 8 amendments before it - there was one publication of the constitution, with 10 amendments. The last two, 9 and 10, address future additions.. 

The 9th says further rights may be enumerated in the future.

The 10th says that all powers of legislature that aren’t EXPLICITLY GIVEN in the constitution may not be exercised by federal government. That includes laws on family relationships, state laws regarding things not regulated by federal government under constitution authority (such as abortion), etc...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37859166870.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it that you find jurisprudence unsatisfactory to explain a right to privacy, but **do** find it satisfactory to dismiss use of the 9th amendment?

It seems inconsistent to argue that we should be strictly texualist in one case and not the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863599912.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well because the 9th amendment is so vague. A plain reading of the 9th amendment would tell you close to nothing about what rights you actually have. Lawrence Tribe explains that the 9th amendment doesn’t confer any substantive rights, but is more of a rule about how to read the constitution. Given this, it is entire inappropriate to derive substantive rights from it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863867900.0" user="SoftZombie5710" delta="False">
    <text>But that seems to be your interpretation, you're in a minority in this thread, at the very least, and your opinions elsewhere are against the majority.

I feel like you're arguing how you interpret a document vs how others do, your insistence on Roe v Wade is suspect, but whatever</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866688937.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>My example of Roe is deliberate to attract more people to engage. The main thrust of my argument is less on Roe specifically, but on courts reading law in what I consider contrived ways and creating new law. And from there springboard into a discussion on legislative vs judicial lawmaking as well as judicial review. This was partly implicit in my OP. I much prefer laws to be written by congress than by a court.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864521957.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>But Tribe’s interpretation is still just that: an interpretation based not on the actual text of the amendment, but on an implied understanding. You have rejected the idea of implied understanding of the right to privacy, despite “liberty” also being quite vague in the 14th, but accept it here. I don’t think you can reconcile this, you are applying different standards to amendments based on your pre-drawn conclusions.

To put it more simply, why are you willing to go outside of the strict text for the 9th, and not the 14th?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866719666.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>In a plain reading of the 9th amendment, I’d simply consider that I don’t know what rights are retained by the people. And unless congress (by enacting legislation enumerating such rights that the people have) tells me what they are, I can’t make decisions based on unknown information. What I think is egregiously wrong is making up a right to privacy and declaring that the people have this right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867615179.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>But you understand that you are now reading things into the 9th just as much as anyone else is on the 14th right? The 9th isn’t actually that vague. It doesn’t say “you have extra rights as long as congress says so,” a plain reading would indicate that it is recognizing rights that you already retain regardless of congressional action. Your interpretation that additional action is required by the amendment isn’t in line with the text. In fact, I’d argue it’s actually more out of line with the text than arguing that “liberty” can include privacy under the 14th Amendment.

So I’m asking you to be consistent in your interpretation. Either you are a textualist, and the version of the 9th you’ve presented is wrong, or you’re not a textualist, in which case you can’t rely on the “plain language” argument to disprove the right to privacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871796663.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>But here’s the thing. Yes, the 9th amendment is saying you have other rights, but makes no effort to elucidate what those rights are. Because a judge would have no way to know what those ‘other rights’ are, it would be wrong to rule whether something is or isn’t a right under the 9th amendment. Hence, the 9th amendment doesn’t have any use in deciding cases.  

I guess you could say I’m a textualist. But I believe laws should mean what an ‘average person’ would think they mean, and if this leads to some unexpected outcomes, it should be amended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37872276459.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>Why would it be wrong to rule that way under the 9th Amendment? It seems that interpreting it broadly is a logical course given the language in it, no? But we aren’t talking about fully fabricating a right, we’re saying that a right to privacy is a logical inference from several amendments, and the 9th confirms that rights don’t have to be enumerated to exist, so we have legal basis for this broad interpretation.

As to the “average person” test, I fail to see any value in it at all. It seems totally subjective, and I’m not sure that “easy to understand” is a value law should aim to achieve in the first place. Why wouldn’t an “average person” conclude that “liberty” includes privacy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874759228.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Because following a strict and narrow interpretation of any law forces lawmakers to be much more explicit when they want something. The framework for amendment is a damn sight more democratic than 9 justices pulling a ruling from a hat. If congress is forced to declare a right to privacy if they want one, then they’ll also explain what exactly does that entail rather than having the courts guess, or even supplant it with its own idea of how society should look like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37875908199.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not going to allow you to frame this as pulling a right “out of a hat.” You have repeatedly dodged the question about whether “liberty” can be construed to include privacy. 

I’ll address your point about essentially wanting a different legal system later, but I need you to address that first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37878554496.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>The question of ‘liberty’ including a right to privacy is a complex one. On one hand, I could see how someone could read a right to privacy as part of ‘liberty’. But where this runs into difficulty is that ‘liberty’ is so incredibly vague. Can I read into ‘liberty’ a right to wear a top hat while eating hot dogs while riding a unicycle? Probably. But can I read wearing a Halloween terrorist costume and shouting Allahu-Akbar in a crowded theater into ‘liberty’? Probably not. The issue here is that since ‘liberty’ is so incredibly vague, you’re bound to have to rely on other sources of law to determine what actually counts under liberty. As such, the liberty clause of the 14th amendment isn’t very useful in determining what is and isn’t a right. And therefore, I characterize deriving rights from this ‘pulling rights out of a hat’.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37879486391.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The issue here is that since ‘liberty’ is so incredibly vague, you’re bound to have to rely on other sources of law to determine what actually counts under liberty. As such, the liberty clause of the 14th amendment isn’t very useful

This is where I think your analysis consistently falls apart. Why does having to rely on other sources of law to interpret the language in an amendment make it useless? Especially when the other sources of law are in the same legal document (right to privacy is heavily implied by multiple amendments)? 

If you are just going to outright reject sections of the Constitution because they are "vague" then you aren't engaging in Constitutional interpretation anymore, but instead you want a different legal document all together. And that's fine, but it seems that your CMV shouldn't be related to Roe, or Griswold, but instead should be that you want to replace the Constitution with something less vague.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880048008.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not rejecting it per se, I’m just not giving it any weight when trying to analyze what rights any given individual has. Just as the preamble doesn’t give any meaningful direction on what rights we have:  

&amp;gt; We the People of the United States, in Order to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defence, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity, do ordain and establish this Constitution for the United States of America.  

So doesn’t the 9th amendment in trying to discern what an individual’s rights are.  

And partly yes, if I was a supreme court justice I’d rule in such a way that’s so annoying that people’ll have to change how the law is written.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880098226.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I’m not rejecting it per se, I’m just not giving it any weight when trying to analyze what rights any given individual has.

No, you are rejecting it. If you believe that it has no use in judicial interpretation then it may as well not exist. The comparison to the Preamble is faulty; the 9th is part of a section of law which is explicitly limiting Government behavior. The Preamble does not purport to establish law, rather it is a statement of intent.

Can you answer these questions:

&amp;gt;Why does having to rely on other sources of law to interpret the language in an amendment make it useless? Especially when the other sources of law are in the same legal document (right to privacy is heavily implied by multiple amendments)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880124535.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>It’s use is a guideline, as in that there may be rights that people have, and when congress creates a law (not amendment) saying that people have such a right, they can use the 9th amendment to give it legal force (so long as they can prove that people have always had that right).  

&amp;gt; Why does having to use other sources of law…?  

Well, because which sources of law and what reasoning you use heavily influence the outcome. You can easily have a different 9 justices and have them come to the conclusion that we don’t have a right to privacy. However, in the case that we have amendment explicitly saying we have a right to privacy, I think you’d be hard pressed to find any majority out of 9 justices to say we don’t have a right to privacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37880261021.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It’s use is a guideline, as in that there may be rights that people have, and when congress creates a law (not amendment) saying that people have such a right, they can use the 9th amendment to give it legal force (so long as they can prove that people have always had that right).

This is very genuinely all over the place, and wildly outside of the actual language of the amendment, which makes no mention of Congress. I'm not even sure what this: "so long as they can prove that people have always had that right" means. So in your view, the 9th is a guideline which allows Congress to codify additional rights, but despite the literal text of the 9th Congress still has to prove that "people have always had that right?" Does this satisfy your "average person" test? Because I can't seem to justify this view with the language of the Amendment at all.

&amp;gt;You can easily have a different 9 justices and have them come to the conclusion that we don’t have a right to privacy.

Sure, but that's just how our system works. The dirty secret is that those 9 justices can decide basically anything and justify it however they want. This isn't really a good argument for why, specifically, a right to privacy doesn't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863356361.0" user="username_6916" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "The enumeration in the Constitution, of certain rights, shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people."

So, how does one determine such rights? How did abortion get included under this, particularly given the history of laws forbidding abortion after 'the quickening' in English common law?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871288022.0" user="PhineasFurby" delta="False">
    <text>All that means is that the Constitution doesn't have to specifically state a right exists for it to actually exist. But it actually has to exist independent of the Constitution. And there's quite a lot of debate on whether or not any right to privacy does in fact exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858080056.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>In the absence of a separate ruling overturning Griswold, do you believe Roe v Wade is incorrect in treating it as precedent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858459740.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, because the precedent is wrong, and egregiously so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
