<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856242285.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>But the fourteenth amendment does protect the right to Liberty, without really saying what that even is. You could interpret this in a nonsensically narrow way, that Liberty is simply the freedom to literally not be in prison, and so what this means is that the government can't put you in prison without due process. But surely, there are other aspects of liberty, no? Would this mean that the government can't put you in prison without due process, but they can post armed guards outside your house who stop you from leaving? Can they tell you what colour you can or can't paint your house without due process? They can't put you in prison if you paint it the wrong colour, but can they fine your for it without due process? 

The right to privacy is implied in the right to liberty, because without some degree of privacy - without some degree of sovereignty in your own affairs and control over your possessions - liberty cannot exist in any way that actually makes sense. The right to privacy between a woman and her doctor and the woman's right to get an abortion are rights that cannot be infringed without due process, because they are an aspect of liberty. The government may have an interest in restricting abortions - for example if the state thinks that abortion is murder and that preventing murder is good - but that has to be weighed against the right of liberty in the constitution, and the court found that there isn't a sufficient argument in favor of restricting abortion that would makes the state's interest in preventing it greater than the individual right to liberty in this case. 

This isn't to say that the constitution isn't bad, though, you know, smarter people would probably have written what liberty actually means as a concept before just giving people the fundamental right to it, and also, probably they wouldn't do that and own slaves at the same time, if they weren't batshit insane. Roe v. Wade was decided correctly given the interpretation that of the vaguely written constitution that we have been using for centuries, but yes, it would be better to just nail down exactly what the right to liberty means</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37857052803.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The right to privacy between a woman and her doctor and the woman's right to get an abortion are rights that cannot be infringed without due process, because they are an aspect of liberty.

I mean, it is illegal for a doctor to provide euthanasia. There are tons of medical procedures that it is illegal for doctors to provide, but the only one that people seem to really care about is abortion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860688034.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>Making things legal again is a huge undertaking for citizens. Gay marriage was worth the fight. Marijuana was worth the fight. Abortions were worth the fight. These other medical practices might be worth the decade long fight it would take to legalize them but I would need to be shown one that is unjustly banned to consider taking up the cause.

I honestly belive the right to not be forced to suffer daily chronic pain and have access to pain management medicines will be the next big fight. Fighting the opiod crisis was a good cause but it has left millions of America's suffering with legit pain and lowered their quality of life immensely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37861624043.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Marijuana was worth the fight

No it wasn't, and the government should have cracked down harder on recreational drug use, and done so without racial bias.

The point is that it's not a *privacy* issue like proponents of Roe v Wade act like it is. It's a new "right" that was pulled out of nowhere on shaky legal ground - judicial activism at its core. If you want to legalize abortion, don't use the courts to legislate it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864174412.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>Why is recreational drug use inherently bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864218115.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>It's degenerate to society. It's what caused the collapse of the Qing dynasty in China. When all people care about is getting high because they're addicted to recreational drugs, they aren't productive members of society and become a burden.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37864920093.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>No alcohol and caffeine too, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865125084.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>Sure. Fine by me, I don’t use either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865286341.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>Ah. So mind your own business since you don't know what you're talkinf about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865312194.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>Do I have to be a smoker to know that smoking is bad for you? No. Same deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865778982.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>Why is moderate use of THC a bad thing though? I smoke every day and have a nice job and provide for my family. I'm not a drain I actually contribute both through my taxes and my work itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866660175.0" user="AyeItsBooMeR" delta="False">
    <text>Your anecdotal experience means absolutely nothing in this discussion. I know a guy who’s 95 years old and has been smoking since he was in early 20s. Does that mean smoking isn’t bad for people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867066141.0" user="upallnightagain420" delta="False">
    <text>I bet you're real fun at parties.

Show me evidence that the majority of Marijuana smokers leech off the system. Please. It's legal in plenty of states now so the data is out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863886277.0" user="SoftZombie5710" delta="False">
    <text>OP didn't like this answer 😅</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
