<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37857046975.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.

There are plenty of examples throughout history where breaking the law was the right thing to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858512074.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think you understand what Rule of Law means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37860444256.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>Elaborate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863605489.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Rule of law is a legal maxim that suggests that no one is above the law and governmental decisions must be made only by applying known legal and moral principles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865363702.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>What about when legal and moral principles contradict each other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866736130.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Then you change the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866756745.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>What about the meantime? What if the people who write the law simply don't care? Why is the law so important to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37866816343.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Because under the law, everyone is equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867029224.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>You can't be serious.

https://www.aclu.org/press-releases/aclu-analysis-dc-stop-and-frisk-data-reveals-ineffective-policing-troubling-racial

https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2020/09/black-latinx-people-overrepresented-in-massachusetts-prisons-study-says/m

https://www.bmj.com/company/newsroom/fatal-police-shootings-of-unarmed-black-people-in-us-more-than-3-times-as-high-as-in-whites/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867053405.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Under the *law*, everyone is equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37867164321.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>I just showed you 3 examples of the law not treating people equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37871778476.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>That’s people not treating people equal. Not the law not treating people equally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37873021376.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>You're splitting hairs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37874771237.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Important hairs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
