<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854974435.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Clarification, yes I am vaccinated, I got it about as soon as I could

&amp;gt;These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of body autonomy as a core human right

Not everyone who thinks this is anti vax, only 63% *of vaccinated people* supported mandates in a July CNBC poll [https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/04/americans-are-sharply-divided-over-vaccine-mandates-cnbc-survey-shows.html](https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/04/americans-are-sharply-divided-over-vaccine-mandates-cnbc-survey-shows.html)

&amp;gt;There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others
&amp;gt;And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord

There is no right to be free of danger to the maximum extent enforceable, for example people (licensed drivers anyway) have the right to travel by car even for nonessential purposes, even though driving a car always creates a certain amount of risk to those around you

People have the right to be free from warrentless searches, even though arbitrary searches could detect illegal guns or dangerous drugs and therefore contribute to public safety

So the question is not as simple as "does exercising this right expose others to risk" it is really "how important is this right and how much risk does exercising it expose others to?"

&amp;gt;But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide

Different people have different views on this, some do support a right to suicide, but not all. My belief is that informed consent to medical treatment is a core human right, this is really a negative right, a right not to be coerced into vaccination or any other any medical treatment (and to be properly informed of the risks and benefits, but that is not the point of contention here), it is not a positive right to do as you please with your body, and therefore does not apply to suicide 

&amp;gt;But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason

Besides the fact that a right to be free from coerced medical treatment does not apply to suicide, even if there was a right to suicide this would not prevent people from attempting to help a suicidal person any more than a right to freely vote for whichever candidate prevents people from encouraging you to vote a certain way

&amp;gt;If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life

This is not comparable, the pilot was exposing people to an essentially 100% risk of death, which is not the case for unvaccinated people 

&amp;gt;While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative

The idea of a right to informed consent is not limited to antivaxers, it can be found in article 6 of the the UN Universal Declaration on Bioethics and Human Rights https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000146180 

&amp;gt;To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy

Typhoid Mary was claiming a right to work in a high risk industry while knowingly infected, not just claiming a right to be free of coerced medical treatment, this was a compleatly different situation</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
