<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37865439514.0" user="Apathetic_Zealot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly.

This is wrong for 2 reasons which can be given with one answer. Are yo9u familiar with the concept of ["penumbra" law](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penumbra_(law)? It is that certain not explicitly mentioned rights, like privacy, still exist by virtue of other written rights. 

Privacy is the easiest example, the 4th Amend. is clearly about privacy stating that people have a right to their papers and effects from unreasonable search and seizure. Both the 5th and 14th Amend mention you shall not "be deprived of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law". This again points to the direction that privacy, ones body and property are not something the government can easily circumvent. Furthermore the 9th states that just because a right isn't listed in the Constitution does not mean it can be deprived from the people.

When it come to abortion the privacy of ones medical history is so important it's part of the doctors oath of service as well as law. So I think it's clear the Constitution does recognize the right to privacy and abortion is a private medical procedure.

&amp;gt;Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’

The SCOTUS is law. And it's far more expedient than a Constitutional Amendment. We shouldn't need an amendment to codify every major ruling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
