<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37856300452.0" user="masterzora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’)

There's no real reasonable way the Fourth could have decided Griswold in the manner you suggest. There were no actual searches or seizures in question in that case. The bedroom searches referenced were purely hypothetical, for the purpose of demonstrating the "repulsiveness" of the relevant parts of Comstock.

Also, even if there had been such a search in that case and they did use the Fourth to rule such searches unreasonable, that could potentially have served as grounds for disallowing certain warrants, but would not have been grounds to strike down the law or even rule it entirely unenforceable. This is not necessarily an argument against a particular ruling itself--judges are not *supposed to* make an incorrect ruling just to reach an outcome they prefer--but it means there likely still would have been a ruling on Comstock itself eventually, so an argument based on something more than "unreasonable search and seizure" would still have eventually been needed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
