<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562492579.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pu9mzn/cmv_body_autonomy_is_not_a_human_right_where_it/">
    <title>CMV: Body autonomy is not a human right where it conflicts with other human rights</title>
    <original_poster>redhighways</original_poster>
    <original_post>  These days the go-to argument by many antivax activists one based on the idea of *body autonomy* as a core human right.

There is an old adage that your right to swing your arm ends where my nose begins. This is a way of saying that rights have limitations: specifically where they infringe upon the rights of others. 

And that, alone, should be enough to quiet vaccination discord. Because being unvaccinated in a pandemic that has brought the world to a shuddering halt is, essentially, swinging your arm around in a crowded room like a five year old child, and acting surprised when there are nosebleeds and disconcerted people around you. 

But I’m more curious about the implication of body autonomy, as a quintessential human right, and how that bleeds over into the philosophy of suicide. 

We’ve all heard the statistic, that every single Golden Gate Bridge jumper who survived says they ‘instantly regretted’ jumping. They say at that moment, they realised every other problem in their life could be fixed, except jumping. 

But the antivax crowd is leaning on the idea of a human right that, by extension, would mean that we should not, and in fact, cannot, help people who want to commit suicide, at any age, for any reason. 

I find that absurd. Especially considering all of the research showing just how impulsive the act of suicide is generally considered by psychologists to be. Something like 90% of suicide survivors do not die from suicide later. Further evidence that it is not a decision they’d make twice. 

While it can’t be denied there are considerable pressures, political and otherwise, pushing an antivax narrative, which is inevitably going to be picked up by some proportion of the population, I think it’s worth addressing what seems at first glance to be the bedrock assumptions behind their logic. 

If we all have the right to suicide, at any time, and this right supercedes all other rights, then the pilot of MH370 was morally superior to someone who gets vaccinated due to a mandate, because his right to suicide was greater than the rights of all of his passengers to life. 

To CMV, I guess I'd need someone to explain a moral system where a Typhoid Mary was the good guy.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37854538476.0" user="Quentanimobay" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest I thought you were going to go in a whole other direction likening not getting the covid vaccination to suicide doesn't really serve much of a purpose. I think in comparison infringing on someone else rights is a much better angle but generally still a hard sell. 

 Body autonomy is a very complex subject, especially in the modern age were (most people) feel morally compelled to keep people alive. The problem is where do we draw the line between providing someone a helpful service and taking away someone's right to body autonomy (and yes, in many cases that right is maintained). 

Honestly, suicide is a bad parallel for covid vaccinations. Suicide has more to do with mental health and mental health issues is one of more complicated issues where a person may lose quite a few of their rights. Here are some better examples:

Someone is seriously injured or is facing a life threatening diseases. That person has the right to deny all medical intervention (provided they are of sound mind) even knowing that they will die as a result.

Someone can heavily smoke cigarettes or excessively drink alcohol despite significant risk of life threatening diseases. 

Someone can become morbidly obese despite significant risk of life threatening diseases. 

These all are cases where the right to body autonomy is preserved despite the extremely well known risks death and these are only a few examples out of many more.

However, it's important to note that body autonomy is often pushed to the side when it comes to safety while doing something that you do not have a guaranteed right to do. For example, almost all states now have seat belt laws that legally require you to wear a seat belt when driving a car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37855079200.0" user="redhighways" delta="False">
    <text>None of the examples, like obesity, or even seatbelts, addresses the fact that unvaccinated people are dangerous to everyone around them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856360271.0" user="StuffyKnows2Much" delta="False">
    <text>Untrue. Unvaccinated people *with a Covid infection* perhaps, but in that case the “unvaccinated” qualifier is useless, as vaccinated people can get and transmit Covid as well</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37856956848.0" user="Quentanimobay" delta="False">
    <text>They were examples about in regards to body autonomy and will fulfill risk of death which the majority of your point is centered around. Unvaccinated people being a risk to others has less to do with being unvaccinated in and of itself but more to do with what they do while unvaccinated which is a different issue and than most of your post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
