<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441433900.0" user="angrystoic" delta="False">
    <text>Do you really think that physically torturing an individual is going to be beneficial for a victim? You think that will bring them peace? You think that is the best thing for them?

I don't see this being the case, in the short-term or in the long-term. I don't think inflicting physical pain on someone is going to be good for their mental health and recovery. 

And if it's not, then there is no good justification for it to be legally permissible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441476734.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>I do believe in some cases it would help the victim, which is why I believe it should be their decision to make knowing the possible long-term benefits or ill effects on their own mental well-being. My whole point is that the victim should be put in that position of power over his/her assailant. There are those who argue that no one would ever truly feel fulfilled from enacting revenge in such a way, but I tend to see that as the rationalization they come to when they cannot personally fathom undergoing those actions. Plenty of people would jump at the opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441520696.0" user="angrystoic" delta="False">
    <text>I don't doubt that many would jump at the opportunity. It certainly seems to be a natural instinct of ours to want to enact revenge. But that doesn't mean that it is the best way, or even a good way, to overcome the anguish brought about by being victimized. 

I suppose it would need to be scientifically studied if we were to come to a conclusive answer. And perhaps it has been-- I'll look for something when I have the chance. But I think we can be virtually certain that those who find it within themselves to forgive are going to have a better chance to overcome their situation than those who brutally assault a powerless individual. And it seems to me that the two are mutually exclusive.

In any case, I think that we should discourage people from seeking brutal violence as a form of therapy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441580061.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. I believe giving them the opportunity to have control of the "helpless individual" will allow them to overcome their own feelings of helplessness and victimization caused by said person. As previously mentioned, I believe it is the opportunity that should be made available so the victim can decide whether or not to go through with it. 

Even at that, I don't necessarily believe forgiveness is as necessary a component of moving on with life as acceptance and understanding are, and I don't believe retaliation would deter anyone from acceptance or understanding. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441676623.0" user="justalittlebitmore" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I do believe in some cases it would help the victim, which is why I believe it should be their decision to make knowing the possible long-term benefits or ill effects on their own mental well-being.

Do you think it's going to be good for them when the guilty party gets out of prison in 10/15/20 years and goes to hunt down the person who tortured them? Considering they've already proven they're okay with violent crime. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441911037.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing is stopping them from coming after them to begin with, especially if there sentence is lengthy and they have time to boil with contempt for their victims.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442505389.0" user="justalittlebitmore" delta="False">
    <text>That's not a counter argument at all. Increasing that chance is the point I'm making, it can't just be dismissed as "it happens anyway". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27443634694.0" user="BrawndoTTM" delta="False">
    <text>In that case, slavery (literally enslaving the perpetrator to be the victim's property) would be both more humane and more useful to the victims. Would you support this as an alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
