<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441737654.0" user="eienseiryuu" delta="False">
    <text>Remember emotions run high in serious crime. What if a young man say age 18 is driving. He hits and kills a young child because he's an unexperienced driver and mistakes happen. What then? Do you ruin this 18 year old's life? Torture is beyond physical afflictions; it inflicts mental trauma as well. 

Distraught parents may wish to have revenge on the man. Do you think this is out of their reasonable demand under your conditions? What if the driver was sober/drunk? Does that change things? Even if he's underage drinking and driving, do you think destroying his life completely for a foolish youthful mistake is right? This is why we do not deal with cruel and unusual punishments in the USA. People make mistakes, we punish them and try to rehabilitate them. Torturing this man would do absolutely nothing to rehabilitate him.

(As a note, in some states reckless homicide is punishable by multiple years in prison of up to over a decade. It is a serious crime regardless of how "innocent" it may feel)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441909829.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>A mistake is asking a fat woman when the baby is due. A mistake is not intentionally drinking alcohol and getting behind the wheel of a car, and if you are old enough to make that decision you are old enough to face the consequences. As far as an accident* taking place that results in a life being lost, I believe it should be treated as an accident and nothing of the sort should take place. I specified a few times that I've restricted my opinions to the intentional, severe offenders who make a conscious effort to take/cause great harm to the life of another, not someone who fucked up due to bad luck.

I believe rehabilitating people who deserve it is a wonderful think, but I do not feel previous mentioned offenders deserve to be or even can be rehabilitated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441995051.0" user="toaadrian55" delta="False">
    <text>mis·take
məˈstāk/Submit
noun
1.
an action or judgment that is misguided or wrong.

Despite what you think is a mistake, drunk driving is still a mistake.

I don't think you understand. If a teen got drunk and did vehicular 
manslaughter, does he/she deserve torture? What does it solve? Psychologists have already concluded that getting revenge doesn't do anything but mentally harm the person who did the revenge, almost like a drug. A quick release of dopamine, and then nothing. Jack shit. Except knowing that you legit tortured someone in your lifetime.  Also, no one here is saying that people shouldn't face the consequences. They are saying that torture is not a suitable consequence. How in the hell is a torture a suitable consequence for vehicular manslaughter? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442106022.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure why you, and others, continue to point to situations that I stated I wasn't including. I'm talking about high level violent crimes with the intent to cause harm. This is purely hypothetical. For as absolutely disgusting as drinking and drinking is, I don't consider it to be the same type of crime as murder, rape, etc. 

Nothing you do is going to change the past. Forgiveness will not change the past, nor acceptance, nor revenge. Torturing someone now to show them what it is like to be made a victim and rid yourself of those urges, to dispense your own form of punishment, does not mean you cannot move on with your life later. As difficult as it is to understand for some people, not everyone places a high value on the life of the person who victimized them, and it's fucked up to expect them to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442291032.0" user="toaadrian55" delta="False">
    <text>Here. Let me make my cumulative point. 

Torturing a person is not how you get them to change. Pain=hate. Not fear.

Revenge is a disease. Or as I described it earlier, a drug. Imagine if we gave people the legal means to take out revenge on people. It would lead to naught. Imagine that the person who killed your girlfriend is sitting in a room in front of you. He chose to do it out of shear anger, and now it is time for the torture. You sit there, watching as the hot metal burns his skin. He cries out in agony. Again and again. As the time ends. You can see him sitting there with not fear, not anguish, but a chilling glare. Simple discomfort, as he is dragged off, you can see him picking at the raw flesh on his body.

You go home. You lay in bed, trying to remember your girlfriends face when you realize that you can't remember it. NO. You can't. remember. All you can remember is him. You can't stop thinking about him. It's become less about HER and more about the MURDERER. And as you sit there realizing how fixated you've become. You can feel him mocking you. He screamed in pain, and then said nothing. He knew IT! He KNEW WHAT WAS HAPPENING. As you sit there, in a wreck, trying to pull yourself together, trying to remember her, you realize that it did nothing. You feel no closure. You only feel...him.

That was an accurate representation of a mental breakdown based on the accounts of people who had gotten revenge on rapists, murderers, etc. by similar means (except those weren't legal)

For my last point.

&amp;gt;Torturing someone now to show them what it is like to be made a victim and rid yourself of those urges

&amp;gt;Show them What it is like to be made a victim and rid yourself of those

&amp;gt;What is like to be made a victim 

&amp;gt;To be made a victim

&amp;gt;victim

For every victim, there is a victimizer. 



tldr; Wow my mom's dead
well at least i got to see a guy get tortured </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
