<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441593200.0" user="BobHogan" delta="False">
    <text>Just to quote the Constitution here 

&amp;gt;Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines imposed, **nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted**

Torture would most definitely fall under either cruel, unusual, or both. Therefor it is unconstitutional. Thus there is no circumstance in which torture would be ok in any stretch of the imagination, as long as you live in the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441608232.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>Which is the basis for my entire argument. I disagree with the constitutions excluding it as a potential sentence for severe offenses. I'm not debating the fact that it is currently unconstitutional, I'm arguing that it should be accepted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441631007.0" user="BobHogan" delta="False">
    <text>Fine, you get your way, torture is no longer against the constitution. So what happens next? Imagine someone was caught speeding and given a ticket. Now there is nothing stopping the judge from giving them torture as a sentence. There is nothing in the constitution forbidding it anymore. Would it happen? Probably not. But could it happen? Most definitely. And where would it stop? You can't say torture should be constitutional simply because you are a violent person, it would have incredibly horrendous side effects that you have apparently give zero thought to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441917705.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>I've said many times now that in this purely hypothetical that obviously has many kinks in the real world that I am limiting my comments to severe offenders, not whatever low-level misdemeanors you want to cherry pick. I'm not an inherently violent person, I prefer rehabilitating the fixable, but paying evil onto evil when you cannot.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
