<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441978448.0" user="toaadrian55" delta="False">
    <text>This is the exact opposite of what justice is. It's not revenge. It's punishment and sometimes simply removing people from society. I'm sorry, but if you would want to torture someone because they killed your mom, then you might have a future in crime or some type of mental illness. The only time TORTURE should ever, ever be used is to get something out of people. Something monumental and extremely important. Something that could save hundreds or more of lives. Just imagine this. You were raped. How is knowing that even more physical pain took place calming? Does it unrape you? No. It just spends more tax dollars on some juvenile form of closure that isn't even closure because right after they torture the person they will still be sent to jail, and still be alive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442094491.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>Important to who? Someone raping my mother is important to me, and her, and the rest of my family. I never claimed it would unrape her, or me, or anyone else, but it would make me feel a whole lot better knowing I get to choose a suitable punishment and inflict proportionate harm on them as opposed to having strangers decide how much time my mothers suffering translates to behind bars.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
