<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441443544.0" user="dale_glass" delta="False">
    <text>"Beyond a reasonable doubt" is the standard for a criminal conviction. The system is clearly imperfect, and wrongful convictions happen constantly. So what should happen if a family member tortures an innocent? Does the exonerated one gain the right to torture them back?

Also, that's more than a million and half people right now, all of which could be tortured, and many of which will be released eventually. Don't you think it's a bit of a bad idea? You'd have it all, from people broken to the point of losing function and becoming unable to reintegrate into society, to people who will thirst for horrible revenge on those family members.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
