<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441582869.0" user="NaturalSelectorX" delta="False">
    <text>Torture causes it's own form of trauma. What happens when a sentence is overturned? Does the victim of the torture get to torture the prosecutor or the one who tortured them?

Also, for what crimes is torture an option? Rape can just be a guy who had sex with a drunk girl who wasn't sober enough to consent; does that deserve torture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441613315.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>We don't typically arrest those responsible for the sentencing of someone who is later proven to be innocent, I don't see why this should be any different in the unlikely circumstance something is found out later. At the time, the facts were such that guilt was assumed. 

Specifically addressing your question, rape is rape. If someone is too stupid to know fucking someone who cannot consent is completely wrong, they should have to face consequences from the victim proportional to how much trauma the victim experiences when they come to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442642517.0" user="NaturalSelectorX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We don't typically arrest those responsible for the sentencing of someone who is later proven to be innocent, I don't see why this should be any different in the unlikely circumstance something is found out later. At the time, the facts were such that guilt was assumed.

When a person is sentenced, the state is carrying out the punishment. When a conviction is overturned, the state pays restitution to the wrongly convicted.

In this case, a private individual is carrying out the punishment. If the conviction is overturned, then the private individual would be on the hook for restitution. Since we have established that heinous acts can include torture as a form of restitution, and torture is a heinous act, then the wrongly convicted person ought to be able to torture the person that tortured them.

&amp;gt; they should have to face consequences from the victim proportional to how much trauma the victim experiences when they come to.

How do you accurately measure trauma?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
