<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441608337.0" user="insurrecto" delta="False">
    <text>The Bill of Rights prohibits "cruel and unusual punishments" (torture). This is prohibited because England tortured thousands of prisoners. You should read about some of the torture devices that were used. They are truly horrible. 

Even criminals have the right to be treated humanely. Also, torturing criminals does not help victims with the grieving process.

As the saying goes, with an eye for an eye, the whole world goes blind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441618624.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are truly horrible.

Yes, I'm counting on it. A hot poker for a child molester seems particularly fitting.

&amp;gt;Even criminals have the right to be treated humanely

Without citing laws, why? Why should someone who purposely victimized and changed the life of an innocent be treated humanely? Treat others the way you wish to be treated. It can hardly be said that we would drop to their level paying a proportionate amount of crime on to someone who clearly deserves it. We wouldn't be harming someone out of the blue, as they did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441647421.0" user="insurrecto" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, I'm counting on it. A hot poker for a child molester seems particularly fitting.

Based on your comments in this thread, it seems like your motivation for torture is based on seeking revenge. The problem that you are failing to understand is that no amount of torture can undo the crime that has been committed.

The criminal justice system is not designed to provide revenge for the victims. It is designed to isolate dangerous criminals from the rest of society and eventually rehabilitate them so that they can join the rest of society after serving their prison sentence.

&amp;gt;Why should someone who purposely victimized and changed the life of an innocent be treated humanely?

What you are failing to realize is that torture has been used for thousands of years in other societies. It is ineffective. Torturing people does not prevent crime. 

The modern justice system is focused on rehabilitating criminals, not punishing and seeking revenge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441662226.0" user="insurrecto" delta="False">
    <text>Here are some arguments written by a man who actually witnessed torture:

&amp;gt;James Wilson lectured on justice and punishments, saying in 1791, “A nation [that tolerates] cruel punishments becomes dastardly and contemptible. For in nations, as well as individuals, cruelty is always attended by cowardice.” He argued that punishments should be swift, certain, and moderate in order to be effective and prevent further crime.

http://billofrightsinstitute.org/resources/educator-resources/americapedia/americapedia-bill-of-rights/eighth-amendment/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441912584.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>One mans moral objections do not speak for the populace. I strongly disagree that torturing someone who has physically/psychologically tortured you to be cowardly. Likely, it would take a great deal of strength.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441980525.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I strongly disagree that torturing someone who has physically/psychologically tortured you to be cowardly. Likely, it would take a great deal of strength.

...Why would it take strength to do what your reptile brain wants to do out of revenge?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
