<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156956555.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2lg4gb/cmv_the_campaigning_to_discourage_shopping_on/">
    <title>CMV: The campaigning to discourage shopping on Thanksgiving is not necessarily the morally correct thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>championofobscurity</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen and heard several times this week the phrase "If I'm shopping on Thanksgiving someone is working." I don't think this campaign stands justified on it's own for several reasons.

1.) It assumes 100% of people don't want to work on Thanksgiving, and is a discredit to the people who do want to work as a minority.

2.) It assumes everyone celebrates Thanksgiving or has someone to celebrate it with. For some people this can be just another day as any other, and so the holiday inconveniences these folks at the very least.

3.) Tearing away those two things, It also may not get in the way of the holiday for the people who do and want to celebrate for them to work, and they get some nifty or needed holiday pay for their trouble meaning that it's not always a net negative for people that do have to work.

To conclude, the campaigning not to shop on Thanksgiving is not necessarily inherently righteous or positive, and from a moral standpoint might even be negatively affecting the lives of certain people if it gains any ground with the general public.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27442362730.0" user="heelspider" delta="False">
    <text>The US is a nation of immigrants, and as a result, its a fairly diverse mix of cultures, religions, races, and backgrounds.  The few things that are uniquely American and open to everyone are therefore important as things that keep us together and unified.

If you think about it, we really only have two major holidays with a rich tradition that are national (i.e. not religious) in nature, Independence Day and Thanksgiving.  It may not be obvious, but there's a value gained by keeping Thanksgiving as an important, shared, unifying experience.

Frankly, I'm glad there's a few gas stations or grocery stores open on that day because people forget things until the last moment, need to travel, etc.  But this new trend of starting Black Friday sales on Thanksgiving takes it too far.  When stores offer low prices on Thanksgiving, it literally gives people a financial incentive to abandon holiday tradition.

The expected result is less time spent with families and friends and less time experiencing an American tradition.  The new then becomes all about capitalism; in other words, just like every other day of the year.

I don't know if attempts to preserve Thanksgiving could necessarily be called moral or righteous, per se, but it is a cause which has at least some merit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442369450.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;The few things that are uniquely American and open to everyone are therefore important as things that keep us together and unified.

I don't really see the value in this. Patriotism is highly overrated and even alarmingly unpopular these days. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Thanksgiving. It may not be obvious, but there's a value gained by keeping Thanksgiving as an important, shared, unifying experience.

This is ambiguous at best.


&amp;gt;&amp;gt; But this new trend of starting Black Friday sales on Thanksgiving takes it too far. When stores offer low prices on Thanksgiving, it literally gives people a financial incentive to abandon holiday tradition.

For my family black Friday is an adventure. In fact I'd say we have just as much fun on black Friday together as we do on Thanksgiving. Our festivities wrap up at about 7 and we take off for the night looking for Christmas deals, and where we live things are a lot more civilized and reasonable than years passed so it's not exactly unsafe either.  


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442386985.0" user="heelspider" delta="False">
    <text>How can patriotism be both valueless and alarmingly unpopular?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
