<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156956555.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2lg4gb/cmv_the_campaigning_to_discourage_shopping_on/">
    <title>CMV: The campaigning to discourage shopping on Thanksgiving is not necessarily the morally correct thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>championofobscurity</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen and heard several times this week the phrase "If I'm shopping on Thanksgiving someone is working." I don't think this campaign stands justified on it's own for several reasons.

1.) It assumes 100% of people don't want to work on Thanksgiving, and is a discredit to the people who do want to work as a minority.

2.) It assumes everyone celebrates Thanksgiving or has someone to celebrate it with. For some people this can be just another day as any other, and so the holiday inconveniences these folks at the very least.

3.) Tearing away those two things, It also may not get in the way of the holiday for the people who do and want to celebrate for them to work, and they get some nifty or needed holiday pay for their trouble meaning that it's not always a net negative for people that do have to work.

To conclude, the campaigning not to shop on Thanksgiving is not necessarily inherently righteous or positive, and from a moral standpoint might even be negatively affecting the lives of certain people if it gains any ground with the general public.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27442369665.0" user="ulyssessword" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it have to be 100% of workers being inconvenienced?  If a store has 10 employees working, and 9 of them are forced to work on Thanksgiving (the other one wants to), then it's still bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27443028912.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Why?  For me, it comes down to need.  You don't need to take a day off, you want to.  The worker who wants to work might need the money. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
