<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156956555.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2lg4gb/cmv_the_campaigning_to_discourage_shopping_on/">
    <title>CMV: The campaigning to discourage shopping on Thanksgiving is not necessarily the morally correct thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>championofobscurity</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen and heard several times this week the phrase "If I'm shopping on Thanksgiving someone is working." I don't think this campaign stands justified on it's own for several reasons.

1.) It assumes 100% of people don't want to work on Thanksgiving, and is a discredit to the people who do want to work as a minority.

2.) It assumes everyone celebrates Thanksgiving or has someone to celebrate it with. For some people this can be just another day as any other, and so the holiday inconveniences these folks at the very least.

3.) Tearing away those two things, It also may not get in the way of the holiday for the people who do and want to celebrate for them to work, and they get some nifty or needed holiday pay for their trouble meaning that it's not always a net negative for people that do have to work.

To conclude, the campaigning not to shop on Thanksgiving is not necessarily inherently righteous or positive, and from a moral standpoint might even be negatively affecting the lives of certain people if it gains any ground with the general public.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27442341191.0" user="KrustyFrank27" delta="False">
    <text>But for me to shop on Thanksgiving, I would need to know that everyone working wanted to be there to earn the holiday pay or because they had no family to go home to.  A local shop might be run by that one single guy with no family, but I'm sure that most of those Best Buy employees would rather be home with their families.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442349596.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>You can't know that one way or the other. This is definitely a situation where you can't have your cake and eat it too, but I think that it's globally more useful to let people work than it is to campaign for the opposite, especially since the campaigning essentially wants to deny millions of people an opportunity to work for a holiday they may not care about, especially in such a country as the United States where holiday celebration is incredibly multi-faceted. 

That is to say, for the few people that have to work a holiday every couple years, it's a greater benefit to enable people who want to work every holiday every year a chance to work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442352819.0" user="stevegcook" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's pretty safe to say that the vast majority of store workers would like to have holidays off.  Obviously there will be exceptions no matter what you do, but on the whole it makes a lot of sense. 


Essentially, you are either allowing group A to be home for a holiday at the expense of forcing group B to not be working, or you're allowing group B to work at the expense of forcing group A to work when they'd rather be home with family.   And group A is vastly bigger. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442358716.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>This is strikingly anecdotal. Do you have any proof that this is even remotely the case? Also, for the people who lose the opportunity to work,  closing the store for a holiday could be the difference between making rent or not, especially since these jobs pay what they do. I'm not really looking to entertain the discussion of making the jobs pay such that holidays are a thing, because that is tangential to the issue, however.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442395198.0" user="stevegcook" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have statistical evidence, if that's what you're looking for.  However, I've worked in retail and foodservice for a combined 9 years, and that's been the general impression I've gotten from the people I've worked with.  

Also, in just about every developed country in the world except the US, holiday pay is mandatory for full-time employees who would otherwise be working on that day.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442354948.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;globally more useful 

Thanksgiving is really only celebrated in 4 countries, and of those the United States is the only one with a campaign to stop people from shopping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442359266.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't this reinforce my point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442361831.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, really. I think it's absolutely pointless to tell people not to shop on a holiday you celebrate. It's pretty much the same thing as telling people not to work on the 5th of June because your grandmother is coming to town. 

I wouldn't say that the campaigning has a global influence, or even a regional one. If people need to shop, they're going to shop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442364368.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know, it's just gaining a lot of steam from various points in my social circle as a thing. I just don't agree with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442365889.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't worry about it. Even if they get the majority of the population on board, the stores will remain open.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442582190.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>You're presenting a false dichotomy here, as though our only two options are "everyone works" and "no one works."

I have no problem with a store staying open and allowing the employees who want to work to work. I have a problem when a store mandates that employees come in regardless of their personal feelings about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442718182.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is, imagine that a simple store needs to have 20 people working over the course of 24 hours. If only ten people want to work on Thanksgiving, it *does* come down to no one works or people who don't want to must work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442723698.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is to remove the need to have those people working, so you can do the work with only 10.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442728918.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>That's not always possible. I work at a coffee shop, and we get a large volume of customers, so we usually need ~30 people working over a 24-hour period. If we could work with 1/3 of the employees that we currently have, I'm sure my boss would love the money she'd save by paying a third of the wages she does now. But that's simply not possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442766277.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, because there is a "large volume of customers" right? So the aim of these campaigns is to *reduce the volume of customers* on and around Thanksgiving so stores do not require as many employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442801011.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>If we're going to get so few customers throughout the day that we can survive easily with a third of our usual employees (again, over 24 hours. That's roughly 3 employees working every shift), then we're probably not getting enough money to afford the electricity we use or the products that we make and throw away that day since no one's buying them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442813263.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The shopping around Black Friday necessitates *extra* employees in a lot of cases. Your everyday coffee shop scenario is completly different. If a shop can stay open during the day on a normal weekday, it could afford to be open on Black Friday for a typical "day off" shopping crowd.

The current system actively encourages people to shop specifically on that day - increasing the normal volume of customers and requiring more employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442829464.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest, I hadn't even considered Black Friday until you just mentioned it. I'm from Canada, so when people here complain about having to work on Thanksgiving, it's not really significantly different from complaining about working on a Friday before a long weekend. Taking this from an American perspective only, I agree with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442832632.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, yes. As far as I can tell the aim is to turn Black Friday into more like a Saturday. Where maybe a few people will shop but hey maybe close if you want!

Instead it's a total shopping mess, and is bleeding into Thanksgiving itself. People are actively encouraged to not eat dinner with their families and instead work retail until the early hours of the morning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442581364.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is that people who would rather be spending time with their families should be able to. Often retail workers are required to go in - sometimes even *on* Thanksgiving - regardless of their personal feelings on the matter.

Encouraging people to not shop on black friday reduces the need for that. Nobody is saying stores have to close and force no one to work. We only want to make it so people who don't want to work don't have to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27443429575.0" user="MistressFey" delta="False">
    <text>The post isn't about black Friday, it's about Thanksgiving. The movement is to stop stores opening on the Holiday itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27443438620.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>It's about black Friday shopping, which starts on Thanksgiving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442468013.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>What about Friday night? Or Saturday? Do you not shop or go to restaurants on those days either just in case one of the employees didn't want to be there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27442731262.0" user="KrustyFrank27" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't avoid shopping on those days, because they aren't designated as a holiday.  I'm sure that there are people who don't want to work any day of the year, but I'm also sure that a vast majority of people don't want to work on Thanksgiving, so I don't want to shop that day.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
