<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1591671739.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qbn1rv/cmv_the_nestle_ceo_video_that_is_currently_viral/">
    <title>CMV: The nestle CEO video that is currently viral on reddit is not that damaging to nestle or the CEO.</title>
    <original_poster>CMThomas25</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now don't get me wrong you would want as an achievement for society, all humans to have access to clean water. Whether you see this as a human right is down to how you define rights, one way of looking at rights which I assume how the CEO looks at them is that human rights are natural to humans and can be only taken away by government decrees such as freedom of speech or freedom to express your religious beliefs. If you look at rights this way that means that no one has a right to a commodity which someone else owns. This doesn't mean that you support people not having water it just means that you don't give the green light for the government to start controlling the commodity as it could use human rights as a justification.

I think what this debate boils down to is whether or not water should be nationalised.

 I think privatised water with no government assured monopolies to any company is a more efficient way of doing things as market prices is a large factor in what determines how much of something is produced. Also it gives the consumers more choice, imagine if there was only one brand of government owned water that they put chemicals in like Dasani, you wouldn't want to drink that so you would hope that you would be able to buy another brand that meets your needs as a consumer.

Edit: As u/ytzi13 points out I mean that I personally don't see a problem with his statement rather than saying that people won't react badly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38055961097.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>But Nestle DOES frequently monopolize the local water source. That’s the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
