<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1591671739.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qbn1rv/cmv_the_nestle_ceo_video_that_is_currently_viral/">
    <title>CMV: The nestle CEO video that is currently viral on reddit is not that damaging to nestle or the CEO.</title>
    <original_poster>CMThomas25</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now don't get me wrong you would want as an achievement for society, all humans to have access to clean water. Whether you see this as a human right is down to how you define rights, one way of looking at rights which I assume how the CEO looks at them is that human rights are natural to humans and can be only taken away by government decrees such as freedom of speech or freedom to express your religious beliefs. If you look at rights this way that means that no one has a right to a commodity which someone else owns. This doesn't mean that you support people not having water it just means that you don't give the green light for the government to start controlling the commodity as it could use human rights as a justification.

I think what this debate boils down to is whether or not water should be nationalised.

 I think privatised water with no government assured monopolies to any company is a more efficient way of doing things as market prices is a large factor in what determines how much of something is produced. Also it gives the consumers more choice, imagine if there was only one brand of government owned water that they put chemicals in like Dasani, you wouldn't want to drink that so you would hope that you would be able to buy another brand that meets your needs as a consumer.

Edit: As u/ytzi13 points out I mean that I personally don't see a problem with his statement rather than saying that people won't react badly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38051049942.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>You need to look at the distinction between a [natural right and a legal right](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_rights_and_legal_rights).

&amp;gt; If you look at rights this way that means that no one has a right to a commodity which someone else owns. 

Ownership is not a natural human right, it is a legal one. The concept of an owned "commodity" is established by the laws that enforce that status. In nature, if I can take something that is in your possession, it then becomes mine. The only thing stopping me from doing that in our world are the laws that punish me for doing so.

When people speak of right to water, it is taken to be a natural right, not a legal one. The problem with the CEO's statements is that natural rights are considered beyond any outright dismissal by any government or authority. Any legal attempts to curtail natural rights are supposed to be strictly controlled; for instance, that's why governments have got thorough mandatory legal proceedings so that a natural right (right to freedom) can be curtailed by a legal right (laws against crime). 

Nestle's activities don't have such controls. To make it worse, there is a strong argument for not ceding any legal ownership at all, since several developed nations have better tap water than bottled water, indicating that there is little public good to be gained by private ownership. This is why nationalizing water supplies is in favor even in more capitalistic economies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38051247686.0" user="CMThomas25" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the distinction you are making but as far as I understand water is not a natural right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38051317618.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>How is it not a natural right?

In context of actual law, it is not a right at all. In context of the people who consider it a right, it is a natural right, same as all our basic necessities. 

Considering it a mere legal right beats the point of making it a right, since the only reason for a right to water is because everyone should have access to water, and legal rights are quite easy to tamper with for such access to exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38051343069.0" user="CMThomas25" delta="False">
    <text>From Wikipedia:

"Under the theory of positive and negative rights, a negative right is a right not to be subjected to an action of another person or group—a government, for example—usually in the form of abuse or coercion. As such, negative rights exist unless someone acts to negate them. A positive right is a right to be subjected to an action of another person or group. In other words, for a positive right to be exercised, someone else's actions must be added to the equation. In theory, a negative right forbids others from acting against the right holder, while a positive right obligates others to act with respect to the right holder. In the framework of the Kantian categorical imperative, negative rights can be associated with perfect duties while positive rights can be connected to imperfect duties."

"Rights considered positive rights, as initially proposed in 1979 by the Czech jurist Karel Vašák, may include other civil and political rights such as police protection of person and property and the right to counsel, as well as economic, social and cultural rights such as food, housing, public education, employment, national security, military, health care, social security, internet access, and a minimum standard of living. In the "three generations" account of human rights, negative rights are often associated with the first generation of rights, while positive rights are associated with the second and third generations."

Am I misunderstanding these paragraphs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38052893719.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand how you arrived at that. We were talking about natural and legal rights, when and where do positive and negative rights come into the picture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38053866795.0" user="Cease-2-Desist" delta="False">
    <text>You never clarified the difference between natural and legal rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38052000797.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>Water is not a natural right because natural rights don't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
