<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27473392228.0" user="carrier_mobility" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you accept that this is a trend that needs to be regulated, the offense is against YouTube and therefore should be regulated by that entity, not Reddit.

Plus, that shit is hilarious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473684421.0" user="merreborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the offense is against YouTube and therefore should be regulated by that entity, not Reddit.

There's an ongoing campaign to destroy reddit, undertaken by the likes of /r/shitredditsays and /r/redditbomb (which [have ties to SomethingAwful](https://web.archive.org/web/20111016020657/http://forums.somethingawful.com/showthread.php?threadid=3440583) [[see also](http://forums.somethingawful.com/showthread.php?threadid=3459512)]) -- this is the campaign that lead to Anderson Cooper's report on r/jailbait, bringing national attention to reddit's seedy underbelly, if you will.  The general goal has been to paint reddit as a haven of pedophiles, misogynists, racists, etc.

The example comment linked in the OP is suspiciously in-line with that agenda.

I don't think it's hard to argue that reddit would be better off *not* being smeared with a false reputation for being a hub for "neckbeard" pedophiles -- and thus that reddit has some interest in not supporting the activities of /r/redditarmie and the like.  However the ban the OP calls for may not be an appropriate means to that end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473984473.0" user="bluemills" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, there is some truth to it. The only reason /r/jailbait was shut down was due to subreddits and websites like SRS, Reddit was aware of it well before that and only shut it down due to the media shitstorm. The users never really left the site and can be found on pretty much every picture or link mentioning an underage teenage girl, defending sex with children. They are also generally upvoted in the main subreddits for comments defending their attraction and right to sexualize or even have sex with underage girls.

There are also subreddits like The Red Pill, The Red Pill Women, Beating Women, Great Apes and more. It's not some seedy underbelly that's completely separate from the site in general, Reddit's admins are so in favor of free speech that they allow any type of scum to flourish as long as they don't get negative media backlash. The people from the vile subreddits are very visible outside their subreddits, they will upvote and contribute vile points of view to the saner subreddits. I'm not a part of SRS and never have been (they're too sensitive and take everything out of context) but they do have a point when it comes to Reddit being a haven for pedophiles, racists, and misogynists. Due to their subreddits being allowed to flourish, they have a much higher presence on Reddit than you'd find on a better moderated website.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27501264958.0" user="prodigiousmuscle" delta="False">
    <text>That is a fair point bluemills, but it brings up a really harsh question about free speech. Where does it stop? 

This is just an idea of a counter argument. You dislike the trying to support their views because you think the views are harmful, but where do you draw the line to what you can and can't talk about. I dislike your ideas and beliefs, therefore what you have to say can no longer be said? It is an age old question that isn't as simple as getting the hammer out and starting to beat down on people.

Scum is always present, but removing rights is not how you get rid of the problem. If it is simply someone speaking or defending their beliefs, then let them defend their misguided bullshit. Saying you can't say that leads to a very dangerous road though, and once rights disappear, they don't come back. If they are breaking an established law then yes, get rid of them. If they are not and simply talking about something, then leave them be and down vote it if you think it is bullshit. 

(If you have a better idea, I honestly would love to hear it. It just is not a good idea to start a censorship of things because it is easy for it to get out of control.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474053831.0" user="SoundMasher" delta="False">
    <text>You had me up until 

&amp;gt; Plus, that shit is hilarious.

It's really not. Not at all. It's just as annoying as all the other mundane and retardedly racist/ignorant comments in any YouTube section</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474103128.0" user="indeedwatson" delta="False">
    <text>I too find it funny, and I understand why you could find it tiring, but really some of the comments are quite "eloquent" in the way they utilize the stereotypes and shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474112517.0" user="SoundMasher" delta="False">
    <text>I'll take your word for it. If they add nothing to any kind of relevant discussion pertaining to the video, I'll just look over it. It's just more noise to me. Different strokes I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474410642.0" user="indeedwatson" delta="False">
    <text>They add nothing to the discussion, that's for sure, but that's the nature of YT comments in general, specially since the stupid G+ move. 

Tbh I don't see them that often, and when I do I either get a chuckle, or ignore them like I would any other "Check out this video I'm posting to my G+ page!".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474222922.0" user="GatoMaricon" delta="False">
    <text>IMO it was funny in the beginning but now it's annoying when every fucking comment in the section is just this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474122699.0" user="carrier_mobility" delta="False">
    <text>Then... ignore it?

Or are you invoking the sacred right to never have to look at things you don't approve of on the internet?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474126763.0" user="SoundMasher" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying I could "fix it" via the YouTube comments section like the rest of the rabble? I'd rather shrug and get on with my life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27474181389.0" user="carrier_mobility" delta="False">
    <text>Even better idea.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
