<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27473321563.0" user="HoChiMiner" delta="False">
    <text>Their comments are pretty funny, the fact that people get upset about it just shows that those people take this website much to seriously. 

Who cares if they make redditors look stupid, most people think that already. All you have to do is go /r/politics or /r/worldnews and you have more than enough evidence to show how damn stupid, ignorant, arrogant, biased, sensationalist, antisemitic, sexist, and racist this user base actually is </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
