<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27472645705.0" user="david12scht" delta="False">
    <text>I've only taken a brief look at the sub, and it looks like classic satire to me. Should /r/pyongyang be banned for advocating dictatorship?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472646484.0" user="Very_Juicy" delta="False">
    <text>Does /r/pyongyang frequently raid other websites?

No it does not.

/r/circlejerk is satire as well but you don't see their users shitposting on a frequent basis outside of the sub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472652233.0" user="david12scht" delta="False">
    <text>Do the users of the sub actually organize these raids? What I saw of the sub, it's mostly mocking the phenomenon that other redditors do this. If this is correct, I would say this is in fact a very good thing: mocking people, while a rather crude form of criticism, might make some people reconsider participating, just as circlejerk might make users more cautious about behaving in a hivemind fashion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472660454.0" user="Very_Juicy" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.reddit.com/r/RedditArmie/comments/2h6kd0/post_your_most_upvoted_post_on_youtube/

They're not mocking the phenomenon, they're organizing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472670268.0" user="420fag420fag" delta="False">
    <text>That is organizing screenshots of posts, not raids. Very different meanings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472916611.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>People get karma for pictures of youtube posts. The sub advocates posting disruptive messages on youtube.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473094980.0" user="420fag420fag" delta="False">
    <text>There are many people who don't post screencaps of their comments and they comment just as frequently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473230443.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How does that change anything?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472672419.0" user="david12scht" delta="False">
    <text>Looks to me like it's a mixture of satire and serious posts, like /r/MURICA . I don't see how any of it warrants a ban. Looks like a classic example of Poe's law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472700286.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing in your linked thread is the organization of a brigading attempt on YouTube.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472979720.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>How so? They are encouraging raiding the youtube videos that are popular on reddit. It's like a trophy case for their best kills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472999636.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>When I hear that a sub is organizing brigades, I'm picturing "go to this video and dislike it and post an inane comment."

Like, Photoshop battles organizes people to photoshop on specific pictures. But /r/pics merely rewards people (in the comments) for that behavior. Would you say /r/pics is organizing photoshop efforts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473008357.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>But it's much more specific than /r/pics. I actually think /r/photoshopbattles is a good analogy. They **do** organize the photoshopping behvavior. I'll admit it is not direct organization as in "go here, do this now", but it is definitely driving the behavior. It seems more like offering a bounty, which most people would consider organizing. 

What if there was a site that asked for people to post their best pictures of stores they vandalized during any riots that break out across the country? Would you also feel that site was not helping to encourage and organize the behavior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473024729.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Encourage? Maybe. Organizing? No.

Organization is more than encouragement or advocacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473038249.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>But it does organize the behavior as well. It provides a central location and an audience to encourage the acts.

&amp;gt;organize - *make arrangements or preparations for an event or activity*

It seems to fit that definition quite well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473044822.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, what arrangements or preparations are being made?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473059870.0" user="ExplainsSocialEnigma" delta="False">
    <text>To organize a raid you kinda need a "let's go to this video" or "here's a video (that has not yet been raided so we can raid it" or at least "here's an armie comment (let's go upvote it and make a discussion on youtube)"

You can't simply laugh about it after the fact - that's too late. It's like saying that a fence organized a robbery. No, the fence just provided a service that increased the value of the robbery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473089543.0" user="HankLago" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the sub 'organizes' anything, it's just a place for the reddit army guys cirklejerking over how funny they are. Banning the sub wouldn't stop anyone from making a fake g+ profile and commenting on /r/videos posts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473143173.0" user="flammable" delta="False">
    <text>FYI /r/redditarmie was created 5 months ago, but those kinds of posts have been prevalent for several years at this point. I feel like you are giving them a bit too much credit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473424610.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Except that it is obvious that they became extremely popular once the subreddit was established. Now it's organized to a ridicucolous degree while before it were one or two stray comments here and there. Now it's, as OP said, multiple dozens of comments in every video that gets posted in the larger subreddits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473103030.0" user="Chris-P" delta="False">
    <text>How are you defining "raid"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473335458.0" user="hellshot8" delta="False">
    <text>They're raiding the Internet equivalent of a garbage dumb. Why do you give a shit? If these guys weren't there with their trolling, instead it would be full of racism and stupidly. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
