<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27472652570.0" user="Arathian" delta="False">
    <text>I know reddit is full of misogynistic men, but this is too much. I did not expect this attack on feminist ideals. Next thing you know people will ask /r/shitredditsays to be banned! This just goes to show that men are the true inferior gender and killing them is justice.

Berta Lovejoy, Feminist, Promoter Of Equality, Love, and Peace. ﻿


On a serious note, I still find them bloody funny. I know this is not much of a defence, but really, you are only asking them to be banned because you find them "not funny any more". Well, that is a personal preference and me liking them also is. It isn't like youtube comments are a grand palace of intellectual wisdom anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472660908.0" user="Very_Juicy" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically stated that it's not just because it's unfunny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472965910.0" user="Bobthemightyone" delta="False">
    <text>OP is requesting it to be banned because it disrupts the comment system of another website in a significant way. I know Youtube comments never have been and probably never will have any real semblance of civil conversation, but it's still shitty that an outside website is making it even worse.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
