<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27473179223.0" user="pennysmith" delta="False">
    <text>Youtube comments as a whole really aren't much better than news article comments...I don't think redditarmie is damaging anything of value

However, I do think that everyone should get the [Alientube](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alientube-for-youtube/opgodjgjgojjkhlmmhdlojfehcemknnp/related?hl=en) extension if you want some sort of meaningful discussion below your videos.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473462032.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>A year ago, youtube comments were totally fine. Sure, loads of copypasta, ASCII art and other useless stuff too but at least the two most upvoted comments were usually something worthwile. People give the youtube community not enough credit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473486934.0" user="TallSkinny" delta="False">
    <text>Are you serious? Did you and I go to different Youtubes? It wasn't the "copypasta, ASCII art and other useless stuff" that was a problem, it was the overwhelming amount of racism, sexism, and pretty much every other form of bigotry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473501917.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Probably depending of the video. In political videos it was just like reddit but when a video of an eight year old girl playing with a cat went viral, there weren't Bertha Lovejoy and McTrillby under this video typing some disgusting bullshit about sexism or pedophelia.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
