<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27472861273.0" user="dahlesreb" delta="False">
    <text>I have nothing to do with that subreddit, didn't even know it existed, but I chuckle at those youtube comments when they're funny (or the responses to them are). Youtube comments are so uniformly bad, it's not like you're missing anything. A chance of humor is better than guaranteed stupidity, in my opinion. I don't think the damage they do to reddit's image is significant, either; a quick visit to the front page will show you they don't represent the majority of people here.

If you want a good discussion, post a link to the youtube video on an appropriate subreddit!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472867591.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>More importantly, I fail to see why there's a need to police them. Seriously, who the fuck cares ? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473185805.0" user="rimnii" delta="False">
    <text>maybe the Reddit PR team?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473207048.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>That explains why they're in crisis mode. You are right. Vote "manipulation" on *Youtube* ? That's serious you guys. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473242782.0" user="rimnii" delta="False">
    <text>idk if passive aggressive sarcasm is meant for this subreddit. I get its not necessarily a big deal but I was just suggesting who might care</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473345231.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>And you are completely right, but since people *paid* to care about it don't, the whole issue is pretty pointless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473507234.0" user="Mattk50" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's against reddit's own rules to brigade, if you link, in reddit, to another post in reddit, you can get permabanned if enough people follow the link then vote on it or something. It's stupid but whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473610716.0" user="EquipLordBritish" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I don't know if that particular screencap OP took is representative of the kinds of things they post, but if it is, it could potentially bring bad press to reddit as a whole.

More likely, though, nothing will happen and nothing will get banned *unless* there is bad press brought to reddit.

Reddit has proven in the past to use reactionary tactics, not preventative ones...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473675322.0" user="oldmoneey" delta="False">
    <text>I do, actually. I do like to look at youtube comments to see how other people felt about the video, and you simply don't get the option to see that anymore. "Dur hurr all youtube comments all shit" well, not quite like this. Sometimes people have something interesting or more pertinently funny to say.

I loved it when there was just one or two trolls, don't get me wrong. Now they're a massive, unfunny, and growing cancer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27488938638.0" user="jaxbotme" delta="False">
    <text>And yet, you got downvoted for saying that. Seriously? Go to any YouTube video that has gotten 'reddit armied', scroll down, and see there are actual useful comments and questions at the bottom. Not always, of course, but they aren't universally bad, and even if they were, there's zero reason to make the world a worse place.

It's like throwing away more things because we already have landfills. It's not the right solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27501253236.0" user="prodigiousmuscle" delta="False">
    <text>Try the hide fedora app in the google store. You can set specific ban words or ban users on youtube altogether and it removes their comments like they don't exist. 

Just found this app, and i wish i found it a lot sooner</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27501315839.0" user="oldmoneey" delta="False">
    <text>That sounds fantastic... Looking it up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473424493.0" user="Suited_Monkey" delta="False">
    <text>It's certainly not helping to make YouTube video comments better though. Saying that they're already bad is just rationalizing being part of the problem. Maybe if people didn't think that way, YouTube comments could become a place for actual conversation, instead of people "pretending" or otherwise being obnoxious, racist, etc. 

In the end it's still spam. We really should not be promoting spam. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473621563.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>They give reddit free publicity (it's how I first found out about reddit I think) so what's the point in trying to police them? They aren't breaking any reddit [rules](http://www.reddit.com/rules) (they only refer to spamming reddit itself) so it would be an abuse of power to delete the subreddit anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473721945.0" user="Slurmz" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people realize just how bad youtube comments really can be... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473789441.0" user="lf27" delta="False">
    <text>Although that is correct, YouTubers amd anyone else won't tend to do that, they (in my opinion) will just assume they represent how everyone here is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473825740.0" user="Lord_Vectron" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is with Youtube's comment ranking system. 

Controversial comments (Ones with lots of replies, dislikes as well as likes) are put at the top. 

This means these reaction baiting comments are always seen by the same people and these people are always going to have the same reaction, like or dislike, comment negatively or positively. There is going to be a large reaction and the comment will go, and stay, at the top. 

The longer this goes on, the more well known and expected it is, the more reaction to the comments, the faster and longer it stays at the top. 10+ copycats emerge and take the 10+ comments below it. 

Suddenly you can't find a comment that's actually relevant to the video or adds anything to any sort of discussion. Youtube commenters aren't famed for being the brightest, but every now and then some useful or interesting information can be found in the top comments, this ruins that. 

I'm going to put some emphasis on that I don't think a subreddit should be banned because of this, I think youtube should simply change their system. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
