<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1610061625.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qml7i1/cmv_service_roads_should_not_exist/">
    <title>CMV: “service roads” should not exist</title>
    <original_poster>tylerderped</original_poster>
    <original_post>My city has a few “service roads”. For those unfamiliar, “service roads” are complimentary roads on either side of a Main Street separated by medians, usually with a lower speed limit. 

The theory is that they make it safer/easier to go into businesses along a main street. 

The problem is they are actually *more* dangerous and make driving more difficult as well. 

Picture this, you’re driving on your city’s Main Street, going to Home Depot. Let’s assume it’s coming up on the right for simplicity sake. You either need to move into the service lane (while watching out for traffic going *both* directions in said service lanes) and have to stop at several stop signs along the way. 

Or you wait til you’re at the intersection, assuming there’s even an opening at an intersection, and once again have to cross over a set of lanes where traffic is going both directions. It adds unnecessary complexity, and more so, it adds additional points at an intersection where a crash can occur. It’s even more dangerous to do a left turn. This objectively makes service roads less safe than simply not having them. 

Due to the difficulty of use and the dangerous nature of it, no one really uses the service roads in my city, not on purpose anyway. Usually you end up on one by accident and it makes life hell. Getting out of the service lane to go onto the main road is also *extremely* dangerous. 

It’s a waste of space, they’re too hard to use, and they’re dangerous. There should be bus lanes or bike lanes in their place instead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38171485626.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying you solved a problem that city planning **professionals** have missed for decades?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171509652.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>No, I’m saying city planners *created* a (somewhat European) solution to a problem that didn’t really exist, and as a result, created an entirely new problem. 

But they didn’t go full European, the service lanes would be *a lot* more useful (and not nearly as dangerous) as transit or bike lanes. But instead, they’re for cars, which makes no sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171895210.0" user="PM_ME_UR_CATTO" delta="False">
    <text>I work for a municipal government in the department that plans roads, and I can assure you the methods implemented are weighed carefully for what has the least amount of drawbacks for a given area, flow of traffic, and numerous other factors that all have to be weighed out. 

In addition there are also nationwide rules that must be followed by the Federal Highway Administration called the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control for Streets and Highways.  

Whatever negatives you might have been experienced have no doubt been considered and weighed against all other alternatives. 

There is a reason public road projects take so long.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
