<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1610061625.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qml7i1/cmv_service_roads_should_not_exist/">
    <title>CMV: “service roads” should not exist</title>
    <original_poster>tylerderped</original_poster>
    <original_post>My city has a few “service roads”. For those unfamiliar, “service roads” are complimentary roads on either side of a Main Street separated by medians, usually with a lower speed limit. 

The theory is that they make it safer/easier to go into businesses along a main street. 

The problem is they are actually *more* dangerous and make driving more difficult as well. 

Picture this, you’re driving on your city’s Main Street, going to Home Depot. Let’s assume it’s coming up on the right for simplicity sake. You either need to move into the service lane (while watching out for traffic going *both* directions in said service lanes) and have to stop at several stop signs along the way. 

Or you wait til you’re at the intersection, assuming there’s even an opening at an intersection, and once again have to cross over a set of lanes where traffic is going both directions. It adds unnecessary complexity, and more so, it adds additional points at an intersection where a crash can occur. It’s even more dangerous to do a left turn. This objectively makes service roads less safe than simply not having them. 

Due to the difficulty of use and the dangerous nature of it, no one really uses the service roads in my city, not on purpose anyway. Usually you end up on one by accident and it makes life hell. Getting out of the service lane to go onto the main road is also *extremely* dangerous. 

It’s a waste of space, they’re too hard to use, and they’re dangerous. There should be bus lanes or bike lanes in their place instead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38171556441.0" user="riotacting" delta="False">
    <text>You say they're more dangerous, but don't give us any evidence, just hypothetical examples.   They could lead to more accidents, I just don't know.  Or they could lead to fewer accidents because of the confusion... which forces people to be more aware of their surroundings and drive more cautiously.  Even if there are more accidents, it may still be a good thing because those accidents aren't as deadly.   I much rather have 20 fender benders a year than only 2 accidents where 4 people die. 

Traffic engineering is complicated and we continue to learn.   25 years ago, the new trends were to keep all lines of sight open.   Wide streets with very few trees.   The theory was better vision will lead to fewer accidents.   But in the last 20 years, we learned that those wide streets can actually be more dangerous.   Narrow streets with large trees make people drive slower, because if they can't see as much, they're naturally more cautious and pay more attention. There's better resources for this, but here's a quick source:  https://www.wri.org/insights/bigger-isnt-always-better-narrow-traffic-lanes-make-cities-safer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171622333.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>If you take a normal intersection, there are points of potential impact at about every corner. When you add service roads, you’re roughly doubling the points of potential impact for no real reason. 

I like you hitting the confusion aspect, and you’re absolutely right that traffic consensus has changed a lot. I love the example about narrowing streets to make them safer. That makes a lot of sense. But sometimes confusion goes too far, like it does in my city. Idk, maybe my city does service roads different, but I doubt it. In my city, everyone *hates* the service roads for the reasons I mentioned, and thus, they don’t actually get used. 90% of the time, they’re wasting valuable space where people could be living, biking, or taking transit that doesn’t get stuck in traffic.

I just don’t see how having annoying roads on either side of a main road can possibly make things safer. I’ve never heard of a serious accident happening because someone slammed into a other person who was turning into a business. The thing is, that can still happen with a service road. You have to get *into* the service road from a main road, which requires the same actions (slowing down and turning) as going directly to a business from an intersection.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
