<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1610061625.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qml7i1/cmv_service_roads_should_not_exist/">
    <title>CMV: “service roads” should not exist</title>
    <original_poster>tylerderped</original_poster>
    <original_post>My city has a few “service roads”. For those unfamiliar, “service roads” are complimentary roads on either side of a Main Street separated by medians, usually with a lower speed limit. 

The theory is that they make it safer/easier to go into businesses along a main street. 

The problem is they are actually *more* dangerous and make driving more difficult as well. 

Picture this, you’re driving on your city’s Main Street, going to Home Depot. Let’s assume it’s coming up on the right for simplicity sake. You either need to move into the service lane (while watching out for traffic going *both* directions in said service lanes) and have to stop at several stop signs along the way. 

Or you wait til you’re at the intersection, assuming there’s even an opening at an intersection, and once again have to cross over a set of lanes where traffic is going both directions. It adds unnecessary complexity, and more so, it adds additional points at an intersection where a crash can occur. It’s even more dangerous to do a left turn. This objectively makes service roads less safe than simply not having them. 

Due to the difficulty of use and the dangerous nature of it, no one really uses the service roads in my city, not on purpose anyway. Usually you end up on one by accident and it makes life hell. Getting out of the service lane to go onto the main road is also *extremely* dangerous. 

It’s a waste of space, they’re too hard to use, and they’re dangerous. There should be bus lanes or bike lanes in their place instead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38171519182.0" user="Rufus_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>I can't speak to the details of your anonymous home town, but people execute good ~~deals~~ [ideas] or implement sound concepts poorly all the time.

An extreme example of service roads - as described by you - is city streets that parallel freeways.  On the freeway, people can go 50+ miles an hour without having to deal with pedestrians or parked cars pulling into traffic, and on the city street, speeds are low enough that on-street parking might work, that it's not too noisy, and that pedestrians can cross relatively safely.  ([I] guess an even more extreme contrast could be made between freeways and indoor malls, but people tend not to think of shopping malls as roads or streets.)

Another analogy to service roads would be parking lots.  Do you think that people should be pulling out of parking spaces directly onto high speed roads?

It seems like you're focused on the transition between the service road and the thoroughfare and not what's happening on the other parts of those roads.  Roads and streets act in a variety of roles - a road that's good for getting from place A to place B fast is not going to be good for commerce.  ("Main Street" is typically a commerce street, and not a freeway between big box stores.)  If you don' think that those roles should be split, can you come up with better compromises?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171955966.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Another analogy to service roads would be parking lots. Do you think that people should be pulling out of parking spaces directly onto high speed roads?

Not *directly*, but none of the parking lots where I live are like that. Walmart, for example, would be in a shopping center with Home Depot and a grocery store and other shops, surrounded by... Idk how to describe them... not quite roads or streets cause they don't have street name signs (so they must not be real roads or streets) like, you gotta drive around the parking lot to actually get out.

It sounds a lot like service roads are meant to compliment highways, not main streets.

The street I'm talking about *can* take you to the other side of town, but that's not its primary purpose -- its primary purpose is to take you to Wal-Mart or a car dealership. So it kind of already acts like a service road? Even tho it has service roads on either side.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38172120150.0" user="Rufus_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>Like I wrote above, I'm really not in a position to comment on the particulars of your situation.   The point is that, because we want roads to serve in a variety of roles it can (and often does) make sense to have parallel roads like that.

Does it really make sense to conclude that "service roads" are a bad idea in general just because you don't like the ones in your town?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38178791583.0" user="pipocaQuemada" delta="False">
    <text>Service roads complement highways, but they're also a good way to eliminate stroads.

A stroad is the kind of thing you see all over the US where you combine a high speed limit (commonly 45 or 55 mph) with a lot of driveways into businesses. 

A stroad tries to do too many things,  and as a result does them all badly and dangerously.  Traffic is frequently slowed down by people turning - particularly left turns when there's no suicide lane.  Rear ending someone who's turning (left or right) isn't uncommon.  Head on collisions in shared turn lanes is common enough that they're often called suicide lanes.  And they're usually incredibly dangerous to anyone not in a car.  Crossing 4 or 5 lanes of traffic is mostly an exercise for people with a death wish. 

Collectors work by separating a stroad into a separate high-speed, low contention road and an adjacent low-speed high contention street.  You should only be able to exit the road at a few points,  like at semi regular roundabouts.  And those points should be low contention.

It's entirely possible that your city implemented collector roads badly, or for a situation where they're superfluous.  Walmart and car dealerships seem like a situation where they could just be in one big plaza with only a couple driveways/ traffic lights in.  

Collectors shine on residential stroads or traditional main streets where there's really just a line of buildings with on-street parking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38186377764.0" user="NoRecommendation8689" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, those are called frontage roads not service roads. And they can be frustrating but the notion is to move traffic that is frequenting the local businesses off of the road before they have to turn, thus forcing people behind them to slow down and causing traffic backup.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
