<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1610061625.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qml7i1/cmv_service_roads_should_not_exist/">
    <title>CMV: “service roads” should not exist</title>
    <original_poster>tylerderped</original_poster>
    <original_post>My city has a few “service roads”. For those unfamiliar, “service roads” are complimentary roads on either side of a Main Street separated by medians, usually with a lower speed limit. 

The theory is that they make it safer/easier to go into businesses along a main street. 

The problem is they are actually *more* dangerous and make driving more difficult as well. 

Picture this, you’re driving on your city’s Main Street, going to Home Depot. Let’s assume it’s coming up on the right for simplicity sake. You either need to move into the service lane (while watching out for traffic going *both* directions in said service lanes) and have to stop at several stop signs along the way. 

Or you wait til you’re at the intersection, assuming there’s even an opening at an intersection, and once again have to cross over a set of lanes where traffic is going both directions. It adds unnecessary complexity, and more so, it adds additional points at an intersection where a crash can occur. It’s even more dangerous to do a left turn. This objectively makes service roads less safe than simply not having them. 

Due to the difficulty of use and the dangerous nature of it, no one really uses the service roads in my city, not on purpose anyway. Usually you end up on one by accident and it makes life hell. Getting out of the service lane to go onto the main road is also *extremely* dangerous. 

It’s a waste of space, they’re too hard to use, and they’re dangerous. There should be bus lanes or bike lanes in their place instead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38171522588.0" user="RDMvb6" delta="False">
    <text>The alternative to service roads is to have turn lanes off of a high speed road. There is often not enough space to have a turn lane big enough for all the people who want to turn, which leads to back up onto the main road. Getting rear ended at 55 mph is worse than a front or side collision at 25- 35mph that you typically see on a service road. Additionally, service roads can funnel all the traffic to local business to a central point where it can enter the main road (usually with several lanes and a traffic signal) instead of having multiple turn offs for each business entrance.

Service roads are not appropriate in every circumstance. It would be great if every store was walking distance but that is just not reality in an area with a lot of sprawl and the low density that many people want to live in. You probably don't need service roads in Manhattan because all the roads are relatively low speed. But if you have business off of a 55mph highway, you pretty much need a service road to make it work. Therefore, saying service roads "should not exist" really misses reality.

Source: am civil engineer, but not specifically focused on traffic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171568444.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the alternative to service roads is to have turn lanes off a high speed road

I’m not following. Where I live, there are no “high speed roads”, 55mph+ is a *highway*, not a street. To get onto a Main Street from the highway, you simply take an exit ramp, which smoothly transitions you into a Main Street by one of those clover things, which usually has a traffic light at the end. Perfectly safe. Speed limit on city streets doesn’t exceed 45mph. On streets without service roads, there is literally no problem turning into a business along the road. You put on your blinker, slow down with your brakes, and turn. It couldn’t be simpler. You don’t need a special lane just for doing that. 

And sure, maybe getting rear ended at *45mph is worse than getting t-boned at 25-35mph. I honestly can’t say, both seem pretty bad. With the service roads tho, you’re increasing the chances that a collision will happen at all tho, cause you have traffic behind you, and to the side you have traffic going *both* directions, where, without a service road, you only run a risk of getting rear ended. In my experience tho, people are usually pretty good about not ramming into you cause you’re turning to go into a business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171719125.0" user="RDMvb6" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about traffic engineering is that it is very location specific. We could each give anecdotal experiences that are true and correct about how a service road in location X is good or bad. What's right for one spot could be dangerous in another. 

And there are plenty of streets where the speed limit is 55mph and having a parking lot right off of these is a pretty horrible idea. Around here, 75mph is a highway and 55 is pretty standard for streets. But there is room for shades of gray here and saying blanket statements like service roads "should not exist" is certainly incorrect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171760028.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>Can you show me examples of service roads that work well/the way they’re supposed to?

Obviously, they don’t work well or the way they should where I live, otherwise, people would actually use them instead of avoiding them like a venereal disease.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38171924227.0" user="RDMvb6" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, google maps Spotsylvania Town Center at the intersection of Route 3 and I-95 in Virginia. Here you have a 65mph highway and a 55mph road. If every business had their parking lot right off that 55 mph road, you would have an absolute clusterfuck of backed up traffic with people trying to get in and out of each lot. Instead you can turn onto the service road at a traffic signal and take that to the individual lot that you want to access. Works fine. Also, many service roads are one way, not two ways like you mention. Turning onto them is basically just like taking an exit ramp from a highway.

Some want to eliminate this entire concept of sprawl and make everything high density and walking distance but that is an entirely separate discussion. If you accept that people want to drive cars and not live in super high density housing, you need roads, and service roads are one way that you can avoid backups on major thru streets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38172154824.0" user="tylerderped" delta="False">
    <text>As far as I can tell, Plank Rd. had all sorts of business that are right off the road. Tobacco Hut, La-Z-Boy, Chilis, Sofa Outlet, Texas Road House, etc. 

The only service roads I’m seeing in that immediate area are Plank Service Rd. And Town Center Blvd. 

Am I missing something? I feel like i really am.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38178819671.0" user="pipocaQuemada" delta="False">
    <text>Check out [13:12 into this video](https://youtu.be/ORzNZUeUHAM).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
