<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161281463.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o0tkn/cmv_there_dont_need_to_be_hundreds_of_gender_and/">
    <title>CMV: there don't need to be hundreds of gender and sexuality names</title>
    <original_poster>YoungRecluse</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can understand gay, lesbian, queer, bisexual, asexual, pansexual, and aromantic. I can understand cis-, trans-, and a-genders. Why does there need to be demisexual and demiromantic and all that? Why do we need so many classifications of gender and sexuality? If you're attracted to the same sex, why can't you just be homosexual? If you're attracted to the opposite why can't you just be heterosexual? If you're attracted to both, why can't you be bisexual? Attracted to all? You're pansexual.
Keep it simple.

Also, I understand people getting offended and angry when they're misgendered, but getting angry doesn't really accomplish anything unless you can be calm in your education on the subject. Hating people for not calling you by your preferred pronouns the first time when they've never met you before is not going to accomplish anything. Hating cisgendered, heterosexual people will not accomplish anything. 

Please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27483559405.0" user="Myproblemsseemsmall" delta="False">
    <text>It's not something that really affects those who aren't atypical sexual preference wise (if there is a typical preference anymore). I think you are taking issue with terms that aren't really directed towards you it would seem. I think it helps those who need to describe their preference, and as another person said, there's more than one so it gives them a group to identify with. It isn't fair to generalize any group and especially any individual, and having three or four generalized terms does a disservice to those people and their identities. Why should they have to conform to what others say just because it confuses those others?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
