<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161281463.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o0tkn/cmv_there_dont_need_to_be_hundreds_of_gender_and/">
    <title>CMV: there don't need to be hundreds of gender and sexuality names</title>
    <original_poster>YoungRecluse</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can understand gay, lesbian, queer, bisexual, asexual, pansexual, and aromantic. I can understand cis-, trans-, and a-genders. Why does there need to be demisexual and demiromantic and all that? Why do we need so many classifications of gender and sexuality? If you're attracted to the same sex, why can't you just be homosexual? If you're attracted to the opposite why can't you just be heterosexual? If you're attracted to both, why can't you be bisexual? Attracted to all? You're pansexual.
Keep it simple.

Also, I understand people getting offended and angry when they're misgendered, but getting angry doesn't really accomplish anything unless you can be calm in your education on the subject. Hating people for not calling you by your preferred pronouns the first time when they've never met you before is not going to accomplish anything. Hating cisgendered, heterosexual people will not accomplish anything. 

Please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27483520629.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>I would actually say you go too far with pansexual.  That doesn't really add any information beyond bisexual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484190033.0" user="omardaslayer" delta="False">
    <text>Pansexual assumes a more fluid gender identity instead of assuming a gender binary.  In this they are different terms.  If you take that genders are nonbinary, then it follows that there is a sexual preference for nonbinary genders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484252172.0" user="Captain_Gamemaster" delta="False">
    <text>I thought that it meant you were also attracted to men who look like women and vice versa.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484264231.0" user="omardaslayer" delta="False">
    <text>Well yeah, but those people wouldn't identify as 'men who look like women' they'd probably say they are trans.  Regardless, bisexuals are interested in men and women, while pansexuals are interested in a person of any gender identity, man, woman, trans, etc. A pansexual is basically not ruling anyone out of their sexual attraction, by definition a bisexual isn't interested in trans people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27489645759.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so it is horseshit.  That's what I thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27490397977.0" user="omardaslayer" delta="False">
    <text>Even without gender politics, there are biologically ambiguous sexes. XX chromosome people with mutated testosterone, or mutated testosterone receptors look exactly like a XY woman.  Calling them a man based on their genetics is unfair when these people are in every other way a woman. They don't have periods, have undescended testes, breasts, and vaginas.  Tell me which camp "man" or "women" these people should be placed in. Or if you think they deserve a little agency.  Should these people be barred from men's or women's rooms?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27505339290.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is, you just said that this ambiguous person looks unambiguously like a woman, and attractions are based on immediate perceptions, not complex DNA profiles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27505400774.0" user="omardaslayer" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that there are cases where there is unambiguous biological support for a nonbinary sex/gender.  This person may not identify as a woman and would have full biological backing in existing outside of male/female so by saying "bisexual" you exclude a very real person.  This person is naturally trans-, and trans- breaks down binaries by examining and presenting what is in between. 

Regarding attraction is based on immediate perceptions, that is not necessarily true. There is some part of attraction that is immediate and some that isn't. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
