<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161281463.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o0tkn/cmv_there_dont_need_to_be_hundreds_of_gender_and/">
    <title>CMV: there don't need to be hundreds of gender and sexuality names</title>
    <original_poster>YoungRecluse</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can understand gay, lesbian, queer, bisexual, asexual, pansexual, and aromantic. I can understand cis-, trans-, and a-genders. Why does there need to be demisexual and demiromantic and all that? Why do we need so many classifications of gender and sexuality? If you're attracted to the same sex, why can't you just be homosexual? If you're attracted to the opposite why can't you just be heterosexual? If you're attracted to both, why can't you be bisexual? Attracted to all? You're pansexual.
Keep it simple.

Also, I understand people getting offended and angry when they're misgendered, but getting angry doesn't really accomplish anything unless you can be calm in your education on the subject. Hating people for not calling you by your preferred pronouns the first time when they've never met you before is not going to accomplish anything. Hating cisgendered, heterosexual people will not accomplish anything. 

Please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27484248799.0" user="TheGreatFaggadouchio" delta="False">
    <text>The constant expansion of labels  (GLBT becomes LGBTQ becomes LGBTQ2AA, etc...) is indicative of one of the fundamental contradictions within the queer movement.  

The reality is that prior to modernity society did not have nor need any of these neat little boxes go place and ultimately force sexuality into.  It wasn't until the 19th century that the first of these terms, "heterosexual", first became popular to describe sexual deviants who had sex primarily for recreation and not for procreation (oh my!).

In ancient Greece you weren't gay if you were attracted to a member of the same sex and you weren't straight if you were attracted to a member of the opposite sex. Rather attraction was attributed to that particular individual *being* attractive,  it simply wasn't engendered the way it is now.

So the ultimate goal of the queer movement should theoretically be to deconstruct all categories to the point that it simply doesn't matter anymore.  In order to do this, however, they need to create categories and include those categories in order to be able to foment solidarity.  You can't really fight against systemic discrimination if you do not identify yourself.   

So you can look at the ever increasing amount of categories as the traditional roles continuing to be splintered into tiny and tiny and more and more specific bits like a mosaic.  The end goal/result of which is the destruction of the categories themselves.  

If you think some of this is too complicated or absurd, that is because on some level it is supposed to be, it is because queer theory reveals the fact the attitudes that seek to define and restrict gender and sexuality are fundamentally paradoxical and can *never* properly capture reality.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
