<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161281463.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o0tkn/cmv_there_dont_need_to_be_hundreds_of_gender_and/">
    <title>CMV: there don't need to be hundreds of gender and sexuality names</title>
    <original_poster>YoungRecluse</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can understand gay, lesbian, queer, bisexual, asexual, pansexual, and aromantic. I can understand cis-, trans-, and a-genders. Why does there need to be demisexual and demiromantic and all that? Why do we need so many classifications of gender and sexuality? If you're attracted to the same sex, why can't you just be homosexual? If you're attracted to the opposite why can't you just be heterosexual? If you're attracted to both, why can't you be bisexual? Attracted to all? You're pansexual.
Keep it simple.

Also, I understand people getting offended and angry when they're misgendered, but getting angry doesn't really accomplish anything unless you can be calm in your education on the subject. Hating people for not calling you by your preferred pronouns the first time when they've never met you before is not going to accomplish anything. Hating cisgendered, heterosexual people will not accomplish anything. 

Please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27483003258.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Crayola has invented hundreds of words for blue. Sure they are all blue, but there are tiny differences between navy, royal blue, teal, etc. Most people can't tell the difference and don't care, but if you're Picasso in the middle of the Blue Period, you need to be specific with your blues. Sure it complicates things and adds hundreds of words, but it's not like we are running out of words. You can apply the same logic to terms about sexuality and gender.

On your last point, yeah people shouldn't be jerks about being called the wrong name. But you have to understand that LGBTQ people have gone their whole life with classmates, coworkers, parents, etc. treating them like crap for being different. Most people aren't nice or willing to learn. It's not right, but it's not unreasonable for them to get pissed off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483028276.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that you don't need any more than-

Homosexual- same sex

Asexual- no sex

Heterosexual- different sex

Bisexual- both sex

It does nothing to go into specifics once you get passed that point other than confuse people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483045460.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Think about it like this. Say you own a coffee shop that only serves drip coffee and espresso. Most people either drink standard coffee or espresso, but every once in a while, someone comes in and says they want an "espresso with vanilla, sugar, and milk. But not not too much milk. More foam than milk." If only one person orders it, it's probably not that big a deal for them to just specify what they want. But if hundreds of people come in and want the same thing, it might be easier to invent a new word for it like vanilla cappuccino. 

The same thing is true for these terms about sexuality. Say there is a man who is only attracted to other men. Fine, he's gay. But say he is only attracted to male to female pre operative transexuals. Is he still gay? Is that the same as being attracted to male cross dressers. You might think so, but male cross dressers are often straight men, and are only attracted to women. If there is only one guy who is into that, fine. But say there are thousands of them. They might want to invent a word to describe their specific tastes so they don't have to keep explaining it to each other. (They'll probably still have to explain to other people because it's still relatively uncommon.)

It's like that eskimos have 50 words for snow myth. If you live in Arizona, it's just snow. but if you see dry powdery snow some days, wet packable snow on others, rainy/icy snow on other days etc. and they affect your daily life you might want to come up with more specific terms.

If you're a straight person who lives in rural Arkansas, your terms will probably get you by. If you live in San Francisco, and are sick of accidentally turning up to bars for the wrong subculture, you'll probably want to learn the nuances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483078270.0" user="Quabouter" delta="False">
    <text>You're argument sounds somewhat plausible initially, but is frankly still very weak: what you describe is merely a difference in taste. I mean, we don't have separate names for those who like blondes over brunettes, asians over caucasians, or big women over small women, while all of the groups I mentioned here are probably a lot larger than the groups you described. Still none of these groups of people invent their own sexuality, the just stick with gay, hetero or bi. The rest is just a matter of taste within those groups. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483252559.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>We could invent new words for those tastes. What's stopping us?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483288307.0" user="bleak_new_world" delta="False">
    <text>A lack of desire to take one aspect of my personality and define myself with it. Or did you mean just in general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483294314.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Like, who cares if someone invents a word to devote their preference for blondes? 

This idea that doing so would define yourself with that aspect of your personality is silly. They're just words. It's really no big deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483298342.0" user="bleak_new_world" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have a preference for other people's actions on that front, it doesn't effect my life. I was answering the question in the sense of why I'm not interested in crafting an elaborate label for myself based on one facet of my personality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483390186.0" user="pikk" delta="False">
    <text>It's important that people are able to describe themselves as if they are a totally unique and individual snowflake. How else would they be able to find someone who loves them expressly for all their eccentricities? /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483346576.0" user="HypnoticPeaches" delta="False">
    <text>The hypothetical "you" are a straight man 
and have a preference for blondes. Great! 

But really, how difficult would it be for a brunette woman to catch your eye? You're still a straight man and she's still a woman so if she's attractive in the face/body/mind/whatever it is you go for. 

Now, imagine the still hypothetical you was like a 0 on the Kinsey scale (Exclusively Heterosexual). You probably wouldn't normally be immediately sexually attracted to pre-operation trans women,  unless you had a specific fetish or, you know, you had an open mind and really liked her. But immediately, if you knew she still had male parts, you probably wouldn't be as interested because you were Exclusively Heterosexual. 

Now, Person A is a man and is attracted to feminine people. They care about their general gender expression being feminine. They may still be sexually attracted to physically male or physically female people so long as they present feminine/as a woman. You and Person A may both be after really similar things but you do not hasn't the same sexuality as Person A, do you? So people come up with better things to call themselves to make sure people understand what they want. What Person A might call themselves would be gynephilic but I'm not sure. 

Sexuality is tricky business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483381299.0" user="BlueKactus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Now, Person A is a man and is attracted to feminine people. They care about their general gender expression being feminine. They may still be sexually attracted to physically male or physically female people so long as they present feminine/as a woman. You and Person A may both be after really similar things but you do not hasn't the same sexuality as Person A, do you? So people come up with better things to call themselves to make sure people understand what they want. What Person A might call themselves would be gynephilic but I'm not sure.

Why wouldn't Person A just be bisexual?  He is still attracted to both male and females.

&amp;gt;Sexuality is tricky business.

Forgive me, but I don't really see anything terribly tricky here.  It just seems like someone has a certain preference for people.  I don't see why it needs to be a sexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483846239.0" user="TheWitchBride" delta="False">
    <text>I agree...all that makes sense what person A and person B wants, but why on earth would we have to make a special name for it? Why cant they both just like what they like...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483395641.0" user="pikk" delta="False">
    <text>being incredibly specific about what you want is the ultimate in treating people as a means instead of an ends in themselves. 

"I'm only attracted to crossdressing trans women, and I need everyone to know it so that crossdressing men don't waste my time" is just as awful an attitude as "ugh, I can't believe that gay guy hit on me" </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483717014.0" user="Quabouter" delta="False">
    <text>I fully, 100% agree with that the straight man that has preference for blonde women and the Person A have different sexualities, but as others have already pointed out, Person A would simply be bisexual. After all it's not that complicated: every single person on earth has people they will feel attracted to and people they don't feel attracted to, there are no 2 people with exactly the same sexual preference. However, it's not very useful to invent a new name for each individual preference. Therefore we as a society have come up with a way of grouping sexual preferences in a very rough way: we indicate to which gender the people belong for which we have a preference. We chose this because this is in most cases the largest common denominator. If a man is heterosexual it doesn't mean he has a preference for *all* women, it just means that all people you're attracted to are female. Likewise bisexual doesn't mean someone has is attracted to *all* people, it just means that in the set of people he/she is attracted to you'll find both men and women.

So if we look at you're hypothetical person A we see that if we take all people he is attracted to we will find both males and females. Therefore he is bisexual. It's that simple.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483416933.0" user="kodemage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I mean, we don't have separate names for those who like blondes over brunettes, asians over caucasians, or big women over small women

I'll wager you there's a word for each of these ending in -philia. When it comes to sex English is Eskimos and snow. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483664791.0" user="RobbieGee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; big women over small women

Ah yes, the good old magnusuperexigufeminaphilia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484213018.0" user="down2a9" delta="False">
    <text>The Eskimo [don't actually have a trillion words for snow](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eskimo_words_for_snow).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484675809.0" user="kodemage" delta="False">
    <text>You should note that I didn't say they did, and when people do they are exaggerating for comedic effect. So, that totally went over your head. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483843360.0" user="TheWitchBride" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, i feel the need to take ever taste and feeling i have and shove it all into a special name for myself so everyone who sees me knows i love puppies and like men with beards and prefer brown rice over white...ever taste and preference doesnt need to be in a classification... If i love men with beards or will only date a man with a beard and blue eyes and blonde hair and over 6 feet tall,cim not going to make up a name for that. Thats nobodies business, thats just the kind of man i will look for, the world doesnt need to know that is my preference. It is irrelevant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483078574.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, it's rather straightforward- unless you are into nonhumans(something I left out, for rather obvious reasons) you *will* fall into one of the categories provided, and clarifying further doesn't make any sense. Especially by adding extra terms.

Biologically, it boils down to "do you like women, men, both, or neither?"

If you're a man who likes women but also men who cross dress- doesn't that, based on anatomy alone, make you a bisexual?

The only place(and you touched on it) where there could be confusion is with transsexuals and hermaphrodites. Even in this case, you could simply go by biological sex, transitioned sex, or both sexes at once.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483087134.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>Attraction to anyone non gender conforming is not bisexuality.

People can be bisexual but like their men and women very gender confirming. Call it taste, preference the desire exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483090023.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe I said that, in fact I actually was speaking biologically.

Although, realistically, if you are interested in both sexes- you are bisexual. Even if it's only a little bit. Even if it's only in special situations.

If you're attracted to the opposite sex, you're heterosexual. 

If you're attracted to the same sex you're homosexual.

If you aren't sexually attracted to anything then you're asexual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483104006.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>This description of sexuality misses out gender expression. That matters a lot. Even to people who don't believe in it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483132267.0" user="iNEEDheplreddit" delta="False">
    <text>That sounds like your talking about something different. Everyone has different tastes. Being a man and being attracted to a certain 'type' of man, whether he be quite effeminate or masculine, still makes it a homosexual attraction. This is literally no different from me being heterosexual and being attracted to a tom-boy or strong independent female. 

And those preferences don't need to given a different names. I understand what you are saying but if heterosexual men gave their tastes, and what specific attraction makes them prefer a certain type of woman, a name, we would be here all night listing them. So why make a exception?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483655965.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>I agree at one level attraction to both genders is bisexuality. But I disagree that means attraction to all gender expressions.

&amp;gt; And those preferences don't need to given a different names. I understand what you are saying but if heterosexual men gave their tastes, and what specific attraction makes them prefer a certain type of woman, a name, we would be here all night listing them. So why make a exception?

You say it would take all night but if you are looking to match with someone, knowing each other's identity is a big time saver.

If you are on a dating site being able to describe yourself and search for others by good descriptions it helps a lot.

Things are not obvious, desires are not explicit. It's about precise communication to save time.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483713562.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But I disagree that means attraction to all gender expressions.

Your disagreement doesn't matter. Bisexuality has been consistently defined by bisexual organizations, activists, and communities in that way for over 25 years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483743253.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>That's interesting because that goes against the experience of the crossdresser community. Even if they are little more gender non conforming friendly it is explicitly not a direct link.

Go ahead ask around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483770316.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's interesting because that goes against the experience of the crossdresser community. Even if they are little more gender non conforming friendly it is explicitly not a direct link.

Really? My experiences are the opposite. But you want direct links? Here you go: 

* http://robynochs.com/bisexual/
* http://www.biresource.net/aboutus.shtml
* http://www.lanikaahumanu.com/biqa.shtml
* http://serf.org/jon/soc.bi/faq/a.html#A2
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484169564.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>Are political bisexuals open to the idea of non gender conforming people? Sure.

What people do is something else.

I have never scene a group of crossdressers agree bi people are universally accepting of them. Note that is not a moral judgement. Nor is it to say they are not more accepting than average but its just not the lived experience reported.

Here's a link
http://www.crossdressers.com/forums/showthread.php?115837-Crossdressers-amp-Bi-women

Some say yes, some say no, but its certainly not universal.

Hence the need for extra words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484380150.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>No group is universally accepting. I'm not certain why transphobia among bisexuals demand a complete dismantling of bi identity when transphobia among straight, gay, and lesbian groups does not. 

It's not a request for "extra words" when you're trying to redefine one of the multiple ways we use to describe ourselves into something undesired and undesirable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484796224.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>I understand you. I'm just defending the use if the word pansexual compared to bisexual.

I'm not saying the word bisexual should be dropped. I'm just saying its more complicated than that.

Its just further refinement. Though I don't doubt that the detail would be lost on most people. That's just the way it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483861557.0" user="iNEEDheplreddit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You say it would take all night but if you are looking to match with someone, knowing each other's identity is a big time saver.

&amp;gt;If you are on a dating site being able to describe yourself and search for others by good descriptions it helps a lot.

This is making it all about 'the sex' and makes these gendered communities sound insular. I know in the real world that i'm attracted to different qualities in different people.

Like i say, at the end of the day if you like men and you are a man you are gay. Men and women, you are bi. You don't need to specify and label the qualities you find attractive as something unique.  Why would anyone like an employer need that  information about your sexual preferences? I equate that to asking what your favourite sexual position is. 

Its a snowflake attitude that has people compartmentalising sexual 'likes'. Do i get a special name for liking only missionary with submissive leggy brunettes? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484187115.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is making it all about 'the sex' and makes these gendered communities sound insular.

I think we are talking at cross purposes. These are "sexual minorities." That's the topic.

&amp;gt; I know in the real world that i'm attracted to different qualities in different people.

Congratulations.

&amp;gt;Like i say, at the end of the day if you like men and you are a man you are gay. Men and women, you are bi.

So labels are good.

&amp;gt; You don't need to specify and label the qualities you find attractive as something unique.

Why not? If it helps others?

To me it's like saying you shouldn't label yourself gay, straight, male or female because it's too narrow.

Why waste the time of not being more precise?

&amp;gt; Why would anyone like an employer need that information about your sexual preferences?

Now you've jumped topics. This is where the cross purposes comes in. This is a different debate.

&amp;gt; I equate that to asking what your favourite sexual position is.
&amp;gt;Its a snowflake attitude that has people compartmentalising sexual 'likes'. Do i get a special name for liking only missionary with submissive leggy brunettes?

Bad analogy. I suspect you aren't going your job if people find you like "missionary with submissive leggy brunettes."

Though I guess it depends on how submissive you like them, but then you are against anyone labelling themselves submissive.

I'm in favour of you being able to find someone who labels themselves submissive. Seems like a time saver.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483232990.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Attraction to anyone non gender conforming is not bisexuality.

Bisexuality has never been defined that way except by overly pedantic advocates for pansexuality. The original theory of bisexuality (which persisted for over a century) was psychosexual hermaphroditism after all, the idea that we were not gender conforming in our attractions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483291586.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying pansexuality doesn't exist?

Are you saying gender expression doesn't matter? I think sexuality is complicated enough to require extra language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483324176.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>Queer sexualities are not, and have never been "gender conforming," a point that's communicated clearly through forms of prejudice ranging from discrimination and harassment to assault, rape, and murder. Bisexuality has, my entire life, been associated with androgyny, gender-nonconformity, and "anything that moves." And since I first came out (1991), the bisexual communities have defined ourselves inclusively as sexuality without the boundaries of gender.

Pansexual is a useful synonym, but trying to make a concrete distinction between bisexuality and pansexuality on the basis of gender conformity is a purely theoretical abstraction that has little basis in the lives of many bisexual people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483672278.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>Would you accept people can be bisexual without being pansexual?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483703669.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to provide a better definition of both before I can answer that question. Are there people with a strong preference for binary gender expression? Sure. Is that a separate essential sexual orientation? I have my doubts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483723623.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>I find labels useful. If someone uses these labels it helps me communicate with them.

In the crossdresser community its understood that bisexuality is not a guarantee of acceptance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483730328.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, more labels are useful, I use a half-dozen to describe myself. But they're overlapping adjectives that can be mixed and matched at will, not essential categories of human difference.

Much less a reason to engage in wholesale revisionism to write non-binary people, gender, sexuality, and spirituality out of bisexuality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483507317.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest, I'm not really sure what pansexuality is.  How is it different from bisexuality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483526763.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>If you accept that bisexuality only means 'attraction to men and women', then pansexuality would include genderqueer people, agender, trigender, etc.

Granted, many (I would even say most) would already consider all of these included under the label 'bisexuality', in which case pansexuality is indistinguishable from it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483540207.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, but you just defined a word I don't understand with words I understand even less.  Gender queer?  Does that just mean your gender is hard to identify?  I'm guessing agender means you have no gender?  No idea what trigender means.  Is there a third sex I don't know about?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483637240.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>Uh... Let me preface by admitting that gender is really fucking complicated and I don't even have a working definition of what 'gender' is. But for people who do, they describe genderqueer (or genderfluid) as sometimes being a man, sometimes being a woman. Their gender changes and fluctuates depending on the day. Agender does mean no gender, yes. Trigender is partially a synonym for genderqueer, but can also mix the two genders at once... it's complicated and awkward at best.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483697169.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pansexuality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483293473.0" user="FiercelyFuzzy206" delta="False">
    <text>You don't seem to understand what he's saying. 

If you like female and men or cross dress. You're bi. It doesn't matter what the guy is wearing, if you're attracted to them, you're bisexual. 


That makes you - bi-sexual. Why would you need a word to describe that you're only into guys who cross-dress? 


Could you imagine if our entire language was made up of words that described phrases? That would just be stupid. There is no reason you need a word to describe that much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483486472.0" user="speckofSTARDUST" delta="False">
    <text>That is basically what our language is made of...can you imagine if it wasn't? That's why I can go order a latte instead of "espresso shot and 7 ounces of 2% milk steamed to 180 degrees with a bit of foam on top" or why I can say I'm a vegetarian instead of "I don't eat beef, or chicken, or pork, or fish, or quail, or lamb, etc."

The more we talk about gender and sexuality, the more distinctions need to be made. If someone knows themselves well enough to define their preferences, why not create a word for it?

I heard the term "butt nuggling " on the radio today, which is apparently when you rub your butt against someone when you're spooning. Doesn't seem like that needs it's own word, but alas, that's how language works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483518233.0" user="FiercelyFuzzy206" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;or why I can say I'm a vegetarian instead of "I don't eat beef, or chicken, or pork, or fish, or quail, or lamb, etc."


You've got the right idea, but implementing it wrong.


We have a word for someone who eats meat (Carnivore) 

We have a word for someone who eats plants (herbivores)

We have a word for someone who eats both (Omnivore) 



Now to use your example.


 I'm a vegetarian instead of "I don't eat beef, or chicken, or pork, or fish, or quail, or lamb, etc."

Sure, this works. It makes sense to do this. We do not, however, have words for people who only eat specific of those.


I don't eat beef(B), or chicken(C), or pork(P), or fish,(F) or quail(Q), or lamb(L), etc."


We don't have a words for any of these:

I don't eat B or C

I don't eat C or P

I don't eat F or P 

I don't eat Q or L

I don't eat Q, L or C

Ect. We don't have words for these because it just simply doesn't matter. It's easier to just say you don't eat C.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483552479.0" user="speckofSTARDUST" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, for the moment, but if there was a sudden surge in people eliminating certain meats from their diet (the way the LGBT movement has grown in the past few years) we would probably see words created to define those other groups as more of them presented themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483767853.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you like female and men or cross dress. You're bi. 

That is not the experience of the crossdresser community.

I kind of agree that bi means an interest in both men and women. But the reality is that an interest in gender non conforming is not guaranteed by the general bracket bisexual.


&amp;gt; That makes you - bi-sexual. Why would you need a word to describe that you're only into guys who cross-dress?

Well crossdressers would need to know because bisexuals like crossdressers as much or only a little more than the general population.

Labels save a lot of time and disappointment.

&amp;gt;Could you imagine if our entire language was made up of words that described phrases? That would just be stupid. There is no reason you need a word to describe that much.

You mean you don't need that word.

Crossdressers and people who want or don't want them do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484374230.0" user="starlitepony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well crossdressers would need to know because bisexuals like crossdressers as much or only a little more than the general population.

Forgive me if I'm totally off-base, but I'm not sure I understand what you're saying. Are you suggesting that bisexuals should like crossdressers significantly more than the general population?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484767581.0" user="theory_of_kink" delta="False">
    <text>So there is a term called pansexuality. Which generally means attraction to anyone including anyone who is not gender confirming.

Its kind of controversial because that sounds like bisexual. However not all bisexuals are attracted to non gender confirming people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483502796.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>So what?  Let's say I'm a straight man who likes chubby women.  I wouldn't demand a unique term for my sexuality.  I'll just say I'm straight.  If you want more details about my sexual preferences, I'll tell you I prefer larger women.  

The same should be true for people with other unconventional sexual preferences.  If you like feminine men and women, just call yourself bisexual.  If someone asks for more details, you can then specify that you like your partners to be feminine.  

Insisting that everyone use a term which acknowledges your preference for feminine partners is as odd as insisting that everyone use a term which acknowledges your preference for chubby women.  It's a little too much information.  Why is it important that everyone reference your specific sexual fetishes when talking about you?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483456864.0" user="123456seven8910" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes the validity of the gender binary. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483554022.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>These words cover everything perfectly fine if all we know about is orientation.

But identity is something different.

Would you also agree that transexual is an acceptable category?  it doesn't tell us who someone likes to fuck, but instead tells us that a person's sex and gender do not (or previously did not) match.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483890715.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>Sort of- it depends on how you look at it.

If you accept the birth sex/gender- than a trans to woman is still a man.

If you accept the acquired/transitioned sex/gender- than a trans to woman is a woman.

Why bother classifying it any further? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484121035.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>So no, you do not believe that transgender is an acceptable label.

Should its use be abolished?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484241314.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not suggesting we should abolish anything- I'm just saying it doesn't make much sense to complicate things further.

We have a system, and the system, for the vast, vast majority of the population, works perfectly fine.

A few individuals here and there who wish to be classified further can call themselves what ever they like- it doesn't change the fact that this is meaningless, especially when speaking biologically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483045452.0" user="YoungRecluse" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that there are, in fact, many many shades and names for one color. 
I don't really care if someone is transgender or pansexual or anything out of the norm. I will treat them the same way I treat everyone, with respect. But what I don't understand is why some people feel the need to "overclassify" themselves, if you will.
Maybe it's because I was brought up an only child and my friends were, and still are, cisgender, heterosexual people. I was raised with the gender binary as the norm, and it's difficult for me to understand the need for the many ways to classify yourself. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483049979.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>If you live in Saudi Arabia, you might know there are Muslims, Jews, Hindus, Christians etc. If you live in Italy, you know there are Catholics and Protestants. If you live in Alabama, you know there are Lutherans, Anglicans, Episcopalians, Mormons, etc.

The more people you meet from these different sects, the more names you need to tell them apart. It might be enough for a Muslim to know that Christians exist, but it's probably not enough for someone from the Bible Belt.

This is all just from the position of practicality. The need for self actualization is an entirely different motivation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483469268.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is, Religous denominations typically don't get offended if you refer to them generally as Christians, Muslims, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483550996.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>And gay, lesbian, bixsexual, transexual, heteroraomantic-cisgendered-non-sexuals do not get offended if you refer to them generally as "people," or "Americans," or "Spaniards."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483557822.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, of the three example descriptors you gave, none refer to sexuality.  Are you saying we aren't allowed to refer to a person's sexuality unless we use very specific terms?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483573875.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>Christians all have a fundamental thing in common: they believe in Christ.

What's the blanket term to refer to all people of any religion?  Religious people?  That's a description, not an adjective.  With religion, we don't summarize people except when we can do so with sufficient specificity.  We do not say that everyone who believes in Christ is Catholic, just because Catholics set themselves up first.

So, with sexuality, we could refer to all people who are sexual as.... sexuals?  We could, I suppose.  Asexual is clearly a real adjective being used nominally for people (and by their own choice), so sexual seems like the appropriate collective name for its opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483600448.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>I think the terms heterosexual, homosexual, bisexual, and asexual are suitably general.  They're can be compared to the larger religions of Christianity, Islam, Judaism, etc.  

If you're a man who's attracted to masculine men and women, then that's just like being in a smaller denomination of the larger bisexual religion.  It should be ok to refer to you simply as bisexual as opposed to a more specific term.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483615756.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>I think I see the disconnect here.  The problem we're having is not one of sexuality, it's one of identity.

If I'm an androgynous woman who was born a man, but has had significant alterations done, what do you call someone attracted to me?

Hetero-, Homo-, Bi-, and A- prefixes work just fine if the gender binary were absolute.  I think we could reasonably fill in the missing space with a simple Pan- prefix.

Also, if I'm a male-to-female transexual who likes men, am I gay or straight?  Does whether or not I've had surgery change your answer?

I think that all those specific terms are needed, but only within the appropriate contexts.  They are essentially technical jargon.  Transistors, resistors, microprocessors, heat sinks, and semiconductors are all *electronics* to most of us, but that word is completely useless to someone trying to fix a computer.

Likewise, Gay, Straight, and Bi do the job in a lot of cases, but aren't necessarily going to solve your problem if you're actually trying to fuck someone, or talk about the particular issues that crop up in various circumstances as a matter of academic interest, personal identity, or perhaps most importantly - representative democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483709419.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hetero-, Homo-, Bi-, and A- prefixes work just fine if the gender binary were absolute.

They work just fine with the gender binary being flexible, since those terms are generally inclusive of wide ranges of gender identity and expression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483737758.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>Bi- Literally means "2"

Those two are "male" and "female"

If you do not identify closely with one of those two, you are not included in that terminology.  The use of bisexual to refer to all people who are attracted to more than one thing is little more than a means of ignoring the fact that the two genders are not set in stone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483759954.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>And "trans-" literally means "physically across or through." And yet, we don't say that "transexuality" is a fetish for the person sitting across from us. 

"Homo-" literally means "same" (or alternately "man"). "Hetero-" literally means difference. And we don't say they're fetishes for sameness or difference. 

Similarly, most "lesbians" don't come from Greece. Wisconsin perhaps. And "Gay" men are not always happy, except when they are. 

An "English Horn" is not English and it's not a horn, it's a French woodwind instrument. A "Planetary Nebula" has nothing to do with planets, it's a stage in some branches of stellar evolution.

Note that the original meaning of "bisexual" didn't refer to sexual orientation at all, when it was applied to sexual orientation by Krafft-Ebing, his explanation was psychosexual hermaphroditism, the idea that we had both male and female sexualities.

Language is defined by the history of use within communities, in spite of what your middle school teacher said. You don't get to erase an entire century when we were institutionalized as gender deviants, followed by the organization of bisexual communities because you want to go all Noah Webster priggish over your Greco-Roman roots. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484114980.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You don't get to erase an entire century when we were institutionalized as gender deviants, followed by the organization of bisexual communities because you want to go all Noah Webster priggish over your Greco-Roman roots.

Doesn't forcing everyone into a small number of predefined boxes do a better job of disrespecting those who were prosecuted in the past than providing higher-granularity language for people to use when referring to themselves freely?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484133948.0" user="cbrachyrhynchos" delta="False">
    <text>They're not boxes, they're adjectives. And they're defined broadly because we claimed the freedom to describe ourselves in that way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483418850.0" user="Sergnb" delta="False">
    <text>Consider the following: the examples you set as acceptable, like bisexual, asexual, aromantic or pansexual, would have been considered completely over the top 40 years ago. "What the hell is a pansexual? I swear you kids are getting weirder and weirder, there's only fags and normal people!" is something you propably would heard from a 50 years old person nowadays. 

You know about the subtleties of sexuality because those sexualities have become more socially acceptable and people that identify as such can openly talk about them. The more obscure ones tho, still are very much frowned upon and received with a weird look. Why do you think these labels prevail in places like tumblr? Because it's the only safe haven where they can say these things without getting violence threats or being dimissed as a weirdo. 

On the topic of "hating people that don't call you appropiately"... well, I don't think hate is right word. More like annoyance. Keep in mind that these people are in the most part people that have been ostracized and alienated by classmates, coworkers and/or family for most of their lives. This creates a need to be heard, a need to be listened to... which leads to bitterness or agressiveness when it doesn't happen, a rebel phase. Sort of like a dog that had a previous owner that used to beat the shit out of him and now he growls whenever he sees you picking up a newspaper. They have been "trained" towards recognizing certain patterns which they think lead to bad feelings. I'm not gonna disagree with you, I too roll my eyes whenever someone classifies himself with 7 different pronouns and goes on a 5 paragraph rant about how misunderstood he is when someone *mistakenly refers to him as a "he"*, but I can't say I don't understand the guy. He doesn't really hate anyone, he is just going through the typical teenage "I hate everyone" (but not really) phase, and not being properly referred to as a "xi" or whatever is only one excuse. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483479242.0" user="kylestephens54" delta="False">
    <text>I dont appreciate you reffering to me as a white cisgendered human male. I am a tri-gender Pyro fox. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483065443.0" user="amicable-newt" delta="False">
    <text>Crayola's words for blue aren't official and no one reprimands you for labeling as turquoise something that Crayola says is Shamrock.

If there was a movement to get people to use the correct color terms in contexts where we didn't use them before, it's not unreasonable to question why this new expectation to be versatile with these finer distinctions has come about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483071794.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>I hear you. It's hard to keep track of the seemingly endless new terms, but I can see why people want to come up with new terms to describe themselves. 

The terms they come up with aren't any more official than Shamrock, (then again, what makes a word "official" anyways?) but if a friend wants me to remember the specific term he or she uses, I'll do it as a sign of respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483083101.0" user="YoungRecluse" delta="False">
    <text>your last point is how I feel. I will use the pronoun or identity you want me to when I'm referring to you, but society as a whole is not going to accept every last one people come up with. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483629991.0" user="RobbieGee" delta="False">
    <text>I'm guessing one of the effects of all this is that it's becoming a topic at all. What I do fear though is that the adage about "all press is good press" is false and this is doing more to damage the LGBT community than help it. Annoy people too much and you'll lose supporters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483868987.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Anyone who wouldn't support LGBT people because they were annoyed by new words is scum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483919490.0" user="celticguy08" delta="False">
    <text>I think it isn't that people would not support LGBT people, but I think it would set back equality as it would lead to further segregation.

For instance, a person may agree with the key points behind the LGBT movement such as the right to marry and not be discriminated against, but after they meet someone who can't stop talking about their gender and becomes very offended and offensive when someone doesn't use the correct pronoun, then they may be less inclined to associate themselves with LGBT people as a whole.

I don't think any rational person would have the actions of a small fraction of a group change their view on the issues that group fights for, but it may affect their decision to befriend people in that group in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483931971.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really see the problem in jerks willingly sequestering themselves from others. And anyone who would write off all LGBT individuals because of a few annoying encounters is a jerk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483947100.0" user="celticguy08" delta="False">
    <text>It's not exactly writing off, it is just a negative factor, a disincentive, which may create an unconscious bias until that person meets someone who breaks the stereotypes they have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27486697145.0" user="RobbieGee" delta="False">
    <text>It's the same thing as someone that is constantly negative, overly pessimistic, etc. They're emotionally draining. I'm disabled and from that I know more disabled people than others (networking happens between us as well). I can see from Facebook posts that there is a *clear* difference in the posts from people that are disabled and those that are not. A larger percentage of disabled people tend to post way more negative/pessimistic/sympathy posts than those with good health. It's understandable, but you can only take so much before you unconsciously distance yourself from that person.

Then again, some focus on the positive and people flock around them to show support. There's a girl I know that's almost paralyzed from muscle loss and recently had to operate in a hose to the stomach (think that was how it worked) since her swallowing muscles had stopped working. So basically she can't eat/taste anything any more. She's just ~30 years old and will die soon. Still there's not a single negative post from her. She posts pictures of her on trips to places, is always smiling and is someone that spreads joy wherever she is.

It gives some perspective when someone complains about their problems. I can sympathize with most of it. It's fine if you're pissed off that you lost your iPhone in the ocean; I understand completely when you're depressed that your girlfriend broke up with you. The problem is when you **only** talk about stuff like that.

Now the problem is that the brain tends to assign trends from a group of people to the individuals in them. That's how racism and prejudice forms. I'm reminded of modern feminism, I see reactions from people I know that they're getting annoyed about all the negative press they create. For instance the shirt of that researcher from the asteroid landing; instead of obsessing over a shirt, they should have focused on praising all the brilliant women contributing to the project.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483410541.0" user="kodemage" delta="False">
    <text>You're implying that there is some kind of gender pronoun police? There is no official source of the English language to repremand you just like the crayons... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483464403.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>He means that people will scold you for using the wrong term.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483542139.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>For all we know, in the artist community people scold each other for using the wrong specific color name too. Outside of the LGBTQ+ community, people really aren't expected to use specific words beyond the basic ones that OP listed, and sure, someone somewhere has been scolded for using the wrong one before, but it's not like it's a common problem in society. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483633426.0" user="RobbieGee" delta="False">
    <text>I read it more like it's something that's happening on Reddit/SRS/Tumbler and it's spreading around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483569090.0" user="kodemage" delta="False">
    <text>people will scold you for looking at them what's your point? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483574687.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>I'm clarifying what the guy you responded to meant.  You didn't seem to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484155149.0" user="stillclub" delta="False">
    <text>and no ones flips their minds when you correct them and tell them its shamrock. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483089307.0" user="Raintee97" delta="False">
    <text>If a color is bluish greenish that's what I'm going to call it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483494897.0" user="speckofSTARDUST" delta="False">
    <text>So what if you had aqua, teal, and a bunch of other "bluish green" color crayons in front of you and you needed to express which one you were talking about to someone else. Blue-green just wouldn't cut it in certain contexts. 

Think about a person who is male and is attracted to females and MTF transgendereds. Some people might call him straight while others may consider him bisexual, while he may not feel comfortable identifying as either. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483273795.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Crayola didn't invent the colors though.  I would say people are definitely inventing genders to call themselves, not just what to name them.  Just because it's a binary system doesn't mean trans doesn't exist.  Just because you aren't stereotypical doesn't mean you aren't a man or a woman.  

Same for sexual orientations.  You either like men, women, both, or neither.  Any other thing is not a sexual orientation or is also made up to make sense along with made up genders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483505548.0" user="speckofSTARDUST" delta="False">
    <text>First, "sex" is binary, for the most part, you either have a penis or a vagina at birth, for the most part. 

Gender, is not biological, and is basically a social construct, many people identify with male or female, but there are other options. I don't totally get it all either, I identify as a female which is also the sex I was born, but I can still understand how someone does not,identify as specifically a boy or a girl.

As far as sexual orientations, consider this. Meet Bob,if I say he's straight, you probably assumed I meant he likes women. However, Bob also likes MTF transgendered. Does this make him bisexual? No, he doesn't like men. So while you personally don't care about Bob or his sexuality, I'm sure you can imagine his,frustration with not really feeling comfortable calling himself straight or bisexual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27483552127.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Bob is straight and needs to get over himself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27484496726.0" user="Nosrac88" delta="False">
    <text>I'm color blind

Can confirm all "blues" are the same </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
