<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487034630.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children.

Clarification question: does this CMV only apply to single-income couples in which one spouse doesn't work AND in which the couple has children? Because if both spouses work and it's a dual-income household, and/or if the dual-income couple doesn't have any children, then #2 doesn't apply. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487275738.0" user="rickbrody95" delta="False">
    <text>This will apply to any couples where the salary of the "workaholic" is necessary to support the family, whether or not the other one works </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487410846.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>Does it apply when the "breadwinner" and family would be doing just fine with less money? Money has diminished returns. If you have excess over the big items (Food, Shelter, Education), there is a point where extra money isn't gaining anything, but extra time would be. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
