<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487067019.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that spending more time with a spouse is an opportunity cost? From that, the spouse of a workaholic can get a pretty good estimate of the monetary value the workaholic places on the relationship. One could also argue that criticizing someone for being a workaholic is a negotiation tactic to help determine the value of the relationship, and that the "unfair" part is the workaholic could be misleading the spouse by not being explicit about the true value she or he places on the relationship. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487141462.0" user="learhpa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are you saying that spending more time with a spouse is an opportunity cost?

To an economist, everything is an opportunity cost. :)
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487274491.0" user="rickbrody95" delta="False">
    <text>The reason time with a spouse isn't necessarily an opportunity cost is that there are times when it's impossible to work, maybe 9 PM to 5 AM, so the workaholic isn't always exchanging one for another. An opportunity cost is something always lost when doing something, which would be the case is the person could work 24 hours a day

Plus, it goes back to the fact that some people have to work longer in order to keep their job or be successful. It isn't a voluntary trade</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487436860.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>So are you saying that you *can't* think of situations where it's reasonable to calculate opportunity costs? I didn't say it was universal. I said it could be done. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
