<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487214358.0" user="AnnaLemma" delta="False">
    <text>Every relationship comes with its own set of expectations, and it's absolutely *normal* that these expectations vary from one couple to the next. Some people are okay with an "open" relationship and some would consider that to be cheating - neither one is objectively "true" or "right" but each party comes into a relationship with certain expectations, and problems *will* arise if the relationship starts to substantially deviate from those expectations.

It's the same thing with work hours: it's not objectively bad to be a workaholic, but it's also not objectively "wrong" of someone to feel that it's a significant deviation from the relationship as it was originally established. It's not wrong to want to earn as much money as you can, but it's also not wrong to feel that at some point the extra money isn't worth it, and that you would rather spend more time with your spouse. 

Both are valid trade-offs, and the balance between the two is something which is up to the couple to determine.

So yes: if you go into a relationship expecting it to remain monogamous, it's "unfair" if one of the partners decides to change it after two years (and vice versa). And if you go into a relationship with the expectation that you get to spend time with your spouse in the evenings, it's "unfair" if all of a sudden s/he is gone for months on end. 

If they are to be fair, the exact nature and parameters of any relationship must be determined by *all parties involved* - and it's "unfair" for one party to make unilateral decisions when those decisions affect everybody in the relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
