<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27486987148.0" user="syd_malicious" delta="False">
    <text>I think that your conclusion is correct based on the 3 axioms you have laid out, but I would like to challenge your axioms.

1. While there is a minimum amount of work and a minimum standard to which most of us are held, people who are typical 'workaholics' are the type who generally do WAY more than the minimum. I'm a teacher and a workaholic. My colleagues leave most days at around 3:45 (the end of the day is 3:15, so they are already doing more than the minimum) but I stay until 4:30 most days. My bosses themselves are gone by this hour and have no idea when I pack up to leave so it would be pretty hard to say that they are the reason I'm stuck at work.

2. 'The more someone works the more they make' is only true if they are a) a waged employee or b) looking for some sort of promotion or bonus. In fact the whole reason salaried pay exists is so that the bosses from part 1 can demand their minimum work requirements and not pay you extra on the occasions that work progresses slower than usual or unexpected issues come up. And again, it only makes sense to work extra hard to get a promotion if you have some reasonable expectation of getting one. I am on steps and ladders - the only way to get a pay raise is to work more YEARS, not more hours. So if my reasons for working late are so my bosses will notice me and promote me I am SOL.

3. For 'workaholics' the alternative is, quite simply: work less. The marginal difference that an extra hour of work makes at the end of a 10 hour day is so minimal that when I look back at the days I worked super late to get super far ahead I laugh at myself to keep from crying because 2 days later the difference is hardly noticeable.

I think spouses should be understanding when things come up UNEXPECTEDLY, or when someone is putting in extra time in order to get caught up or get ahead. But when there is no discernable benefit, its hard for a partner to look at the costs of your time together and say 'yeah, sure, it's great that you're working so hard even though it means I never see you and even though it's not making much difference in the grand scheme of things.'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487198062.0" user="TheWitchBride" delta="False">
    <text>Not trying to offend or anything im sure you work very hard, but working an extra hour hardly makes you a workaholic. I think the OP is mostly talking about people who work like an extra 20+hours a week and barely make it home for family time...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487207282.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>Someone working an extra 20 hours a week will never make it home for family time. 20 hours would be 4 extra hours a day. My kids go to bed at 8, which is 3 hours after I get off. 

That said, and extra hour a day would cut my family time in half, so it is a reasonable complaint that 20% more time on the job = 50% less time with family. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487503837.0" user="syd_malicious" delta="False">
    <text>I get that. I was not trying suggest that working an extra hour makes me a workaholic. I am a workaholic because I also bring 3-4 hours of work home with me a night. My point was about the diminishing returns of doing the extra work compared to the cost to the other person in a relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
