<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487563611.0" user="dorky2" delta="False">
    <text>Successful relationships happen when a couple A) shares the same values or B) comes to a mutually satisfying compromise when their values differ.  If one person values his or her career highly, and the other feels that family relationships are more important, it is their responsibility as a couple to both put forward their perspectives and to arrive at an arrangement *together* that they can agree on.

My husband and I have this very issue.  I put in my M-F 40 hours and when I come home from work, I want to be with my family.  He often works late into the night and on weekends.  That is partially because of the nature of his work and partially because of his personality.  (I wouldn't call him a workaholic but when he has a project he's working on, he gets very ambitious and focused.)  The way we compromise is by scheduling time together ahead of time.  It he were totally unwilling to commit to spending that time with me, or if I were unwilling to support him working odd hours, we would have an ongoing issue.  This way, we both feel supported.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
