<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487306236.0" user="I_eat_veal" delta="False">
    <text>I want to preface by noting that this critique only applies to those not working in certain demanding industries (medicine, police, EMT work) since those careers come with expectations that hours are variable. 

1. For the average salaried worker, amount of work =/= hours worked. There are always ways to increase efficiency and improve your working style. I've seen managers with a 10-5 pound out a demanding job, but they allocate 30min every morning and evening to deal with emails and urgent requests at work. It really boils down to your personal time management skills and how focused your remain at your job. Some companies have a toxic office culture that encourages "presence" at the job more so than ability, meaning management wants to see you at the desk, regardless if there is any productivity achieved. See 3.

2. False, most workaholics work for the sense of self satisfaction. Don't bullshit around this, there are numerous comparable jobs, but they may not command the same level of respect, status, etc. Ultimately, you will be rewarded based upon ability, not staying 2 hours later than everyone else. In fact, this could have a negative impact on your career mobility as your will always be seen as "the analyst" or "the sales guy", instead of moving upwards towards a more balanced role.

3. There is an alternative. Find a new job. During job interviews, clarify what you're looking for in a position. Believe it or not, so many companies now encourage telework/flexible work schedules because their employees are more productive with their time, plus its seen as an employee benefit to attract better talent.  And don't leave a current job until you have a new one lined up for god's sake. This should be obvious. 

In the end, time is precious, and time=money in more ways than I ever realized before working FT. Most people already spend more than 50% of their waking hours at work, and once they reach retirement age, their biggest regret is usually working too much. Don't lose focus of what's important in life, just like your job, relationships require work and commitment. If you're not willing to put in the time, things will pass by and those opportunities will be lost. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
