<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487274249.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>On point two - you are saying they work hard to support themselves and their family. What if they aren't even the one who makes the most money in the relationship? does the spouse have a right to complain then? 

Say spouse A is working 40 hours a week making 100k, and spouse B is working 60 hours a week making 50k. Can Spouse A complain then? 

If you have two working parents, what if the person who is *choosing* to work extra hours is causing the other spouse to take at hit at work? IE: spouse 1 refuses to leave at 5 to pick up the kids from daycare, so spouse 2 ALWAYS has to leave on time, even when they have deadlines at work. 

I would also disagree 100% with the idea that the more someone works (hours) the more money they make. Overall wage is usually much more dependent on what type of job and career you have. 

Finally, a marriage is a relationship. Of course its going to fail if one person refuses to put anything into it. As it is I see my coworkers far far far more than I see my husband or kids. I'd rather make less money and have a happy family than make more money and have my personal life be in shambles, and I expect my husband to give me that same respect. And he SHOULD complain if I started picking up more hours, as I'm salary. My paycheck will not change if I start working more. And I already pick up hours when deadlines require them but there is no need to actively hunt for more. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
