<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487007155.0" user="trublood" delta="False">
    <text>1. Of the workaholics I can think of, they nearly all work extra by choice.  They use overtime, they choose the hardest cases, and they're perfectionists to their own detriment.  The one exception just couldn't say "no", but once he got a more reasonable boss, the problem went away.

2. There's a balance to be struck.  My uncle, for example, had always been a workaholic.  Sure, this helped his kids go to private schools and attend the best summer camps, but he also missed their piano recitals and sacrificed a lot of leisure time with them.  He could have worked less hours, put them in public schools, and had more fun with them on the weekends.

3. You're asking that the boss pot them up to the extra hours.  From what I've seen, this is not always the case.  My husband wouldn't have suffered at all of he didn't work extra hours in his last job.  He took on an extra project that involved odd hours because he wanted to.  Not that I minded, since it was a fascinating project, I'm just making the point that you can choose to work a lot, and it isn't always forced on you.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487281836.0" user="rickbrody95" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between something you're forced to do (finish this or you're fired) and something you have to do

Whether or not it would be possible for, for example, your husband to stretch the project over more days and be home earlier, it was probably important for him to do it at the rate that he did, and would have cause problems if he slowed down  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27487292364.0" user="trublood" delta="False">
    <text>He couldn't have stretched out the project.  It involved checking an instrument and performing procedures at precise times.  He took on the responsibility knowing that he couldn't back out, because he was one of only two people who knew how to use said instrument.  He could have chosen from the beginning not to take on the responsibility though, and wouldn't have been thought less of or penalized in any way.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27490176629.0" user="maxpenny42" delta="False">
    <text>I take issue with your definition of workaholic. A workaholic is not someone with a crappy job and demanding boss. It is not someone who wants to work less but cannot through circumstance. A workaholic is someone who chooses to work crazy hours because they want to or can't stop themselves. It is often time highly paid individuals and often executives. They work crazy hard and climb the ladder and could have lots of less demanding options if they bothered to find them. But they don't want them, they like bein busy and needed at work. 

So when a SO complains they're not saying "how dare you provide for me" they're saying "we are provided for already and can get by with less. I want to spend time with you, not earn more cash we won't spend". Sometimes time is more valuable than money. Workaholics don't want to spend their time at home with family. It's very different from being overworked by circumstance. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
