<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="161698126.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2o9r2m/cmv_its_unfair_to_complain_that_a_spouse_or_so/">
    <title>CMV: It's unfair to complain that a spouse or SO works too much</title>
    <original_poster>rickbrody95</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27487714910.0" user="funchy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've seen many marriages have problems because one of the spouses works too much, or is a "workaholic." While I understand that it's frustrating that a spouse or SO is gone for a long time, it seems completely unfair to get mad directly at the person because he/she works the amount that they do

&amp;gt;1. The amount of work one does is normally controlled by a boss; having to stay overtime or work an extra shift is often times out of the control of the employee

But where you work and the career chosen *is* under your control.  

&amp;gt;2. They work hard to support themselves AND their family. It's not easy to support yourself, let alone a SO/Spouse and/or children. The more someone works, the more money they make (normally).

But do you work to live... or live to work? 

What's the point of having a family if you spend every spare moment at the office?   Why not stay single?

&amp;gt;3. There is no good alternative. The employee could request to work less, but that could result in less money and conflicts with employer. They could look for another job, but that's unrealistic; jobs are hard to come by, and leaving a job could leave a person unemployed for a prolonged time.

That sounds like an excuse.  Not every job requires you to work 70 or 80 hours a week.  If you have a family or want one,  you don't take a job where you're never home. 

&amp;gt;I understand that an SO/spouse working a lot can be upsetting, but saying you're mad or upset at someone for being a workaholic seems unfair. CMV!

What you're not acknowledging is that a person has more than a responsibly to make money.   When you have a family, to them you're more than a paycheck.   You're a spouse and a father.   That means you have responsibilities to those people.   To show your partner emotional support,  friendship,  affection, and intimacy.   To be there for your kid,  teaching him how to play baseball or helping him with homework.    

When your spouse married you,  they didn't marry a paycheck -  they married a person.   When you said those marriage vows, you made a promise to be a good spouse.  *Not* a good income -- a good spouse.  By marrying them under false pretenses you are breaking that promise.   That is unfair. 

Also consider what that behavior says to your spouse and kids:  your action tells them that money is far more important than them.  That may be hurtful.  

Nobody is forcing you to have a partner or children.   If you want to work 80 hours a week, that's fine.  But don't drag others into your life just to vanish.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
