<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1617149478.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qqt4iu/cmv_tone_policing_is_ok/">
    <title>CMV: Tone Policing is OK</title>
    <original_poster>bluepillarmy</original_poster>
    <original_post>  

Just from the get go, I want to say that I am rather on the left as opposed to being on the right or liberal. What I am about to say, therefore, is targeted as people who lean left but it is applicable to anyone. 

I have a feeling a lot people are going to disagree but here me out on this one but, I don’t really subscribe to the received definition of tone policing. If we go to my favorite source, Wikipedia, we find this [article](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tone_policing). If you don’t feel like reading the whole thing, check out this quote: 

*Tone policing has been described by one writer as "when someone (usually a privileged person) in a conversation or situation about oppression shifts the focus of the conversation from the oppression being discussed to the way it is being discussed. Tone policing prioritizes the comfort of the privileged person in the situation over the oppression of the disadvantaged person."*

This to me seems a rather narrow definition? Tone policing is a lot of things. The term “mansplaining” is policing the tone of arrogant and pompous men with privilege who try to talk down to people. When we use the word “mansplain” we are criticizing pretentious men for their condescending tone. A similar case is the use of the term “Karen”. What are Karens? They are women who demand things in an overly aggressive and entitled manner or tone, right? I think that there are few rational people that would argue that men should never try to explain things, or women should never raise valid concerns about customer service. The terms “mansplain” and “Karen” exist to police tone. 

What’s more, no one likes being tone policed. Mansplainers would never admit that they’re mansplaining, Karens would never admit that they are Karening. And it’s not hard to understand why. When we use these terms, we are changing the focus of what they are they are trying to say to how they are saying it. We are not listening to them. 

But I would argue that’s OK. Because no one wants to listen to something that is being said in a rude, condescending or confrontational tone. Not your partner, not your kids, not your parents, not your teachers, not your students, and certainly not your audience. Tone policing is OK. 

But there is a qualitative difference when tone policing is done by privileged people to marginalized people, right? 

Yes and no. I understand that not everyone has equal access to power and a lot of people have perfectly valid reasons to lose their temper when someone inadvertently insults them in a demeaning and dehumanizing manner. However, this does not change fundamental facts of human nature and human behavior. Think about it for a second. People who are insulting can be insulting in one of two ways, purposefully and inadvertently. Let’s look at inadvertently first. 

Imagine that someone, an African-American woman, is offended by a middle aged coworker who uses some horrifically outdated and tone deaf but ultimately innocuous phrase like, “forshizzle”. Yuck.

And this is infuriating. I get that. But what is the proper way to deal with this? To shout at the coworker? To berate and belittle them? What will that achieve? Most like fear and resentment about being publicly embarrassed about something that they did not intend to mean as offensive. That does not mean that we should let the offending coworker off the hook. But it does mean that we should be careful with our tone. Because if we don’t, we run the risk of alienating a lot of people who might otherwise be sympathetic. 

What about people who are intentionally offensive? What about racists, white supremacists, and alt-right trolls? Surely we can unleash our rage and fury on them, right? 

Wrong. And it’s not hard to understand why. Just think about it. If you are someone who finds themselves on the non-Trumpian side of American and world politics, I’m willing to bet you love watching videos of Karens throwing tantrums, or popular subreddits like r/insanepeoplefacebook or r/neckbeards or which are devoted to mocking privileged and entitled people. It’s funny to watch people lose their shit, isn’t it?

So, if you are someone deplores the rise of bigoted, intolerant, nativist politicians (like me), you’ll probably want to police your tone and the tone of your ostensible allies a bit *more*, rather than less. Throwing a tantrum, calling names, losing your cool is playing directly into the hands of your opponents. You are making yourself look ridiculous when you do that. You are making yourself look like them. 

But, one might say, it’s natural and healthy to express anger and frustration. Perhaps, in personal relationships, but not really in professional settings and certainly not in political ones. We are in for a bumpy decade and the last thing we need is to act as though losing one’s cool is a righteous political expression. Let’s work more on being measured, calm and ruthless in the pursuit of our goals. Contrapoints has a great video about this. [Check it out. ](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QuN6GfUix7c) And change my view. I would love to hear from people who think that tone policing is a bad idea.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38218333829.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're kind of missing the point of the concept of "tone policing".

My understanding of "tone policing" is not that complicated discussions should always be done in a calm, measured, and reasonable manner.  Rather, it's when you *stop having the conversation about the topic at hand in order to have one about the manner in which the conversation is happening.*

If you're trying to explain to someone how, say, systemic racism works without explicitly racist laws and that person says "whoa now, no need to get all defensive, you're not going to convince anyone if you talk to them like that", *the conversation has ended.*  Now you are no longer talking about systemic racism, you are talking about *how to talk about systemic racism*.  Said person has successfully deflected the conversation away from one that they find uncomfortable to one that is more palatable - the "appropriate" way to have discourse about whatever grievance you have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38218766298.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>Just to piggy back on your comment, there are so many posts on this very subreddit that get into the word "privilege" being problematic because it offends conservative white people.  There's no real way to address this in an objective way that *doesn't* offend conservatives, as it contradicts a core tennet of conservative thought and values.  "I am 100% responsible for my own actions, and my success was attained through my own hard work and effort."

They use ambiguous and cute sounding terms like "equality of outcome vs equality of opportunity" to justify their position that limits equality to the greatest degree possible.  I've even seen conservatives disagree with public education as it ultimately influenced "equality of outcome."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38218979698.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the reasoning behind the idea that the word "privilege" puts people on the defensive, although I agree that it inherently won't square with the ideal that people are 100% responsible for their own success, independent of any social factors.  Defensive people are generally not interested in changing their viewpoint because they have become vested in defending it.

However, the idea of "black disadvantage" seems like a reframing at best (disadvantaged compared to *white people*, not necessarily compared to *everyone*) and a divide-and-conquer tactic at worst (is "black disadvantage" different than "indigenous disadvantage", etc.).  If we focus on disadvantage and are looking to do the most good, we basically devolve into gatekeeping who is *actually* disadvantaged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219496112.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>Reframing the question as "black disadvantage" also allows an out - it's not about them anymore - which is ultimately what they're looking for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219547881.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>That is an excellent point as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219701655.0" user="gyroda" delta="False">
    <text>Also, isn't this kind of why the term "privilege" was created? It's used to reframe issues like homophobia, racism and sexism in exactly the way you're talking about.

Like, we already have a term for "racial disadvantage", it's called *racism*. And there are plenty of people who will get *just* as defensive if you start using that word instead of "privilege".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38220570627.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>I believe so. I think it's great at it, because pretty much every discussion nitpicking about the use of the word end up being perfect examples of what the word describes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
