<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1617149478.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qqt4iu/cmv_tone_policing_is_ok/">
    <title>CMV: Tone Policing is OK</title>
    <original_poster>bluepillarmy</original_poster>
    <original_post>  

Just from the get go, I want to say that I am rather on the left as opposed to being on the right or liberal. What I am about to say, therefore, is targeted as people who lean left but it is applicable to anyone. 

I have a feeling a lot people are going to disagree but here me out on this one but, I don’t really subscribe to the received definition of tone policing. If we go to my favorite source, Wikipedia, we find this [article](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tone_policing). If you don’t feel like reading the whole thing, check out this quote: 

*Tone policing has been described by one writer as "when someone (usually a privileged person) in a conversation or situation about oppression shifts the focus of the conversation from the oppression being discussed to the way it is being discussed. Tone policing prioritizes the comfort of the privileged person in the situation over the oppression of the disadvantaged person."*

This to me seems a rather narrow definition? Tone policing is a lot of things. The term “mansplaining” is policing the tone of arrogant and pompous men with privilege who try to talk down to people. When we use the word “mansplain” we are criticizing pretentious men for their condescending tone. A similar case is the use of the term “Karen”. What are Karens? They are women who demand things in an overly aggressive and entitled manner or tone, right? I think that there are few rational people that would argue that men should never try to explain things, or women should never raise valid concerns about customer service. The terms “mansplain” and “Karen” exist to police tone. 

What’s more, no one likes being tone policed. Mansplainers would never admit that they’re mansplaining, Karens would never admit that they are Karening. And it’s not hard to understand why. When we use these terms, we are changing the focus of what they are they are trying to say to how they are saying it. We are not listening to them. 

But I would argue that’s OK. Because no one wants to listen to something that is being said in a rude, condescending or confrontational tone. Not your partner, not your kids, not your parents, not your teachers, not your students, and certainly not your audience. Tone policing is OK. 

But there is a qualitative difference when tone policing is done by privileged people to marginalized people, right? 

Yes and no. I understand that not everyone has equal access to power and a lot of people have perfectly valid reasons to lose their temper when someone inadvertently insults them in a demeaning and dehumanizing manner. However, this does not change fundamental facts of human nature and human behavior. Think about it for a second. People who are insulting can be insulting in one of two ways, purposefully and inadvertently. Let’s look at inadvertently first. 

Imagine that someone, an African-American woman, is offended by a middle aged coworker who uses some horrifically outdated and tone deaf but ultimately innocuous phrase like, “forshizzle”. Yuck.

And this is infuriating. I get that. But what is the proper way to deal with this? To shout at the coworker? To berate and belittle them? What will that achieve? Most like fear and resentment about being publicly embarrassed about something that they did not intend to mean as offensive. That does not mean that we should let the offending coworker off the hook. But it does mean that we should be careful with our tone. Because if we don’t, we run the risk of alienating a lot of people who might otherwise be sympathetic. 

What about people who are intentionally offensive? What about racists, white supremacists, and alt-right trolls? Surely we can unleash our rage and fury on them, right? 

Wrong. And it’s not hard to understand why. Just think about it. If you are someone who finds themselves on the non-Trumpian side of American and world politics, I’m willing to bet you love watching videos of Karens throwing tantrums, or popular subreddits like r/insanepeoplefacebook or r/neckbeards or which are devoted to mocking privileged and entitled people. It’s funny to watch people lose their shit, isn’t it?

So, if you are someone deplores the rise of bigoted, intolerant, nativist politicians (like me), you’ll probably want to police your tone and the tone of your ostensible allies a bit *more*, rather than less. Throwing a tantrum, calling names, losing your cool is playing directly into the hands of your opponents. You are making yourself look ridiculous when you do that. You are making yourself look like them. 

But, one might say, it’s natural and healthy to express anger and frustration. Perhaps, in personal relationships, but not really in professional settings and certainly not in political ones. We are in for a bumpy decade and the last thing we need is to act as though losing one’s cool is a righteous political expression. Let’s work more on being measured, calm and ruthless in the pursuit of our goals. Contrapoints has a great video about this. [Check it out. ](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QuN6GfUix7c) And change my view. I would love to hear from people who think that tone policing is a bad idea.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38218475633.0" user="TheBlindingSmoke" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about tone-policing is that it seeks to derail the conversation at hand - that's it. It takes the focus away from the topic being discussed and instead puts it onto the specific words or tone of voice being used to portray it. Tone-policing, in essence, is saying that 'well, maybe if you were nicer to people they wouldn't be racist/sexist/homophobic/whatever towards you'. I'm sure that might be true in some instances, but if 'being nice' was all it took to solve these problems, surely they wouldn't still exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38218553536.0" user="bluepillarmy" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you are saying, but don't you think that they're are always times we should tone police?

I mean, it's does not have to be about racism/sexism/homophobia.  People can bring up legitimate concerns that in ways that are counterproductive in totally mundane situations. 

For example, if my partner says to me, "I have told you not to leave your fucking socks on the floor 1000 times!", I'm going to get defensive.  That's just human nature. 

I don't mean to dismiss people's oppression with this analogy, but I will maintain, that the fundamentals of human nature remain the same not matter what you are talking about.  Nobody likes to be berated.  Full stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38218910202.0" user="TheBlindingSmoke" delta="False">
    <text>See, but in your example, your partner's frustration and anger comes from having told you the same thing again and again and again and you not heeding it the first, second, or fiftieth time they asked you to pick up your socks. Their anger would be justified because clearly telling you nicely and calmly to pick up your socks didn't result in the desired outcome either! This can be applied to cases where tone-policing happens. I only said racism/sexism etc. because it's within these contexts where the topic of tone-policing is primarily discussed (more recently, anyway). People don't always start off angry, the anger develops from having to repeat the same talking points over and over and it going nowhere. Anger is the natural progression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38218995900.0" user="bluepillarmy" delta="False">
    <text>Yes.  I agree.

But, this is where my inept analogy falls apart.  We do not live in a monogamous relationship with society.  We meet people who are our ignorant of our own personal challenges and suffering everyday.  And if they inadvertently transgress, the default reaction should not be to berate them. 

And that's not easy! I admit that.  Losing your temper is *just*.  But it's not smart politically.  There are lots of opponents out there ready to pounce on every tantrum.  We are not living in a perfect world.  There are hearts and minds to be won.  Preaching to the choir is not an effective strategy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219233139.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But it's not smart politically.  There are lots of opponents out there ready to pounce on every tantrum

Doesn't that basically imply that the people who are tone policing are not doing it in good faith? That they are only doing it to attack? That they wouldn't have changed their mind even if the tone had been civil?

Sure on a purely theoretical basis, it is possible that tone policing is done in a purely constructive manner, in which case fine. But in practice, it is basically never done that way.

And since we are not living in a perfect world, we need to consider how a thing is actually done rather than a hypothetical case which basically never happens</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219556682.0" user="bluepillarmy" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that we should tone police ourselves.  We should avoid looking ridiculous by losing our tempers.  

It's poor strategy not to tone police ourselves.  That is my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38219608225.0" user="TheBlindingSmoke" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that it puts people on the defense, and of course no one likes being berated or shouted at (that's partly why anger can actually be a useful tool in some cases). If tone-policing is done in addition to giving an actual response then I'd say it's not as much of an issue, as you're criticising their tone whilst also furthering the conversation. But that isn't what's happening in most cases. Usually, the tone-policing is where the discussion ends, it's a way to bow out of difficult or uncomfortable situations by blaming their delivery for your lack of engagement.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
