<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1628195465.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qxdvnt/cmv_copyright_contradicts_with_decentralisation/">
    <title>Cmv: Copyright contradicts with decentralisation</title>
    <original_poster>planetoryd</original_poster>
    <original_post>By copyright, I mean the copyright applied to information which is easily copied and spread. It can't be held secret as long as one copy has been delivered. Software doesn't really satisfy this criteria since the information, the binaries can be obfuscated  without hindering its functionality, but opensource works nonetheless. 

It is not authorship either, here. Instead I believe copyright encourages plagiarism and copycats get more attention.

The present internet is underdeveloped, so that it is possible to set up paywalls. As the internet progresses, it will be more decentralised, making it impossible to enforce copyright laws.

The problem is how the industry should be financed, in the future where it is not possible or acceptable to do advertising, or it doesn't need to.

Edit

**In a hypothetical future internet which is more decentralized, thanks to the tech advancements, copyright will become impractical to enforce, so that the only way to finance creators is donation, or something else. At that point purchasing is effectively donation for how easy it will be to get a copy.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38290164645.0" user="Melodic_Plate" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah copy right is not for decentralization but as an incentive to innovate.
It gives creators protection from people who just steals the idea and use the economy of scale and mass production to under cut the original creator.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38290742095.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that copyright won't work under a network that is decentralized enough, so that no enforcement is actually done outside where copyright works. 

If the network is going to be more decentralized, the lack of copyright or a better system will result in chaos, for example, possible gradual reduction of income for some people. And the 'unregulated', anarchy region will expand.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
