<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1628195465.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qxdvnt/cmv_copyright_contradicts_with_decentralisation/">
    <title>Cmv: Copyright contradicts with decentralisation</title>
    <original_poster>planetoryd</original_poster>
    <original_post>By copyright, I mean the copyright applied to information which is easily copied and spread. It can't be held secret as long as one copy has been delivered. Software doesn't really satisfy this criteria since the information, the binaries can be obfuscated  without hindering its functionality, but opensource works nonetheless. 

It is not authorship either, here. Instead I believe copyright encourages plagiarism and copycats get more attention.

The present internet is underdeveloped, so that it is possible to set up paywalls. As the internet progresses, it will be more decentralised, making it impossible to enforce copyright laws.

The problem is how the industry should be financed, in the future where it is not possible or acceptable to do advertising, or it doesn't need to.

Edit

**In a hypothetical future internet which is more decentralized, thanks to the tech advancements, copyright will become impractical to enforce, so that the only way to finance creators is donation, or something else. At that point purchasing is effectively donation for how easy it will be to get a copy.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38290315623.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As the internet progresses, it will be more decentralised

As the internet *has* progressed, it has become *less* decentralized. How do you see this trend reversing itself to make copyright laws less enforceable than they are now when copyright holders only have to got to two or three major international corporations to have something struck from like 90% of the websites that actually see traffic? 

Se this article from the Atlantic: "[So Much for the Decentralized Internet](https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/07/twitter-hack-decentralized-internet/614593/)"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38290971817.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>It is getting more monopolistic, for the time being, but the core of the topic is that decentralization is better than monopoly. I know a lot of projects going on as a dweb enthusiast. A typical example of decentralizing is the use of E2E technology, by which sharing copyrighted works among friends is not possible to censor. And that scenario is going to be more common, which is the direct result of dweb tech advancements.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
