<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1628195465.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qxdvnt/cmv_copyright_contradicts_with_decentralisation/">
    <title>Cmv: Copyright contradicts with decentralisation</title>
    <original_poster>planetoryd</original_poster>
    <original_post>By copyright, I mean the copyright applied to information which is easily copied and spread. It can't be held secret as long as one copy has been delivered. Software doesn't really satisfy this criteria since the information, the binaries can be obfuscated  without hindering its functionality, but opensource works nonetheless. 

It is not authorship either, here. Instead I believe copyright encourages plagiarism and copycats get more attention.

The present internet is underdeveloped, so that it is possible to set up paywalls. As the internet progresses, it will be more decentralised, making it impossible to enforce copyright laws.

The problem is how the industry should be financed, in the future where it is not possible or acceptable to do advertising, or it doesn't need to.

Edit

**In a hypothetical future internet which is more decentralized, thanks to the tech advancements, copyright will become impractical to enforce, so that the only way to finance creators is donation, or something else. At that point purchasing is effectively donation for how easy it will be to get a copy.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38290602206.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>NFT are more or less decentralized copyright.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38290813265.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>But that is no more than a ledger recording authorship, and 'ownership' which is not really owning something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38290998100.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but then you're can control that ownership decentrally.

In the real world you could always copy IP, you could just be sued by lawyers.

Now it can be all bots.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291065509.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>Using a VPN or Tor solves it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291281992.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>Can use case what you're talking about.

If your concept is look at me, I put something online I'm not supposed, I mean yeah. 

But if you've fully decentralized copyright then legitimately every service that is between you the file can be notified that you don't have right to the file, and could be sued accordingly. So in this great network, the internet your fucked.

When you use, VPN what you're basically saying is, it will be this difficult for you to find me in this sea of users. But the site you're connecting to can just be, "Your right," and the Block the VPN it's entirety or just sue the VPN. The only reason VPN's work is apathy by the content providers and media fall out.

So your entire view is basically people being apathetic to you when it benefits you, and also apathetic to your when it doesn't fall in your favour.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291332915.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about me, but millions of other people doing that. 

btw, How is it morally right to support copyright ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291571725.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>Generally speaking, if you believe in personal property then you believe people can own something.

If I for example own a rake, and you steal the rake in the night use it to clean up your yard, and then return it undamaged, you have still violated my rights to my property. I may have no lost the rake or suffer monetary damage but my property was still used with out my permission. If you don't believe that's okay then you're moving into collectivism.

If you extend property rights to copyright, its' people can own concept and ideas that they create. But unlike actually object after a set amount of time that copyright ends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291805070.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>If concepts are owned by others, then my thought is not free, for fear of violating copyrights. Anyway I'm not pro-copyright</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291920680.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>Copyright is the exclusive legal right to produce, reproduce, publish or perform an original literary, artistic, dramatic or musical work

Thought falls under known of those.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38292009782.0" user="planetoryd" delta="False">
    <text>Then it should be 'my thought, and my expression for the thought'.

(I didn't intend to discuss the morals of it, and it's off-topic)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38292278555.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>You can express your ideas and discuss them.

Just because Marx published the communist manifesto doesn’t mean you can’t discuss communism. It would just mean you can’t publish his work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291290211.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>That's incorrect. For example if you buy a NBA top shot NFT you are not allowed to upload the video to your youtube channel or do anything commercially with it.

If you happen to have heard of theoretical ways NFTs can be used for copyright, I'm curios.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38291548920.0" user="NetrunnerCardAccount" delta="False">
    <text>When you buy the NBA NFT you are buying a license of the for that content. The license let's you do exactly nothing with that license.

There are NFT that include an actual license that would allow you to redistribute content. As well as ones that allow you to own the content. They are securities at that point so the can't be traded on Open Sea.

In this case the NFT is just a copy of the legal license, with the license/contract saying who ever own the NFT owns the content. Sort of like a bearer bond.

It get's more complicated after that...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
