<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499127933.0" user="Mac30123456" delta="False">
    <text>To me, the problem lies with a lack of education. Voters often don't take the time to learn about every single candidate or they don't care, so they end up voting for the democrat or the republican, whichever embodies their opinions more. I think that if every voter got educated on who they were voting for, we would not have such a divided, two-party government.

Although I find your idea practical, elected officials are more than just people who vote on issues (or at least they should be!). They are leaders, they inspire and negotiate and create a culminating image of those they lead. If there were no leaders, we would have no one to look up to, we would only have ourselves and our own opinions.

Another point I must make about the importance of leaders is that they are smart. They **should** think logically and make choices based upon what they think will benefit the people the most. If every issue was voted on by every citizen, I think we would be worse off. Why? Because despite the US being educated, there are **a lot** of stupid people out there. 

That's my two cents, anyone is welcome to change my view if they want!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499153245.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that it's because of a lack of education.  I think it's because of a lack of motivation.  People are motivated based on the size and certainty of a reward.  People know that in all likelihood a democrat or republican will get elected, so their best bet is to vote for one of those.  Then between those, there are only a few differences that are obvious, so they choose based on that.  

When it matters, people are very engaged.  During election time, people follow the race very closely.  But then, they have no control.  Imagine if people could watch their participation in democracy happening all the time.  It would become a major pastime, I imagine.

Also, if you do a game-theory analysis on our current system, it is much more difficult for 3rd party candidates to get elected than in some of the European systems.

As for the "leaders" thing.  That would be great, and they could still be leaders, trying to educate the public on their opinion.  In fact, with the policy out of their hands, they would pretty much be elected solely on their charisma.

I think people are a lot smarter than people give them credit for.  Usually when people go on about "the masses" making stupid decisions, they really just do not understand what is causing it.  

Eating fast food?  Unless you've been broke, you don't understand just how much cheaper and easier it is.  When you work two jobs, going to the grocery store for organic arugula every other day is not an option. 

Spending money on big screen TVs?  When you're in a hole, and you literally have (if only in your mind) no way out, there is no incentive to save.  You spend on what is going to make you feel good that day, because you're never going to get to the point where you own a house.  If you're 20, and you're going to have to work 50 years to get good enough credit to get a house, there is no point.  You would have to be an idiot to try.

There are all kinds of misconceptions like that that result in people saying that people are stupid.  I think it's because it's easier to hear that, than it is to hear that people are forced into these situations and you aren't doing anything about it.  And the media likes to give you the easiest thing to hear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499574975.0" user="Mac30123456" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for responding. 

I think you misinterpreted my point on the 2 party system. My point was that if people knew more about the candidates , there wouldn't be a likelihood of a dem or rep getting elected, because people would spread out their votes based on who they like best. They wouldn't vote for the candidates most likely to win. That is, however, in a perfect world. 

Thank you for bringing up the point of incentives, that is something I didn't consider in my argument, and I'm an economics student for Christ sake! You are right in that voters need more motivation, I think if voters today had more incentive to vote, the US would be much better off.

You probably changed my view a bit, to not be so pessimistic at the least. Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499964830.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah,  I think most people are well aware of the drawbacks of voting republican or democrat.  It's just that they presume there's no other realistic option.  

The US system actually makes it a lot harder to promote viable 3rd party candidates than a lot of the European parliamentary systems just because the game theory of the setup.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
