<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499057673.0" user="fanningmace" delta="False">
    <text>What do you say to people who do not have internet access?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499070360.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, it's not like such a system would be implemented immediately tomorrow.  There would be a transition, and I think in such a system, it's highly likely people would vote a solution to that problem in.

At this point, I think internet should be considered basic infrastructure like electricity or water.   

Of course given that that's not the tangible reality right now, and even if it were, sometimes people haven't paid their bill.  It seems like it would be feasible to have set dates and go set up polling stations for particularly important issues.

Another solution *could* be to have kind of default settings for different issues.  Like now you can check "All democrat" or "All republican" on an American ballot, but why not "All pro-environment" or "All pro-life"?  Not my favorite, but it could be workshopped.

You could even have party committees with different setups and policies that are basically experiments, see how effective they are, and vote on implementing the optimum policies on the general sites.

People would still have more input than they do when they just give their vote to someone else to do with what they please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499078285.0" user="fanningmace" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well, at this point, I think internet should be considered basic infrastructure like electricity or water.
Of course given that that's not the tangible reality right now, and even if it were, sometimes people haven't paid their bill. It seems like it would be feasible to have set dates and go set up polling stations for particularly important issues.

So you're saying it is OK to allow a system that prevents 15% of Americans from having a say in the vote? You think that having internet should be a pre-requisite to having your voice heard on not "particularly important issues"?

It seems to me that is very unfair and, likely, targets poor people (since I'm guessing the vast majority of people with no internet access are poor.)

It seems like a terribly unfair qualifier.

&amp;gt; People would still have more input than they do when they just give their vote to someone else to do with what they please.

This is debatable. Also, 15% of people would have their input completely removed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499110853.0" user="LuminiferousEthan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So you're saying it is OK to allow a system that prevents 15% of Americans from having a say in the vote?

Well, there are libraries and other places to get on the net for free. If someone wants to vote, they can go there. Or better yet just set up the same polling stations but with laptops instead of ballots. Since its digital, it would eliminate having to count the votes too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499143659.0" user="fanningmace" delta="False">
    <text>But that doesn't solve anything.

&amp;gt; Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election. Now we have the internet.

If you require people to go to a polling place, that defeats the purpose OP laid out in the post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499214463.0" user="LuminiferousEthan" delta="False">
    <text>Ya, but with the people who have internet, which would likely be a good portion, they don't have to go anywhere. 

Honestly i dont even agree with OPs premise, but i dont think people having access to it just because its online would be a problem. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
