<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499072091.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>1. This is simply mob rule. We have an indirect democracy for a reason. 

2. What about hackers? 

3. What about the fact that some people are just more fired up about issues than others? Anti-abortion people are better at mobilizing than pro choice. 

4. The layman isn't an expert on most issues, tell me how would you vote on farming? Whatever SOUNDS good, may not yield results but it sounds pretty. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499118110.0" user="smacksaw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is simply mob rule. We have an indirect democracy for a reason.

Yes, the reason is that the "mob" can rule us instead.

You talk about "mob" in one way, I think of "mob rule" as a cartel, like organised crime.

Considering the payoffs and racketeering that we prosecute, you have to wonder why the government doesn't go after their own politicians.

Representative democracy is neither good nor bad, but has to do with the people in charge. Ours is corrupt. It stands to reason that "mob rule" isn't even worthy of consideration if the people voting don't act like mobsters. 

If you have a corrupt senate or congress and a bunch of honest and thoughtful voters, the mob are the elected representatives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499636107.0" user="Dr_Merkwurdigliebe" delta="False">
    <text>Mob rule is literally never used in this sense. Mob rule is a term that specifically describes rule by the masses — *a mob,* not *the mob.*

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499124892.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>1) I think we have an indirect democracy because a direct democracy has been physically not viable for the past 4000 years.  Civilizations were just too big and transportation too slow.  When it was viable, it existed.  I'm not really sure what you mean by "mob rule," could you explain?  It sounds scary, but I'm not convinced that it's something that has ever existed.

2)  What about hackers now?  There have been accusations of improprieties with ballot tallying software, issues with hanging chads, etc.  In a system that people respect, people work to protect it.  

Edit:  Also, the fact that most of the infrastructure of the internet runs on open-source software shows that a solution can be reached.

3) I think this would actually even something like that out.  Currently, if you don't even think about an issue that much, you just vote for someone totally independent of that issue.  Then people who care so so much vote solely on that issue.  So they're more likely to vote a candidate in who will then cast all of their votes against your interest.  In a direct democracy, you merely vote on the issue, you don't have to make it the main thing you look for in a candidate to balance out the crazies.

4) It's true.  I think most people would abstain from voting on issues they don't understand, because there would be a lot to pay attention to already. I think this would be good.  People shouldn't necessarily vote on issues that don't affect them.  The other thing is, elected officials aren't generally much better about voting just for what sounds good, because they have to get re-elected.  It has to sound good to their electorate.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499201808.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think we have an indirect democracy because a direct democracy has been physically not viable for the past 4000 years. Civilizations were just too big and transportation too slow.

Actually, when we first had democracy, it was direct democracy (i.e. Athens). This is because it was a fairly small population, and pretty much all the major events were local, as there was no way to know what was happening halfway across the world (for example, ancient Athens would have had absolutely no idea about anything that happened in the new world, no matter how important). The fact that population is far higher, and that the world is very convolutedly interconnected makes it a pain to attempt in modern society.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499224565.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, sorry 4000 years was a guess, I was talking about Athens.  

That's the beauty, is you could vote on local issues locally and national issues nationally, all in the same system. 

I think being interconnected doesn't make it a pain, I think it makes it easier.  

Go home every night, read the news and vote on the issue of the day</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499276216.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah, sorry 4000 years was a guess, I was talking about Athens.

And it worked because Athens was small, and the majority of the issues had to do with either Athens, or other Greek city states, which were things that pretty much all the population knew about. And once we find large enough empires that have large numbers of people for the time such as Rome, they end up adopting an indirect democratic system since it's just unfeasible to attempt direct democracy with an empire that large.

&amp;gt; That's the beauty, is you could vote on local issues locally and national issues nationally, all in the same system.

As I said before, most people do not care/understand international issues. As for local, that's already a mixture of both direct and indirect. Also, if voting on major national events is so important, then all you need is a referendum, which already exists in the US under the current framework.

&amp;gt; I think being interconnected doesn't make it a pain, I think it makes it easier.

Far from it. Now it's not just an issue of your city and any immediate cities/empires, its a massive and convoluted system on foreign relations that spans 206 different states, not to mention other assorted regions that want to be states (i.e. Chechnya). 

&amp;gt; Go home every night, read the news and vote on the issue of the day

That will not educate you anywhere near enough to know what to do in most situations. Again, going back to Yemen, the news would only really tell you who the terrorists are, where they are in general, and possibly their goals. That's not really going to help decide what to do to react to the group. And not only this, but not everything makes the news. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499932909.0" user="fernando-poo" delta="False">
    <text>Are we assuming that every single action would need to be voted on in this hypothetical system? Currently we have a separation between the legislative and executive branch. I'm not sure what the OP's view on this is but it makes sense to me that direct democracy would replace or supplement the functions of the legislative rather than the executive branch. 

So you would still have ambassadors and other officials dealing with foreign policy issues and making decisions on that basis. It's just that when an actual change in law occurs, there will be a chance for people to research, debate and vote on it. So in the foreign policy sphere, this would cover things like ratifying treaties or declaring war, which would certainly be something the majority of people would want to have input on.

&amp;gt; And once we find large enough empires that have large numbers of people for the time such as Rome, they end up adopting an indirect democratic system since it's just unfeasible to attempt direct democracy with an empire that large.

I'm not sure that's really the reason they adopted an indirect democratic system. Many were simply skeptical of majority rule in general. The argument that issues are too complex can be extended to cover domestic issues as well, and I'm sure you will find domestic issues that are more complicated than foreign ones. So if we take this argument to its conclusion, why allow people to vote in the first place?

Yes, it's true that not everyone understands every issue. But I doubt the citizens of Athens fully understood every aspect of their local society. For that matter, the elected politicians of today are not the experts you are making them out to be. You will often hear stories about legislators not even reading bills, but simply relying on lobbyists to tell them who to vote for. 

The nice thing about direct democracy is that it would create a marketplace for issues to be openly debated. Rather than law-making occurring behind the scenes (and having the process completed captured by special interests), the experts in every field could summarize arguments for the public and allow them to vote based on the evidence. It wouldn't be perfect, but it's worth considering that some variation on this could be a better system than we have today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500912122.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are we assuming that every single action would need to be voted on in this hypothetical system?

It seems so. OP seems to have said that it is about anything and everything.

&amp;gt; It's just that when an actual change in law occurs, there will be a chance for people to research, debate and vote on it.

And how will we account for where people get their info? Also, like I told the OP, you have way to high hopes about how much people will know about things even within their own country. As I said before, imagine the clusterfuck that would happen if the budget was decided by the population.

&amp;gt; I'm not sure that's really the reason they adopted an indirect democratic system. Many were simply skeptical of majority rule in general. 

The Roman's used it for a few reasons. One of the biggest was that it would be almost impossible to have direct democracy throughout the empire. Instead, it made much more sense to have representatives that could speak for the areas and be able to stay in Rome. with Direct democracy, you would have to coordinate voting throughout the empire for everything, which considering the size of the empire and the population size in it, is pretty much completely unfeasible. 

&amp;gt;  The argument that issues are too complex can be extended to cover domestic issues as well, and I'm sure you will find domestic issues that are more complicated than foreign ones. So if we take this argument to its conclusion, why allow people to vote in the first place?

We elect people who have experience dealing with the kinds of problems specifically, and who have staff on hand to advise them. Not only this, but the US does have referendums so that national issues can be voted on by the entire population if it's important enough. 

&amp;gt; Yes, it's true that not everyone understands every issue. But I doubt the citizens of Athens fully understood every aspect of their local society.

You have to consider the fact that ancient Athens was a very different place than modern US

&amp;gt; The nice thing about direct democracy is that it would create a marketplace for issues to be openly debated. Rather than law-making occurring behind the scenes (and having the process completed captured by special interests), the experts in every field could summarize arguments for the public and allow them to vote based on the evidence.

And why would this automatically make things more open? Also, how will you make sure everyone can get unbiased information about the subject?

&amp;gt; but it's worth considering that some variation on this could be a better system than we have today.

But there's already the ability to hold referendums, which is pretty much what you seem to be advocating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500996336.0" user="fernando-poo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not only this, but the US does have referendums so that national issues can be voted on by the entire population if it's important enough.

There is no national referendum on individual issues in the U.S. Some countries such as Switzerland do allow this, but it doesn't exist in the U.S.

&amp;gt; And how will we account for where people get their info? 

&amp;gt; And why would this automatically make things more open? Also, how will you make sure everyone can get unbiased information about the subject?

The idea of a perfectly informed electorate or unbiased opinion doesn't exist of course. However I think it's important to acknowledge the extent to which the current system has been captured by special interests. The so-called elected experts in Congress don't spend a majority of their time studying the issues, [but on fundraising](http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/08/call-time-congressional-fundraising_n_2427291.html). Bills are often [drafted entirely by lobbyists and business interests](http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2014/12/spending-bill-992-derivatives-citigroup-lobbyists) rather than the representatives themselves. There are entire organizations such as ALEC devoted to this practice of ghostwriting laws.

The reason things have turned out this way is because of the need to be reelected. Once you take issues out of the control of elected representatives and allow people to decide them directly, the same incentives simply don't exist. There's no practical way to buy off a country of 300 million people on most issues. A bill that was ghostwritten by the banking industry is not going to slip through when the issue needs to be openly voted on by the public.

So I do think direct democracy has the potential to solve some of these issues. The question of course would be to find a way to make it work, but keep in mind many people had similar doubts about representative democracy when it was first proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27501025823.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is no national referendum on individual issues in the U.S. Some countries such as Switzerland do allow this, but it doesn't exist in the U.S.

First of all, Switzerland is a mixture of direct and indirect, with both of them being used for things. As for referendums, they are used at state level. It seems like a far better idea to just add in the ability for national referendums, instead of overturning the entire system of government. Most countries have the ability to hold referendums, even at the national level.

&amp;gt; The so-called elected experts in Congress don't spend a majority of their time studying the issues, but on fundraising[1] . Bills are often drafted entirely by lobbyists and business interests[2] rather than the representatives themselves. There are entire organizations such as ALEC devoted to this practice of ghostwriting laws.

And why would this change if the people wrote the laws directly? Instead you'd just have the groups go after the sources of information, and they might even have an easier time since they wouldn't have to pay people to lobby for them. My point is that no matter what kind of democracy we have, interest groups will still try and take advantage of it. It's not something unique to representative democracy.

&amp;gt; So I do think direct democracy has the potential to solve some of these issues. 

The issue I'm seeing is that all your issues could be fixed by implementing the ability for national referendums. You'd be able to have people vote on major decisions (i.e. legalizing gay marriage, going to war, etc...) but also not have to have people vote on boring laws like "farming subsidies simplification bill" or something like that, and they could instead have their elected representative do it for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500012645.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so you could have a system where people have their local issues that they vote on, their county/parish issues, their state issues, and the national issues.  They would be limited to their membership in each locality.  

For international issues, we're going to be in disagreement.  The general public is much more isolationist than our current policy, and I think the public policy should reflect that.  The middle east is not part of the US, and the US should stop treating it as such.  People would tend to vote this way.

Referenda would potentially work, but it would have to be much more common than it is now for people to have enough input into the system.  The problem is the current system has much more input into people's daily lives right now than we have into the system.

I'm not suggesting that the CIA work by referendum.  Although it would be a process to figure out the details, I agree that there are certain branches that would need to run on their own a little.  But I do think that your average person should have some say in the US's operations in other countries, and right now we have very little.

The reason a bunch of terrorists want to kill everyone is because the US has been drone bombing them, and finding various other ways of killing their families for years.  I didn't want that, yet they want to kill me, too.  This is unfair.  

Rather than finding ways of de-escalating, we keep upping the ante.  It's like a teacher who doesn't have control of the classroom, so they just scream louder and louder, using more and more intimidation.  At some point that stops working.  You have to de-escalate and assess the root of the problem.  Turns out it's usually your own control issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500919563.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; For international issues, we're going to be in disagreement. The general public is much more isolationist than our current policy, and I think the public policy should reflect that.

That's not really a good thing, especially since trade and relations are vital to most countries survival.

&amp;gt; Referenda would potentially work, but it would have to be much more common than it is now for people to have enough input into the system.

So then the solution would be to have more referendums, not to completely overhaul the entire system.

&amp;gt; But I do think that your average person should have some say in the US's operations in other countries, and right now we have very little.

And this brings up the danger of people having no clue about these issues.

&amp;gt; The reason a bunch of terrorists want to kill everyone is because the US has been drone bombing them, and finding various other ways of killing their families for years. 


That's a vastly oversimplified reason.

&amp;gt; I didn't want that, yet they want to kill me, too. This is unfair.

It turns out that even if you don't want it, many others might. Before the start of the Iraq war, between 47-60% of people supported an invasion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500957455.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;since trade and relations are vital to most countries survival.

This is an opinion.  Many countries are protectionist of certain industries to incubate them, and gain competitive advantage in them.  Most countries are protectionist of their food industries, because that's kind of common sense.  Not all globalism is good.  The last decade or two have shown some of its major drawbacks.

&amp;gt;So then the solution would be to have more referendums, not to completely overhaul the entire system.

I was agreeing that it might work... It might also not.  It would depend on its implementation.  But if you're trying to grow tree in an empty pool filled with dirt, eventually it will just hit the edges of the pool and kill itself with its own roots.

&amp;gt;And this brings up the danger of people having no clue about these issues.

You could require people to take a quiz before voting.  But if we have so little connection to a country that nobody knows anything about it, maybe we shouldn't be getting involved and acting like they're under our sphere of control.  If the average person knows nothing, do you really think our politicians know enough for any good to come from it?

&amp;gt;That's a vastly oversimplified reason.

OK, well all I'm saying is if Russia was bombing my state and everyone in my state knew someone that those bombs had killed, people would start to get pretty pissed at Russia.

&amp;gt;It turns out that even if you don't want it, many others might. Before the start of the Iraq war, between 47-60% of people supported an invasion.

Sorry, but I think there should be a higher threshold than we have now for causing people to murder each other.  Didn't they teach you in school that violence doesn't solve anything?  It turns out, that's actually pretty true.  It pretty much always results in more escalation.  Unless we really are trying to build an empire like every other country seems to think (which is why they're trying to stop us), then we should CHILL THE FUCK OUT WITH THE BOMBS!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27501082511.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is an opinion. Many countries are protectionist of certain industries to incubate them, and gain competitive advantage in them.

There's a pretty big difference between very moderate protectionism and all-out isolationism. It's also not really an opinion, since economies are now constantly interlinked. If Malaysia suddenly decided not to trade with anyone, they would very quickly have their entire economy collapse.

&amp;gt; I was agreeing that it might work... It might also not. It would depend on its implementation. But if you're trying to grow tree in an empty pool filled with dirt, eventually it will just hit the edges of the pool and kill itself with its own roots.

The way I see it is that referendums are the best of both sides. You can have people vote on major national issues (i.e. gay marriage, going to war, etc...) and also not make people vote on boring bills like "streamlining of agricultural subsidies bill" or something like that. 

&amp;gt; You could require people to take a quiz before voting.

That's unconstitutional. It would infringe on the right of anyone being able to vote.

&amp;gt; But if we have so little connection to a country that nobody knows anything about it, maybe we shouldn't be getting involved and acting like they're under our sphere of control. 

The US has major ties with most countries in the world. Just because people don't know about them doesn't make them unimportant as allies or traders.

&amp;gt; OK, well all I'm saying is if Russia was bombing my state and everyone in my state knew someone that those bombs had killed, people would start to get pretty pissed at Russia.

Except that there are more reasons than just that there have been drone strikes. My issue is that you're oversimplifying an extremely complex geo-political issue with more than just one cause. 

&amp;gt; Sorry, but I think there should be a higher threshold than we have now for causing people to murder each other. 

That may be so, but direct democracy won't solve anything. The numbers show that even if we had direct democracy, we still would have probably invaded.

&amp;gt; Didn't they teach you in school that violence doesn't solve anything? It turns out, that's actually pretty true. It pretty much always results in more escalation. Unless we really are trying to build an empire like every other country seems to think (which is why they're trying to stop us), then we should CHILL THE FUCK OUT WITH THE BOMBS!!!

This isn't about whether or not the invasion was justified. I'm just pointing out that even if we had direct democracy, many descisions you might disagree with would still happen. That's the whole issue with [Tyranny of the Majority](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyranny_of_the_majority).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27503339907.0" user="Tsuruta64" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure why you're suggesting that a direct democracy will necessarily be more pacifist than a representative democracy. Let us not forget that the Athenian democracy collapsed because they threw themselves into a needless war in Sicily which ultimately destroyed their empire. Sure, the American people may be more pacifist NOW, but we don't construct government systems on what will work now, or even for the next ten years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27503373091.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>This is a good point.  My reasoning is basically that people tend to vote towards their self-interest, and war is usually not in your average person's self-interest.  But with that historical example, I might be totally wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499301232.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What about hackers now? There have been accusations of improprieties with ballot tallying software, issues with hanging chads, etc. In a system that people respect, people work to protect it.

Exactly. There is enough voter fraud now, so let's not put it online. 

The biggest issue right now for a hacker is that they need a lot of time alone with the machine, like longer than it takes to vote. 

Imagine if they had all the time they needed at the comfort of their own home </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499316028.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>There are ways to make it pretty difficult.  It's not like they'd all be stored on a windows 2000 machine.

People don't trust bitcoin, but the actual protocol has not been breached, just servers that they're on. There are ways of making similar technologies where they'd have to hack more than just 1 server.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499321077.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are ways to make it pretty difficult. It's not like they'd all be stored on a windows 2000 machine.

The problem is that it will always create doubt 

&amp;gt;People don't trust bitcoin, but the actual protocol has not been breached, just servers that they're on. There are ways of making similar technologies where they'd have to hack more than just 1 server.

Oy vey don't get me started on bitcoin but let me say something, these votes don't need to be like bitcoin they can be stolen or manipulated, people don't trust computers for certain things </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499330756.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying it should be exactly bitcoin.  I'm just saying, people can figure this stuff out.  

As long as they were never all going through a central server, it would be pretty difficult to hack them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499333744.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>But EVERY vote is supposed to count and paper ballots are simply the best way to do that. 

Even if they just get to one server, then they destroyed thousands of votes 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499339954.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Not if there are no servers.  You could bounce it to different computers inside something communally encrypted.  Or have a distributed public tally that is further encrypted with every vote that comes in.  Then that file could be stored in pieces on thousands of computers.  If this was all happening with different variations every vote, I don't think you could mess it up without taking over the entire system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499520407.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>But there is no hard copy. No one can "I want a recount" a hard copy is important </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500015632.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>they could be printed into hard copies.  Or there could be some device that each person has that sends an encrypted file via usb, that is then sent to the various tallying servers, and receives no input from the computer itself.  That device could then maintain a physical representation of how someone voted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499340998.0" user="mcribb_runner" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "mob rule," could you explain? It sounds scary, but I'm not convinced that it's something that has ever existed.

["In 1837 Abraham Lincoln wrote about lynching and "the increasing disregard for law which pervades the country—the growing disposition to substitute the wild and furious passions in lieu of the sober judgment of courts, and the worse than savage mobs for the executive ministers of justice"."](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ochlocracy)

Mob Rule simply refers to where the will of the majority rules everything, including the rights of minorities; a lynch mob is an extreme example, but ultimately it illustrates that direct democracy would create an environment that only benefits the most prevalent and numerous groups. 

Let's use Athens, which you mentioned in other comments: you know who was allowed to vote in Athens? Adult, Athenian men, who ["varied between 30,000 and 50,000 out of a total population of around 250,000 to 300,000."](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Athenian_democracy) The only reason that direct democracy worked there is that there *were no minorities* to worry about, because they had no say in the system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499364374.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"disregard for law"

I fail to see how a legal system where people make laws indicates a disregard for law

I think voting privately online would have totally different dynamics from a lynch mob.  

Here's one thing that makes me think it would work in spite of this:

Usually the majority are less passionate about a cause than the minority.  I think most people in the majority tend to just not pay that much attention.  

It's not necessarily that most white people wanted segregation back in the day, but the only people who elected politicians over that issue did.  So the 20% who passionately want segregation get a candidate

However, the whites who don't care also still have a 50% chance of aligning with a politician who supports that issue, all other things equal.  So they might vote for a segregationist despite not caring.  

In this system, that issue wouldn't happen.  And I think that has had significant effects on the state of our political system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499387748.0" user="mcribb_runner" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that people would *disregard* laws, it's that it would be much easier to make laws that would either only benefit the majority or harm the minority. I'm not only talking about race here, but religion, social class, gender, sexuality, anything that can divide people.

&amp;gt;It's not necessarily that most white people wanted segregation back in the day, but the only people who elected politicians over that issue did. So the 20% who passionately want segregation get a candidate

And if it were put to a direct vote to either end segregation or continue it, what would most white southerners at the time have chosen? The one that is: A) Backed by a militant, vocal group who will burn your house down if they find out you supported the opposite side, or B) The one that they aren't affected by, and is purely a moral issue that won't benefit them if it passes.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500119915.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Read federalist 10 or 51, I can find others if you'd like. We didn't pass up direct democracy just because it wasn't feasible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500360361.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I will check those out, but only because of your username</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499861125.0" user="togtogtog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The layman isn't an expert on most issues, tell me how would you vote on farming? Whatever SOUNDS good, may not yield results but it sounds pretty.

That actually would be a good thing about directly voting on issues. There would be a BIG incentive for people who were experts on a particular issue and who had a big interest in it to campaign, to inform and to educate members of the public about it.

You could also have easily accessible arguments for both sides in the same area where the vote is, so that people are able to make an informed choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499877244.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>People simply don't have time to log in or educate themselves over the issues. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499886741.0" user="togtogtog" delta="False">
    <text>but that is the same now for any type of voting.

The thing is, people wouldn't need to vote on every issue. They could just vote on issues that they cared more about or that they were more involved with.

Also, campaigners would be bound to have tv campaigns on issues, or poster campaigns just like they do now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500036943.0" user="SoulWager" delta="False">
    <text>1: we have indirect democracy because our government was set up when the fastest way to send a message was by horse.

2: it can be made more secure than the current election system.

3: Then they'll get a bit overrepresented, but no more than they are now. Consider the effort required to go to the polls compared to the effort required to vote online.

4: Nobody's making you vote on an issue you're clueless or apathetic about.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
