<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499072277.0" user="LivingReason" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think the opinion of the average U.S. citizen is even in principle going to be better then that of elected officials as we have them now?

At least congressmen generally have some particular background in writing laws, or literally anything related to law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499083561.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good point.  This is particularly useful for reading and writing legislation.  Unfortunately most congressmen in the US do not read or write legislation.  They have assistants do it, or lobbyists.  

I think there are enough people who are educated in the general public who could blog about it and things that would actually serve to generally inform people better.  A crowsourced law?  I definitely think it would end up serving peoples interests better than the ones being written now.  More eyes is better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499087293.0" user="LivingReason" delta="False">
    <text>There's a lot more to this though.

For instance, why would we think people who don't know anything about law will be good at putting it together?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499102281.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I think there are a lot of people who don't know about physics, yet wikipedia was created for free and it didn't even matter.  It's the most accurate and biggest encyclopedia.

You think a few hundred people getting paid will do a better job than 316 million working for free?  Sorry, but this has been proven to be untrue time and time again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499104258.0" user="LivingReason" delta="False">
    <text>Was wikipedia written by crowdsourcing how electrons work?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499141648.0" user="Gygsqt" delta="False">
    <text>Except Wikipedia has systems in place which ensure that the correct work of the small group of people who have the expertise to write certain articles isn't undone by people who don't know anything. Your system gives everyone an equal vote and doesn't have this protection. It isn't a fair comparison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499157750.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>But that system sprung out of essentially anarchy.  Don't you imagine a similar system might spring out of what I'm proposing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499168951.0" user="Gygsqt" delta="False">
    <text>No because Wikipedia isn't a democracy. Its a select group who editors who allow individuals to write articles based on their credentials. If we applied these same rules to your system we would limit peoples right to vote. We may end up with a "better" system where each bill is voted on by only experts but at that point we would have diverted so far from your original idea that it would morph into a different system entirely. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499176289.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>In the image of it in my head, people would vote on the system's policies as well, which is part of the reason why i liked it so well.  I guess that could have been written better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499208348.0" user="Gygsqt" delta="False">
    <text>The way I see it, in order for the system to function in a civil and productive way, people will need to vote in a ton of rules and new subsystems. Eventually the system may be become so complex that only career politicians have the expertise to function within the system. Now we have gone back to a system which resembles the current system. Except instead of voting for a rep, you align yourself with a politician who you agree with (because only they know how to navigate the system) and vote along their lines rather than along party lines. Is this an improvement to the current system? Maybe, but once again we have moved pretty far away from your original premise of a simple direct democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499218589.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe it would result in basically a representative system with a bunch more layers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499302654.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Which is bad and less efficient than the current system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499309466.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe not... it works well in biological systems</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499118989.0" user="smacksaw" delta="False">
    <text>So then people can condense those into initiatives that we vote on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499130508.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>OK, well if the work is distributed by elected officials, what wrong with the public distributing it. 

Wikipedia is the result of "the masses" creating a whole encyclopedia.  Most people are not particle physicists, so they didn't work on that part.  

It is more accurate and comprehensive than any body of knowledge put together.  You really think a few hundred people are going to do a better job at understanding what's going on than hundreds of millions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499142107.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Unfortunately most congressmen in the US do not read or write legislation. They have assistants do it, or lobbyists. 

What's unfortunate about having a reasonable hierarchy of command? An office manager in an engineering firm doesn't draft, run simulations, design aesthetics, calculate load and force vectors. They Manage the team that does. And each manager will likely have their own specialties, philosophies, and ideals. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499156010.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>OK, well by that logic, despite the fact that the average US citizen doesn't have a law background shouldn't bother you either.  The people with law backgrounds can help everyone else figure it out.

Edit: also, the point is that that's what they're elected to do.  If we wanted to elect groups of people, why not let teams run for each position?  I bet a group of 5 or 6 people each managing teams would do better than 1 person managing a team.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
