<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499086917.0" user="a_guile" delta="False">
    <text>We already don't have people researching what their candidates *actually* support. They just vote for the guy who their parents/friends/role model is voting for. People were excited to get a Canadian style healthcare system when Obama was elected, and instead we got... something, but it was really not what most people were thinking when Obama promised universal health care.

So if we can't get people to research the handful of representatives they are voting for, how do we get them to research the hundreds of bills and laws they are supposed to be voting on? Check the "I have read the terms and conditions" box?

I don't think direct democracy is reasonable in a country this big. I do agree that we need a more representative system, but that does not require direct voting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499095932.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>What Obama supported when he got elected was completely different from what was actually implemented (in terms of healthcare.  Initially he said he would stand for the public option).  They weren't fooled, this is just how that kind of system works.  People were just hoping for anything along those lines, where they didn't have to go bankrupt because of health.  It was either that or Romney.

People shouldn't have votes counted toward things they don't care about.  They will research the things they care about and vote on them.  

Considering how many people their votes count for, there is only so much research a representative can do.  Collectively, there will be more attention put into what's happening.  Each individual won't necessarily put as much attention in, but when you add it all up, society will be paying more attention to each law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499107387.0" user="a_guile" delta="False">
    <text>No, I know that most reps spend around 99% of their time fund raising and only occasionally read documents. Trust me, there are a lot of problems.

What I suspect would happen in this case is people would look to news outlets for a snappy 30 word summary of a thousand page document. This means that their votes would be hugely influenced by the media (even more than currently) and this would basically end up with parties run by corporate new stations instead of political parties.

(I must have been mistaken about Obama's campaign, I seemed to remember a speech where he said it would not be like Canadian healthcare but would rely on existing insurance structures. But that was over six years ago and my memory is not perfect.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499188813.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I personally think that people would see that their vote might actually get a policy implemented, rather than possibly getting someone elected, who might vote the way they want, and whose vote on that issue might push a certain issue forward, which then may or may get shot down somewhere else.  And seeing that their vote might count, they would do more research.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499206537.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>You only have so much time in a day to do research, and there's so much to know</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499220114.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>But that's true for current politicians and law, too.  They give most of their research to assistants.  Is that much better than just watching the news or reading a blog by your favorite blogger?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499322444.0" user="Irishbasketball" delta="False">
    <text>The news (usually) will say whatever think will get the most people to read/want them, usually resulting in huge biases. They are businesses, and for most profit is the primary concern. Same with bloggers, they just want to attract as many readers as possible.

Obviously bias is impossible to completely remove, but those research assistants are paid specifically to be as accurate as possible to give their boss the best possible grasp of every issue. The incentive for bias is much, much less. And like /u/sailorbrendan said, there's only so much time in the day to research. While one person would have to read news on every single topic, a politician can have different teams of assistants/experts on different topics at the same time. It's more efficient.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
