<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499078785.0" user="dfountain62" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you could get this system working "perfectly" with 100% voter turnout, no fraud, no hacking, etc. Since you didn't specify a level of government (or a country for that matter) it would also have to work for all subsets of voters (local, state, federal).

Regardless it would most likely produce terrible results. Voters are systematically biased against good economic policy and at the end of the day that's all that really matters. Social policy would probably change faster but its unclear whether individuals would also start to restrict individual freedoms such as owning weapons, or using drugs, or freedom of speech or more just because it "feels right". Voters are notoriously uninformed about the empirical effects of legislation and there is no reason to suspect that they will choose better policies than legislators who can at least be voted out of office if the effects they implement go too far awry. You can't prevent voters from voting on something if they systematically vote to increase minimum wage to absurd levels like 30 2012-USD an hour for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499253507.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you need 100% voter turnout for every issue?  People shouldn't be voting on issues they don't care about.  The problem is that when you vote for someone, you usually pick them on a few issues that you care about, but you are stuck with their votes on everything else (and their potential compromises).  

I think it would work particularly well on a local level, but it would work nationally, too.  In fact, I think localities should experiment with different policies and systems and see what works best, then propose those for other localities that face similar problems.  At this point, the separation between all the different levels of government makes any collaboration like that very difficult.

&amp;gt;Voters are systematically biased against good economic policy

I want to see what you have to say on this...  Just because you have certain opinions about economic policy doesn't mean you're right.  Your opinion probably just rationalizes your self-interest, like everyone else's

&amp;gt;who can at least be voted out of office if the effects they implement go too far awry

What if every official's policies keep going slightly more awry and no viable candidates have the nerve to go against it
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499263345.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Voters are systematically biased against good economic policy

I'm not the original commenter, but let me just say this:  I know next to nothing about macroeconomics and what sort of fiscal policy is ideal for a nation's success.  Furthermore, I don't really have the time to learn this the depth required for a responsible decision.  With elected officials, I can vote for the candidate the the best credentials/experience in the field.  If I were simply voting on issues, I'd have to choose between sacrificing time I need to do other things to study up on economic policy or making an uninformed and potentially dangerous decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499269667.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>Or voting in a policy such as "go with the science"

People obviously don't get it perfect now, and you don't even get a say in monetary policy at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499278094.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Or voting in a policy such as "go with the science"

What does this mean?

&amp;gt;you don't even get a say in monetary policy at all.

No, but I have a say in choosing who decides monetary policy.  I would much rather vote for the more educated/capable candidate than vote on policies I don't understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499288297.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What does this mean?

You know how now you can choose to vote all democrat or all republican on the ballot?  Imagine if you could do basically the same thing by issue.

"go with the science" could be a vote that follows a party committee that compares all the scientific studies to see what the consensus is.

&amp;gt;No, but I have a say in choosing who decides monetary policy.

No, you don't.  It's controlled by the chairman of the Fed who is not elected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499297528.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"go with the science" could be a vote that follows a party committee that compares all the scientific studies to see what the consensus is.

There are tons of differing opinions in science out there.  What if there is no consensus?  And how do we decide who gets to be on the "follow the science" committee?

&amp;gt;It's controlled by the chairman of the Fed who is not elected.

Who is appointed by the President and approved by the Senate.  I vote for Presidents and Senators who I believe are capable of making responsible economic decisions, *including* selecting a capable chairman of the Federal Reserve. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499326402.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are tons of differing opinions in science out there. What if there is no consensus? And how do we decide who gets to be on the "follow the science" committee?

Right, that was just one idea of a way to get around that issue. 

The fact is, I think a much more populist economic policy would actually be good, and most people would vote for this sort of thing.  So what is a negative to you is a positive to me.  

Economic issues would certainly tend toward the populist, however if you look at all of the "golden ages" of various civilizations, they resulted form economic equality.  

Economics in general, and especially macroeconomics is not an absolute science.  Nate Silver recently wrote an article about political bias in economics, and it certainly supports this view.  

I think this would even itself out pretty well.  I actually am pretty sure that it could be mathematically proven, but there's no point in getting into that.

&amp;gt;Who is appointed by the President and approved by the Senate.

That's a pretty disparate influence you have, then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499394106.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>You haven't done anything to answer my question of "who decides what the 'science' is?"  If we need a special committee to decide what the "expert opinion" is, how is this different from electing policy-makers in the first place?

&amp;gt;It's controlled by the chairman of the Fed who is not elected.

Not really.  Sure, I'm not voting for a presidential candidate because of who he'll appoint to the Fed board.  But I vote based on things like experience dealing with economic issues, education, and things like that.  The point isn't to ensure that your choice of Fed chairmen gets appointed.  The point is to elect capable leaders who can make an informed decision in appointing the Fed chairman (appointing the Fed chairman here is a proxy for all economic issues).

And I don't mean to limit decision to the economy.  There are plenty of areas where I am not educated.  I don't know anything about international diplomacy or national defense policy, either.  Should the general populace with no military training be voting on defense protocols?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499418220.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If we need a special committee to decide what the "expert opinion" is, how is this different from electing policy-makers in the first place?

First, the division would be based on area of expertise, rather than our current committees, which are just used as political pats on the back.

Second, it would be like voting for a team instead of a single person, which would be a bit more reliable and probably better at its job.

I doubt the Fed even enters most people's mind when they go to the voting booth, and the President has a lot of factors that end up weighed when choosing the chair that are irrelevant to economics.

&amp;gt;Should the general populace with no military training be voting on defense protocols?

I don't know about this, but there could easily be limits placed.  I definitely think the general populace should be able to vote on war, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499436537.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First, the division would be based on area of expertise, rather than our current committees, which are just used as political pats on the back.

I'm not saying our current bureaucracy is ideally formulated.

&amp;gt;Second, it would be like voting for a team instead of a single person, which would be a bit more reliable and probably better at its job.

So, instead of having to figure out each person's individual views, we should have them affiliated with some organized group of people who share that position.  That way, voters can easily know where they stand on issues.

&amp;gt;I don't know about this, but there could easily be limits placed. 

I don't care what "limits" you place, there are always going to be military decisions that should not lie in the hands of the public.  How do we deal with a terrorist threat?  Schedule a vote on which covert black-ops mission to undertake?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499452946.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So, instead of having to figure out each person's individual views, we should have them affiliated with some organized group of people who share that position.

I see where you're going with this.  But rather than endorsing candidates, these "parties" would specialize to individual issues, which I think would make more sense.  Of course if those groups formed coalitions, they could develop a collaborative marketing campaign and gain influence that way.  But people would still have the option of voting on individual issues underneath that, even if it didn't happen most of the time.

&amp;gt;I don't care what "limits" you place, there are always going to be military decisions that should not lie in the hands of the public. How do we deal with a terrorist threat? Schedule a vote on which covert black-ops mission to undertake?

I meant limits on the reach of the vote system..  I was imagining the military maintaining its current structure.  

You definitely bring up good points, but they don't necessarily convince me that the system would be less effective than our current one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499900311.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>So who runs the military? Is it someone the people elected, as it is now, or does the military operate entirely independently from the populace? That seems like a great recipe for a coup right there. 

Ultimately, what I'm getting at is that there are some areas for which elected officials are absolutely necessary. Could we adjust the system to include more referenda? Probably. But we can't get rid of elections altogether. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499989655.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>We don't elect people to the military as it is.  I guess there would have to be a figurehead electee who just listened to people on major issues that they voted on.

&amp;gt;Could we adjust the system to include more referenda? Probably. But we can't get rid of elections altogether.

 I would support that.  It would need to be a lot more referenda, though. This is very practical, though, I think.  

But that doesn't mean it isn't possible to work out the details of the other system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500002864.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>We vote on a president, who is the head of the military. All I'm saying is that it's impossible to completely eliminate elected officials without seriously endangering freedom. For instance: you have to elect some sort of leader of the military. Having no leader threatens national defense, and having an unelected leader creates the risk of a coup. Once there's a military leader, there needs to be some meaningful system of checks to prevent him from seizing power, which would likely require more elected positions. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
