<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499078299.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>The average citizen simply isn't knowledgeable enough to make every decision for the country, which is why we eject people who are supposed to be knowledgeable enough to make these decisions for us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499245155.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is highly inaccurate.  The house science committee is full of people who don't believe in evolution or global warming.  One person said that women can shut down a pregnancy resulting from rape if that rape is legitimate.

The idea that "the masses" are stupid is a trope that gets passed around all the time to legitimize power, but when you really analyze these things that they do that are supposed to be so stupid, you find out that it's not out of stupidity but necessity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499318697.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One person said that women can shut down a pregnancy resulting from rape if that rape is legitimate.

And that person was promptly voted out of office.  The masses are stupid and they will only vote on what they see benefits them in the here and now.  Look at any state ballot measure that involves increased taxes on the entire population and it gets voted down.  The only time taxes get voted for approval (on ballot measures) is when it affects the minority (rich people or drug users, generally).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499334842.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>The masses voted that guy out.  He was the one in office.  They got him out.  

Maybe taxes on the rich don't get voted in is because trickle-down economics isn't the right policy.  It apparently isn't serving the majority of people very well, or they wouldn't vote against it.

If you look at history, the times when societies do well is when they have income equality.  It is very obvious.  Voting against taxes on the poor is support for that argument, not stupidity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499445208.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>You literally missed the entire point of my discussion and just focused on taxes.  

If the masses got to vote on everything, Obamacare would be gone tomorrow.  The next day every student loan in the country would be forgiven, and the day after that banks would probably be outlawed from charging interest or something equally ridiculous.  None of thse are good things, but they would all have mass appeal. People literally only vote for their own selfish short term desires.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499477700.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Obamacare would be gone tomorrow.

When Obama got elected, he had majority support for a healthcare system that included a public option.  If Obamacare is unpopular, it is not necessarily because of the taxes.

&amp;gt;The next day every student loan in the country would be forgiven

When Iceland was in a mortgage crisis, they flat out forgave a significant portion of the mortgages, and almost instantly recovered from near bankruptcy, while the rest of Europe and the world were desperately struggling.  Do you realize how many jobs would be created if the entire generation that is floundering under debt were suddenly able to invest in their own small businesses?  Small businesses create more jobs than large ones, this is a fact.

If you look at any civilization's golden age, it was when they had very low income inequality.  The labor market is more efficient when people are able to take time off to find the most suitable employment, or start their own businesses.  Financial services should be like lubrication for the markets that actually produce things.  They cannot be the basis for a whole economy.

&amp;gt;and the day after that banks would probably be outlawed from charging interest or something equally ridiculous

Speculation which I don't believe.  You think people are stupid, I don't think so.  They act in their interest, but they are risk-averse enough not to do anything like that.  This may be radical or something, but if an industry is serving to make a majority of people's lives worse, so much that they would take steps to destroy it, maybe it should be destroyed.  

&amp;gt;None of thse are good things, but they would all have mass appeal.

None of these are things you agree with, which is why i'd rather let people actually vote in their interest instead of people like you deciding for them.  

&amp;gt;People literally only vote for their own selfish short term desires.

Desires, yes.  Selfish and short-term?  No.  People die for causes, they do not always act selfishly and short term.  Just because you don't understand all of the myriad effects that student loans, banks, or minimum wages have on people doesn't mean they are totally invalid.  You also act selfishly and short term, because you have a limited ability to understand other perspectives.

I imagine benefit greatly from our current system.  So is it possible that your views stem from that?  It's fine to have a view that you support.

But thinking other people are stupid and that their views don't deserve representation is very arrogant.  It's how our system got into this mess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499521365.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I imagine benefit greatly from our current system. So is it possible that your views stem from that? It's fine to have a view that you support.

Always wonderful when someone just assumes what your background is.  That always lets you know that you're dealing with an unbiased person.

&amp;gt;But thinking other people are stupid and that their views don't deserve representation is very arrogant. It's how our system got into this mess.

Not really sure what you mean by "mess."  But yes people think short term and selfishly.  Look at the number of people with next to no retirement savings, yet they are still driving fancy cars.  Look at the number of people that have massive amounts of student loan debt for degrees that they can't and aren't even using.

Look at the ballot measures your state had last election.  I can guarantee you that there are large amounts that would have definitely been good, but because they were going to raise taxes or only benefit a small section of the population they didn't pass.

People are incredibly selfish.  Obamacare got support because everyone thought that it would be paid for by the rich.  Then when their own premiums started to rise slightly, they all freaked out and voted the Dems out.  

Also, can you leave your own economic views out of this?  Most of what you are saying is highly disputed and I don't care to turn this into an economic debate.

Additionally, people can barely bother to vote once every two years and don't even take the time to look up the person's views they are supporting and just vote on party lines.  And you think they are going to vote on issues every day or week?  Not going to happen.  Voters would be even more uninformed than before and just listen to whatever talking head they like on the news.  So, instead of having people actually voting you're just going to get whatever media outlet is the most popular controlling the electorate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499961065.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>If I'm not wrong, you can't say it was out of bias.  There are logical reasons that I came to that conclusion.

&amp;gt;Look at the number of people with next to no retirement savings, yet they are still driving fancy cars.

This is how I know I'm right about your background.  If you had ever experienced anything close to poverty, you wouldn't have to say this.  

&amp;gt;Look at the number of people that have massive amounts of student loan debt for degrees that they can't and aren't even using.

And this is because they're selfish?  Not because the job market is in shambles?  First of all, half of the people with these loans went to college before the financial crash.  I don't know what you were doing before then, but they were highly encouraging people to do take loans out, similar to housing.  So you're going to say an 18 year old kid who is told that everyone needs college now and the loans will pay themselves off in a few years is selfish?  You need to learn to relate to people.

&amp;gt;People are incredibly selfish. Obamacare got support because everyone thought that it would be paid for by the rich. Then when their own premiums started to rise slightly, they all freaked out and voted the Dems out.

Some people are told that they earned their money fair and square, all on their own.  That's impossible.  The economy runs through infrastructure.  Infrastructure is public.  The more business you do, the more you use infrastructure.  The police?  The military? Without that, the profits that businesses rake in would be impossible.  The roads?  The FDIC? 

The rich benefit disproportionately from this public spending.  If nothing else because of cops.  If our nation didn't have a wll funded military and police force, the rich would no longer be rich.  Rich owe a debt to society.  Hoarding resources is not some inherent right, it is something the police allow them to do.

Regardless, even if you take violence off the table, rich people still benefit disproportionately.  For every public dollar that is spent, a person with investments profits off of that public good multiple times.  Roads?  Every time a privately owned truck uses a publicly funded road, and investor is making a free penny or so.  Every time workers get to work a bit cheaper because of public transportation, a company can get away with paying them slightly less.  

Unfortunately this doesn't increase wages.  It does, however increase cost of living, as the rich people get rich off of government dollars, the government still spent the money, and this can drive inflation.  If they weren't specifically trying to prevent wages from increasing, then maybe you would have a point, but that is actually something they have done on purpose at the Fed.  

The dems got voted out because Obama didn't do the things he said he was going to.  He proposed a public option.  That didn't happen.  He said he would get rid of wiretapping and try to help the environment, he didn't do anything.  He said he would close guantanamo. Nothing. 

It is not selfish and short-term to support taxes on the rich or healthcare.  If you think that, it is glaringly obvious that you are either filthy rich and rationalizing your position, or have a lot of dealings with people who are who have gotten into your head.  

&amp;gt;Not really sure what you mean by "mess."

This is the point.  If you don't understand how this level of income inequality is a mess, then it is obvious which side you're on.  It doesn't make you bad.  Just like being poor doesn't make people stupid.  It just means you have a certain perspective, and if you want to understand the other, you have to put effort towards it. 

Meet some people without your background and live a little.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500017445.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>You think retirement savings are low because people lack the means?  Sure some do, but most are just buying shit on credit.  its not just poor people who lack retirement savings.  Also, my parents didnt pay a dime for my college education so can you get off your 'check your privilege' high horse.  Its basically ad hominem at this point because you just keep repeating it ad nauseum.

I am not just talking about taxes on the rich here.  Just look at ballot measures and you'll see a bunch of failed good ideas.  Sure there will be personhood amendments do, but my main point is this and you havent even bothered to look at it.  You keep just going back to an economic discussion that I dont want to have because it is outside the scope of this cmv.

Half those people with student loans didnt have job prospects before the crash and student loan debt continues to rise despite these students entering post crash, so yes, people are short sighted if they keep jumping into debt even in a slow economy.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500044541.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>Btw, I havent actuallyvtold you that I dont support taxes on the rich, I was just using it as an example to show that people vote selfishly, but since that failed we could just talk about sin taxes.  I hate sin taxes, sin taxes hurt the poorest people, but they invariably get passed as some sort of 'its your fault' measure, so pay for our schools.  But they wont go away and more keep coming.  

So, yeah I think people only look at themselves and not all of society when voting.  The tax code in our country is a giant clusterfuck of special interests. If I was in charge id get rid of most of those deductions and credits.  We dont need to be giving people  tax free money to pay mortgage interest, and I dont think marriage or having a child should get you tax breaks.  If we need to lower taxes on the poor because these removals screw them, then go ahead, but if its for the 70k a year girl married to a sahd, then im not too concerned about them making ends meet.

As for my political views, I feel that politics are overwhelmed wuth helping the 99% when I feel that most of the middle class has it pretty good.  I would rather focusbour efforts helping those in poverty then getting the joneses out of their condo into a single family house with a yard.  Help those stuck in generational poverty, the I will care about myself and the rest of the middle class.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499627632.0" user="Exribbit" delta="False">
    <text>Of course people deserve representation! Key word: representation.

The majority of people, apparently including you, have no idea how complex the inner workings of our government is. You have to realize that trillions of dollars of spending means, well, trillions of dollars of budgeting. People simply dont have the time to devote to that kind of research.

Even Senators and Congressmen, people who devote their jobs to politics, have entire platoons of researchers, lobbyists, and think tanks just to gauge what a topic is **about**.

 I'm assuming, based on your posts, that you're a liberal. Having representatives that vote EXACTLY how their constituents would have voted is the largest obstacle to progress today. Think about the Tea Party, who refuse to compromise because they came in on a platform of not raising taxes at all. A career politician realizes when compromise is needed, so we get a fairly even and well balanced plan. 

Additionally, career politicians are not reactionary, and are able to form coherent plans before action. How would the nation react to 9/11 under your system? In 2006, **5 years** after 9/11, 39% of Americans said they had strong anti-muslim sentiment, the same said they wanted muslims to carry special ID's, and 33% said U.S. muslims were sympathetic to Al-Qaeda.

http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/nation/2006-08-09-muslim-american-cover_x.htm

Keep in mind this is FIVE YEARS LATER. If we had your system in place on 9/12, we'd be putting muslims in camps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499974364.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text> People simply dont have the time to devote to that kind of research.

316 million people have much more time to do this in their spare time than all of the elected officials in DC do full-time.

I actually do have an idea of how complex the inner workings are.  Not everyone has to spend that time.  I imagine a situation where people make a few drafts for each part of a budget, and those who it affects vote on it.  There are articles on wikipedia about everything from quantum mechanics to historical linguistics written for free for no reason, I think we can take care of budgeting when it actually affects our lives.

&amp;gt;I'm assuming, based on your posts, that you're a liberal. Having representatives that vote EXACTLY how their constituents would have voted is the largest obstacle to progress today

I disagree.  Sometimes voting is conditional.  "I want this, but only if this, too."  This sort of idea is impossible to translate in our current system.  You want the Keystone pipeline, but only if the tax revenues are invested in green energy?  There is no way to indicate that through our current election system.  So there are these shifts in public opinion that people don't get.  It's because the details of implementation matter.

&amp;gt; In 2006, 5 years after 9/11, 39% of Americans said they had strong anti-muslim sentiment, the same said they wanted muslims to carry special ID's, and 33% said U.S. muslims were sympathetic to Al-Qaeda.

So... not a majority?  I have to admit, a major reason my view changed is because of things like this.  White people don't have muslim or black friends, and thus could oppress unchecked out of ignorance.  The extent to which people can delude themselves scares me a bit.  But I think most people just don't care rather than specifically feeling like they need to go out of their way to oppress.  So its possible that the votes would even themselves out.  

That said, apparently Switzerland is close to a direct democracy, and they banned minarets, which I think is a bit much.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499561818.0" user="TimoculousPrime" delta="False">
    <text>Taxes don't only increase when they effect a minority.  [A few years ago California voted to increase its sales tax to fight education cuts.](http://www.nytimes.com/2012/11/08/us/politics/in-california-voters-approve-ballot-measure-that-raises-taxesin-california-approve-voters-ballot-measure-that-raises-taxes.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499596061.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Supporters of the plan said it would bring in $6 billion a year over the next seven years through a one-quarter-cent increase in the state sales tax and income tax rate increases for those earning more than $250,000 a year

The majority of the taxes were levied on those earning more than 250K, a 1/4 cent increase in sales tax is nothing.  You're not really proving anything to me when the only way you can get the majority to vote for taxes on themselves is as a pittance combined with a much larger tax on a minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499625576.0" user="TimoculousPrime" delta="False">
    <text>I am not trying to proving anything to you.  I am bringing up a counterexample to your statement.  I looked at a ballot measure that involves increased taxes on the entire population and it was not voted down.  Clearly it is possible to get voters to raise taxes on themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499663457.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>A 3.5% increase in sales taxes on the majority when the minority is gettting a 10%-30% increase on their income taxes is hardly levying a tax on yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499630328.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think this is highly inaccurate. The house science committee is full of people who don't believe in evolution or global warming.

First of all, source? And do they actually believe this or do they say that they believe this to get votes from people who actually believe this and would be voting on every issue under your proposed system?

&amp;gt;One person said that women can shut down a pregnancy resulting from rape if that rape is legitimate.

And that person was then voted out of office like another commenter said. What's your point?

As for your last comment I'm not really sure what you're talking about. What does your average citizen know about foreign policy in sub-Saharan Africa? Or the U.S military presence in Japan? Or Arctic land claims? There are countless issues that the average citizen isn't nearly knowledgeable enough to vote effectively on, and can't get educated enough on these issues because they have more important things in their lives that they need to focus on. This is why we elect representatives who's job it is to know about these issues, because the average citizen isn't nearly knowledgeable enough to vote on them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499979374.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/the-curious-wavefunction/2014/03/31/the-house-of-representatives-committee-on-science-is-turning-into-a-national-embarrassment/

http://www.nationaljournal.com/energy/the-house-science-committee-has-held-more-hearings-on-aliens-than-on-climate-change-20140521

 &amp;gt;As for your last comment I'm not really sure what you're talking about. What does your average citizen know about foreign policy in sub-Saharan Africa? Or the U.S military presence in Japan? Or Arctic land claims? There are countless issues that the average citizen isn't nearly knowledgeable enough to vote effectively on, and can't get educated enough on these issues because they have more important things in their lives that they need to focus on. This is why we elect representatives who's job it is to know about these issues, because the average citizen isn't nearly knowledgeable enough to vote on them.

They could essentially set their vote to go along with a committee that does research on something.  

I don't trust Congress' vote on foreign policy in sub-Saharan Africa anymore than the general public's.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500026842.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>None of those sources say anything about the House Science Committee being full of people who don't believe in evolution, and they also day that this committee is more focused on space exploration than climate change. If you think they should focus on other things then fine, but I don't see how that supports your argument. These politicians represent people who don't believe in climate change or evolution, so what would happen is that people with these views would vote directly on issues instead of having representatives vote on them. I don't see why anything would change.

&amp;gt;I don't trust Congress' vote on foreign policy in sub-Saharan Africa anymore than the general public's.

Would you have supported scale invasion of Uganda in 2012? Because it's entirely possible that this could have been voted on and passed in 2012 after the Kony 2012 video went viral under your proposed system. Things like this are why the general public shouldn't be left to decide issues that it isn't knowledgeable enough to make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500312452.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.dallasnews.com/news/local-news/20121006-u.s.-house-science-committee-member-calls-evolution-big-bang-theory-lies-straight-from-the-pit-of-hell.ece</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500313711.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>As for invasion, I don't think most people would have voted on something like that without researching it more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500377829.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>I think your overestimating how much people would research certain issues before voting on them. As it is right now many people don't do a whole lot of research before they vote. What makes you think people will all of the sudden do more research if they can vote on more issues?

Also, in terms of that representative you cited as not believing in solution, he will no longer be in office after this current term. The comments by him that were cited in that article were also from a speech that be made at a church at a private function. Obviously he is going to pander to his audience in a situation like this. Finally, do you think that be genuinely believes these things, or that he says them because his constituents believe them? I'm inclined to believe that it's more likely the latter than the former, especially when you consider his past education and career as a doctor. The people he represents genuinely believe that evolution is false, but it's more likely that Broun says that to pander to his constituents rather than genuinely believing it. Would you rather have people who genuinely don't believe in evolution making policy decisions, or ejected officials making policy decisions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500396177.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of the reason people don't do much research is because their motivation to do so is proportional to how likely it will affect anything.  When a person votes, in all likelihood, their vote will not affect the outcome of the election, let alone the legislation that is passed, as the representative bodies further dilute any probabilities.  Motivation is proportional to the size of a positive outcome and the difference in likelihood of that outcome.

If the likelihoods of affecting the outcome are larger, people will put more effort into research.  This is why people spend so much more time looking at Presidential elections.

&amp;gt;do you think that be genuinely believes these things, or that he says them because his constituents believe them?

I think people, and especially politicians, are masters at finding "rational" justification for their viewpoints, which are usually determined by forces of local convenience.  So while I don't think he necessarily believes this in his heart of hearts, I think he wasn't lying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500422788.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>How would a direct democracy allow individuals to have more of an effect on governmental issues? Even if 1% of the population which is eligible to vote actually voted on every issue, there would still be millions of voters, meaning that individual still wouldn't decide any outcomes. Direct democracy can work on a very small level because individual votes can make a difference, but on the national level of a country with more than 300 million people I don't see why any individual would feel that their vote is any more important than it is now.

&amp;gt;I think people, and especially politicians, are masters at finding "rational" justification for their viewpoints, which are usually determined by forces of local convenience. So while I don't think he necessarily believes this in his heart of hearts, I think he wasn't lying.

The comments that you cited were taken from a speech that was made in a church to members of that church by an elected representative to potential voters for him. Obviously he is going to deny evolution in a situation like this to gain support in future elections. Has Broun taken any legislative actions to back up these views? Hell has Broun done anything other than state these views to potential voters at a church who probably hold these views? If not, I don't see why the connects you cited mean that he genuinely rejects evolution as opposed to making these comments to gain support from potential voters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500440041.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If not, I don't see why the connects you cited mean that he genuinely rejects evolution as opposed to making these comments to gain support from potential voters.

I don't think you can just speculate that someone is lying and then put the burden on me to prove that he was telling the truth.  If he states that that is his view, he shouldn't be involved in determining policies that have far-reaching effects on the scientific education of our country.

&amp;gt;How would a direct democracy allow individuals to have more of an effect on governmental issues?

Vote for politician (avg. 50% chance) -&amp;gt; politician's aides write bill (?% chance) -&amp;gt; politician votes on bill (avg. 50% chance) -&amp;gt; other house votes on bill (avg. 50% chance)

versus:

Vote on bill. (avg. 50% chance)

I think it clearly gives your vote more control over actual policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27500857179.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>Stating his view and acting on it are two completely separate things. Has he actually acted on this view as an elected representative in any meaningful way, or did he simply say that evolution doesn't exist in a private speech at a church to a bunch of potential voters who most likely share that same belief? I think the fact that he has a background in chemistry and medicine qualifies him to be on the science committee, especially when you consider the fact that most representatives have backgrounds in either business or law, or both. Also, I'm not sure why you're mentioning policies on the scientific education of our country when he is/was a member of the Science and Technology Committee, not the House Committee on Education and the Workforce. Either way, curriculum isn't determined at the federal level but rather at state and local levels, so his stated beliefs on evolution wouldn't have any effect on the scientific education of our country.

As for voting, none of what you said changes the fact that every person's individual vote won't change whether a policy is enacted or not. With millions of people voting on any given issue, there's no reason for any one person to believe that their one vote will make a difference. The best way to have an effect on governmental issues has never been through voting, but rather through various methods of influencing elected officials. Voting has always been the bare minimum in terms of having an effect on governmental issues. By taking away elected officials, it makes it even harder to influence governmental issues as people now have to get their message out to millions of people as opposed to the representatives of these millions of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499687735.0" user="ZenDragon" delta="False">
    <text>The average elected official is no more knowledgeable than the average voter unfortunately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499689821.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>What is this based on?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
