<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499164731.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>I could see this being used for major issues (except that this is already a thing anyways, so it's a moot point), but for *every* issue? That's just asking for failure. Picture this scenario. A terrorist cell has popped up in Yemen, is gaining traction throughout the Arabian Peninsula, and is disrupting vital shipping lanes. How does the US respond? There are two issues here. Firstly, that most people barely care, and probably couldn't even tell you where Yemen is on the map. The second issue, is most people have absolutely no clue how to respond. Do we send military ships to patrol the area? Do we sit back and hope Yemen fixes the problem? Do we straight-up invade Yemen to get rid of the terrorists? When it comes to issues like this, most people are far too under qualified to make descisions about these kinds of things, which is why we elect people who's job it is to know about these kinds of issues and who have staff with specific knowledge of things like this to help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499169111.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>You could have default options, or just ignore the issues you don't care about.  If they're controversial enough, people will dig them up and post them all over with outrage anyway.  

If you don't care enough or know enough, why should you vote on it anyway?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499191989.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You could have default options, 

Really? So what's your default opinion on current trade agreements and development assistance with regards to Indonesia? See what I'm talking about where most people have absolutely no clue where to even start?

&amp;gt; or just ignore the issues you don't care about.

That doesn't really work though. Lets take our Yemen example. How many people do you honestly think would go into the issue informed enough to not only know what's going on, but how to try and fix the problem? The answer is a small minority of people. And don't forget that you will still have people voting who have absolutely no idea what's going on, and whose default position could easily be "just nuke them", which is not something you want to have your country do. We elect representatives to the government because we understand that when it comes to issues like this, they are far more likely to know what to do then we would. And here's an even better example of an issue that would not end well: what should the budget be, and what should we focus spending on? Ask 5 different people this question, you'll get 6 different answers. 

&amp;gt; If you don't care enough or know enough, why should you vote on it anyway?

Because the problem has to be fixed regardless of if you give a shit or not. 

Also, we can still vote on major issues, since that's the entire point of referendums/plebiscites. The issue is that by allowing us to vote on *everything* we end up with far too many people who either have no clue what they're doing, or are far more willing to do stupid shit if they don't understand the possible repercussions (i.e. using nuclear weapons, severing relations, etc...)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
