<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1630071154.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qyi2ya/cmv_sellside_equity_research_is_useless_to_retail/">
    <title>CMV: Sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market</title>
    <original_poster>BAIIIPLUS</original_poster>
    <original_post>What is the value of information for investors? The most valuable information to generate superior return is getting inside information. However, it is not usually available and you will be prosecuted if you trade on such information.

In addition to traditional media, brokers offer sell-side equity research. I don't think is is useful for retail investors to generate return above index.

1. Accuracy of recommendation  
 No one knows the future price. I don't see sufficient evidence to believe an analyst can accurately predict the future price. If he/she has such a predictive power, he/she should've quitted the job and made money by his/herself.
2. Knowledge  
 Some people may argue that we can accumulate knowledge reading sell-side equity research. However, could you generate superior return above index by knowing more? I don't think so because what you learned is already known by other rich investors who would have more significant influence on market prices.

Therefore, sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market. They are marketing materials of brokers. To beat the market, there are more important factors than information from brokers such as investment experience and mental control.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38308019372.0" user="SuccessfulOstrich99" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I'm not so sure. Perhaps the answer is not that sell side equity research is not valuable, but that the valuable research does not get published. 

Just imagine I create valuable sell side equity research. This will have enormous value to those with the assets to take advantage of it. It would not make sense to publish this to the general public, or even a limited exclusive audience for me. I'd want to keep this information private until I had acted upon it. I'd then sell it to those who would be willing to pay most for it (and could act upon it too). This research would likely just reach the general public once it's lost value most or all of its value, if at all. 

I believe this is the case for most if not all concrete investment advice. Only idiots would give away valuable investment knowledge. Idiots are not likely to have valuable investment advice anyway. 

Evidence in the form of a good advice track record is also not useful. You have so many people/groups giving advice some will inevitable be lucky and get things right for an extended period of time. Bad advice gets forgotten. Good luck figuring out who's smart and who's selling hot air. 

My conclusion: do your own research if you're smart enough, know what you're doing and have the right temperament (hint: you don't). For everyone else: buy trackers, keep your costs low, and spread your buy-in moments over time. Boring as hell but your best bet. Otherwise go ahead and treat the stock market like a casino. 

Not sure this is helpful but this is what I'd be inclined to believe after 15 years or so of investing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
