<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1630071154.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qyi2ya/cmv_sellside_equity_research_is_useless_to_retail/">
    <title>CMV: Sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market</title>
    <original_poster>BAIIIPLUS</original_poster>
    <original_post>What is the value of information for investors? The most valuable information to generate superior return is getting inside information. However, it is not usually available and you will be prosecuted if you trade on such information.

In addition to traditional media, brokers offer sell-side equity research. I don't think is is useful for retail investors to generate return above index.

1. Accuracy of recommendation  
 No one knows the future price. I don't see sufficient evidence to believe an analyst can accurately predict the future price. If he/she has such a predictive power, he/she should've quitted the job and made money by his/herself.
2. Knowledge  
 Some people may argue that we can accumulate knowledge reading sell-side equity research. However, could you generate superior return above index by knowing more? I don't think so because what you learned is already known by other rich investors who would have more significant influence on market prices.

Therefore, sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market. They are marketing materials of brokers. To beat the market, there are more important factors than information from brokers such as investment experience and mental control.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38302558485.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/BAIIIPLUS (OP) has awarded 2 delta(s) in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [here](/r/DeltaLog/comments/qyjh6z/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_sellside_equity_research_is/), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view doesn't necessarily mean a reversal, or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
