<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38317041574.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic, Henry Ford created the Model T just to take a short joyride in a vehicle that was slower than a horse. Private rocket launches by SpaceX, Virgin Galactic and Orbit, and Blue Origin are dirt cheap compared to those by the US (NASA), Russia, China, India, etc. Those were really only cost effective for scientific research and military applications. But even small side projects had huge implications for humanity. 

For example, because the US government launched 31 GPS satellites at considerable expense, all GPS receivers can pinpoint people's exact location on Earth for free. Airplanes and ships are able to travel in safer, faster, and greener ways. Imagine what we could do with hundreds of thousands of satellites launched into orbit? Musk's plan is already to provide free internet for every person on Earth and use the satellites to coordinate all the self-driving cars. There are dozens of high value applications of dirt cheap rocket launches.

The problem is that rockets are extremely expensive and they explode a lot. People don't want to crowdfund it. But people are willing to pay a ton of money to go into space. So why not combine the two? If you have to launch rockets into orbit for R&amp;amp;D anyways, why not stick a few people who pay a few hundred thousand dollars each into them too? It the cheapest and easiest way to raise funding for what is literally rocket science.

All together, cheap rocket launches are going to create trillions of dollars of value for humanity. The sooner we can fund them, the better. If rich people today want to pay a ton of money for a brief joyride, that's wonderful because it means that my grandchildren will live in a world where accidents (especially car accidents) aren't the third leading cause of death. 

Space "tourism" is the single best investment humanity can make, but it will take decades to centuries before anyone gets a payoff. No one wants to fund it because we'd all rather deal with problems that are happening today. We think one human alive today matters more than a million hypothetical humans alive in 10,000 years. Branson, Bezos, and Musk have figured out a way to incentivize people to think long term. Getting people to believe in the hypothetical and very long term gains of innovation is one of the hardest skills in the world, but it's the best paying job if you can pull it off. You get nothing if you plant a tree today, but if you convince people that it's prestigious to plant trees today (or pay a bunch of money to fly into space), then everyone benefits tomorrow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317441636.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment about needing someone to fund rockets is very true. And letting rich people go on a joy ride to support research efforts is valid.

But, are we sure the rockets Branson and Musk had taken to suborbital space had a greater purpose than to just transport them back and forth? If yes, you would have changed my view.

If not, and the rockets were just built for this kind of joyride, I do not think they are a meaningful thing to spend so much money on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317611645.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>1. SpaceX is the most advanced of the private rocket companies. SpaceX hasn't carried any tourists into space yet, but they've filled lots of contracts to launch satellites already. It's more profitable to carry satellites into orbit than tourists. Plus, they're building out [Starlink,](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starlink) which is the big satellite internet network I talked about (and would theoretically link to self-driving Teslas and other vehicles).

3. Blue Origin has similar aims, but they're playing catch up. They have fewer private contracts and recently lost a big NASA government contract to SpaceX. They've launched a few tourists into space so far, but no satellites. They have plans for more advanced rockets in the near future, but until they can get enough contracts and funding for that, they're stuck with a less profitable tourist business model. Bezos is personally losing over a billion dollars a year right now, but if it works out in the long term, it will be well worth it.

2. Virgin Galactic has carried a few tourists into space, but they are relatively behind. They've only managed to get into suborbital space so far, but they are using the research to find cost effective ways to reach orbit. Virgin Orbit is technically a different company, but they share infrastructure. They have smaller publicly stated aims than SpaceX and Blue Origin, but they are the smallest and least funded company. They have the cheapest method of reaching suborbital space so far (6 figures a ticket vs 7 figures) though. It's basically a plane that flies up and shoots a rocket into suborbital space, which glides back to earth. Theoretically, this could lead to faster/cheaper/greener air travel than normal planes. But they've had some setbacks and have reigned in their promises, prompting some famous investors like Cathie Wood to sell the stock. The big advantage they've had is that rich tourists have had to put down huge deposits to reserve their seats, which is basically a 0% interest loan without a clear date they have to pay the money back. Plus, it's a public company so they can sell stock and raise cash whenever there's a lot of hype around the company.

The Wright Brothers first flight was in December, 1903 and only lasted 12 seconds. NASA's lunar landing was in July 1969. It only took 66 years to go from not being able to fly at all to humans sticking a flag on the moon, (not to mention being able to fly to the other side of the planet in less than a day.) The big discoveries have been made. Now the goal is to figure out how to make them cheap and accessible like we did for computers and pretty much every other technology.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
