<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38316669123.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes

And in the process, making that flight orders of magnitude less expensive.  Also, Musk's company can make it well past suborbital.  

&amp;gt;This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

Fuel is also expensive (and heavy), so making more efficient rocket engines is the name of the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316766479.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>So use those flights to do something other than shoot billionaires into space, contributing to global warming for the pleasure of people rich enough to never live with the consequences of thier actions is not good because it later down the line makes space travel better.  If those same exact innovations were occuring on launches dedicated to cleaning up space debris or something, then we could both have innovation and also do something instantly tangible that is somewhat important to justify the environment cost.  Space tourism doesn't justify that cost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316860775.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>u/Bookwrrm well said! I completely agree.

My problem is not with space exploration. It is to do with aimless space tourism for the benefit of the ultra wealthy, without real thought and consideration about the implications for those left on earth. There are innumerable better ways we can use the gazillions of dollars the three billionaires listed above collectively have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318405818.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It is to do with aimless space tourism for the benefit of the ultra wealthy, without real thought and consideration about the implications for those left on earth.

So musk sending people are cargo to the ISS is a bad thing? What about the satellites for cheap internet for the entire globe? Yeah it must only be benefiting billionaires.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316865719.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>You're in luck. We have a publicly funded space program specifically for that kind of stuff. It's a bloated joke. The space shuttle was the most expensive and most lethal crewed launch vehicle  ever made. SLS is costing more and more every year, despite never having launched and still somehow being worse than the Saturn V that was designed in the 60s.

Private industry is the only way forward as a species. Government workers are just too slow, inefficient and unmotivated. And since private indusrty doesn't get billions from Congress every year, they need to make money in other ways. Like satellite launches and space tourism.

Without private space, we would stay in LEO for centuries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316955011.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>Hmmm I wonder what might motivate government workers, perhaps not having to fight with 90 year old senile congressmen over funding allocation.  And perhaps not having their options be working for NASA or working for Elon musk 100 hours a week until you burn out in two years and move away, in your amazing capitalist utopia.  Also the sheer unadulterated hilarity in saying that it's more efficient to require scientists to devote years of work shooting dipshit billionaire Timmy into space to get funding for your actual interest.  The sheer absurdity of saying its more efficient to do shit you don't care about to drive innovation rather than just directly work on it is hilarious.  It's only more efficient in your mind because for some reason you both can't imagine a better system nor believe that it can be brought about, which is why we are stuck in this shitty system, because too many people think exactly like you.  Also it's literally factually untrue we would stay in LEO forever since we kinda landed on the moon a litttttttlllleee while back if you forgot.  Wasn't SpaceX launching that rocket was it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317238595.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Hmmm I wonder what might motivate government workers, perhaps not having to fight with 90 year old senile congressmen over funding allocation.

SLS has gotten more than 20 billion dollars in funding so far more, so clearly, they are very good at that fighting for that funding thing. Just less good at delivering the rocket the promised.

You would think that with that much money and time, we would be gettimg a cutting edge, ambitious rocket. But no, they are reshuffling space shuttle parts to make a worse Saturn V. Reused SRBs, reused main engines, upper stage engines from the 60s, yet still costs more than actually new rockets.

&amp;gt;Hmmm I wonder what might motivate government workers, perhaps not having to fight with 90 year old senile congressmen over funding allocation.

Right, at NASA they have a much more relaxed atmosphere. Letting critical safety flaws, that they where warned about, continue until they kill people, multiple times.

But at least they weren't stressed.

&amp;gt;Also the sheer unadulterated hilarity in saying that it's more efficient to require scientists to devote years of work shooting dipshit billionaire Timmy into space to get funding for your actual interest. The sheer absurdity of saying its more efficient to do shit you don't care about to drive innovation rather than just directly work on it is hilarious.

The proof is in the results. In the last 10 years, private companies have churned out dozens of innovative systems. From reusable boosters, to carbon fiber tanks, 3d printed engines, to ultra high performance methalox engines.

In the last 40 years, NASA stagnated. The rocket they want to use up until the 2060s runs on engines made in the 1960s. The space shuttle was a dangerous, poorly designed, expensive mess, that was so bad we where stuck riding Soyuz to the ISS for almost a decade.

&amp;gt;It's only more efficient in your mind because for some reason you both can't imagine a better system nor believe that it can be brought about, which is why we are stuck in this shitty system, because too many people think exactly like you.

The current system is making rockets more ambitious than NASA has ever proposed, faster than NASA could ever imagine. Why would I want to change from this? After decades of inactivity, the private sector has revitalized space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317551577.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>Wow your saying private companies have achieved reusable rocket engines, a feat only met by the exact same reusable rocket engines in the exact same program you are complaining about.  And let's not forget about these innovations in the last ten years that were due to technology itself advancing to the point they could do stuff like 3d print engines.  I'm sure the scientists at NASA in the early 2000's are very sorry for not teleporting to the future where 3d printing technology required existed to print those engines.  The private sector is making these advancements because they are funded by the US government and have contracts with NASA, and because they are built off of decades of advancement to get them to the current level of development, advancement driven in part by decades of NASA research.  It's asinine to compare current rocketry developments to the shuttle program that started in the fucking 1970's to modern rocket companies doing modern rocketry work.  NASA since you obviously don't know or care is currently developing a lunar space station, which in conjunction with a new launch system and reusable spacecraft is leading the way towards manned missions towards Mars.  Last I checked that doesn't seem like they are just sitting on their hands like you want to imply, indeed what they are doing is offloading responsibility of Leo missions like resupply to the ISS to companies like SpaceX while pursuing entirely scientific driven missions like the Artemis program, an actual qualitative step towards Mars via the moon development beyond the constantly shifting goal posts of Elon Musk.  So far we have NASA directly working on the 2024 development of a lunar space station and we have private enterprise like SpaceX preparing to deliver cargo to it who boy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317757408.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Wow your saying private companies have achieved reusable rocket engines, a feat only met by the exact same reusable rocket engines in the exact same program you are complaining about.

The RS-25 didn't work. They cost over 100 million dollars each, and despite that, NASA has opted to use them as a disposable engine anyway.

&amp;gt;And let's not forget about these innovations in the last ten years that were due to technology itself advancing to the point they could do stuff like 3d print engines.

Right, technology is moving forward, NASA is stuck in the 70s.

&amp;gt;I'm sure the scientists at NASA in the early 2000's are very sorry for not teleporting to the future where 3d printing technology required existed to print those engines.

No one is asking for future tech. We're asking them to build something half ways modern, and actually check for safety. Instead, they build old, expensive, dangerous rockets that drain the budget and kill people.

&amp;gt;The private sector is making these advancements because they are funded by the US government and have contracts with NASA, and because they are built off of decades of advancement to get them to the current level of development, advancement driven in part by decades of NASA research.

NASA was forced to contract to private companies after the rocket they designed was grounded for safety and cost, the rocket they wanted to replace it (Ares 1) was also canceled for cost and safety.

Because of that, those private companies they where farced to contract to did more innovation in ten years than NASA did in 40.

&amp;gt;It's asinine to compare current rocketry developments to the shuttle program that started in the fucking 1970's to modern rocket companies doing modern rocketry work.

NASA is developing rockets right now. And guess what, it could have been made in the 70s. NASA hasn't moved forward in decades.

&amp;gt;NASA since you obviously don't know or care is currently developing a lunar space station, which in conjunction with a new launch system and reusable spacecraft is leading the way towards manned missions towards Mars.

The lunar gateway is a symptom of the bloat. It serves no real purpose in the Artemis program, other than to justify the existence of Orion. The Orion capsule is so underperforming, it can't carry it's own lander, it can't even make it to low lunar orbit. So they take it to this hyper elliptical lunar orbit instead, then transfer to the actual lander, that was launched form earth anyway.

Orion, the SLS, and lunar gateway are redundant steps that have delayed and bloated our return to the moon. Boarding the lander, on earth, or LEO, is safer, quicker, cheaper and easier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317777111.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>Wow it's almost like the point of them isn't to return to the moon but instead begin to put a long term human presence on the moon.  Something none of these hyper advanced private companies are doing.  Are you suggesting we wait for another 20 years SpaceX to step up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317855320.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Orion, SLS, and the lunar gateways are still redundant steps to doing that.

The actual moon bases are going to be carried on the starship landers they have contracted for. Because Orion and SLS can not land on the moon, none the less sustain a presence. Only private companies will have the technology too.

Furthermore, SLS can launch at best once a year. No presence can be 'sustained' on that. Even if you ignore it's tiny payload, and inability to actually reach the moon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318391681.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So use those flights to do something other than shoot billionaires into space

You mean like how Musk is sending people and cargo to the ISS? Or satellites for cheap internet for the globe?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38325646990.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah sure, and he is also wasting time shooting cars into space and shooting millionaires into space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38326058388.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes. That one time as a literal test flight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38385656366.0" user="Strider755" delta="False">
    <text>Some rocket engines, like the one used in NASA's SLS (and in the Apollo program) use hydrogen fuel. These engines emit zero carbon - only water.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
