<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38316634474.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA\_spinoff\_technologies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies)

Here's a list of all the technologies that NASA had a hand in creating.

You see going into space is very difficult. It requires a ton of innovation. That innovation often ends up in our houses some years down the road. In the form of........ well just look at the list. 

So no Space Tourism is not a waste of resources. In fact it's a fantastic use of our resources. We are paying very bright minds to solve very complicated problems. This has a tremendously positive effect on the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316636858.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[NASA spinoff technologies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies)** 
 
 &amp;gt;NASA spinoff technologies are commercial products and services which have been developed with the help of NASA, through research and development contracts, such as Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) or STTR awards, licensing of NASA patents, use of NASA facilities, technical assistance from NASA personnel, or data from NASA research. Information on new NASA technology that may be useful to industry is available in periodical and website form in "NASA Tech Briefs", while successful examples of commercialization are reported annually in the NASA publication "Spinoffs". The Spinoff publication has documented more than 2,000 technologies over time.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316658381.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>hi! 

I completely support NASA's space exploration missions. But i think space tourism by Billionaires with no astronaut training and no real aim to help society at large is a waste of resources. They are driven by revenue, profit and scalability when they should be driven by research, scientific innovation, and social good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317339837.0" user="LeastSignificantB1t" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They are driven by revenue, profit and scalability when they should be driven by research, scientific innovation, and social good.

So you expect billionaires to be motivated by altruism rather than profits or pleasure.

That's an understandable position. That's a respectable position. It is also naive and unhelpful.

Let me go off topic for a second. What is better, a democracy or a dictatorship? I'd bet democracy would be your answer. But why? What makes democracies good while absolute monarchies and dictatorships are bad?

The answer is incentives. You might expect a dictator to care about their people, but in reality, a dictator has no incentive to care. Meanwhile, in a real democracy, the president depends on the citizens, both because of their votes and because of their taxes, so politicians are incentivized to look after them and provide a decent standard of living.

Similarly, you might expect for billionaires to spend their billions in altruistic pursues instead of space tourism, but the reality is that they are going to spend millions for pleasure one way or another, completely selfishly unless they are incentivized to do otherwise. 

So I ask you this: would you rather have billionaires spend their fortune in houses and yachts? Or is it preferable if they spend their pleasure money in something that helps advance science and space exploration, even if indirectly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317421771.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>That is a very well framed question.

But saying billionaires will continue to be billionaires and there is nothing we can do about it, is a little weak, in my opinion.

I think your points are really valid. But maybe it just goes to show that space tourism is only one part of the problem. Maybe we need to think about how to incentivise the wealthy to be more altruistic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317403413.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But i think space tourism by Billionaires with no astronaut training and no real aim to help society at large is a waste of resources.

Both Bezos and Musk have aims to help society at large. At least in Musk's case there's some credibility to that idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318177302.0" user="Benzimin92" delta="False">
    <text>LOL! None of his ambitions are about helping humanity, that's just the marketing. He wants to make bank.
For instance, if he wanted to help humanity he wouldn't have made tesla chargers incompatible with other electric cars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318180563.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Laughing at people is very rude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318417955.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;LOL! None of his ambitions are about helping humanity

I guess that global internet thing is just for show then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318989291.0" user="Benzimin92" delta="False">
    <text>It's a monopoly. Much like electric cars and space travel. It's designed to capture the market, nothing more. Maybe it will have a byproduct of doing good, but the good will be constrained by what makes the largest profit/share value for Elon himself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38319044915.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>By definition it is not a monopoly since there are other satellite internet companies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38319331834.0" user="Benzimin92" delta="False">
    <text>You're right. It isn't yet, but that's what it's designed to be. I think it's just another way to monetize SoaceX.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38319699410.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>Its designed to be better than the other companies using decades old technology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317517145.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is scientists are curious children so if you give them big and interesting toys they are going to play with them and that often ends up producing innovation, but usually if you want to run that as a business, then you're management will tell you not to play but to focus on the assignment, which in this case is space tourism or in otherwords a waste of time and energy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
