<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38316967221.0" user="effyochicken" delta="False">
    <text>We used to have heavily polluting cars, then we had less polluting cars, and now we have electric cars all over the place. 

We used to have rockets that used massive fuel drums on the sides due to how much fuel they consumed. Then we had the Saturn V design burning 788 kg/second. Now we have the falcon doing 250 kg/sec. In time, we'll have even more efficient rockets. (idk, maybe even all-electric ones?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317035575.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>Technological innovation is fascinating! But i still don't think thats a strong enough argument for aimless travel to space today. Maybe 100 years in the future, we would have solved the climate crisis and have discovered rocket fuel sources that do not pollute the earth at all. But today, space tourism is a waste of precious resources (natural resources, money etc)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317491490.0" user="effyochicken" delta="False">
    <text>Space Tourism is just an excuse to continue building rockets and improving suit technology, and countless other little bits of technology that all move with the space industry. 

Now we're at a place where a person can be sent up into orbit without any major training in how to operate a space craft. This will have massive implications down the line for sending non-experts up into orbit for various reasons during short trips. (ie: repair crews on turnaround trips to the International Space Station.)

Right at this exact moment, sure, you could say it's a waste of resources. But how do you go from "waste of resources" to "not a waste of resources anymore" without all the stuff that happens in between? All the inefficiencies that get improved over time. If we stopped space travel now, it's not like in 20 years we'll just all pick it back up again but with 20 years of progress. 

We need to actually get those flight hours in to keep progress going.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317532206.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Ironically the heavily polluting cars probably still produces less polution due to the fact that there were less cars. (in terms of CO2, lead poisoning and other stuff were still and issue).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
