<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38316644190.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>Isn’t this true of literally *all* tourism, generally?

Moreover, can’t we extend this line of thinking to a stoic affect in which absolutely all activities the people in gauge and waste resources reduce pollution and carbon?

As a species, we’re not going to survive by cutting back alone. The solution is going to be moving technology forward — not standing still. We should encourage people to be responsible, but in the end, it just buys us time. We need to see innovation as the answer, not the enemy. 

I don’t see any value in these individuals making it to space. I see it as a trivial side-effect for massively valuable acts or progress like SpaceX generally.

Abhorring these milestones is like abhorring the first transatlantic flight because it meant commercial airlines would be coming. Sure, but the economic progress afforded by flight generally is worth it. Tourism is just a side effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316804907.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>That is a good point. I think most tourism can be viewed as a waste of resources. However, with general tourism, you experience a new culture making you more accepting of individual differences, you help the economy of the place you visit, you can do more than just look and come back because you would typically visit a place for if not a few days, a few hours at the least. 

Space tourism is a whole different ball game. At this stage, you can only go up for a few minutes because the Gforce would crush you and make you sick, meaning you don't do anything for the greater social good by going up there for 10 minutes. 

As for your point about tourism being a side effect, I think it is an unnecessary side effect. I am all for exploration, scientific research and innovation by trained professionals who will benefit society. My argument is against the wealthy going on a joy ride with no real consideration of the implications to the general population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316925526.0" user="raznov1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;However, with general tourism, you experience a new culture making you more accepting of individual differences

Viewing the earth from space is known to have a profound effect on people as well.

&amp;gt;you help the economy of the place you visit,

Space tourism would still require people to go somewhere and support those economies, let alone all the jobs the manufacturing creates

&amp;gt;you can do more than just look and come back because you would typically visit a place for if not a few days, a few hours at the least. 

No counter there, but... So?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317968597.0" user="shoelessbob1984" delta="False">
    <text>How much culture do you take in from a resort?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38318989454.0" user="caster" delta="False">
    <text>Look at it from the perspective of a spectrum of decreasing cost over time. Largesse of the unimaginably wealthy is an inevitable point along the trip from "utterly impossible" to "commercially typical."

In the 1960s no one no matter how rich could have done this. It took a concerted national effort for a decade to build a space program from nothing. After the technology was initially invented, and proved it could be done, barriers had been overcome. You could make the argument (and many did) that going to the moon was a waste of resources. But we did it anyway because enough people believed the long-term benefits would massively outweigh even a decade of investment.

Today it is still exorbitantly expensive. But a billionaire like Bezos can get it done with an amount of resources controlled by one person. This was **inconceivable** in 1950. Again, you could make the argument that going to space is a waste of resources.

But tomorrow when the costs have fallen still further and it becomes possible, albeit expensive, for a commercial flight into space? Industrial vessels and activities that are expensive and unusual, but still routinized, like oil prospecting expeditions or crab fishing ships? When a middle class job can be had aboard such a vessel? I wonder if people then will still look back on the "ridiculous" expense of these first few projects as being a waste. Likely not.

And even further into the future when asteroid mining and industrial stations have lifted much of the heavy industry from Earth's surface into the vacuum of space? With the inexhaustible raw materials of our outer solar system at our disposal? And habitable environments housing a potentially infinite number of people- limited only by influx of raw materials and production rate? How could we not look back at these first early efforts as being critical to the long-term growth and progress of humanity?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

A similar trajectory of increasing scale and decreasing costs with advances in technology occurred with the development of seagoing ships. Starting with very small, costly, and undoubtedly extremely high-risk sea voyages. But then as technology improved, including navigation, seagoing technologies, and ship production technologies, costs fell and they increased greatly in size and power. Ships went from insanely risky and costly curiosities, to mainstays of commerce, politics, and war. And today you can have a small watercraft for less than the price of a car that would be the envy of the fleet in a royal navy of the 17th century.

Those brave souls who spent their fortunes and even sacrificed their lives in experimentation and suicidally risky first sea voyages, paved the way for naval technology we know today.

I would argue that spacecraft will inevitably go through a painful early period before they become as mature a technology as naval ships. But it will happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38333762801.0" user="jhw2011" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That is a good point. I think most tourism can be viewed as a waste of resources. However, with general tourism, you experience a new culture making you more accepting of individual differences, you help the economy of the place you visit, you can do more than just look and come back because you would typically visit a place for if not a few days, a few hours at the least.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Space tourism is a whole different ball game. At this stage, you can only go up for a few minutes because the Gforce would crush you and make you sick, meaning you don't do anything for the greater social good by going up there for 10 minutes.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;As for your point about tourism being a side effect, I think it is an unnecessary side effect. I am all for exploration, scientific research and innovation by trained professionals who will benefit society. My argument is against the wealthy going on a joy ride with no real consideration of the implications to the general population.

Just a few questions to consider maybe:   
P1: Would you consider relaxation (contributing to mental health, and not only) a waste of time? Also, even if you visited a place for a limited time, would you say that your brain is the same as before experiencing that place?  
P2: There is a start for everything. How many innovations turned mainstream/perfect from the first iteration?  
P3: Yet the majority of the population still follow the 'news'. And who has a higher chance of landing in the news/ making a bigger sensation? An unknown researcher or a celebrity? I'm not making any pro arguments for the "wealthy", but maybe their act serves to increase mass awareness by leveraging availability bias?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
