<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38316790242.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>You mentioned Elon Musk, but he is not in the same category as the others you mentioned. SpaceX has actually transformed the space industry. They have saved US tax payers billions of dollars by dramatically reducing the cost per kg to orbit. For reference, NASA’s SLS rocket will likely cost over 1 billion per launch. SpaceX’s Starship will cost a several million per launch. Even just looking at their current Falcon 9 rocket, no one else comes even remotely close on costs.

&amp;amp;nbsp;

Edit: SpaceX isn’t in the space tourism business. They are in the business of bringing low cost internet to the whole world, enabling new applications in space that were impossible before due to cost, and going to mars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316896536.0" user="MrHeavenTrampler" delta="False">
    <text>Also, Blue Origin is developing a fucntional lunar module meant for recollection and potential setting of a lunar base. Their liquid hydrogen engine is also pretty innovative for the space, as it'd allow us to source fuel from the water in the moon's surface via electrolysis if I'm not wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38316996073.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>I have high hopes for Blue Origin, but the OP seems like someone who will only be convinced by the here and now, and not the “hopefully in a few years”. SpaceX today is saving NASA (and the air force/ intelligence services) billions of dollars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317010548.0" user="MrHeavenTrampler" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if OP can't understand the importance of a moon base for future endeavors such as industrial complexes, artificial habitat assembling and asteroid mining, as well as colonization of Mars and Venus, then I do nit think this debate is going anywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317205284.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>i understand the value in scientific exploration. My problem is with space tourism for the sake of experiencing microgravity or saying you have been to space. This is something only extremely wealthy people can do and I would argue that money can be used for the important things you mentioned instead of taking a handful of wealthy people into space aimlessly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317317837.0" user="PoorCorrelation" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying it’s unethical for me to buy as a millionaire or unethical for me to sell it to millionaires so I can redirect their money to worthy causes?

Because the reality is that a lot of good causes get a lot of their money from appealing to the rich in extravagant ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317074119.0" user="rsirdeshmukh" delta="False">
    <text>Those are thought provoking points. Thank you!

However, and correct me if I'm wrong, didn't Elon buy a ticket for Branson's tourism space flights?

I think SpaceX is supporting innovation and social good. But, I think the larger issue is about space tourism being a wasteful venture when their money can be used for better and the resources used can be applied to other solutions and inventions to help more people on earth. And i don't think Elon is advocating against space tourism, even if he is not directly making it happen. Neither do I think SpaceX's good initiatives can compensate for space travel!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317124580.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt Elon bought a ticket from Branson, since Branson’s company is sub orbital and Elon’s company regularly takes Astronauts to the space station…

&amp;amp;nbsp;

You mentioned in another comment that you support NASA’s research and exploration. SpaceX has saved NASA billions of dollars already. And SpaceX will continue to save them billions in the future. NASA was paying Russia almost 100 million per flight per astronaut to get to the space station. Now SpaceX flys them for close to 50 million. NASAs budget is not that large. These cost savings are allowing nasa to do missions they couldn’t afford before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38317389425.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody will likely be able to convince you that there are "better ends" that those resources could be put towards. However, If Elon and Bezos were not investing in space flight, do you think they would be using their money according to your own view of what those more important ends are? No, of course not. Seeing how it is their money, and they'll use it as they see fit, better they use it to develop new technologies for getting to space, which has infinite potential for the betterment of humanity, than buying a fleet of yachts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
