<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38317132406.0" user="Careless_Clue_6434" delta="False">
    <text>Apparently, Bezos's rockets use a non-carbon-based fuel, so while there are negative environmental effects, they're mostly not warming-related: [https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/factcheck/2021/07/28/fact-check-jeff-bezos-new-shepard-rocket-launch-didnt-emit-carbon/8073047002/](https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/factcheck/2021/07/28/fact-check-jeff-bezos-new-shepard-rocket-launch-didnt-emit-carbon/8073047002/).

The distinction between space tourism and real space research seems kind of false - making space tourism cost-effective requires finding ways to make launches cheaper, which in turn benefits research activities which can take advantage of those innovations.  

Space tourism won't exacerbate the wealth gap; like you said, pretty much only the rich will partake, so the economic effect is to redistribute wealth from them to the much poorer employees involved in the industry, just as in other forms of luxury consumption.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
