<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1632394760.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qzvvuw/cmv_space_tourism_is_a_waste_of_resources/">
    <title>CMV: Space Tourism is a Waste of Resources</title>
    <original_poster>rsirdeshmukh</original_poster>
    <original_post>In 2021, three billionaires, Jeff Bezos, Richard Branson, and Elon Musk, entered the "space race" to take flight into space with no aim other than to reach suborbital space for a few minutes. 

While much of the world marvelled at this technological milestone, I was taken aback. If these billionaires get their way, there will be many spacecrafts jetting off to space for a joyride. This is scary because the carbon footprint of each of these space expeditions is extremely high due to the amount of fuel they use, the energy used to manufacture the fuel, and the soot generated which pollutes and damages the atmosphere while heating up the earth.

To me, space tourism seems like just an obscene display of power and wealth. With so many problems on earth, such as climate change and the pandemic, their money can be used more productively. Whether that is helping save earth or funding real space research, both are much better than just going up to space for a few minutes. Especially since doing so continues to exacerbate the wealth gap because space tourism is only a reality for those who can afford it while having serious implications on those left on earth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38319403236.0" user="adrianw" delta="False">
    <text>The same thing was said about sending people to the moon.  

It turns out it was a significant boon to our economy.

Satellites and miniaturization are two examples.  The total number of examples are too numerous to mention here.  

The people who worked on Apollo went everywhere and helped develop our modern technology.  

So yes it might seem like a waste of money, yet the technology that goes into will have benefits decades to come.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
