<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1634622433.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r17mqp/cmv_likes_reactions_and_upvotes_should_be_removed/">
    <title>CMV: "Likes," "Reactions," and "Upvotes" should be removed from social media sites.</title>
    <original_poster>AmigoDelDiabla</original_poster>
    <original_post>These reactions, whether positive or negative, reduce online engagement to anonymous, binary interactions.  They lack nuance, insight, or accountability.  And they are *wildly* misinterpreted in that they don't convey degree.  A high quantity of likes, or dislikes, just means a number of people saw and reacted to a statement/post/comment, but not the degree to which they reacted.  Especially in the event of downvotes/dislikes, I too often see the OP react as if that conveys hate.  Nah, it usually just means people disagree with you.

And it goes without saying how positive reactions can distort the owner's perspective of how his or her work is received.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38330128733.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38330138876.0" user="AmigoDelDiabla" delta="False">
    <text>It's really the binary, anonymity behind it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38334228509.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Monotonous_DeMeanour – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Monotonous_DeMeanour&amp;amp;message=Monotonous_DeMeanour%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/r17mqp/-/hlwrom5/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
