<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1634622433.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r17mqp/cmv_likes_reactions_and_upvotes_should_be_removed/">
    <title>CMV: "Likes," "Reactions," and "Upvotes" should be removed from social media sites.</title>
    <original_poster>AmigoDelDiabla</original_poster>
    <original_post>These reactions, whether positive or negative, reduce online engagement to anonymous, binary interactions.  They lack nuance, insight, or accountability.  And they are *wildly* misinterpreted in that they don't convey degree.  A high quantity of likes, or dislikes, just means a number of people saw and reacted to a statement/post/comment, but not the degree to which they reacted.  Especially in the event of downvotes/dislikes, I too often see the OP react as if that conveys hate.  Nah, it usually just means people disagree with you.

And it goes without saying how positive reactions can distort the owner's perspective of how his or her work is received.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38330147760.0" user="quarkral" delta="False">
    <text>There are far too many posts and comments on Reddit, especially on any larger subreddit. How do you even begin to decide which one to read? Heavy-handed moderation on comments works for small subreddits, but it simply doesn't scale to 100k+ users unless the moderators are willing to dedicate significant amounts of time and effort for free essentially. The upvote/downvote/report system isn't perfect but does give signal. A similar reasoning applies to other social media like FB/Twitter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38330156793.0" user="AmigoDelDiabla" delta="False">
    <text>Actual engagement with the post (e.g. number of sub comments)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38330197519.0" user="quarkral" delta="False">
    <text>what stops that metric from being gamed? If you got rid of upvote/downvote, people would just start to comment spam or one word replies to indicate agreement. That actually makes it harder from a ranking perspective because you've turned two or three signals (upvote/downvote and comment) into one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38340845207.0" user="gyroda" delta="False">
    <text>Also, make controversial/unpopular things will garner a lot of comments.

Inflammatory posts getting lots of interactions is a real problem in social media sites that use engagement to judge whether something should be ranked higher in the sorting algorithm (YouTube comments, twitter)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
