<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1634622433.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r17mqp/cmv_likes_reactions_and_upvotes_should_be_removed/">
    <title>CMV: "Likes," "Reactions," and "Upvotes" should be removed from social media sites.</title>
    <original_poster>AmigoDelDiabla</original_poster>
    <original_post>These reactions, whether positive or negative, reduce online engagement to anonymous, binary interactions.  They lack nuance, insight, or accountability.  And they are *wildly* misinterpreted in that they don't convey degree.  A high quantity of likes, or dislikes, just means a number of people saw and reacted to a statement/post/comment, but not the degree to which they reacted.  Especially in the event of downvotes/dislikes, I too often see the OP react as if that conveys hate.  Nah, it usually just means people disagree with you.

And it goes without saying how positive reactions can distort the owner's perspective of how his or her work is received.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38330726653.0" user="thefujirose" delta="False">
    <text>The like and dislike features are a tool used by the social media site and the users. The site will use it as data to process. For example: disliking something will get similar posts recommended less whilst liking something will get similar posts recommended more.
 
On the other side, dislikes and likes provide information for users. Humans are lazy and rather not type an entire comment or even push the like/dislike button. This commicates a vague sense of degree they react to. 
If a person views it and doesn't like or dislike, then there wasn't really a reaction. If a person views it and likes or dislikes then they put enough effort in to voice that. If a user does that and comments, then the degree of their reaction is much greater, and by this point it depends on the effort spent in the comment itself. 

This commicates a vague degree of reaction without using facial expressions. Reaction is important because it's feedback. That being said, you need to understand the feedback to use it properly and if you don't you will misinterpret the reactions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
