<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506463910.0" user="Grozak" delta="False">
    <text>Engineering student here with over 100k in debt so far and growing.  When I graduate I'll start paying this debt off, but it's going to take some time.  Say I have a car accident or some sort life-changing event that leaves me alive but otherwise unable to work for an extended period.  If during this time my debts grow beyond my ability to service them I'm out of luck when it comes to those student loans.  If I'm out of the work force for a year, maybe I'll get back on my feet and be able to pay, but what about 5 years?  What if I'm never able to work in my field again?

The fact is, as things are now, student debt will *never* leave me, regardless of circumstance.  The sensible and compassionate thing to do is allow the courts to consider the circumstances of each case and act accordingly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507705489.0" user="RU_Crazy" delta="False">
    <text>There's actually exceptions in the law where you can get loan forgiveness if you become physically/mentally incapable of performing your job.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
