<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506850353.0" user="karnim" delta="False">
    <text>Without going into the issue of scholarships, you're ignoring the historical causes of high debt. First off is that it really wasn't until quite recently that people commonly suggested going to community college first, or even not going to college at all. I would say up until about when the financial crisis hit, the basic assumption for all students was "go to college, you'll make more money because of it and can pay it off".

So, many students entered college having been told by their family, teachers, and government that they would be able to pay off the loans with no problem. An 18 year old kid certainly doesn't know not to enter a certain field because of over-saturation in the job market. Plus, they were always told "Pick something you're passionate about, and you won't hate working. You might not make as much, but you'll make enough".

Now we can recognize both of these statements as not being true in all situations.

Further, you're ignoring the financial crisis. There are thousands (if not hundreds of thousands) of people with student loans affected by this. Between 2007 and 2009, the unemployment rate shot from 4.5% to 10%. Younger people tend to be laid off first, since they are less valuable to the company and are likely still in an at-will hiring period. People who graduated from 2000 and later were very likely to be out of a job, unable to find one, and still have student loans looming over their head. (Mind you, the banks caused this situation, and they got a bailout while still getting to screw people with student loans)

Then of course, there's the people who had already started college when the financial crisis hit. People who started from 2005-2008 had no clue that the financial crisis was going to happen, and many found that their parents could no longer afford to fund their education, or even had lost their jobs entirely. Education is a sunk cost, so once you're in, leaving only results in an unrecoverable loss. If you at least take out the insane loans and finish your degree, you have a degree out of it.

So, if loans are forgiven, yes, it does dick over the financial institutes. However, the financial institutes are the ones who caused this whole mess in the first place. Maybe they should take some responsibility for the people who they dicked over that didn't get a bailout.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506923186.0" user="Snapdrackon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Younger people tend to be laid off first, since they are less valuable to the company and are likely still in an at-will hiring period.

Also, union seniority protects the older workers, forcing layoffs to focus on the newer, younger workers.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506926050.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say it was caused by the ridiculous inflation of tuition, not the banks, but I agree with some of your points </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507185930.0" user="karnim" delta="False">
    <text>The tuition increases are ridiculous, but that does not relieve the banks from the financial crisis they caused, and the effects it had on people pursuing a higher education. I have my thoughts about tuition increases as well, but that's not really the issue at hand here. (If it were, it would likely lend more credibility to the debt forgiveness side)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
