<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27507133768.0" user="chefranden" delta="False">
    <text>I commend you for your hard work in securing these scholarships.  However, you are perhaps failing recognize that these scholarships are not available to everyone.  You received these moneys mostly via competition, which means they are only available to a few.  You won these scholarships so good on you, but this does not mean that everyone else was being lazy. 

Lucrative employment after college has been a bit of a crap-shoot at least since 2008.  So lots of people are stuck with debt they can't reasonably pay and yet cannot discharge through bankruptcy. 

It isn't okay to crap on other just because you have secured a leg up.  You worked hard, but try to remember you won these moneys you didn't earn them.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507140179.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>But if I didn't get these scholarships, I wouldn't go to the school I know I can't afford. That's my main point </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507991649.0" user="morallyharmful" delta="False">
    <text>And to that I'd say that maybe OP is more "gifted" and has more to offer and that's whey he/she got those scholarships. Should we (the people offering the scholarships) be forced to give money to everyone?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27508810302.0" user="chefranden" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I said that. 

However, I do think that since college or tech school is now necessary for a decent living for most people, we ought to tax ourselves and provide that after HS education like many developed nations do.   And before you think I'm looking for a handout I'm 65 and my children are college educated and working.  So I and they would be paying our share of the taxes.

That being said though I realize that my fellow Americans would rather have another fully equipped air craft carrier then debt free children. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
