<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506446411.0" user="Pipstydoo" delta="False">
    <text>You had an experience so *everyone* must have an identical experience.

You had options so *everyone* must have identical options.

Are you seeing a trend here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507723973.0" user="Unconfidence" delta="False">
    <text>This.  OP is talking about scholarships like it's just a matter of going out and growing one, and presuming that his aid will remain unchanged b y outside events.  I went to college during Katrina, I know better than that.  Shit fucks your life up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507992058.0" user="morallyharmful" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Let's say that OP is truly more gifted than most people, why should everyone expect to be carried for 4+ years when they're incapable of doing the work? Not everyone is cut out for higher education and that's OK. But we shouldn't devalue it to make things even for *everyone*, that's exactly what the SOL's attempted to do and that's been a universal failure.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
