<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27507415358.0" user="diggadiggadigga" delta="False">
    <text>Debt forgiveness programs already exist.  I know of a few for law and medicine (and I'm sure there are others that I don't know about because I don't personally know people using them).  And they aren't just coddling people who decided to go to expensive schools and didn't want to think about who was going to pay for their schooling.  The debt forgiveness programs have tangible benefits from society.


 For example, there are several doctors that I know who had their student loans reduced or forgiven in exchange for working in underprivileged areas (think Appalachia region).  These are regions that pay very very little, but have a high need for services.  Someone with a lot of debt would not be able to afford to work in that area, as they would have to prioritize salary over everything else.  By offering loan forgiveness, it is making it possible for quality doctors to choose to work in these areas.  You can't expect someone to want to live out in the middle of nowhere, with very little resources (hospitals don't have the necessary equipment, constantly understaffed so you are going to have to take on more work), for a salary you are struggling to live on, AND also have a mountain of debt to work off.  Without loan forgiveness programs, the good quality doctors would not choose to live in those conditions and e underserved areas would be even worse served.



 I have another friend who is a Harvard educated lawyer.  She wants to work with children who have been abused. Not surprisingly, that is the kind of law job that pays next to nothing.  It is also a high burnout job that few people want. The amount of loans she had to take to get a Harvard law degree means that without loan forgiveness, she would not be able to do that.  She simply wouldn't be able to afford to live and pay back her loans.  So instead of working for abused children (an area of law that sorely needs better lawyers than they can attract with the salary the state gives) she would be working for a big firm, doing work that is much less rewarding.  Because of loan forgiveness, she is able to help these children instead of rich businessmen.




Education is really expensive.  Someone who graduates with a prohibitive amount of loans has to go for the job that makes a lot of money to pay it off.  This leads to a brain drain to big corporations, and away from certain areas of need.  Loan forgiveness allows people to prioritize differently.  It gives our best and brightest the opportunity to contribute to the world, instead of just working for whoever pays them enough to pay off their loan.  We stagnate society by forcing people to prioritize money over other values.  And a huge loan is forcing someone to make money their number one priority (maybe forcing isn't the correct word, but it definitly contributes in a substantial way to the decision making process).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
