<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506537691.0" user="jetpacksforall" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying the scholarships you won are available to every college student, if only they'd try harder or something? Or are you saying that scholarships should be available to **all** students instead of student loans, making the US more like Europe with its subsidized universities?  

Because if you're not saying scholarship money is available for all or most students, and if you're not saying the US should switch to subsidized education, then you are effectively saying that your own situation is irrelevant to the vast majority of college students. It doesn't matter if you were able to win the few competitive scholarship awards available: the simple fact is that scholarships don't have the funding required to cover all students. Which necessarily means most students must seek other sources of funding, like loans.  

Does it change your point of view knowing that most students by definition cannot have access to scholarships? 

Would you then say that those students simply shouldn't go to college? But then what would happen to American industries who find themselves unable to find qualified employees in the coming years? Should the entire country become less qualified and less capable of competing in a global economy, just because the idea of easing student debt burdens offends you? 

Student loan debt is currently around [$1.2 trillion](http://www.usatoday.com/story/money/personalfinance/2014/10/25/student-loan-debt/17773131/): it's the largest single source of private debt outside of home mortgages ($13 trillion). It therefore exerts an enormous downward pressure on the economy, as young educated people just entering the workforce find their buying power greatly reduced (average student loan debt for people 20-29 is $25,500). And unlike a mortgage, you can't sell your degree for equity or take a HELOC loan.  

The US government made $66 billion in profit on student loans from 2007 to 2012. Bully for people who like to lower federal deficits, right? But does it make sense to lower corporate and capital gains taxes on the backs of young students just trying to make their way in the world? The feds should not be profiting off people trying to get an education: it makes far more economic sense for them to pump money into educating young Americans than to extract money from them.  

Finally there's an underlying problem that affects **all** students, and parents, regardless of whether they personally take on student loan debt or not: [tuition hikes](http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Education/2012/0606/Student-debt-What-s-been-driving-college-costs-so-high-anyway). Everybody knows American university tuitions have been rising far above the rate of inflation for a couple of decades. The reasons why are complicated, but it seems pretty likely that cutbacks in state budgets have been largely to blame. As state university systems, formerly generously subsidized Euro-style to enable in-state students to afford college, have seen their public endowments shrink, they have naturally shifted to other sources of revenue. One major source of revenue: tuitions. Federally-subsidized student loans... which count among the best-secured debts in the entire country... have risen to fill the gap. And you can see that a vicious cycle is born. Colleges need money, so they raise tuitions. In order to meet the higher costs, students borrow more. Congress increases borrowing limits, and universities raise tuitions again. Now, rather than competing for endowment funds and direct federal grants, the way universities used to do, they can compete for the ability to increase tuitions, and increase the loans available to pay tuitions. 

It is these large, complex, macroeconomic shifts in the cost of education that people want to see addressed. Reducing the student debt burden on young people will help boost consumer spending and therefore drive the economy. Reducing the cost of education in the first place will broaden the availability of education to more people, thereby making the country as a whole more competitive globally. 

This has nothing to do with scholarships.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
