<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506352812.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>What if there had been an understanding that you were paying so much for the food because it would make you lucky for the rest of your life.  After the meal you discover you are not in fact lucky and were far worse off because of the huge debt you took on to pay for the meal?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506356652.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>Ignorance is not an excuse for the forgiveness of debt. You signed a contract or agreement stating that the amount would be paid back(likely with interest).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506378130.0" user="jerry121212" delta="False">
    <text>It's not ignorance, it's empty promises.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506392626.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>It is ignorance. Very few- if any universities guarantee you a job upon graduation, they tell you that you have a better chance as a graduate(which you do, in the whole) to be employed.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506422515.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>High Schools tell you this...when you're basically still a kid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506425610.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>So the university/government should forgive your debt because a separate institution misinformed you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506442665.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Well considering public schools are the government, yes.  I do think that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506459020.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>This does not apply to private schools or university loans(read: not government loans).

How specifically have public schools misinformed you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506494352.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Public schools push college and specifically advise you to not put school off.  They basically aim to leave you off with believing college is the only option for success.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506529990.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>And do they suggest that you take out a student loan?

Pushing college/uni is a good option- you are more likely in many cases to be more employable after you have been educated.

This is not the same as guaranteeing you employment in a good job in the field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506580835.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Yes they suggest that.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506754870.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>They suggest what?

Suggest is not the same as explicitly stating, nor promising, nor a guarantee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506800624.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>They suggest taking out a loan because you'll pay it back.  Again, are you thinking in terms of an average 16-17 year old brain, or someone with basic world experience?  You act like teenagers are thinking 100% logically and realistically.  It's all about the impression adults leave on them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506828352.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>You will pay it back, eventually.

I went through this exact same thing when I was 17, and I had people in my class who had no idea what they were doing.

If you are going to be spending thousands of dollars, you should- by virtue of common sense- at least research what you are getting for your money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506843741.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you.  I just don't see why the same logic isn't applied to other debts.  Every argument your making is logical, but it's not applied across the board for reasons I don't understand.  The extent to which information is taught *against* going to college is heavily outweighed by what's taught in favor.  It's hard for me to say that college debt is more inexcusable than business debt or failure - which is much more forgiving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507121423.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I just don't see why the same logic isn't applied to other debts.

It is, to an extent.

What needs to be remembered is that University/college is a service, one that is offered for a fee with no guarantee from any relevant party that the investment of time and money will pay off.

I posted this to another commenter, but I think it applies here.

If my vehicle needs to be repaired, I take it to a mechanic. The mechanic's job is not to guarantee that the work he does will make the car more valuable, his job is to fix/repair the car at a cost. If I pay this mechanic $4500 to fix my car, only to find out that the most I could hope to sell the vehicle for after the work is done is $1200, it is not the mechanic's fault- it is my own for not properly doing research on the topic.

Similarly, if I want to be educated, I go to a university/college. The school's job is not to guarantee that my education will make me a valuable employee or net me a higher income career, but to simply educate me. If I pay the university $50,000 for my degree, only to find out that I couldn't hope to get a job in my field after graduating- that is not the fault of the university.

This is not the same as starting a business, nor is it the same as investing in the stock market- this is paying an institution to perform a service because you believe that the service will benefit you.

As with any service- I don't have my debts forgiven because I made the wrong call. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506531420.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>They tell you not to put school off because most people who put school off never end up going, and you're better off having a miserable 20 years paying off debt and eventually having a middle class career/retirement than working unskilled labor for your entire life and trying to live off of the dwindling social security system.

They absolutely should explore the various other options though, public service (military, etc) and trade schools are viable paths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506573811.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>You can start working right out of high school and move up the ladder.  People act like you're doomed at the same position you're entire life without a degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506580758.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>That path is still likely going to involve higher education, unless you want to watch 22 year olds straight out of college become your boss for the next few decades.

Joining the workforce immediately and leveraging that to build your skills is one thing, but the janitor-to-owner career path isn't realistic and shouldn't be encouraged by schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506585933.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;unless you want to watch 22 year olds straight out of college become your boss for the next few decades.

This isn't commonplace.  They don't hire 22 year olds with 0 experience to be managers.  They usually hire you for 30-40k at a shit desk job.  It's not glamourous...ever.  By the time you make any real money, you're an old man.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506591422.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>They don't have to be managers to be your boss.

Also this is exactly what the military does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506613355.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>The military does what?  If you enter the military with a degree, you start as a higher rank.  but you can also reach higher rank without a degree if you join earlier.  It also depends on what branch and what field you're talking about.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506620028.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>Taking young college graduates and putting them in charge of longterm employees is exactly how military officership works. Longterm employees without degrees can never advance to officer ranks without returning to college and entering the workforce at the same place as the 22 year olds. You can get into the workforce and then work on your degree, but you can't progress to degreed positions without it, regardless of seniority.

It happens in civilian life too, but the lines aren't as sharply drawn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506626706.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know.  I read the army's site for more info.  It says they typically hire officers with degrees, but specified professionals, not 22 year olds with Bachelor's degrees. I could be misunderstanding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506631789.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>A bachelor's degree is currently mandatory to become an officer. The vast majority of officers are commissioned via academies and college training programs (ROTC). Most new officers are 21-24 years of age and (technically) outrank those who have been enlisted in the military for even 20+ years. In short, all positions requiring degrees outrank all positions not requiring degrees. This is a holdover from a time when attaining a college degree placed you strictly into a higher class of society.

Even though civilian jobs do not maintain this strict division, the pressure is still there to attain a degree or watch those with less experience be placed above you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506652336.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>I see, well thanks, I did not know that.  I assume you know this from personal experience?

Regardless, that's not how it works everywhere.  You *can* work your way up from mail room to management as you learn the company.  You still have to prove yourself and it's more difficult than college, but it's an option that is not spoken for often enough.  I know this from personal experience.

I think the pushing a degrees has more to do with how terrible high school is.  Most degrees now days are really just high school 2.  I went to a fairly rigorous high school for example, many people went into business straight from there.  They did have connections, but they still had to work their way up.  Their education was probably on par with a typical college grad right after working for 4 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506380301.0" user="squeakyonion" delta="False">
    <text>But they didn't hold up their end of the bargain; I'm not lucky in the job market after eating the meal, like they promised. Why should I pay full price? I've been duped.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506388148.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>What was their end of the bargain? Was this present in the contract you signed?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506409328.0" user="squeakyonion" delta="False">
    <text>Well, after spending *fifteen years* as a CAPTIVE AUDIENCE to purveyors of their product, my schoolmates and I didn't know to make sure that was in the contract. The sellers of the product didn't teach us how to interpret the legalese in contracts, but of course, that's in their best interest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506423833.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>So the contract you signed did not include a guarantee that you would be employed, or even have the ability to get a job in your field, yet they promised that you would be employed, likely in your field?

I truly wonder how it is not ignorance that lands people in this situation. You are just as ignorant to the truth while dealing with incorrect information as you are dealing with no information.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506441152.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>It is ignorance, but let's not pretend people aren't kept *deliberatly* ignorant throughout their prime brain-development years on this issue, then expected to make life-altering decisions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506454587.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>We aren't pretending that.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506456944.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me like you're being slightly pedantic over the meaning of the word "ignorance."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506463464.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>You are just as ignorant to the truth by being misinformed as you are being uninformed.

I am using ignorance as it is defined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506475062.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I know what ignorance means. But you're missing the point of the people arguing with you when you fall back on, "this is how ignorance is defined."

Of course "not knowing something" regardless of how that state came to be is ignorance. But then you went on to say that ignorance isn't an excuse. And people disagree with *that premise*, even if they didn't word it quite right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506483841.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>I understand what people are arguing back- though this does not change the position.

Ignorance(lack of knowledge) of a subject does not excuse you from your actions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506466407.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>But look at the standard of care society takes for other things.  Consider not just the amount of paperwork and warnings that go along with major financial investments like mortgages, revolving lines of credit, and investments such as mutual funds - also consider the regulations the companies involved in these products have to adhere to when marketing their products.  And these things are mostly creatures of adults - the vast majority of mutual fund buyers are in their 40s - 70s.  Imagine what a higher standard they would have if they almost exclusively targeted and sold to 18 year olds.  Likewise compare the risks of these things.  Which is a riskier investment?  A small cap mutual fund or a fine arts degree from a private university?  When you compare the risk of losses that investors face shouldn't the universities have even tighter warnings?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506480296.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>You're not investing, to say the least.

You are purchasing a service from an institution that will train/teach you in a field, and provide you with a certificate or degree upon completion.

These are not the same things.

This is why we don't have incredible regulations on services. A mechanic can fix a vehicle for $4000, but that won't change the fact that the vehicle will only be worth $1000 when work is completed. The same applies to your schooling.

If you chose to have a service preformed(in this case, being educated) in a field where there aren't any jobs, or few high paying jobs, it's the equivalent of the mechanic example above. This is not the fault of the institution, nor is it the fault of the mechanic.

You are not required to go to university/college. You are not required to incur a debt. If you go into the situation ignorant about the world and the field, it is not the schools fault for charging you for that service. It is not the governments fault for providing you a loan. It is your own fault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506522563.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct but arn't I as well?  We are paying a huge amount of money because we expect to make a return on it in the future by way of an improved steam of income.  That is investment-ish isn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506550386.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>It is an investment in a non traditional way.

You are expecting your money and the service you purchase to go towards a better future for yourself- but this is no more guaranteed than what was outlined in the example with the mechanic.

This is an individual paying for a service which may or may not benefit them in the long run. Think of the mechanic again- just because money was invested in the vehicle does not mean that the vehicle is going to be worth the investment, in fact, with very minimal research one could find out that their 1997 Yaris is not worth the $10,000 they are investing in it.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506358245.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>But to be fair, I'd know how much was in my pocket, or how much I could spend on my meal and I would've kept that in mind when ordering. Maybe instead of going to Ruth's Chris, I would've gone to Outback. I'm still getting steak, but I'm getting a more affordable version</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506360767.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think most people who would like debt forgiveness went to really expensive schools or something?

Debt is literally the only way a lot of people get to go to school. We can't all get scholarships.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506416453.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>One of my good friends is working 3 jobs in richmond as she attends VCU because she really wants the education. There are hundreds of community colleges across the country that are affordable and will give some education that in many cases can transfer to in state universities while you spend two years saving. People are just unrealistic in their spending, and debt forgiveness will promote that activity in the future </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506437210.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>If I were working three jobs in college I doubt I ever would have made it to class. Even one job on top of taking classes is *hard*. That one semester I spent in class or at work from 8am until 10pm Monday-Thursday was rough.

And yeah, there are lots of community colleges where you can get an Associates. But the jobs these people are after require Bachelors. So you'll need to take on debt for your last two years, even at an in-state University.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506497464.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I were working three jobs in college I doubt I ever would have made it to class. Even one job on top of taking classes is hard.

So you say "I want to focus on school, someone else can work that job while I go to school and I'll pay them back later." That's what a loan is. The job is being worked either way, you're just deferring the difficulty so you can focus on one thing at a time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506504476.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>This is typically how any kind of victim blaming works.  One person's success story is used to invalidate other people's challenges. It's a sad fact of human nature that when we see someone with a problem, we take it as proof of a character flaw, especially when it gives a person the opportunity to feed their own feeling of superiority. It's not by coincidence that everyone who posts a CMV on this topic considers it incomplete without the opportunity to prop up their superior
life choices. To be clear,  I'm not saying that this is victim blaming,  only that it uses the same disingenuous tactics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506511630.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Debt is literally the only way a lot of people get to go to school. 

Debt is literally the only way a lot of people end up going to school. It doesn't mean it was their only option. 

There are a host of options available to young adults in how to pursue education. The primary education system is very likely failing in demonstrating all these options, but they are there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506377558.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying these students are blameless.  No matter how low university tuitions are students complain about it bitterly (see canada).  However you take a 17 year old who is applying for universities, you combine their inexperience in life with what their parents are saying about how university is the path to success, you add in statements by politicians that this is the case, you mix in the universities selling this line as well, and then you provide government financing and private lending for hundreds of thousands of dollars to a kid who couldn't get approved for a 2K credit card, and then four years later there are no jobs for him and he has no way to pay back the debt.  He can't even go bankrupt like a businessman could if he borrowed 200K he didn't have to launch a crazy product.  

I am a foaming at the mouth conservative but even I think there is something deeply wrong about this picture from a social justice perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
