<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506360626.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think private financial institutions would be so against this idea. My loans are 100% federal loans, meaning the money came directly from the government, not from a private bank's capital. If I didn't have that debt to manage, I could more easily take on a different kind of debt from a private institution, such as a mortgage.   
  
However, debt forgiveness can lead to issues collectively called a moral hazard, taking on debt should require taking on risk, risk that should not be easily removed down the line since that would incentivize poor financial behavior. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506412815.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand federal debt forgiveness but some people seem to want what Iceland did in 08, which I think makes the banks much less willing to loan in the future and will lead to higher interest rates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506454116.0" user="BaconCanada" delta="False">
    <text>They really aren't. Banks are willing to loan student loans to anyone because they are very much aware it is the hardest type of loan to discharge. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506510051.0" user="nillby" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly do you think Iceland did in 08? They adjusted peoples mortgages for inflation. People in the end are still paying off their original loans to the bank. Their loans did not vanish. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507706581.0" user="RU_Crazy" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is that the federal government is the predominant lender in this country.  Not private banks.  Those interest rates are set by Congress. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
