<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27507593516.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt.  I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. 

Your assumptions are based on 

* keeping scholarships that are (often) conditional based on your academic achievement and/or market performance with the scholarship funds
* that the price of the school you go to doesn't go up

A lot of students, particularly those who went to school from '06-now, faced the double-whammy of the recession.  It caused many schools prices to skyrocket *while they were attending* (particularly state schools, as public funding dried up), then they graded into a dead job market and got their student loan rates jacked up.

You can't predict costs or market movement accurately over 4 years.  If you can, don't bother going to college - you'll be a millionaire in no time with that skill.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
