<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506394227.0" user="Vornnash" delta="False">
    <text>Considering college education is free in most European countries I think some leeway with debt forgiveness is called for.  You have done remarkably well, no doubt having top grades that justify the scholarships you've acquired.  However, not everyone is so gifted, and yet education is still important for most of us.  You should have a little more empathy for those less fortunate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506424651.0" user="Ndlaxfan" delta="False">
    <text>I think the bigger problem is predatory institutions that offer "degrees" to anyone that is willing to pay, but at least in my home state, there is a very robust two year community college system that cheaply gives two years of college credit that transfers to any 4 year college in the state while you work to save up for the college. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506451864.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any source that can quantify how easy it is to work your way through a community college and then transfer to a four year Univeristy? You're making it sound like most people would be able to do this without ever going into debt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506489038.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>Here's some cost comparison tables: http://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=76

Notably 2011-2012 for two-year public institutions you're looking at $8561/yr as compared to double that for a four-year public institution. Even assuming you are completely ineligible for even small grants and scholarships, that is manageable without debt.

Good community colleges do their best to ensure that their credits are transferable to local 4-year institutions. It is in their best interest to be seen as an effective gateway to a more expensive school.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506533084.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Notably 2011-2012 for two-year public institutions you're looking at $8561/yr as compared to double that for a four-year public institution. Even assuming you are completely ineligible for even small grants and scholarships, that is manageable without debt.

And when you're paying double that ammount at the more expensive school?

I'm not saying that this route isn't cheaper. I am saying that for many people this route *still requires debt*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506542158.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>"Requires" is a tricky word. If they're working a minimum wage job they should be able to cover their costs entirely as long as they save a few thousand dollars during the cheaper community college years. This is assuming they work full-time for as little as possible and have well-off parents who are unwilling to help out. If their parents aren't well-off they should be able to pull in a decent amount of grant money yearly and live more comfortably.


At what point is "That's too hard, I don't wanna work that hard" become "requires debt"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506548413.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If they're working a minimum wage job they should be able to cover their costs entirely as long as they save a few thousand dollars during the cheaper community college years.

Sure, as long as they don't need to eat or live anywhere I'm sure they could save loads of money.

&amp;gt; This is assuming they work full-time for as little as possible and have well-off parents who are unwilling to help out.

Ah yes, assuming they can eat and live for free. Pretty big assumptions.

&amp;gt; If their parents aren't well-off they should be able to pull in a decent amount of grant money yearly and live more comfortably.

Are you still assuming that they'll be living with their parents and eating their food?

&amp;gt; At what point is "That's too hard, I don't wanna work that hard" become "requires debt"?

At the point it is literally impossible to work enough hours to make enough money to afford to go to school.

But hey, maybe everyone should just bootstrap themselves some parents to provide them with free room and board for four years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506553430.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>Those tuition costs cover board, and eating does not cost $500/month.

We're not talking $50,000/year educations here. We're talking $8.5k and $16.5k/year, respectively. Those are manageable on unskilled labor even without the benefits that the vast majority of people are eligible foe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506590680.0" user="SpunkyMG" delta="False">
    <text>$7.50x40x4x12= $14400

Taxes:30% 

$14400x.30= $4320

$14400-$4320

Minimum wage take home if the minimum wage is $7.50 = $10080

What part of taking home just over $10,000 a year after taxes affords anyone either one of those options from "working hard".  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506610666.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>With an income of 15k~ you won't be paying 30 % taxes. Once again we're unrealistically assuming rich and unhelpful parents here, and zero opportunity for scholarships. There's also the opportunity to pick up extra funds in the summer when classes aren't on.

Four years at the $16.5k university aren't possible for our hypothetical extremely unlucky student, but if they're able to sock away some money at community college they can get their bachelor's without going into debt.

Of course, assuming this bachelor's degree will indeed increase the student's income potential beyond minimum wage, it may be prudent to defer some of those costs until graduation by taking loans. Loans aren't necessary, but they may be worthwhile after a realistic cost/benefit analysis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506636663.0" user="SpunkyMG" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;With an income of 15k~ you won't be paying 30 % taxes.

Tax rate for minimum wage is 24.1% before factoring in state taxes. We can hem and haw about 6% if you want, or we can factor in state income taxes too, and use 30% as a model. 

&amp;gt;There's also the opportunity to pick up extra funds in the summer when classes aren't on.

Working full time already, what you mean to say is you can get a 2nd job during the summer, since the 1 full time minimum wage job you have isn't enough. 

&amp;gt;Four years at the $16.5k university aren't possible for our hypothetical extremely unlucky student, but if they're able to sock away some money at community college they can get their bachelor's without going into debt.

Even if we use a state like Florida, that has no state income tax(24.1%), $10930-$8500 a year still leaves billy with $2400 a year to take care of everything else. Health/Car insurance, food for a year, expenditures, etc. Where is the money left to "sock away"?

&amp;gt;Of course, assuming this bachelor's degree will indeed increase the student's income potential beyond minimum wage, it may be prudent to defer some of those costs until graduation by taking loans. Loans aren't necessary, but they may be worthwhile after a realistic cost/benefit analysis.

So they can't in fact afford it, and debt is the only realistic alternative. Glad we agree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506648423.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>They can afford it, the simple fact is that they don't want to live a shitty life of ramen noodles and netflix for four years. They want to go out and have the "college experience". That means buying toys and fun on credit. Bare minimum college is affordable even in unrealistically bad circumstances. If you want to start talking about having a "good" quality of life where you don't have to work full time while going to school or want to enjoy luxuries, you either need to go above the bare minimum or start asking others for money.

There's nothing wrong with buying toys on credit as long as they're willing to accept the consequences of building that debt and pay it back. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506686365.0" user="SpunkyMG" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They can afford it

&amp;gt;That means buying toys and fun on credit.

&amp;gt;There's nothing wrong with buying toys on credit as long as they're willing to accept the consequences of building that debt and pay it back. 

Having to use credit is in fact, not being able to afford it. Unless borrowing money that you don't have has changed the definition of "affording it".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506725216.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>I said they could afford college. They can't afford the lifestyle they want in college, thus the financing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27507284736.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Tax rate for minimum wage is 24.1% before factoring in state taxes. We can hem and haw about 6% if you want, or we can factor in state income taxes too, and use 30% as a model.

You want to source that?  Or use a tax calculator like [this](http://us.thetaxcalculator.net/) to find out you're wrong?  Not to mention someone at min wage would be elgible for public assistance like SNAP.  Not sure if students are elgible, but it's worth a try.

Not going to get into a dollar by dollar analysis of affording college, but fix your number for taxes and then maybe billy will be doing a little better.  Also, could you include Pell Grants in there?  Or is this some middle class kid getting screwed by his parents?
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
