<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38379291367.0" user="DhananjayAshok" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is this: consumers shape the market that corporations work with. If this year all Americans decided to cut down on electricity spending, never buy from environmentally harmful brands even if it is more expensive / lower quality/ takes longer etc then in 2 years the unsustainable companies disappear or change their practices. There are two reasons why this doesn't happen

1. Because push comes to shove consumers care about the end result and not what happens to the environment in between. The overwhelming majority of ppl do not care if Amazon pollutes and is unsustainable because it will give them cheap, quick delivery for many items. The few that do care are not enough to shift market incentives. This is clearly the consumers burden to change- companies are not unsustainable because they enjoy hurting the earth, it's because it optimizes cost and consumers reward them for this optimization.

2. Consumer preferences are to an extent shaped by corporations. But this again is within a consumers control. If they stop listening and allowing themeselves to fall for ads that tell them they need gas guzzling cars to truly be a man etc then it will lead to a market shift. 

This is not to say companies don't have any blame here. But think of it this way, if you replace all companies with sustainable ones then as time goes on they will be outcompeted by more efficient unsustainable companies. But if you replace all consumers with ones who reward sustainable companies then it will lead to sustainable companies outperforming the others.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
