<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="50" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38402204709.0" user="sajaxom" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with putting this on corporations is that they have to compete with other corporations. If a company decides to become sustainable and that raises their product costs by 50%, they are going to get beat in the market by the unsustainable companies. The only way to make broad change here is to manipulate the market itself, which is the realm of government. You can provide incentives/subsidies for sustainability, disincentives/fines for unsustainable practices, regulation/mandates for others, etc. Government is the only body powerful enough to change the rules of the market, and so long as unsustainable practices are cheaper than sustainable ones, that is the only way you can direct the change without killing the companies that lead the charge.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
