<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38377974078.0" user="Careless_Clue_6434" delta="False">
    <text>According to the EPA, the largest source of emissions (29%) in the US is transportation ([https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/sources-greenhouse-gas-emissions](https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/sources-greenhouse-gas-emissions)), and the majority of that's a result of individual decisions (to some extent it's also a result of cities being designed in a very car-oriented way, but the design decisions that lead to that problem are mostly a result of local policy, which is primarily influenced by local homeowners, not corporations).  Another 10% of emissions comes from agriculture, and this is heavily determined by consumption - a kilogram of beef produces about 200 times the carbon emissions as a kilogram of potatoes or nuts ([https://ourworldindata.org/environmental-impacts-of-food](https://ourworldindata.org/environmental-impacts-of-food)), and it's very difficult to imagine a change in meat production methods that would cover that gap (intuitively, an animal consumes a lot more calories than its meat provides, since it uses those calories on being alive and isn't 100% edible), so there's not really a regulatory solution that wouldn't take the form of a change in consumption patterns.

Industrially, the two main sources of emissions are from fuel (which I agree is a regulatory issue), and chemical reactions necessary to the manufacturing process (which really can't be changed without a corresponding change in consumption patterns).

Finally, residential emissions are hugely a result of individual consumption choices - one study estimates a factor of 15 difference in per capita emissions between neighborhoods in similar regions ([https://www.pnas.org/content/117/32/19122](https://www.pnas.org/content/117/32/19122#:~:text=Residential%20energy%20use%20accounts%20for,emissions%20in%20the%20United%20States.&amp;amp;text=However%2C%20grid%20decarbonization%20will%20be,and%20fuel%20oil); note that this paper gives a higher estimate of overall contribution from residential emissions; I'm unsure which is correct); additionally, this is another place where the main barrier to political reform is local homeowners, so even if a regulatory change is preferred that still requires a shift in individual attitudes and behaviors.

This isn't to say there's no role for regulation - after transportation, the next largest source of emissions is electricity use, and decarbonizing the grid is almost entirely about changing the supply to rely on clean sources rather than changing consumption.  Nonetheless, it does seem like a large share of the problem (very plausibly a majority, depending on which estimates you accept and how you slice up mixed obligations) is the result of individual consumption decisions, and it seems like the burden should correspondingly fall to a large extent on individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378198945.0" user="MansfromDaVinci" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; (to some extent it's also a result of cities being designed in a very car-oriented way, but the design decisions that lead to that problem are mostly a result of local policy, which is primarily influenced by local homeowners, not corporations).

In the states the car companies deliberately destroyed mass transit to force people to buy cars.  In the UK a Tory transport minister gutted the railways then got rich off motorway contracts for his company</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378373286.0" user="Careless_Clue_6434" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know the history of mass transit well enough to comment, but at least in the US that's not the primary issue.  A lot of the problem is a result of zoning laws - minimum lot sizes, single-family and low density development, mandatory parking spaces, and similar issues all contribute to a city layout in which most people live very far from their workplaces (the average American commutes 16 miles each way daily: [https://itstillruns.com/importance-safe-driving-5985472.html](https://itstillruns.com/importance-safe-driving-5985472.html)).  If people lived closer to their workplace, then even in the absence of functioning mass transit, you'd see a lot more walking and biking to work, which is a similar emissions save; likewise, high density makes mass transit more cost-effective because you get more ridership per mile of coverage (which is why a lot of big cities actually have fairly good public transit), and of course you'd also get direct savings from any drivers being on the road for a shorter period.

I assume car companies are pretty happy with this state of affairs, but the primary political force in maintaining it is homeowners, who are a lot more directly involved and impactful on the local-scale politics where most of this stuff is decided.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380252726.0" user="Books_and_Cleverness" delta="False">
    <text>There's some of that but if you think corporations are the ones forcing us into cars, go to a local zoning meeting and propose eliminating all parking minimums and replacing all street parking with bus and bike lanes.  See who objects--it ain't gonna be a consultant from Ford.  It's gonna be a local homeowner who wants to drive his car into town and doesn't want to pay for parking, doesn't want apartment buildings or mixed-use buildings developed nearby.

[Parking alone is a disaster for climate](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Akm7ik-H_7U).

I do want to reiterate that car companies obviously lobby to protect their interests but the primary reason transit is bad in the US is land-use and zoning.  LA has a *huge* metro system but it's functionally illegal to surround the stops with tall buildings and walkable neighborhoods.  Car companies have nothing to do with that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
