<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38377802091.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them.

Ultimately, what constitutes the burden of corporations is decided by consumers either by where they spend their money or how they come together to govern society. If consumers aren't either boycotting unsustainable practices or democratically involving themselves to enforce sustainability, then that is the reason sustainability isn't being achieved. 

A governing body could be created to do this, but the consumers would have to decide they wanted that. Consumers simply aren't willing to do what is necessary to bring about this change because it would cost them resources and likely require them to make peripheral political reforms to enable a governing body to be created. The nature of, at least the American, political systems is that one issue is often competing with many other issues. Changing that dynamic must come from the people. The people simply do not value sustainability over other political issues and the people are the only ones who can drive reforms.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
