<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38378071154.0" user="smww93" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, I don't think there needs to be any governing body ensuring corporations meet their targets. They are just that - targets/goals. There is no legally binding consequence for failure to meet them so there is no need to have a governing body to monitor it. If you have someone watching over you to make your target, you make less ambitious targets. I'm sure many of us have made ambitious goals around new year, which are nice to work towards but we do it without fear of consequence if we fail. If there was consequence, people wouldn't aim so high. 

As for the other part of the argument, there is a big incentive for change to be consumer driven and that biggest change is actually financial. There are plenty of articles you can find about start-ups wanting to be eco-friendly and do things like look for recycled cardboard for packaging, only to find that it's more expensive than new cardboard and therefore, on that sort of scale, it's quite a significant increase in expense - something that then has to be passed to a consumer. Consumers, being of the nature we are see the same thing at 2 different price points and usually go for the cheaper one. So overall, if consumers aren't in the mindset to pay a premium for sustainability if another company can undercut simply by being less sustainable, then actually you do need to work on consumer mentality of reduce, reuse and recycle. 

An easy example of this can be something as simply as energy bills. Most people will go for the cheapest provider offering what they need. There are companies out there who you pay a premium for who help invest in green energy but as I said - you pay more for it. So knowing that people are going to find the cheapest plan they can, you then have to work on the "insulate your home, keep the heating a bit lower, don't leave lights on etc." This is putting the onus on the consumer because sure, energy companies can suddenly start going green but it's going to put prices up and force people to look elsewhere. This same concept applies to nearly all businesses so you can't simply make it all about companies changing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
