<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38378595658.0" user="succachode" delta="False">
    <text>I’m a huge libertarian, so obviously I want no part of regulation or government intervention in how businesses operate, personally. You are presenting a huge problem with our capitalist economy, and i agree it needs to be fixed. My question to you is, why don’t you start a company aimed at either A) researching and touring company facilities and rating them on their efficiency so people can make an informed and conscious decision about who to spend their money with, since the onus is on them (this could be started through a simple blog, and could effect consumer spending and investments in companies) ; B) create a company that tours facilities and evaluates their energy efficiency and lets them know how to implement a better system with as little cost as possible. You could research what foreign companies are doing and let CEO’s who are only worried about advertising, product research, and distribution know how they can save their asses with affordable sustainable environmental practices. (I believe this will happen anyways, and soon experts on environmental issues auditing companies will be as common as health inspectors at restaurants). My thinking is why put the “onus” on anyone else, when you already see the problem, and could make some money solving the problem yourself. It will take a lot of work, but these could be extremely relevant business models in the near future in my opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
