<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38379512839.0" user="NewyBluey" delta="False">
    <text>One publication that significantly contributed to my philosophy of industrialisation and it's consequences, both good and bad was "The Waste Makers" by Vance Packard published 1959.  The theme was that production is driven by consumption and increased consumption was driven by the desire for the latest product. Replacing the last model with the new one encouraged the production of products with an expected short life cycle. 

The big drivers of increased consumption was, and still is, the advertising and fashion industries. 

If l could have an influence to alter one aspect of society it would involve incorporating a social responsibility and honesty in the advertising industry. I think the way advertising has evolved and is now conducted has more adverse influence on society and culture than any other endeavour.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
