<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38377747450.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38377904318.0" user="Fluffy_Owl4316" delta="False">
    <text>That's great and I totally agree! We should all do our part, I just wish our part made more of a difference than it does!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379106410.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Picards-Flute – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Picards-Flute&amp;amp;message=Picards-Flute%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/-/hmp4bga/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
