<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38378857576.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>It shouldn't be on Corporations, either, it should be on *behavior.*

Corporations only want what makes them money.  
Consumers only care about getting the best product/service for their money.

Currently, unless "environmental impact" is something that is a significant contributor to what makes something the "best product," in some customer's mind, that means that *nobody* cares about the problem.   Indeed, the race to the bottom for Airline fares (in exchange for decreased quality of service) proves that for most customers, the dominant term in "best product/service for the money" is "for the money."

And Corporations are going to do what Customers want.  If people were willing to pay more for more sustainable practices, they would, but by and large, they don't.  After all, if they cared about sustainability, [they'd bus or carpool rather than drive themselves, and take a coach or the train rather than fly,](https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-49349566) but we don't.

...except when the train is cheaper/more convenient than flying, or the bus/carpool is cheaper/more convenient than driving.

Want to cut down on Carbon Emissions?  Enact Pigouvian Fees on Carbon Emissions.  Make people *pay* for the environmental damage they do.  That's part of why Europe tends to have such high fuel taxes: it changes the calculus on what form of transportation is more efficient.

If I'm being generous, that's why I believe Mr. Biden's administration is lying about wanting to drive down the cost of fuel.  I'm guessing that he doesn't *actually* care about that, I'm guessing he's saying that to placate voters, while allowing the market to encourage them to adopt cleaner transportation habits.


If you want to get people to care about environmental sustainability, link that to their *pocketbook's* sustainability.  What will happen if we do that?

Corporations will use more sustainable processes, and produce more sustainable goods/services, because that will improve their profits (relative to less sustainable options).
Consumers, in turn, will buy those goods/services not just because they're more sustainable, but because they are easier for their pocketbooks to sustain purchasing them.

Thus, it would move us from a vicious cycle (people buy polluting trucks because corporations offer them [at economies of scale prices], because people buy them [because of the economies of scale prices]), into a virtuous one (people buying clean vehicles like Teslas and Leafs, because Tesla and Nissan make them [cheap enough to make financial sense], because people buy them [because they make financial sense])</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380761455.0" user="adelie42" delta="False">
    <text>It is worth noting that in the whole "only wants to make money" thing is 100% a reflection of the way certain types of corporations raise money. Specifically, if you want to "sell stock" in the traditional sense, you are saying, "if you give me money now, i will do my best to make you lots of money in the future, but if I lose it all, that's your fault".

This premise creates "fiduciary responsibility". You are legally obligated to not just throw the money away on whatever you want. It must be in alignment with some agreement.

Someone invents something or comes up with an idea. They get as much money for the idea as people how've in it instead of it being 100% on the inventor to borrow money that they then have to pay back no matter what.

Further, within this system we may like to imagine sole guy smoking a cigar on a yacht buying stocks like lottery tickets. That certainly exists, but a LOT of the money in the stock market is public and private pensions of wage laborers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38386481146.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>If by "certain types of corporations" you mean "literally every corporation with stockholders, either private or public," which in turn translates to "approximately every corporation in existence, because closely held companies are rare as hens teeth"

So, yes, you're correct, that my hyperbole only applies to *almost* every corporation in existence.

...but it *does* apply to *almost every corporation in existence*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38387416484.0" user="adelie42" delta="False">
    <text>My issue with skipping over this detail is the why and the reason "corporations are people" is lost by so many when the idea corporations are people is literally nothing more or less plus an idea.

The solution to the problem you presume is to innovate on the way ideas get funding that are in alignment with basic contract law. Lots of people want to make the world a better place through innovative ideas, other people want a safe place to put money for retirement presumably supporting good business ideas.

It seems far too often people claim that those groups are at odds with each other, and I find that completely absurd, seemingly requiring a complete ignorance of what fiduciary responsibility is and the role it plays 8n getting money from potential investors to entrepreneurs that want to grow fast and don't want to hold all the risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38388555376.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, just take the logic of *Citizens United* to its logical conclusion:

* *CU* found that Corporations were (*made up of*) people, so abridging the rights of people working in concert in the form of a corporation *is* abridging the rights of the constituent people
* In other words, Corporate action is *actually* the action of *individual persons*
* ...but if corporate action is the action of individual people, then that means that *individual persons* can be held responsible for *corporate malfeasance*

...which means that when a *corporation* engages in criminal action, the *individual persons* who engaged in those actions, and those who instructed them to do so, can, and *should,*  be *individually* be held liable for those actions.

Do that, and no need to come up with alternate funding, just make the people who make the decisions (stock holders, for example), liable for actions they engage in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38388852364.0" user="adelie42" delta="False">
    <text>Citizens United was stupid, and the legislature was in the wrong for coming up with a bad solution that wasn't the court's job to fix. It was right for the court to kick it back to the legislatire.

I'm with you about malfeasance, but that had nothing to do with that case.

The prescedence was Santa Clara County vs. Southern Pacific Railroad where Santa Clara was rightfully laughed out of court.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38392796433.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>*Citizens United* was *not* stupid, nor was it stupidly ruled.

A corporation, fundamentally, is nothing more than a group of people who band together for some cause or another.  

If we were to say that *individual* rights didn't apply to *groups* of people *because* they were groups, then we'd run into problems *very * quickly.

Freedom of religion?  You can practice any religion you want, but that's an *individual* right, so you can't *get together* to practice religion...

Preposterous, right?    But that's the precedent that would have been set were *CU* ruled the other way...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38393231261.0" user="adelie42" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I wasn't clear. I absolutely agree with the ruling. I thought the misinformation driven mania against the ruling was stupid and the law that enabled the lawsuit in the first case was low effort and short sighted.

It is one of the few cases where I actually read the argument transcript to basically fact check what people were saying was being said. My take away was that the government was making the case that there was no limit to censorship if they invoked The Greater Good™. Thankfully the court did not agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38393716642.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, my apologies.  As I'm sure you're painfully aware, most people who talk about *CU* are woefully misinformed as to what it was *actually* about, so I assumed the ambiguity fell into that category.

It really is sad how few people realized that the government's argument was that they should be allowed to ban books if they deemed it beneficial to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38383274897.0" user="simgaleed" delta="False">
    <text>I see where you're coming from, but I don't think this is possible until we fix our greater socioeconomic problems. As an example: the very green/progressive state of Vermont is working towards the goal of reducing it's climate footprint, and this includes removing oil heat from use in the next 10-15 years or so. The problem is that the average Vermonter can barely afford to heat their house to begin with, let alone pay tens of thousands of dollars to switch to something "greener". Same logic applies to electric vehicles or hybrids. 

Yes, we can fine people for not being green enough, and this will probably cause change from those with the money to do so. But you are leaving behind those who can't, which makes up a significant portion of the population. 

Also re: trains: I barely get a few weeks of paid time off per year. Spending 3-4 days one-way to ride a train across country to see family is always going to loose to spending a single day to fly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38386382645.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I don't think this is possible until we fix our greater socioeconomic problems

Oh, I'm right there with you.

* Zoning, for example, allegedly costs the average American something like $3.6k a year.
* Throwing people in jail costs an average of [$33k/year](https://www.vera.org/publications/price-of-prisons-2015-state-spending-trends/price-of-prisons-2015-state-spending-trends/price-of-prisons-2015-state-spending-trends-prison-spending), so if we were to limit that to murderers, rapists, and other people who are active threats to the populace, rather than (e.g.) non-violent drug "crimes."  At 698/100k people incarcerated, and 1/5 of them being non-violent drug offenders, sure, that's only about $46-$47 per taxpayer per year, but... for the poor? That could be huge.

&amp;gt; The problem is that the average Vermonter can barely afford to heat their house to begin with, let alone pay tens of thousands of dollars to switch to something "greener".

Putting aside the fact that using heat to generate electricity to generate heat is less efficient than just using it to generate heat...

One thing I'd *really* like to see is a program where homes could be retrofitted to be more energy efficient, free to the user with the work paid for by a government/utility company, paid back by the energy savings.  Basically, my idea would work as follows:

* Owner requests energy efficiency audit
* The auditor makes suggestions on how to save energy (replace windows/insulation with more efficient versions, more energy efficient heating/ac, air sealing the property, etc)
* If the owner agrees, the work is done with *no* upfront cost to the owner, because the gov't/utility company would pay the upfront costs, as a (inflation-rate) loan
* The improved efficiency would lower costs to heat/cool the house, regardless of the energy source used.
* The loan would be paid back out of the savings.  Save $10/month on your average utility bill?  The utility company deducts an extra $10/month from your account to pay down the loan.

 
Because you're right, it *is* a "spend $10k today to save $11k over 10 years" problem.  So *address that problem.*   The hypothetical program above would turn that problem into a "Spend nothing today to save $500 in 10 years."  That's like free money, paid to you for being *more comfortable.* 

Who *wouldn't* go for that?

Like I said, it's all about making the behavior we want *less expensive* than behavior we don't want.

Make The Market work for us.

&amp;gt; Also re: trains: I barely get a few weeks of paid time off per year. Spending 3-4 days one-way to ride a train across country to see family is always going to loose to spending a single day to fly.

I'll spot you the Trains/Coaches vs Planes thing, because time is the *only* resource you can never get back.

...but what about carpooling, or taking mass transit, rather than single occupant cars?

All in all, you're proving my point: that we *could* choose to be greener, but we *choose* not to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38388592005.0" user="simgaleed" delta="False">
    <text>No disagreement in terms of your solutions, nor the general sentiment that we could be greener if we choose to be. I was mostly pushing back from what I perceived your core idea was: if you make non-green things too expensive for the consumer, they will be forced into more sustainable behavior, and industry will follow suit. The logical continuation of that would be that the most direct way of raising prices for the consumer without directly attacking companies is through taxes (which your OP suggests). My argument is that doing so without first fixing economic issues would lead to much greater economic disparity, and a general resentment towards green policies. I already know many working class folks who love the environment but hate "green policies" because they view them as "out of touch feel-good measures that make life harder for those of us who actually work for a living"

And I'd love to overhaul our cities/country to support efficient public transit systems. Tricky part would be doing so without greatly impacting private property. It'd be one thing to just say "we are building a new rail line" and another to then say "and we will need to domalish X number of homes/businesses". Is it impossible? Not in the slightest. But not likely to see the political will for it + the work be completed in the next 10-30 years in most places. 

Carpooling is, IMO, great when possible. But, and this is totally antidotal, I've never been in a position where it would work. Even living in a major city, I don't live anywhere near my coworkers commutes. Besides, I've seen other drivers. I'd much rather drive myself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38393699362.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; through taxes (which your OP suggests

*Fees.*  Or, perhaps more accurately, *fines.*

Pigouvian "taxes" are  nothing more than codified fines for certain externality-creating behaviors.  They are meaningfully different from what people canonically think of as taxes (which are not, generally, *intended* to disincentivize behavior)

&amp;gt; And I'd love to overhaul our cities/country to support efficient public transit systems

Step 1: Eliminate (most) zoning laws.

In order to make transit worthwhile, you need to have enough people trying to travel along the same route.  If the distance between their points of origin or destination and the route itself are too large (see: suburbs, where people will well over a mile from the nearest major thoroughfare),  people will choose a X minute drive to an X minute transit ride plus Y minute walk (subject to weather)

For example, in my previous job, in order to take transit from my home to my work, it would have been about 3 hours (most of it walking 

&amp;gt; "we are building a new rail line"

Don't build a new rail line, then.

Buses require less infrastructure (and thus are *much* cheaper to install), and have comparable improvements of environmental impact.

Rail is only really an advantage if you have *lots* of people who want to travel the same place at the same time, and even then it has significant limitations.

&amp;gt; antidotal

Recognizing that that might be an autocorrect: 

You mean Anecdotal.  If it were antidotal, it would solve the issue.



&amp;gt; Even living in a major city, I don't live anywhere near my coworkers commutes

I, likewise, don't have enough people going from my neighborhood to my work, especially not at the hours I wish to travel. 

...but that's part of the short sightedness of the populace in general, and people running transit/carpool programs in specific: people tend to be too narrow minded (in the literal sense) as to what "carpooling" means.

The  thing is that I understand it to be well established that a "Hub &amp;amp; Spokes" model of transit is far superior to the "direct route" model.

To that end, we should stop thinking of "carpools" as *just* an "End-to-end" solution, and instead think of them as the *spokes* solution.

Imagine a carpool paradigm where you had *two different* carpools each way.  The first would be a carpool of your *neighbors,* to some sort of transit center.  Once there, you and your neighbors each take your own various transit options (local bus, commuter bus, long haul coach, train, light rail, whatever) to your second carpool, one of your coworkers (or at least people working at locations close together), which would take you to your work.

Heck, depending on how things worked, you *could* have Spoke-to-Spoke commute, where your "transit option" to your second carpool was "walk from one vehicle to the other."

&amp;gt; Besides, I've seen other drivers. I'd much rather drive myself.

Again, with respect, this is you focusing too narrowly.   Let's say you're right, let's say you *are* one of the better drivers out there.  With carpools, you could arrange it so that the *best* driver was the one driving.  That would mean that if *you* drove the carpool, you would be getting *three* drivers who were worse than you out from behind the wheel.

And that doesn't even bring up how much more efficient traffic would flow if you there were fewer cars on the road, giving bad drivers who were still driving fewer opportunities to cause accidents.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
