<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38377746962.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Consumers hold all of the power, so ultimately it will always fall on them. They chose which companies to buy from, which politicians to elect and what stuff to consume. Corporations can't make them change any of that. Walmart could suddenly have nothing but the best intentions for the climate, but if the consumers aren't on board, they will just lose market share to their competitors and achieve nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38377799027.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Corporations can't make them change any of that

In which world do you live in? Advertising, legislation and propaganda exist.

&amp;gt;but if the consumers aren't on board, they will just lose market share to their competitors and achieve nothing.

Not if it is illegal for the competitors to go below a certain bar. And legislation like that is prevented by the propaganda about individual responsibility.

At the lower end, consumers hold no power either. Eat or die. So they go for the lowest cost that is available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38377900324.0" user="Fluffy_Owl4316" delta="False">
    <text>This is a deeper conversation of what I was getting at, so thank you! In a sense, it could be on consumers to drive the conversation by demanding the change, but if the world is truly serious about sustainability, shouldn't legislation be passed to hold corporations responsible for their actions and keep them accountable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38377970436.0" user="ttinchung111" delta="False">
    <text>Then isn't this a shift from your initial view? Then the onus is on the government to pass legislation (which is representative of the people, or consumers), in order to help push for sustainability, not the responsibility of corporations?.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38377987384.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In which world do you live in? Advertising, legislation and propaganda exist.

Advertising can't make you buy anything, and legislation is determined by the voters. France had Paris shut down by riots for weeks over a small increase in gas prices. Good luck 'advertising' your way out of that.

Corporations are selfish, shortsighted and don't care about the environment because so  their customers are too, and they reward that behavior.

&amp;gt;Not if it is illegal for the competitors to go below a certain bar. And legislation like that is prevented by the propaganda about individual responsibility.

It's never going to be illegal if the voters don't already want it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38392504398.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Advertising can't make you buy anything, and legislation is determined by the voters. 

Of course it can, and propaganda and advertising determine what people vote for. That is what advertising and propaganda *are*, putting thoughts into people's heads.

It's not perfect of course, but statistically, it works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380204449.0" user="Books_and_Cleverness" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;consumers hold no power either. Eat or die. So they go for the lowest cost that is available.

This is objectively not true, if it were then everyone would be vegetarians, eating rice and beans and apples and carrots and celery every day.

But people like eating meat.  I certainly do, even though I am increasingly worried about the very large emissions (and animal suffering) involved in that process.  Whose fault is it that people eat beef?  Corporations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38382446985.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In which world do you live in? Advertising, legislation and propaganda exist.

Consumers also are voters, and with the social media they can do propaganda themselves and name and shame corporations. 

&amp;gt;Not if it is illegal for the competitors to go below a certain bar. And legislation like that is prevented by the propaganda about individual responsibility.

On the contrary, legislation like that is prevented by people thinking they have no responsibility whatsoever, their consumption patterns are not a problem, and they are entitled to cheap meat, gasoline, and endless supplies of cheap plastic crap. So they'll resist voting for any legislation that might make it harder to get those things, as long as they think they are doing nothing wrong, only corporations are, and somehow everything can be changed at the factory without any impact on their own lifestyle and the price of goods.

&amp;gt;At the lower end, consumers hold no power either. Eat or die. So they go for the lowest cost that is available.

Some people exist like that, but those aren't the drivers in consumption. The very large majority have quite some slack in their lifestyle choices... and all of them have votes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38383393592.0" user="mtanti" delta="False">
    <text>And why would there be legislation if voters are against it because they don't want to pay higher prices and be inconvenienced? You need the consumers to be on board first, which can happen through advertising, but it has to happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38392521718.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, and advertising and propaganda is why people are not on board.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38383766202.0" user="Readvoter" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Advertising, legislation and propaganda exist

Corporations don’t vote, unlike individuals. Advertisement and back room pressure don’t even come close to the political power voters have if they vote for climate regulations. But they don’t. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Not if it is illegal for the competitors to go below a certain bar. And legislation like that is prevented by the propaganda about individual responsibility.

Individual responsibility and regulation aren’t mutually exclusive. 

A single firm, even as big as walmart, could not single handedly get a carbon tax passed in the US. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; At the lower end, consumers hold no power either. Eat or die. So they go for the lowest cost that is available

Generally emissions intensive foods like beef or lamb are also some of the most expensive. This argument has some validity in terms of car ownership vs public transit, but individual consumers can make choices to reduce their emissions in the areas where they are able to. 

Companies can’t do that. If they stop selling beef, for example, shoppers will just go to other supermarkets and they’ll lose their market share.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38392534556.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Corporations don’t vote, unlike individuals.

Sure, but corporations decide what individuals vote for, through advertising and propaganda. 

&amp;gt;But they don’t.

Exactly

&amp;gt;A single firm, even as big as walmart, could not single handedly get a carbon tax passed in the US. 

Fox news could. A couple others too. the go the opposite way though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378358433.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379467656.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MountNevermind – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20MountNevermind&amp;amp;message=MountNevermind%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/-/hmphew1/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378671488.0" user="carneylansford" delta="False">
    <text>1. Reduce
2. Reuse
3. Recycle

In that order.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379102681.0" user="rhb4n8" delta="False">
    <text>That's bullshit. All the best consumer intentions in the world can't make government regulators shut down the Clariton coke works. As a Pittsburgher I get really pissed about this because everything any individual does is trivial compared to these massive industrial polluters. I have to get my hybrid emissions tested every year while Clariton can have a fire damaging their pollution controls and then operate without pollution controls for over a fucking year easily being one of the worst polluters in America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379902598.0" user="Grizelda179" delta="False">
    <text>Consumers hold all the power, really? You must have forgotten that the US is basically ruled by corporations. Around half the legislative decisions are impacted by corporations and favor corporations (mostly from donations of course). 
You missed out on the part where corporations actively lobby to prevent the government listening to the people and not legislate on environmental issues (you might have heard of thr propaganda of the cigarette or the oil industry). 
It is extremely hard for people to just band around and say, hey, were boycotting amazon. It is unrealistic to unite billions of people for something like this. Thus your suggestion just doesnt work. Also, Some people dont have a choice but to buy the cheapest product. 

The voice of the people comes when they elect candidates or parties that promised to legislate on environment and then fail to do so for a number of reasons, one of them being corporations influence. The burden is thus on the corporations, who exploit the system, blackmail entire countries to allow them to continue their unsustainable practices, not the other way around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380034164.0" user="cortesoft" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is one of collective action... as an individual, my choices are to buy from a company that does bad things, and get the individual benefits but still have the company so bad things... or buy from the better company, pay more, and STILL have the bad company doing the bad things. My individual choice does not have an effect on whether the bad company keeps doing bad things or not; my only choice is whether I at least get the benefits of the bad company.

Basically, it means as an individual the rational choice is to shop at the bad company. I can hope that everyone else will choose to shop at the good company, and that the bad company goes out of business, but again, my individual choice won't change the business prospects of either company. I'd be willing to sacrifice the benefits of shopping at the bad company if it meant the bad company went out of business, but why would I give up the benefits if the bad company is going to stay in in business anyway?

If you expect consumer behavior to solve things like greenhouse gas emissions, you are expecting a majority of people to behave irrationally. The only way to curb business practices we don't like is to use laws and regulations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380556197.0" user="droxius" delta="False">
    <text>It falls on consumers to vote appropriately and pressure governments and corporations to do the right thing. The cultural change that is essential to get this to happen has to come from regular people.

But pretending that suburban families failing to recycle their cans is a major contributor to the ecological downfall of our planet is ridiculous.

Basically corporations have to actually make the changes, but they won't unless forced. But conservatives (ironically) oppose conservation, and liberals are all talk when it comes to climate change.

We could save our planet if we wanted to, but WE don't want to. Too many of are perfectly happy letting oligarchs run things into the ground, so that's what they're going to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38381048535.0" user="mmmfritz" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Antz is a great movie with a powerful message. We could go a long way if everyone did what they can first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38383361009.0" user="ModdingCrash" delta="False">
    <text>The more covert monopolies there are (and they are growing in size and numbers) the less of a choice we truly have. That's why the tsrl "illusion of choice" or "illusion of variety" comes from. We are not free to chose the choices that are presented to us, we are "free" to pick from those. When huge conglomerates have dozens of apprantly different product lines, and present them to you, you might think you are choosing, but the money goes to the same people at the end.

This is one of the problemas regarding sustainability and corporations, such as Nestlé.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38384062513.0" user="GlitterFanboy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Consumers hold all of the power

That's patently false. Through various schemes, corporations have been able to advertise, popularize and normalize tobacco smoking out of nowhere. They invented the concept of "jaywalking" and created a massive propaganda campaign to blame pedestrians for crossing the road (completely normal stuff 120 years ago). They have the money to influence mass media, and therefore to influence people. They have the money to lobby politicians and corrupt them. They have the power to create oligopolies and monopolies and therefore disrupt the supply and demand. Fuck, in some countries they hire militias to impose their will by force. 

Consumers absolutely don't have the power.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
