<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38379204819.0" user="2penises_in_a_pod" delta="False">
    <text>Corporations don’t do things not dictated by consumers. When you buy a diesel truck, is that the companies burden or yours? Who’s pollution is that attributable to? The answer is both. 

By saying “focus on the corporations” what you’re saying is make items and practices illegal. Bc as long as there is demand for something companies will do it. 

So they COULD go after corporations and say “hey it’s illegal to make these trucks now”. What happens then is that consumers are forced to buy more expensive electric trucks, and it disproportionately hurts the poor and small business owners and helps the rich and the mega corps. I don’t think that’s fair. Is an environmental goal worth it if another 10% of our population slides into poverty? And no, that number is not an exaggeration. 

At the end of the day, government CANT wipe items off the face of the earth. Less environmental, more cost effective items will just be in unregulated black markets which are more dangerous for everyone, just like drugs. 

Simply case of supply side vs demand side restriction. Supply side has never and will never work so long as people are mostly free. Demand side restriction (such as encouraging ppl to smoke less) is proven effective and allows for a freer populace.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
