<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38378020573.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="False">
    <text>The onus of sustainability rests with the consumer. 

If the consumer isn’t on board and the government makes a change, the consumer elects a new government. The consumer carries the power, they have to be convinced.

And beyond that this has always felt lazy to me. I had a liberal friend over for dinner who criticized me for driving a Mustang, and talked of the need for EVs and mote homes with solar cells.

I asked what he drove, and it wasn’t an EV. Why? To expensive, and better tech was coming soon. Basked if he had solar panels on his roof and he said no. Why? Too expensive and better tech was coming soon. I mentioned a Texas company that would put the panels on your roof without cost. You didn’t get to sell power, but you would get a discount and you would be helping. Also a no, he didn’t want the holes in his roof.

This from a guy who griefed me for driving a sports car with a V6 that gets 31 mpg on the freeway. His accord? It got 36 mpg on the highway.

He didn’t want to do it himself, he wanted everyone else to either feel the discomfort first, or at least all at the same time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378632773.0" user="Fluffy_Owl4316" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think individual consumers (even collectively), have the influence to make an impact on the climate if corporations are still producing the same products at the same rate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378716908.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="False">
    <text>They do. Do you imagine companies keep producing products that aren’t selling?

If people stop buy a product, that product is no longer produced.

Look at the Trabant, the car most common in East German before the wall fell. It was a total piece of crap.

There was a ten to thirteen year wait, and then there was a legitimately terrible car at the end of the wait.

Trabant shut down in 1991. Why? The people now had options from Western Europe which were better in all areas, and stopped buying the Trabant.

And you see this in the USA where large companies go away because the consumer has chosen something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378787295.0" user="Moikanyoloko" delta="False">
    <text>Not the guy, but my 50 cents.

Yes. If consumers collectively consume in a sustainable manner then corporations simply won't produce in a unsustainable manner.

What use is there in producing a gas-powered car if everyone wants an electric car and won't buy the gas one?

Corporations won't produce the same product at the same rate if consumers don't consume the same products at the same rate, because if there's no demand, there's no profit, it's simply capitalism.

Of course, the exception to this rule are monopolies, because then consumers do not have a choice, but even then we have very few true carbon producing monopolies, and in these cases its the government's duty to regulate and minimize pollution.

Corporations ultimately are not active actors in the fight against climate change because in our capitalist economy they are entities whose main goal is their own profit, the only way to change their processes is making it unprofitable to be unsustainable, be it through consumer action or government regulation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38382149577.0" user="FierceDeity_" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like this mostly works in theory only, because I think that the "hivemind" is a dumbass and won't collectively decide for a more expensive but less... climate-damaging solution. 

Also a lot of time the initiative is up to the corporations and companies because when there's no better product we, the consumers, can try, we can't steer towards it. So many things are very theoretical and can't ever become a thing unless attempted. 

&amp;gt; Corporations ultimately are not active actors in the fight against climate change because in our capitalist economy they are entities whose main goal is their own profit

I think that this point is good, but also frustrating: Corporations could be active actors, if they were inclined to look at profits in 10, 20, 50 years. If their whole base of production breaks away due to climate change in whatever many ways, changing to green NOW is probably better for the company in the very long term. 

But company shareholders and such are damn short sighted it seems and as such keep the company on course of producing cheaper for more profits right now. Governments are attempting to steer against this with things like CO2 taxes and CO2 budgets that companies which are greener can "sell" to other companies... But often they're very flawed and seem to have been built with the lobby so their companies won't be affected as much.

There have been calculations (that I have not handy right now) that going "green" is going to be much cheaper in the long run than staying on course.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379312792.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>What world do you live in where companies make products that people aren't buying? This is basic supply and demand stuff. If the demand shrinks so does the supply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38382534700.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you think individual consumers (even collectively), have the influence to make an impact on the climate if corporations are still producing the same products at the same rate?

If nobody buys their products, those corporations are going bankrupt. If less people buy their products, they'll produce less products.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38384478437.0" user="MayanApocalapse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If the consumer isn’t on board and the government makes a change, the consumer elects a new government.

This seems like an incredibly idealistic view of how Capitalism and Democracy intersect. It seems to ignore the large influence that money and lobbyists have over elections, or suggest that consumers aren't swamped in a deluge of misinformation.

The onus is on those with the most capability of affecting change. In a well functioning democracy, you might hope that would be the average citizen, but in our world that means the people with the most money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38385104821.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t mean the people with the most money. The people with the most money don’t keep it without the consent of the consumer.

Which is why the list of the wealthiest people changes every year.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
