<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38380496697.0" user="MeetInPotatoes" delta="False">
    <text>My rebuttal is mostly going to focus on the "instead" part. The number thrown around was that there are 100 companies who together account for 71% of global pollution. With numbers like that, there's really no arguing that it's not chiefly their responsibility except for the fact that we the people are usually the end user of the products corporations make. A lot of us work for corporations too. We aren't making that pollution ourselves but it is done on our behalf in other words, but I'm not neglecting to mention that skimping on money they could be spending on being more green however is due to greed and irresponsibility as you say. I don't think there's any rational argument then with "excessively placed on consumers" when at most we must account for 1/4. 

"Instead" though and arguing that it should be placed on them has some issues. I think "it's all of our responsibility and corps need to do their fair share."  It's a stronger argument, more likely to open minds than "it's all THEIR fault." which though oversimplified, is what shifting the entire burden boils down to. I think that only people doing their fair share though really have the right to raise hell at corporations, so not only is it a better argument but it comes with the credibility of practicing what you preach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38381855022.0" user="jamvanderloeff" delta="False">
    <text>That number thrown around counting only oil/gas/coal companies, and including the emissions of all of their customers downstream, so it's more like saying 71% of the fossil fuel extractors are the top 100 fossil fuel extractors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38384989339.0" user="MeetInPotatoes" delta="False">
    <text>Either way, we the people are usually the end users of corporate products and the workers, so it just falls on everyone to be greener. I suck at it, not gonna lie, not coming at anyone with my compost heap sustainability garden of vegan magic here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
