<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38380097455.0" user="sessamekesh" delta="False">
    <text>**TL;DR - I think you're partially right, but enough of the onus falls on the consumer to make it worth talking about.**

I think you're completely right for some *very* important parts of climate change - right now in the USA, there's a lack of limits, regulation, taxes, fees, incentives, etc. that shields producers ("corporations") from the environmental costs of their actions. For example: burning a gallon of gasoline has a toll of $0.46 in CO2 emissions \[1\], but nobody pays that toll right now (other than *maybe* fuel taxes). This trickles down to perverse cost incentives to the consumer - i.e., your *cheapest* or *most available* option is rarely the *environmentally responsible* action.

**You're** ***partially*** **right because there's important levers at the climate change machine that only governments and corporations have access to. Transportation, logistics, and energy especially come to mind - you have no say in the bad decisions that have been made.**

But, there *are* things that you have more direct control over. At the end of the day, the corporations that are producing all this pollution are doing it to address consumer demand for goods and services - e.g. the oil companies aren't burning gas because they like how it smells, they're selling gasoline to make vehicles move. Corporations and consumers don't exist in a vacuum, they very much respond to the behaviors of the other. When it comes to regulation, corporations *absolutely* have more say, but in many cases you, the consumer, are the one "voting" with your dollar on which corporations and what operational activities to support.

I'd say a few much better examples of things where consumers have power might be:

* Speaking of gasoline, drive less. Carpool. Ride your bike to work. When it's finally time to put your old car out of its misery, consider an EV (preferably used, but new is also good). Average driving activity accounts for \~4.6 tonnes \[1\] of emissions every year, which costs \~$230 to reverse - that ain't a corporation's doing, that's an "average" American driver's fault.
* Food consumption - this is *more impactful* than your driving emissions, and something that you have complete control over *today*! \[2\] Avoiding food waste and reducing high-impact foods (e.g. beef) from your diet is something that you can and should do *today*. McDonalds sure has some blame for making their burgers look so delicious on TV, but *you're* the one who bought the burger despite knowing it's not good for the environment.
* Buying used, extending lifetime of items (furniture, clothing, electronics, etc). This is less impactful, but using an approximation that \~30 items of clothing contributes 1 tonne of emissions \[3\] still means that *your* behavior has an impact. If you can thrift half of your wardrobe this year, that's still saving $20 or so in emissions vs. buying new clothes - again, all you - alternatively, try buying clothing from brands who focus on sustainability (which leads me to...)
* Selecting where you buy goods from is huge! Are you going to buy from the cheap mass retailer who's known for huge emissions, or from the newer local business who's focusing on operating sustainably? You'll probably have to pay more for the sustainable option because of the perverse incentives, so I hate to call this your responsibility, but you still have room to make impact there. At the end of the day, even if the incentives *were* properly aligned, it would still probably end up either on your checkbook as the consumer, or your tax bill as the tax payer.

**There's still** ***many*** **choices that you the consumer make that impact global emissions at a small scale. Even if by some miracle corporations and governments get their shit together by this weekend to do their part,** ***you'll*** **still have to shoulder a lot of the burden as well, and you can get started on that** ***today***.

*EDIT: Formatting*

\[1\] Optimistically assuming 1 gallon of gas produces 18.74 lbs CO2, and that one imperial ton of CO2 costs $50 to mitigate.  
\[2\] This assumes you're an "average American" with a (excuse the outdated term) carbon footprint of \~20 tonnes, and food consumption being \~5 tonnes of that. Driving 11,500 miles on a 22mpg car produces 4.6 tonnes. Both estimates are pessimistic but realistic AFAICT ([source](https://www.inspirecleanenergy.com/blog/clean-energy-101/average-american-carbon-footprint)). So sorry for mixing imperial and metric units, I am an American after all.  
\[3\] [source](https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2019/09/23/costo-moda-medio-ambiente)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
