<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38378550655.0" user="UnfinishedThings" delta="False">
    <text>We have a congestion zone charge in London where drivers of the more polluting vehicles pay a fee if they enter it. My wifes suggestion was that rather than making the drivers pay, make the manufacturers pay the fine. Encourages them to make cleaner cars. If people are driving their older models it encourages them to offer better trade in deals etc. 
If it weren't for the fact that theyd just refuse to pay or would just pass the additional costs on then I think its a great idea</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38378669434.0" user="Fluffy_Owl4316" delta="False">
    <text>This is a great idea, I love this. This could extend to gas taxes to push more electric cars as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
