<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38380246270.0" user="SCN_Attack" delta="False">
    <text>In addition to the general concept of “voting with your wallet” that others are making, a point that I would make is more systemic.

We have to remember that corporations are, at the end of the day, made up of people. They cannot exist with people to work for them and run them. Because of this, we need individual people working within the corporation to want to make change. If an individual is more likely to make sustainable choices at homeC they are probably more likely to take that mindset into the workplace. 

In addition to “voting with our wallet,” we need to, at a more systemic level, get a larger sum of people work to be sustainable, because individuals who are sustainable make corporations that are sustainable. 

An analogy could be that people are like atoms. Corporations are objects, made up of atoms. If an object is mostly gold atoms, we say it is good. Likewise, if a corporation is made of people that are sustainable, it’s pretty likely that the corporation as a whole will try to be sustainable. 

Essentially what I mean is, we need an entire paradigm shift towards sustainability, and so the onus is on everybody, because everybody has to be involved in it, if that makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
