<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513557216.0" user="rodw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge

Could this be like saying "I don't like Shakespeare because he uses too many cliches"?

That is, is it possible that these messages are common knowledge *because* of the popularity of Christianity and the new testament?   

&amp;gt; all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

Are you sure of that? I'm no biblical or ethics scholar, but it sure seems like Jesus' story involves a lot of railing against the conventional Jewish theology/ethics of the time--welcoming "unclean" people of various stripes (prostitutes, lepers, gentiles, foreigners) for example. A lot of the gospels seem to be about Jesus upsetting one contemporary religious authority or another. His views and/or influence were controversial enough to get him killed, after all.

&amp;gt; Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc.

Setting aside the question of divinity, I think you've got a simplistic view Jesus' message.  Popular culture and conventional wisdom really don't do it justice. Like Gandhi said: "I like your Christ. I do not like your Christians. They are so unlike your Christ." Jesus advocated a much more radical form of ~~tolerance~~ acceptance, charity, economic justice, pacifism, etc. than you or conventional wisdom give him credit for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513831323.0" user="CantPenTheSnowden" delta="False">
    <text>Acceptance?
Matthew 12:30 if your not for Christ then you are against christ.
Sounds alot like Anakin Skywalker in the third star wars movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513835149.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Matthew 12:30 if your not for Christ then you are against christ.

But all can be for Christ. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
