<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513415180.0" user="klw" delta="False">
    <text>You know, I didn't really get it, either. I've always been an atheist, for as long as I can remember. When I was a kid I remember sobbing over Aslan's sacrifice in **The Lion, the Witch, and the Wardrobe** and agonizing over the loss until his resurrection, which I found very comforting. I had no idea that I was reading a Jesus allegory; I mean, I was six or seven years old. Fast-forward a few years and I came to an understanding about the nature of the allegory and I could see how my emotional reaction over a fictional character could be related to the feelings people have for Christ. I don't feel those feelings myself, but my experience reading C.S. Lewis helped me understand people's affection for him.

&amp;gt; I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love?

Oh, come now, we all know that organized religion and the scholarship generated by it is separate from the actual words attributed to Christ. The Bible can be used to justify all sorts of bullshit, but I can't find much to criticize about anything attributed to Christ. There are thousands or millions of so-called "true believers" who behave in an objectively un-Christlike fashion. That has nothing to say about Christ and everything to say about the so-called believer. This isn't unique to Christianity by any means. There are violent Buddhists, for example. The Japanese League of Blood assassination plot was led by a Buddhist.

&amp;gt;I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom

I think you're answering your own CMV here. His martyrdom and subsequent worship *is* the feature that makes him unique. It doesn't matter if thousands of sages were doing unto others if *his* message was the one that penetrated and spread, either as a result of his self-sacrifice or just via some sort of ancient zeitgeist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
