<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513918767.0" user="NAOorNever" delta="False">
    <text>I am also not religious, but Jesus does have to be viewed in the context of the time. Yes those messages are common now, but that sort of philosophy was extremely novel in Western culture at the time. If you read writing at and before that era of history, most cultures saw the world as having a natural hierarchy.

For Greeks, there were the Greeks and the Barbarian tribes. For the Romans, there was a similar dichotomy. This was a time of imperialism and slavery, where violence was common and there really weren't any philosophies focused around the idea of equitable moral good.

The clearest example is the Scala Naturae, basically Natural Heriarchy, that Plato and Aristotle talked about
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_chain_of_being#Humanity

When they wrote about this idea, laid down their beliefs on what constituted moral action. For instance, if you capture other Greeks in war they can be made slaves, but are of an intrinsically higher moral status than say Barbarian slaves. Greek slaves were still Greek, but Barbarian slaves were on the level of livestock.

I don't know as much about other cultures, but this seemed to be a prevalent viewpoint around the time of Jesus. So, for a philosopher (whether or not you believe him to be the son of god) to come out and say that everyone of every birth deserved equal moral action, was pretty fucking revolutionary.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
