<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513388354.0" user="LtCmdrShepard" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry for being crass, but it's really obvious you haven't actually read anything Jesus said. "Be a good person" is not his message.  

But I'd like to help, so here goes.  

His primary message is this: You are a poor, miserable, unrepentant (and *unable* to repent) sinner. God says you should die for this (you didn't think transgressing against the supreme being would be a misdemeanor, did you?). But, because God loves you, he sent his only begotten Son to take the punishment (death) for you. Yes, YOU op. And everyone else on Earth.    

The Gospel (meaning "Good News") message is this: Cling to Jesus. You can never save yourself on your own, but in Christ you are saved already.   

&amp;gt;In what other fashion can you justify... 
 
The biggest misconception about Christian thought is that it allows for "good people" on Earth. There is no such thing as a "good person" outside of Christ. We are all rebels against God. We all bite the hand that feeds us, and there is no way we can stop. Try as we might, we are condemned for our actions. All the time. And there is nothing we can do to save ourselves from his wrath.   

But, thanks to Jesus, *we don't have to save ourselves.* Because he did it for us. So yes, this life is wrought with sin and despair. But because of His death and resurrection, we can look forward to a better lot in the next life.   

(Sorry if the whole "simultaneously condemned and saved" thing is complicated. The cliff notes of Jesus' message is: You don't deserve to be saved, but God's a bro and sent me to save you anyway).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513398018.0" user="CantPenTheSnowden" delta="False">
    <text>This argument is dependent on how you interpret the fruit consumed by Adam and Eve (the origin and nature of original sin).
See for Christians what you said makes sense.
However, for those who don't believe that a talking serpent existed in the first place, all of the concepts pertaining to original sin, the redeeming power of the cross of Christ and salvation are all unnecessary and invalid.
In fact, I am certain that Judaism does not espouse the concept of original sin. It would make sense that the Jews have a much better understanding of the Bible than the Christians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513427674.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with your interpretation, I think you are weaving in and out of topic here.

Is your view that Jesus is not unique? or that Christianity (and Jesus by extension) is not compelling as a faith?

As you stated, LtCmdrShepard explained the rules of the Christian ideology quite well, but simply that you do not find it compelling (neither do I.) 

But really, I think LtCmdrShepard didn't really challenge your view all that much, as there wasn't any mention of a comparison to other faiths. Obviously Jesus is technically unique in a lot of ways, but is his whole package really that unique? That is what we are talking about right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513463656.0" user="CantPenTheSnowden" delta="False">
    <text>yep. sorry for the ambiguity. I get sidetracked sometimes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513447887.0" user="sm0cc" delta="False">
    <text>I thought the point of your CMV was that Jesus was not unique, not that you didn't believe in Jesus as divine. As far as I'm aware the Christian conception of sin coupled with the idea of a divine savior are pretty unique among world religions.

If you're concerned that the stuff about sin and divinity were made up later and that Jesus only said mundane things I'd recommend you study the gospels. He said some pretty radical stuff that tends to get filtered out in secular discussions.

---
Let me give an example from John chapter 6.
Shortly after Jesus had miraculously fed the five thousand, he sneaks off in the night. A large group of people follows him and ask him why he left. He turns and scolds them:
&amp;gt;"Very truly I tell you, you are looking for me, not because you saw the signs I performed but because you ate the loaves and had your fill. Do not work for food that spoils, but for food that endures to eternal life, which the Son of Man will give you. For on him God the Father has placed his seal of approval."

They tentatively respond "yeah sure, that's what we want. How do we do it?" This is when Jesus declares himself "the bread that came down from heaven." It is a declaration of his divinity and the people 'grumble.' He further claims that no one can get salvation
&amp;gt;"Unless you eat the flesh of the Son of Man and drink his blood, you have no life in you. Whoever eats my flesh and drinks my blood has eternal life, and I will raise them up at the last day"

and
&amp;gt;"This is why I told you that no one can come to me unless the Father has enabled them."

After this John tells us that many of his disciples stopped following him because they didn't like this new teaching where Jesus was somehow divine and the sole source of salvation.

Even in the gospels Jesus wasn't just a dispenser of proverbs about being kind. While that is an important part of his teachings he also had a much grander, more eternal message.





</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513572532.0" user="Toptomcat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm sorry for being crass, but it's really obvious you haven't actually read anything Jesus said. 

I must beg your pardon in turn, but it sounds like you're paraphrasing a great deal of theology that has its roots in the doctrine of Augustine, the early church fathers, and the apostles, rather than anything *Jesus* is directly quoted as having said in the Gospels. Read the [Sermon on the Mount](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sermon_on_the_Mount), the [Missionary Discourse](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_10), the [Parables](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parables_of_Jesus), the [Olivet Discourse](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivet_Discourse): the essential sinfulness and misery of man, God's condemnation of them, Jesus' being offered for punishment in their stead- *none of it* is the central idea of any one of Jesus' actual teachings. After the fact, you can make the argument that he obliquely referred to it, here and there. But it isn't a major focus of *Jesus*' teachings, only those who came after him. 

Jesus *himself* talks about being a good person at great length.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513889166.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know, it seems Jesus is pretty direct about it on a few occasions.

"I am the way, and the truth, and the life; no one comes to the Father but through Me."

"With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513913357.0" user="Toptomcat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"I am the way, and the truth, and the life; no one comes to the Father but through Me."

Not present in any of the Gospels but John 14:6, which seems *extremely* odd for something so centrally important. Also seems implicitly contradicted by a number of declarations elsewhere that people can or cannot 'enter the kingdom of Heaven' if they are certain kinds of people, or do certain things- like much of the Sermon on the Mount, for instance.

&amp;gt;"With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible."

Without John 14:6, insufficient by itself to establish many of the details of the dogma of original sin, let alone the stronger doctrine of [total depravity](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Total_depravity) espoused by LtCmdrShepard.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513893031.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>How does any of this show that Jesus is unique? This sounds like a rather classic story of the need for a savior because men are not capable on their own. You could even make a decent analgoy to Islam. Muhammad laid down a perfect example and it is up to Muslims to attempt to live up to that example, but it is accepted that no individual will ever be able to live up to Muhammad's perfect example because he was God's directly chosen messenger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514284630.0" user="Samuelgin" delta="False">
    <text>unique is era-dependent. what do you think made the "classic story" classic? you tried to say Jesus wasn't unique because of a prophet (an Abrahamic one, too) that lived 700 years after him. that's like saying the Wright Brothers weren't unique for flying in a plane in 1903 because of how many people fly in planes today. sure, it's pretty common now, but what do you think it rooted from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514966860.0" user="kabbotta" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good point, but that is kind of why I said "You could even..."

&amp;gt;but what do you think it rooted from?

My ultimate point was that the notion of mankind needing a savior, because they are incapable of grappling with Gods one-to-one, certainly predates Jesus. It obviously does because Jesus was supposedly fulfilling a bunch of prophecies claiming such a person was coming and needed. In fact, the entire reason Judaism still exists is because they believe Jesus didn't fulfill those prophecies which came long before his appearance, and were themselves modeled off even earlier thoughts and religious figures.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
