<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513340743.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Christianity is almost entirely responsible for the modern concept of evil. Different concepts existed before that were referred to with the same word, but the particular concept of evil we have today derives almost entirely from Christianity and the teachings of Jesus.

According to Jesus, if you so much as think an impure thought, you are putting your immortal soul in danger of eternal torment and outraging the almighty being who sustains your existence through every second of your life. Every thought and action has to be completely in accordance with the will of God, and any slight violation of God's will is as bad as the worst violation. 

This is a much more stark either-or alternative than exists in prior worldviews. Contrast Jesus with Aristotle, who wrote 500 years before Jesus. There is no concept of evil in Aristotle comparable to Jesus' concept of evil - rather, Aristotle measures moral character in degrees along a number of different axes, and there is no ultimate penalty associated with being a bad person apart from the fact that bad people generally aren't as happy as good people.

G. E. M. Anscombe argued that many of the mistakes in modern ethics are due to philosophers attempting to find a foundation for the stark "either-or" conception of morality that we got from Christianity, and that we should return to the more fine grained virtue ethics of the Greeks. So Jesus certainly still has a lot of influence on us today.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
