<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513330616.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>Well, for believers, Jesus is by definition unique since he is the Son of God, of which there is just the one.  It's hard to be more unique than that I'd say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513361515.0" user="CantPenTheSnowden" delta="False">
    <text>But the only justification of Jesus being the only Son of God is from either Jesus' words or from the words of his apostles.
That is sort of a circular argument right there</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513368564.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>Well, your CMV isn't "prove Jesus is the Son of God", it's about his uniqueness.  

Surely you must admit Jesus is a unique figure for Christians.  And a logical extension from that it that Jesus is therefore unique in the wider world since he is the only one considered to be the Son of God by Christians.  I mean, it's just simple logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513440698.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>See my reply below to OSkorzeny. Their perspective does not exist in a vacuum. They'll need a real justification for why their perspective is correct, not just their perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513454042.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't matter if they're correct or not.  The fact of the matter is that *they believe* Jesus is the Son of God.  That makes him unique to them.  

Let's assume God doesn't actually exist.  Jesus is still a unique figure to Christians.  

Now lets assume God does exist.  Jesus is still a unique figure to Christians.

Either way, Jesus is a unique figure for Christians.  And the rest of the argument is just logic.

Edit:  It actually seems like OP really meant to make a CMV about his teachings not being unique.  I can agree to that.  But that's not how I originally read the topic.  And here we are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513474504.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It doesn't matter if they're correct or not. The fact of the matter is that they believe Jesus is the Son of God. That makes him unique to them.

But again the point is it doesn't matter what their perspective is, it does not exist in a vacuum. They STILL have to justify why their perspective is correct while all others are wrong. Not that what they claim is true, but that if we're taking perspectives, there must be some reason to prefer theirs over another's for it to be CORRECT that the CHARACTER of Jesus is unique. If I say "hey, this [generic movie trope character] is unique" and I've only ever seen one movie, while other people have seen hundreds and can point out that no, many movies have a character with those main features, then they are correct, not me.


&amp;gt;Edit: It actually seems like OP really meant to make a CMV about his teachings not being unique. I can agree to that. 

I'm not really seeing any difference in the alleged teachings of Jesus and the Jesus character really. They're one and the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513820432.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>This is very simple:  There is only one character Christians worship as the Son of God.  His name is Jesus.  Any other historical or mythological character that might be similar in some ways, Christians do not consider to be the Son of God, which makes Jesus unique among them all.  Not only do Christians think he's unique in that way, but because they do, the character is unique in the world since he's the *only* character worshipped by Christians in that way.  

It doesn't matter at all that others believe Jesus wasn't the Son of God or that he's similar to a thousand other characters, and it doesn't matter who's actually right.  He is unique because of what Christians believe about him.

Edit:  If you don't believe Jesus is unique, then please name at least one other figure who Christians currently consider to be the Son of God.  If you can't name any, then Jesus is unique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513828781.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; He is unique because of what Christians believe about him.

No, something is what it is, regardless of what someone believes about it. That's what we're discussing.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513843829.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No, something is what it is, regardless of what someone believes about it

I agree.  And what Jesus is, is the character worshipped by Christians as the Son of God.  That's just a fact about him.  And that makes him unique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513865485.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>No, that's a fact about CHRISTIANS. It doesn't add to the personage of Jesus, just his followers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513867664.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>I think we're done here.  Thanks for the discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513872349.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Why are we done here? THat's not a fact about Jesus, what someone ELSE does is not a fact about me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513874992.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>I'm done because I'm tired of repeating myself.  You don't have to agree with me.  It'll be OK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513884025.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>You keep repeating yourself and I keep telling you why what you're saying is wrong. 

What people believe != what is true. It's simply not what the discussion is about. I'm tired of you not engaging the discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514074507.0" user="footballfinanceguru" delta="False">
    <text>I'll try to break down what he's saying in a clear manner, because frankly I don't understand your logic at all. 

Topic discussed: is Jesus a unique figure?
Ops cmv: prove that Jesus is a unique figure for Christians
Argument for: Jesus is worshipped as the son of god, making him an extremely unique figure.

Which of these three statements do you not agree with?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514124204.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>The second one is not accurate. The third one is irrelevant. We're taking about what is true, not what people believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514337638.0" user="footballfinanceguru" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you need to re-read the original post, because the second and third statements are extremely true and relevant to the conversation.

"I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me."

No where in the op are the views of Jesus criticized for legitimacy.we ate not discussing whether Jesus" teachings are right or wrong but whether his views and life were unique.

Your arguments are off topic and irrelevant from the cmv. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514442667.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Uh, the character of Jesus IS his views on life. Which again, are not original or unique. There are other characters in history that are quite similar to him in action.  I am completely discussing the Jesus character, not whether he's correct. So once more for clarity, he isn't, there are plenty of contemporary messianic apocalyptic cult leaders from the era. The person I was responding to kept saying "well, people believe he was the only one!" And my response was clearly "I agree, but it's not actually true he was the only one".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513434858.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>From a Christian perspective, he is unique because he is believed to be the son of God.

From a non-Christian perspective, he is unique because billions of people believe that he was and is the son of God.

How is this circular?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513439461.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>From a Christian perspective or not, objectively there were MANY humans who have lived who have claimed to be sons of gods, or even a god themselves. The deluded may think themselves Napoleon, but is that the case? You can't just say "well from my perspective this is so" and not acknowledge that other people have different ones. If you take that into account, then you need more than simply a perspective, you need a justification for why you're right and every other perspective wrong, not SIMPLY the perspective.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513455521.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, plenty of people have claimed to be the son of God, but how many get significant traction? From a purely secular position, Jesus founded a religion that would dominate a continent for millennia. Not many can claim that, and so Jesus is clearly a "unique figure" at the very least, which is what this CMV is about. I don't see how you can rationally deny that, the fact that we talk about a carpenter from Galilee 2000 years after his death is evidence enough of his uniqueness.

That isn't even getting into his actually message and ministry, which is more unusual than OP gives credit for. Other posts have argued that point better, though, so I won't beat a dead horse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513469777.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Significant traction or not, the figure is not unique. You can't equate the movement with the figure when other figures were quite similar.

&amp;gt;I don't see how you can rationally deny that, the fact that we talk about a carpenter from Galilee 2000 years after his death is evidence enough of his uniqueness.

We talk about many things from the past. The archangel Jesus that was later turned into a human as a story for theological points got a lot of traction, that I'll agree to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513510345.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>What do you call unique? I think we're dealing with different definitions here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513515174.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>The only instance of, or one of a very select few. The teachings of Jesus, his acts, that's the only thing that Jesus "is" as a character/figure. Many other characters in history were similar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513522202.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give me an example of who you consider to be a unique figure in history? I don't know who would be unique under that definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513537720.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>I think that if I get any more broad with my definition, then the "uniqueness" of an individual will become washed out, so I'll try to explain. If you can find a LOT of characters in the place and time, (Messianic ones just like Jesus existed in history, preaching similar things, tons of contemporaneous ones) then that character isn't unique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513569479.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>So would you consider, say, Frederick the Great to be unique? Lots of militaristic German states at the time, Prussia's big claim is really only it's success.

Or to continue the German theme, what about German unification as a unique event? Lots of nationalistic unification movements in Europe at that time, and Italy even unified the very same year! I'd call the German unification a unique event, but maybe you disagree. 

 What about Julius Caesar? He wasn't the first dictator for life (that was Sulla), he wasn't the first to instigate a civil war due to the personal loyalty of his men (Marius takes that honor), and he didn't consolidate his power into what we think of as the Empire today (Augustus was largely responsible for that). Really, Caesar was just another charismatic, power hungry Roman general, one in a long line of power hungry Roman generals. What makes him unique in your definition?

The point I'm trying to make is that even if a person or an event has numerous contemporary events that share superficial similarities, the particulars and the effects of those events and that person can serve to set them apart and make them unique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513629245.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The point I'm trying to make is that even if a person or an event has numerous contemporary events that share superficial similarities, the particulars and the effects of those events and that person can serve to set them apart and make them unique.

Sure, then everyone is unique and the definition no longer really carries any weight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513673229.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>I think there exists a middle ground. Why must we resort to absolutes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513688669.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>At no point did I resort to any absolutes. I'm only following the logical entailment of your definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513704184.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>So please, give me an example of a unique historical figure. Otherwise the word is useless, because it can never be applied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513746244.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>The ones you listed are unique. Noone else will perform those actions, there are demonstrable historical events that can be pointed to, they cannot effectively be swapped out with some other contemporaneous figure, and there is someone specific to point to at the time NOT very, very similar occurrences of messianic prophets that achieved accuracy* via volume of fire. 

*Accuracy in this instance means, their message got picked up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513754549.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>Who would you point to as a possible substitute for Jesus, that would lead to a similar Christian theology? As I said, most messianic figures of the period took a more militaristic stance (eg various Zealot leaders), so who would you point to that could lead to a Christian-esque religion forming?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513788290.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Again, there is no singular Jesus.  But of course there was this guy: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apollonius_of_Tyana

This is the one black swan that shows you that not all swans are white.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513804561.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with Apollonius in this context is that we don't really know *what* his theology is. It's hard to compare his message with that of Jesus when not much of his message survived. I haven't seen anything suggesting that Apollonius came to forgive sins, and that's kinda the core of the Good News. But again, in fairness, not much survived, and it's possible that Apollonius preached a similar message. It wasn't exactly a fair question, since so little survives from that era, and a more obscure version of Jesus would implicitly have more sparse coverage. The question was in bad faith, and I'm sorry about that.

Edit: forgive me if I'm wrong, but did Apollionus claim to be the Messiah at all? If not, then that's certainly at least one major difference between him and Jesus.

I'm confused by your statement that there was no singular Jesus. Certainly the apostles focus on different themes and aspects of Jesus, but saying that they're each talking about entirely different people seems rather ungenerous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513832621.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>They paint a picture of very different Jesuses. The stories might be the same in general, but how they are portrayed is quite different. It would be akin to the same movie being shot with the same scenes, but with 4 different actors ad libbing the lines. One Jesus is kind of a coward, one's a badass. Richard Carrier and Nathan Fitzgerald do a better job of me than explaining it, read/watch their stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513899838.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>I don't recognize Nathan Fitzgerald, and googling reveals nothing, but Richard Carrier is an evangelical atheist and a Jesus Mythicist. Hardly an unbiased source, and most of his conclusions go against historian consensus. That's not ad hominem, these are factors that very well could cloud his judgment on the character of Jesus. I'd be cautious using such partisan sources as the core of your argument.

In any case, it's late, and I need to sleep. I've enjoyed our conversation, it's been surprisingly civil considering the subject matter. I still think you're wrong, but I'm OK with that. You probably think the same of me. Good night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513917042.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't recognize Nathan Fitzgerald, and googling reveals nothing, but Richard Carrier is an evangelical atheist and a Jesus Mythicist. Hardly an unbiased source, and most of his conclusions go against historian consensus. That's not ad hominem, these are factors that very well could cloud his judgment on the character of Jesus. I'd be cautious using such partisan sources as the core of your argument.

I'm aware of them. Fitzgerald lays out arguments well known in "Nailed" and Carrier, though he goes against the grain, offers excellent reason to believe historical  methods are extremely flawed for accurate conclusions.

&amp;gt;In any case, it's late, and I need to sleep. I've enjoyed our conversation, it's been surprisingly civil considering the subject matter. I still think you're wrong, but I'm OK with that. You probably think the same of me. Good night.

If I wasn't okay with people being wrong, i'd probably go insane.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513677824.0" user="OSkorzeny" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, and one more point: Jesus is not indicative of the typical messianic figure of the era. Most Messiah claimants advocated for some type of violence and revolution to found an independent Jewish state. Jesus was remarkable pacifistic compared to most "Messiahs".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513690658.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>First off, there's more than one Jesus character. The gospels do not paint the picture of the same guy, so there's 4 for you right there. 

Secondly, that's also not true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513834348.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Significant traction or not, the figure is not unique.

The traction is unique. 

&amp;gt;The archangel Jesus that was later turned into a human as a story for theological points got a lot of traction, that I'll agree to.

What? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513866949.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The traction is unique.

Ignoring all other major and well known religions, sure.

&amp;gt;What?

Read up on where the idea of Jesus probably came from. There is an older myth than that of Jesus. It probably started with an archangel named Jesus. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513877949.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, no. There's no evidence for that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513883122.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.bibleinterp.com/articles/2014/08/car388028.shtml

Except there is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513888544.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>Richard Carrier is a fraud. You'll notice he doesn't actually give evidence for any of his claims. He just says "it could have happened this way." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513897098.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Except he cites the sources that exist, in the thing I linked you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513897372.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Except he cites the sources that exist, in the thing I linked you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513905437.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>No, he does not. He just says "maybe the first Christians thought Jesus was an archangel." He offers no proof (a recurring problem with him). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513915251.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Except for the links he provides that reference previous myths with that exact idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513926230.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Except for the links he provides that reference previous myths with that exact idea.

He offers no evidence that Christians ever believed this. He just says that there were legends of demigods in Greece. That proves nothing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513938994.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;He offers no evidence that Christians ever believed this. 

Then you miss the point. JEWS believed this, the earliest "christians" were messianic JEWS who would know to some extent the old beliefs, like back when Yahweh was part of a pantheon of gods and how lesser servant beings interacted with him. The issue here, and I do not say this an insult, but a simple fact of the matter is that you're ignorant of how much there is to know that surrounds the myths of these people. Seriously, go actually see where the rabbit trail leads.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513944922.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then you miss the point. JEWS believed this

He says the first Christians did. He's also a liar and provides no evidence for this claim. So what? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513980868.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the first Christians also knew about what Jews believed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513992001.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>And the first Christians did not believe Jesus was an archangel. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514040970.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>But they derived their beliefs from somewhere. To be honest, we really don't know what the first christians believed, but it's entirely possible because it's happened before and is supported by the evidence OF archangel Jesus that the Jews previous to this DID believe in, that the 4 gospels are a story told for some theological reason; NOT as events that actually occurred. The story of Jesus as an actual person is NOT supported because all the people you'd expect to record about him, don't. Seriously, research this, you can get a primer on one of his talks or debates. It makes a fair case that he's got the right idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514524265.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But they derived their beliefs from somewhere. To be honest, we really don't know what the first christians believed, 

We have a pretty good idea. 

&amp;gt;because it's happened before

So what? 

&amp;gt;and is supported by the evidence OF archangel Jesus that the Jews previous to this DID believe in

They did not. Some of them believed in archangels though. 

&amp;gt;that the 4 gospels are a story told for some theological reason; NOT as events that actually occurred. 

There's no evidence of that. 

&amp;gt;The story of Jesus as an actual person is NOT supported because all the people you'd expect to record about him, don't. 

Who would we expect to record Jesus' life? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514530212.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not the best person to explain all this. Go watch Carrier's videos or read his books, because that's the primer. You can find sources from there if you really care to learn. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514538833.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>Carrier's a fraud. He's making this up, and you're falling for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514577637.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Except he isn't and you haven't researched the first thing on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514578141.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Except he isn't 

Yes, he is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514584185.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Prove it. I've given you somewhere to start, show me how I'm wrong. Don't assert it. Carrier doesn't assert it either, he provides evidence for his points, and WHY he believes what he does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514585920.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Prove it. 

He makes crap up and provides no evidence. 

&amp;gt;Carrier doesn't assert it either

That's all he does. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514891216.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;He makes crap up and provides no evidence.

You're demonstrably wrong. He cites the ideas the people at the time already had. You are aware that people from antiquity "re wrote" old powerful deity types into humans right? There are reasons to believe, that he cites as already known that would make it plausible. Seeing as it requires no supernatural explanation to make sense of it, this makes it a stronger case than a supernatural deity. Educate yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27514897057.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;He cites the ideas the people at the time already had. 

No, he says they may have had certain ideas. 

&amp;gt;You are aware that people from antiquity "re wrote" old powerful deity types into humans right?

They also deified men. A lot. Remember Vespasian? 

&amp;gt;Seeing as it requires no supernatural explanation to make sense of it, this makes it a stronger case than a supernatural deity.

Nor does the argument that Jesus existed. Educate yourself. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515088749.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>No, he did not say they may have. The Jews previous to the supposed events actually did justifiably believe these things, and that is where they got the ideas. The events where a story, based on well documented knowledge of ancient people doing  before, were constructed to tell a theological tale. They're known practices at that time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515093046.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No, he did not say they may have. The Jews previous to the supposed events actually did justifiably believe these things, 

No, they did not. He made it up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515116000.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Then you clearly haven't read his sources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515116816.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>There aren't any. He just makes this stuff up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515123570.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>You're just plain wrong. There's no argument here. I've shown you where to look and you demonstrably haven't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515125809.0" user="MRB2012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There's no argument here

You're right about that. Carrier is a fraud. There's no argument to be had. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27515149075.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Well you have a good day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513488067.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  You can't just say "well from my perspective this is so" and not acknowledge that other people have different ones.

Yes they can, its called faith.

&amp;gt; you need a justification for why you're right and every other perspective wrong, not SIMPLY the perspective.

Not if its based on faith.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513491820.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes they can, its called faith.

They're certainly capable, but the issue here is you can point out that they're wrong. People can believe whatever they want, but if the facts directly point to the opposite of their conclusion, they're wrong. Also known as delusional if they know these facts.

&amp;gt;Not if its based on faith.

See above. Let me be clear on the point further. Knowing what they believe and what's demonstrably true are 2 different things. It is objectively true that they believe by faith, it is also objectively true that they are wrong. (About this particular instance) Let's not equivocate here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513506620.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're certainly capable, but the issue here is you can point out that they're wrong. 

They believe without proof or facts, so why would they not believe with proof or facts?

&amp;gt; It is objectively true that they believe by faith, it is also objectively true that they are wrong. 

No one is saying they are right or wrong, they just believe that Jesus is the son of God and therefore is unique.  That is what the View is about.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513509812.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They believe without proof or facts, so why would they not believe with proof or facts?

What they believe vs what's objectively true. Much like someone thinking they're napoleon when they aren't.

&amp;gt;No one is saying they are right or wrong, they just believe that Jesus is the son of God and therefore is unique. That is what the View is about.

But their view is not what's objectively true, which is what we're discussing here. A lot of Americans think that the US is the greatest country on earth, but when you point out that a lot of people exceed our standard by miles, it's clear we have a lot of work to do in many areas. If we're the greatest, we should be #1 in many, many areas. THeir belief does not accurately reflect reality and THAT is what we should be discussing. NOt what people believe, but what is actually true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513523698.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But their view is not what's objectively true, which is what we're discussing here.

The fact that "Lots of people currently and in the past believe he is is the son of God and therefore unique" is objectively true.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513530891.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Correct. However that belief is demonstrably false. If you can compare him to other figures in history and he's not unique, then he's not, no matter how fervent the belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513538267.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However that belief is demonstrably false.

The correctness of the people's belief have nothing to do with the fact that people believe that he is unique.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513541120.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>But the correctness of people's belief is the discussion we're having. We're NOT discussing "Do some people think Jesus is a unique figure?" we're discussing "Is Jesus actually a unique figure?". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513553036.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; we're discussing "Is Jesus actually a unique figure?".

Yes, he is unique because people believe that he is a unique figure like no one else (son of God) now and in the past.  This has impacted history and the current world like no one else has.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513633132.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, he is unique because people believe that he is a unique figure

No, if someone is unique it is because they are unique, not because people believe it is so. People believe a good many things that are not true. Again, I can point to that area at the time and you can swing a small number of dead cats to hit a large number of apocalyptic messianic prophets.

&amp;gt;This has impacted history and the current world like no one else has.

People's beliefs have impacted history and the current world, not the alleged person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513373718.0" user="BigTayTay" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, he is not the only "Son of God" by any religious means. The egyptian religion was copied almost idea for idea by the christian faith. 

EDIT: Horus. Or even further, the idea of "Jesus" can be correlated with the myths of many religious Deities, such as: Zarathusa, Heracles, Dionysus, Odysseus, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513380993.0" user="rigamortus76" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Actually, he is not the only "Son of God" by any religious means.

I didn't claim he was.  I said he was unique for Christians (or more generally, believers).  They don't believe in those other gods you mentioned.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513383481.0" user="BigTayTay" delta="False">
    <text>Ah my apologies, I misread you. Carry on!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513397270.0" user="NightCrest" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Horus

I suggest you actually read up on [Horus](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horus) instead of taking your facts from bullshit documentaries. Horus's mythology has almost nothing in common with Jesus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513541637.0" user="irondeepbicycle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Horus. Or even further, the idea of "Jesus" can be correlated with the myths of many religious Deities, such as: Zarathusa, Heracles, Dionysus, Odysseus, etc.

It's the kind of statement you make when you watched Bill Maher's Religulous, and have never read literally anything else on the subject.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513398040.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The egyptian religion was copied almost idea for idea by the christian faith.

That's nonsense that was debunked a long time ago.  Finding vague correlations does not imply any sort of causal relationship or inspiration.  If I look at two lives or stories and try hard enough, we can find the sort of correlations that people use to suggest this.

For reference, [this guy](http://users.adam.com.au/bstett/BJesusandHorus74.htm) found quite a few correlations between Horus and Hitler.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
