<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513354638.0" user="theophilus153" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom.

It seems like you want your view to be changed about whether or not Jesus was a unique figure; on the condition that we argue from your own preconception that Jesus' story is largely legendary.  

Of course, if the Jesus story is simply a legend, then there is nothing unique about Jesus.  How could there be?


However, I think that you should be able to recognize that for people who believe in Jesus, they *don't* believe his story to simply be a legend.  Would you agree that if the story of Jesus (particularly his claim to be the Son of God, and his resurrection from the dead) is actually true - that there *is* something unique about Jesus?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
