<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513335980.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>I could be wrong on this, but I do believe that whole concept of the Trinity is actually a concept that is unique to Christianity.

The "I, God, sent myself down to Earth to be born of a virgin (not unique) wherein I then orchestrated my own sacrifice (not unique) and resurrection (not unique) to save my own creations from their sins and the original sin that I gave them."

While Christianity as a whole is a patchwork quilt of different mythologies, that specific thread is unique to my knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513367144.0" user="Nikcara" delta="False">
    <text>It's not unique to Christianity though.  Triad gods are actually very common in tons of pagan beliefs.  Maiden/Mother/Crone moon goddess is fairly popular right now among modern pagans but there are many male and female triad gods.  The Norse had a goddess that was past, present, and future.  The Celtic goddess Brigid is also often considered a triple goddess.  Lugus is a male trinity god.  So is Triglav.  In fact, trinity gods are so common that Carl Jung categorized it as a general archetype in the history of religion, though he included many gods that were closely related and not three gods in one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513412029.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>You are right. Like many aspects of Christianity, the general theme of the Trinity is not unique, neither is the birth/resurrection concept, the sacrificial feast, the virgin birth, etc etc. But you did touch upon what I was referring to, in that the "Three in One" concept is possibly unique. Not that Jesus mentioned it at all, and it ignores the entire history of differing factions that disagreed with the Trinity.

Really, it just depends on how pedantic OP wants to be with the definition. 

Thanks for the well researched short list though, it is useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513443294.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>Well, Christianity doesn't have Karma. You can find something unique in every religion. To be clear, my point is a single unique factor of a religion does not equal demonstrable nature of the religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513475350.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. It's hard to tell where OP is drawing the line with respect to what qualifies as "unique"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513480709.0" user="Raborn" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't actually agree with what I said. Whether or not he's qualified what he means by unique (A necessary item, but not what I was attempting to bring up) I was referring to YOUR point that might be a unique factor. I've always seen that backwards. It's a unique feature of the religion, not the one that makes it unique out of all the other ones.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
