<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="164456368.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2pwvcg/cmv_jesus_is_not_that_unique_of_a_figure/">
    <title>CMV: Jesus is not that unique of a figure</title>
    <original_poster>CantPenTheSnowden</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've always wondered why people are so obsessed with this Jesus character.

His messages are not unique, in fact they are rather common knowledge, except for the few clever sayings that are attributed to him. Feed the poor, don't let your heart be consumed with wealth and material goods, believe in a higher power, do unto others what you want others to do to you etc. are all common sayings that were preached by hundreds of sages before and after the life and death of Jesus. 

I think of Jesus as being another charismatic figure whose death or martyrdom was made into a legend by his followers in order to legitimize Christendom. I mean what other fashion can you justify genocide, bigotry and forced conversion other than proclaiming that your message is about peace and love? This sort of doublethink astounds me.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27513336623.0" user="Fleedle_Dee" delta="False">
    <text>You're fitting two arguments together which cannot be addressed that well at the same time: that Jesus is not a unique figure and that Jesus' martyrdom was used to justify heinous acts. Because of your title, I will focus on the first. 

I do not know whether you have read the New Testament, but there is plenty of there to make him a fairly unique character. While the messages you list are fairly generic, much of his preaching addressed other things, mainly the hypocrisy of the scribes and Pharisees (i.e. Jews in positions of authority). A large  portion of Jesus message was specific to a particular place and time; that is, he was angry at powerful Jews for putting on a show of piousness through strict adherence to laws and advocated that true godliness came through humbleness and  servitude, and was wholly incompatible with how the Jews behaved. So in this way, Jesus is unique in that he was preaching for a particular time and place. 

However, his message has a particular timelessness to it which allows us to improve our lives today and to critique superiors, even within the framework of Christianity itself. Hypocrisy is something which is always present, as it is so easy to feign good intentions, and as such it is something which is always worth addressing. So in this sense he is also unique, as his teachings are just as effective today as they were way back when (sans the eschatological preaching, but I think we have long since noticed that the apocalypse is not happening any time soon).

If you really want to be convinced, then read one of the gospels. They are fairly short, and I think it is easy to see in one reading that he is a fairly convincing and well-spoken figure, regardless of history and how he is presented by others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513367698.0" user="CantPenTheSnowden" delta="False">
    <text>I have read the gospels. 
Most of them are fairly inconsistent with one another with regards to important events such as his death or resurrection and his birth.
So you're saying that Jesus is unique because he criticized Jewish authority and because he advocated godliness?
Most of the things that Jesus said are too generic or are plainly false. The meek shall inherit the earth? Those who mourn will be comforted?
Those who are hungry are satisfied? 
These beatitudes sound like propaganda used by Stalin to encourage peasants to work for this distant utopia where everything is sunshine and rainbows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27513388580.0" user="Fleedle_Dee" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say anything about the inconsistencies, and I would need more clarification as to how they impact your opinion of Jesus' uniqueness as a religious figure.

And again, the beautitudes which you are pulling up are some of his more generic messages, I agree, but they were not what I was referring to. For example, I was thinking more along the lines of Matthew 23:11 : "The greatest among you will be your servant." That particular message, that leaders must be servants to others above all else, was fairly radical at the time, as far as I know, and is still just as applicable today. 

I don't really know what to do with your comparison to Stalin. What are you saying there? Are you saying that Jesus is not unique because he sounds like Stalin or that there is something sinister to his message? Either way, I don't see that having much to do with the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
