<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1645876697.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r7wul5/cmv_altered_carbon_s2_was_good_on_its_own_just/">
    <title>CMV: Altered Carbon S2 was good on it’s own, just not as a continuation of S1. It would have had better reviews if it had been presented as a separate, tangential show. SPOILER</title>
    <original_poster>DetroitUberDriver</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main issue with the second season of Altered Carbon was the fact that the majority of the main cast were gone, and or had less screen time, and were played by different actors (riding different sleeves). The one constant was Poe, as he’s an AI, and had no physical embodiment, and was beloved by many, he had significantly more screen time. 


The reason Takeshi Kovacs was in a different sleeve was actually explained, at the end of the last episode, he had cleared Ryker of the charges he was framed for and Ryker would be spun back up and want his sleeve back which Takeshi was riding. 


People had become attached to Joel Kinnaman and his performance of Takeshi Kovacs, and didn’t like the sudden change to him being portrayed by a totally different actor. Anthony Mackie did a good job, and the second series was good in it’s own right, people just didn’t like the change from season one.


However, the nature of the show, the ability to avoid real death by having your consciousness (DHF) stored in a stack and resleeved into a new body kind of made this aspect unique and predictable. 


CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38399476505.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Season 1 was essentially a crime show with sci-fi twist. Second was weird blend of political action thriller. Genres, themes and styles of two seasons where wildly different. Even setting and characters were essentially different. It's honestly two different shows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38399540435.0" user="DetroitUberDriver" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why I don’t think it fits quite right as a second season, among the things I listed. But none of those things make it bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38399643485.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Most of your OP was about change in cast but that was really a minor thing. Lot of shows can recast their character without ill effect. It wasn't about actors or casting choice. Those were minor issues.

Altered Carbon changed genres between seasons. Big thing was that S2 just wasn't same show as S1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38399960530.0" user="DetroitUberDriver" delta="False">
    <text>That’s because the majority of the poor ratings for S2 were complaining about the different cast so I chose to focus on that.

Edit: Also it was still very much Cyberpunk genre, it just changed theme.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38406171680.0" user="Ninjavitis_" delta="False">
    <text>The cast wasn’t just different. It was objectively bad. The two female leads weren’t interesting or diverse. There was no chemistry between the cast. The dialogue was flat. The interactions between the characters wasn’t exciting. 

As a stand alone show S2 was not entertaining and the plot was a mess</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
