<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1645876697.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r7wul5/cmv_altered_carbon_s2_was_good_on_its_own_just/">
    <title>CMV: Altered Carbon S2 was good on it’s own, just not as a continuation of S1. It would have had better reviews if it had been presented as a separate, tangential show. SPOILER</title>
    <original_poster>DetroitUberDriver</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main issue with the second season of Altered Carbon was the fact that the majority of the main cast were gone, and or had less screen time, and were played by different actors (riding different sleeves). The one constant was Poe, as he’s an AI, and had no physical embodiment, and was beloved by many, he had significantly more screen time. 


The reason Takeshi Kovacs was in a different sleeve was actually explained, at the end of the last episode, he had cleared Ryker of the charges he was framed for and Ryker would be spun back up and want his sleeve back which Takeshi was riding. 


People had become attached to Joel Kinnaman and his performance of Takeshi Kovacs, and didn’t like the sudden change to him being portrayed by a totally different actor. Anthony Mackie did a good job, and the second series was good in it’s own right, people just didn’t like the change from season one.


However, the nature of the show, the ability to avoid real death by having your consciousness (DHF) stored in a stack and resleeved into a new body kind of made this aspect unique and predictable. 


CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38400104171.0" user="electric_onanist" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't good because of Anthony Mackie. He has that wholesome quality and is excellent at playing the hero character.  However, Takeshi Kovacs is supposed to be an anti-hero, a person who is very morally compromised and comfortable committing horrific acts of violence, a lost soul who has been damaged by his experiences, and is looking to find his way in the world.  The actor who played him in S1 captured the essence of the Kovacs character pretty well.  It also helped that S1 was closer to the source material, S2 diverged pretty wildly from it.  It tried to combine elements of the second and third novels in a way that was confusing and didn't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38400222787.0" user="DetroitUberDriver" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t comment on the novels as I haven’t read them, but I somewhat disagree about Kovacs in S1. He seems morally compromised on the surface but he clearly has feelings and empathy and a moral compass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38401045824.0" user="goodnamesweretaken" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, and Anthony Mackie didn't do a good job of showing us all of that. Electric is giving you the correct answer here.

To elaborate, books 2 and 3 have a bit more character development that explains Kovacs' increased emotional vulnerability. Some of it is explained as part of the skin he jumped to, but a bigger part is explained by his interactions with women in book 2 and 3. The show tried to merge these 2 books together and didn't do a great job of fleshing this aspect out, which is actually a pretty important aspect for this series.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38402594732.0" user="electric_onanist" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point. I should have said 'morally injured' instead of 'morally compromised'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38404920204.0" user="ThatGuyMarlin" delta="False">
    <text>It really took me out of the show when Kovacs's actor in S2 absolutely butchered his Japanese lines. Like, holy shit, his character is supposed to be Japanese hire a language coach.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
