<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1645876697.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r7wul5/cmv_altered_carbon_s2_was_good_on_its_own_just/">
    <title>CMV: Altered Carbon S2 was good on it’s own, just not as a continuation of S1. It would have had better reviews if it had been presented as a separate, tangential show. SPOILER</title>
    <original_poster>DetroitUberDriver</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main issue with the second season of Altered Carbon was the fact that the majority of the main cast were gone, and or had less screen time, and were played by different actors (riding different sleeves). The one constant was Poe, as he’s an AI, and had no physical embodiment, and was beloved by many, he had significantly more screen time. 


The reason Takeshi Kovacs was in a different sleeve was actually explained, at the end of the last episode, he had cleared Ryker of the charges he was framed for and Ryker would be spun back up and want his sleeve back which Takeshi was riding. 


People had become attached to Joel Kinnaman and his performance of Takeshi Kovacs, and didn’t like the sudden change to him being portrayed by a totally different actor. Anthony Mackie did a good job, and the second series was good in it’s own right, people just didn’t like the change from season one.


However, the nature of the show, the ability to avoid real death by having your consciousness (DHF) stored in a stack and resleeved into a new body kind of made this aspect unique and predictable. 


CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38400920709.0" user="bug_the_bug" delta="False">
    <text>I like S2 significantly less than S1 for a couple of reasons. Changing actors and even main characters isn't a problem for me, but it may have contributed to the problem I did feel.

It felt like Kovacs' character reverted, and lost much of his development from S1, then didn't get it back. By the end of 1, he seemed to trust his friends, he helped them, and cared about them. For S2, he was right back to acting like they were worthless again. It didn't make sense to me, and it seemed like he was simplified or dumbed down. S2 also walked back a lot of the bloodsport/explicit type stuff, and even left out (if I remember correctly) any significant deep dive type plot lines. I really liked the dark, techy, grunge of S1. I think both changes came as a result of the writers trying to play it safe? Whatever it was, it just didn't work for me the way S1 did.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
