<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1645876697.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r7wul5/cmv_altered_carbon_s2_was_good_on_its_own_just/">
    <title>CMV: Altered Carbon S2 was good on it’s own, just not as a continuation of S1. It would have had better reviews if it had been presented as a separate, tangential show. SPOILER</title>
    <original_poster>DetroitUberDriver</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main issue with the second season of Altered Carbon was the fact that the majority of the main cast were gone, and or had less screen time, and were played by different actors (riding different sleeves). The one constant was Poe, as he’s an AI, and had no physical embodiment, and was beloved by many, he had significantly more screen time. 


The reason Takeshi Kovacs was in a different sleeve was actually explained, at the end of the last episode, he had cleared Ryker of the charges he was framed for and Ryker would be spun back up and want his sleeve back which Takeshi was riding. 


People had become attached to Joel Kinnaman and his performance of Takeshi Kovacs, and didn’t like the sudden change to him being portrayed by a totally different actor. Anthony Mackie did a good job, and the second series was good in it’s own right, people just didn’t like the change from season one.


However, the nature of the show, the ability to avoid real death by having your consciousness (DHF) stored in a stack and resleeved into a new body kind of made this aspect unique and predictable. 


CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38400051435.0" user="AllHale07" delta="False">
    <text>Altered Carbon is probably in my top 3 favorite shows.

Although people became attached with Joel Kinnaman, this is pretty much the only show that can completely change the actor while having it be the same main character, and have it make sense. I think they deserve some credit for taking such a bold leap in changing the main character.  With the whole show based around people sleeving to different bodies, it was almost inevitable that they would switch the main actor for a different season.  Also, with the way S1 ended, there wasn't really a logical way for the Ryker sleeve to not be significantly damaged or destroyed. 

I felt that Season 1 was significantly better than Season 2.  I think the S1 story line was very good, and the thought of stacks/sleeves was such a cool new concept to see as they did a great job showing Kovacs past life as the season progressed.  I think since I liked the first season so much, it was hard to think of a second season without seeing Kinnaman as the actor.  Even with the information stating the reason for the different sleeve, I personally didn't feel like Mackie did a good enough job portraying Kovacs from season 1.  Despite this, I think S2 was still essential to providing some unanswered questions and conclusion about Quell.  I personally would have been more disappointed if they ended it after S1 than with what they presented in S2.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38400206812.0" user="DetroitUberDriver" delta="False">
    <text>I also agree that S1 was better, and I agree that the concept of resleeving opened up the ability to recast different actors for the same roll and make it make sense in line with the story, and I’d considered that early on in S1. 


Mackie’s portrayal of Kovacs was definitely different, but that’s to be expected, he’s a different person. I mean just the different sleeves that Kovacs was portrayed in in S1 alone in his flashbacks to set his character were all quite different as well, despite them being all the same person, the same DHF.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38401028954.0" user="Vulcryn" delta="False">
    <text>what are your top 3 favourite shows?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38403386284.0" user="AllHale07" delta="False">
    <text>1.Breaking Bad 

2.Altered Carbon 

3.Hard to pick between: Punisher/Ozarks/South Park</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
