<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1645876697.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r7wul5/cmv_altered_carbon_s2_was_good_on_its_own_just/">
    <title>CMV: Altered Carbon S2 was good on it’s own, just not as a continuation of S1. It would have had better reviews if it had been presented as a separate, tangential show. SPOILER</title>
    <original_poster>DetroitUberDriver</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main issue with the second season of Altered Carbon was the fact that the majority of the main cast were gone, and or had less screen time, and were played by different actors (riding different sleeves). The one constant was Poe, as he’s an AI, and had no physical embodiment, and was beloved by many, he had significantly more screen time. 


The reason Takeshi Kovacs was in a different sleeve was actually explained, at the end of the last episode, he had cleared Ryker of the charges he was framed for and Ryker would be spun back up and want his sleeve back which Takeshi was riding. 


People had become attached to Joel Kinnaman and his performance of Takeshi Kovacs, and didn’t like the sudden change to him being portrayed by a totally different actor. Anthony Mackie did a good job, and the second series was good in it’s own right, people just didn’t like the change from season one.


However, the nature of the show, the ability to avoid real death by having your consciousness (DHF) stored in a stack and resleeved into a new body kind of made this aspect unique and predictable. 


CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38399482132.0" user="Morasain" delta="False">
    <text>The second one went from a detective mystery cyberpunk sci fi thing to something of an entirely different genre. That was the issue. I liked the actors, but the show went too far off the original path.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38399544177.0" user="DetroitUberDriver" delta="False">
    <text>But if it had been presented as an independent, yet related show, would it have been good?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38399693552.0" user="Sirhc978" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think so.  I absolutely binged S1, but season 2 could not keep my attention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38402824027.0" user="MrHeavenTrampler" delta="False">
    <text>Same here. Although I did feel like Anthony was a bit of a turnoff for Takeshi Kovacs as the other guy had done it pretty well, and keeping track of original asian Takeshi, white Takeshi, and now black Takeshi was a bit too much lmao. 

Maybe an actor with a similar look to the one in S1 would have been a better cast. Idk, the dissonance was just too heavy, probably related to the medium, as in books visuals are not off putting since they are just descriptions.

Besides, the political thriller stuff instead of the detective-esque vibe might have indeed played a factor. It was good tho, can't say it was bad. It was simply not as good as S1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38400578844.0" user="Gygsqt" delta="False">
    <text>How could it be independent? it was literally based on Takeshi's backstory built in season 1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38400529485.0" user="Gauss-Light" delta="False">
    <text>The production values went off a cliff as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
