<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="165660639.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2qmokf/cmv_activity_on_the_internet_should_be_much_more/">
    <title>CMV: Activity on the internet should be much more heavily regulated</title>
    <original_poster>e05bf027</original_poster>
    <original_post>Before I begin, I understand how unpopular the following will be on a site such as this, but I really want to hear opinions. I have, over the last little while, gone from feeling that essentially unregulated and uncensored activity on the internet is a good thing, to believing the opposite. Here are my reasons, though not in a particularly lucid or well-structured form. Also, I understand that the gap between principle and practicality is vast, so I offer my points only as ethical ones.

Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

Data protection: Despite the above, I think companies should be extremely limited regarding what data they are allowed to store about people. The fact that millions of lines of code in various places churn through my online activity and that Google, Amazon, etc. have a virtual model of me should not be allowed. For example, Amazon should not be allowed to record the history of what I browse. I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Now, I understand that there are a great deal of complicated parts of this, especially when it comes to things like expressing dissident political views, government surveillance, etc. and I know how ill-formed my point is. I suppose that by offering these views for criticism and rebuttal I want help clarifying what I truly think.

TLDR: Unregulated, anonymous activity that is largely without personal consequence is not a good thing. People should be as liable for what they do online as if they did it on TV or in the middle of the street. 

Edit 1: let me be explicit in saying that I am not claiming innocence of any of these things, but that recently I have been asking myself ethical questions and an uncomfortable with answers I find myself giving, and my beliefs are changing because of it.

Edit 2: I have to go out for the rest of the night, but I will reply tomorrow and give more thought to all points made. Thanks for taking the time to reply, I already have a lot of food for thought.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27524692355.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>you are missing 3 things, 

1 anonymity gets abused by the minority regardless of medium, but anonymity is to valuable to remove 

2 you can actually block tracking cookies and there are data protection laws, how strict you want it is personal opinion

3 all data is the same,  your porn is the same 01 as someone else's, the thing you need to understand about piracy is is that  music movies and games are worth only a fraction of the cost that they are sold as, yet the industry still wants pre digital prices for them.  as seen by steam its not that people don't want to pay, its that they don't want to pay exorbant prices for a bunch of zero's and ones</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524706755.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>1 this intuitively makes sense, but sometimes parts of the internet resemble and allegation machine, an echo-chamber for poorly thought-out nonsense. Though, this also is true of life before the internet and it now just has a bigger audience. I will think more about this.

2 I understand that, but I think many people don't. I still think it should literally be illegal for companies to store any information about a person unless it is specifically volunteered.

3 I understand that this is true, but I don't see how anyone can easily rationalise the idea of disobeying this law. If copyright is to be disobeyed, why not just disobey any law that you dislike? I only really see civil disobedience (if we can call it that) as a valid course of action if it is a matter of rights. I still do not believe that information is a right, especially if it relates to entertainment or to journalism that sits behind a paywall. I don't believe it is a consumer's right to not obey this law, though I completely understand why it is done in reality. The 0s and 1s don't belong to you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524739187.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>1 interconnection has its risks, but its irreversible, and non anonymous sources have had years to spout nonsense (politicians tabloids etc)

2 technically they did volunteer it, (some sites have do you allow cookies), some have check boxes that have to be unmarked during installation, eula's etc.  just because you did not have another choice if you wanted to use the site or software doesn't make it any less of a choice,   and we can't make the choice illegal 

3  copyright is outdated, in the early days it made sense to have 70 year for a song, but now a song can be in and out within a week, and songs get written at such a pace that people could listen to new songs every day without ever repeating any during their life. 

what your missing is that the law  is their for a reason, blindly obeying a law is worse then breaking it.  

what people do is route around the broken parts of the law to get what they want, because the idea of letting the market correct its own prices does not work if its being sustained by broken laws</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524915185.0" user="i_lack_imagination" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 3 I understand that this is true, but I don't see how anyone can easily rationalise the idea of disobeying this law. If copyright is to be disobeyed, why not just disobey any law that you dislike? I only really see civil disobedience (if we can call it that) as a valid course of action if it is a matter of rights. I still do not believe that information is a right, especially if it relates to entertainment or to journalism that sits behind a paywall. I don't believe it is a consumer's right to not obey this law, though I completely understand why it is done in reality. The 0s and 1s don't belong to you. 

Copyright laws are basically a compromise between the public and people who create intellectual works. For this hypothetical, imagine copyright laws don't exist. If you made music, you could play in your house and so long as no one can hear it outside, it's your music on your property and you have control over who can come in your house and listen to it, if they can bring recording devices etc., but if you played in public, you lose all of those rights. You don't get to tell people in public that they can't record, you don't get to tell people that they have to leave a public area because you don't want them to hear your music etc. It's a public area, you chose to play your music there and you have to accept everything that comes with that.

Copyright laws in this sense are supposed to give a musician like yourself incentive to create music without fear of having it ripped off and losing your ability to make a living off the music you worked to create. This doesn't mean that a copyright law should give you the option to play in public and kick people out if you don't want them to hear you play, because that would be giving you too much control over others, but it could mean that certain recordings etc. you would have control over. All of this is only to the extent that it is required to keep you and others like you producing content and allowing you to make money off your work, but it is not supposed to give you 100% complete total control over your product in all facets of life, if it did, it would mean you could control when someone listens to your music, in what places they could listen to it etc., which would be completely ridiculous. 

But the public (ostensibly represented by the government that passes these copyright laws) doesn't have to give you these protections at all, they would just have to accept that you might not ever want to play your music or spend time developing your craft and the public would lose out on any potential works you may have created. That would be a sad world though, so the public wants you to create things and will concede certain things to give you what it takes to create music. Copyright laws have been heavily co-opted by the gigantic media companies who have lobbied governments to increase these protections well beyond what is actually required to keep people creating. Some things can be copyrighted for well over a hundred years, and by that time they may lobby for longer copyright durations. This is counter intuitive to why the public would have given out copyright concessions in the first place. The creator is sometimes no longer even alive while their work is still being monetized by a different copyright holder. So how does this benefit the public? Why should the public allow these companies to basically monopolize the intellectual property market and then mark up the prices ridiculously? Why should a country who always gets intellectual property releases months after the US actually pass any copyright laws at all? They don't have to, if it were an important enough point they could actually make it a negotiating move.

From a general business perspective, the US and I'm very sure pretty much all other developed nations do this as well, most of these governments make businesses agree to certain terms to conduct business. You can't just make a business and then say that you get to do whatever you want. No, if you want to run a business, you have to serve everyone, you can't deny service to black people or to women etc., that's discrimination and the public has decided that it shouldn't be allowed. There's all kinds of things like that that we do to businesses, and we could do the same thing with copyright law. 

The thing with intellectual property is that it doesn't have the same kind of constraints physical property has. You can reproduce intellectual property at phenomenal rates for basically no additional costs. I don't see how the public benefits from letting companies abuse this to make billions of dollars for something that they barely have to do any work to distribute to everyone. It's a hell of a lot different than a car manufacturer that has to have lots of infrastructure and lots of manpower etc. to make enough products for everyone and because of that, they can't make nearly as much profit as intellectual property sales can. No matter what they will always have certain fixed costs that scale up with production, but making a song costs only an initial cost of money and the costs of reproducing/distributing does not scale nearly as much as physical property does. Therefore it's not really fair to even consider giving it the same kind of protections physical property has.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27528147449.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting. I think that what lies at the essence of my point is that, despite all the problems with profiteering, etc. it feels so strange that people (I am not excluding myself here) are so willing to rationalise piracy, which feels ethically wrong if you value the principles of it. I know it is not the same as theft, and I know that some laws have been corrupted by corporate influence, but it feels so questionable to me that there seems to be an attitude that, if something can be digitised, then you have a right to view it on your computer because you've paid for your internet connection.

From another perspective, it concerns me that lots of infrastructures are dismantling. I have been reading Jaron Lanier's book Who Owns The Future? It got me wondering about lots of these questions, and wondering if digital technologies are helping or harming society as a whole despite their obvious benefits to individuals. He specifically mentions the recorded music industry at one point; there used to be recording technicians, people working in factories that produced physical media, people to transport that physical media, people working in the shop that sold it, etc. All of that was funded by sales of physical media. That is all evaporating. I know the tide can't be turned back, I know that digital distribution has its advantages. I know that we can easily get into saying that I am arguing against progress, and that there's a reason we don't have blacksmiths, etc. but something about the way the world is changing is making me uneasy so I am asking myself these questions and am probably just pining for the "old ways".

Thanks for taking the time to write such a detailed response. It has given me much more to think about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27528214192.0" user="i_lack_imagination" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it feels so questionable to me that there seems to be an attitude that, if something can be digitised, then you have a right to view it on your computer because you've paid for your internet connection.

I agree to a large extent. I've personally grown up downloading things that I didn't own very often. I didn't rationalize it by saying I had a right to them, but I did rationalize it by saying that it didn't hurt anyone. My views have advanced on this, I do recognize possibilities for financial harm and I do recognize just the mindset of believing that it doesn't have harm is actually contributing to financial loss. 

How I used to see it was that I'd never watch X anyways if I had to pay for it, and I'd never play Y game if I had to pay for it, and even now, I'd probably say it was true when only looking at each specific case. I'm sure you've heard a lot of people use that reasoning before, and the problem I had in overcoming this was that people who argued against it had the poorest of arguments. It probably reinforced me more in my thoughts. Always the same classical argument where it was "not yours", "illegal", "copyright owner didn't give you permission", so on and so forth, but in my mind, I knew I never would have bought them so those arguments were just plain wrong. I could easily prove wrong the arguments that each download is a lost sale because I could download 1000 movies which would easily cost such a large amount of money that I could prove I don't have, that it's not a lost sale.

What I eventually thought about though was why would I not buy them? The answer was "I'd do something else", but what would I do? Well, maybe I could do something else for a bit, but the reason I had no problem saying that is because enough of my free time was taken up by watching movies/playing games that I didn't pay for that I took for granted the time I spent and entertainment they gave me. Sure, when I have watched a ton of movies and played a lot of games, not watching any one of those movies or games in particular is really not a problem. It's true, I could easily have gone without watching or playing one of them if I had to pay for it and I likely would have. But if I applied that to all of them all of the time, I would soon find that I'd have more time than I knew what to do with and the value of the entertainment that they provide would rise to the point where I may have been more willing to pay for them. The value of entertainment, for me at least though I'd strongly suspect it's the same for many others as well, is correlated with the time you have and the way you spend the rest of your time. If you don't get enough entertainment/stimulation with your time, then they offer more value. The more entertainment/stimulation you get, the less value they represent to your overall time.

I fit somewhere borderline on it. I don't think it's morally right to get free intellectual property, you don't deserve to get anything for free just because it exists, but I don't think it's always morally wrong either but it has to be stated carefully for people who will abuse that like I once did with that poor mentality of not looking at the big picture. Overall I'd say if you can afford to buy something you probably should, but I have a problem promoting this idea too much because I think copyright law has been ruined by corporations lobbying and getting way more control than they ever should have. Imagine if they could have sold CDs that could detect what room of the house you are in and they would have sold a "Living room Beatles CD" or "Dining room Beatles CD" etc., people would find that disgusting and a flagrant misuse of copyright to extort more money from people, but they can and they do limit what devices we can use our content on and people rationalize it by saying if you don't like it don't pay for it. The point is that it's just egregiously wrong.

It sounds like the content of the book you are talking about would align quite well with robotics and automation. That's an extremely interesting and extremely complex future theory crafting, because in my view it's going to challenge all of our current notions of earning and property ownership etc. What seems most likely to me is that the rich and powerful will have to find ways to slowly transition everyone else to a situation in which not enough people are too unhappy to do anything about it but eventually the population would dwindle. It isn't in their interest to allow the public to become to aggravated that they're willing to overturn the whole system, willing to challenge the notions of earning and property ownership etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27528262827.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I think I am just exploring these ideas in an adult way or the first time, which is fairly shameful because I'm old enough to have done it a long time ago. I even have friends in the TV &amp;amp; film industrious, working on one of the largest TV shows on earth and they pirate things the most out of anyone I know, despite the fact that they are fully aware of the impact it has on their own livelihoods. Thanks for the reply; I have sme learning about copyright to do!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27529301963.0" user="Alterego9" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; there used to be recording technicians, people working in factories that produced physical media, people to transport that physical media, people working in the shop that sold it, etc. All of that was funded by sales of physical media. That is all evaporating.

More efficiency is not harming society. 

200 years ago, 90% of people were farmers. 

Better technology that made it possible for 2-3% of the population to do all the agricultural jobs, didn't create 90% unemployment rates. It created cheaper food, and cheaper food meant people could spend their leftover money on more products, which created demand for more production in the manufacturing industry.

Later, mass production made many of *those* jobs redundant in turn, but that just meant cheaper products, more spending money, which people spent on more human services. 

All that crap that your house is filled with, has been made possible by industries trying to more efficiently produce stuff with less workers, that need less payment.  

Every cent that a music publisher spares on transportation, is a cent that they can spend on hiring more employees in other sectors.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27527613809.0" user="Alterego9" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I still do not believe that information is a right, especially if it relates to entertainment or to journalism that sits behind a paywall.

The ability to freely receive and impart information, is also known by it's better names of "freedom of speech", "freedom of expression", and "freedom of the press". 

The very reason why the US. Constitution has a copyright clause, is because without it, putting entertainment or new behind a paywall through copyrights, would be as illegal as randomly censoring any other text from being printed by all but one person.  

At least on a conceptual level, forbidding the public to print Bibles and limiting it to the Catholic Church, and forbidding the public to print The Hunger Games and limiting it to Suzanne Collins, is the same type of government action. The latter's relative frivolity is irrelevant, after all free speech doesn't just apply to important speech. The latter's younger age, and the cultural benefit that result from authors profiting from copyrights, is a practical justification for why it was *a good kind* of restricting free speech away from it.  *I'm not saying that copyright is evil*, or well, I'm saying that it was a necessry evil, a practical limitation of a right for expected greater benefits.

This conceptual collusion was irrelevant for centuries. 99% of people had no reason to care that their hypothetical right to print The Iliad isn't applied to the latest Charles Dickens book, because they didn't have a printing press, they bought both from the book store anyways, it was irrelevant what arrangements printers made among each other about the flow of profits. And for the remaining 1%, it was a benefical arrangement, with them getting more control,  they were the priviliged side of the regulation. They were the only ones who ever had any interest in caring how long the copyright terms should last, or how Fair Use should be defined. 

But on the internet, we write and share our texts every day, and link to others', we play videos, we edit them, and re-upload remixes. We sing songs, we play songs while playing games and upload that video together, we share pictures, and draw, and we download, and stream, and copypaste, and quote, and cite. 

Suddenly, it's very clear how the "1s and 0s" of a privately "owned" content are similar to the 1s and 0s of any other data that we communicate with each other every day just as we breath and walk. What used to be the obscure regulatory laws of an industry, are now felt as a restriction on our daily usage of our most basic tools. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
