<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="165660639.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2qmokf/cmv_activity_on_the_internet_should_be_much_more/">
    <title>CMV: Activity on the internet should be much more heavily regulated</title>
    <original_poster>e05bf027</original_poster>
    <original_post>Before I begin, I understand how unpopular the following will be on a site such as this, but I really want to hear opinions. I have, over the last little while, gone from feeling that essentially unregulated and uncensored activity on the internet is a good thing, to believing the opposite. Here are my reasons, though not in a particularly lucid or well-structured form. Also, I understand that the gap between principle and practicality is vast, so I offer my points only as ethical ones.

Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

Data protection: Despite the above, I think companies should be extremely limited regarding what data they are allowed to store about people. The fact that millions of lines of code in various places churn through my online activity and that Google, Amazon, etc. have a virtual model of me should not be allowed. For example, Amazon should not be allowed to record the history of what I browse. I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Now, I understand that there are a great deal of complicated parts of this, especially when it comes to things like expressing dissident political views, government surveillance, etc. and I know how ill-formed my point is. I suppose that by offering these views for criticism and rebuttal I want help clarifying what I truly think.

TLDR: Unregulated, anonymous activity that is largely without personal consequence is not a good thing. People should be as liable for what they do online as if they did it on TV or in the middle of the street. 

Edit 1: let me be explicit in saying that I am not claiming innocence of any of these things, but that recently I have been asking myself ethical questions and an uncomfortable with answers I find myself giving, and my beliefs are changing because of it.

Edit 2: I have to go out for the rest of the night, but I will reply tomorrow and give more thought to all points made. Thanks for taking the time to reply, I already have a lot of food for thought.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27524710453.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

The exact same laws apply on the internet as off the internet.  If a magazine depicted Ted Neugent having sex with his mother in an outhouse, in the US, [that could be constitutionally protected free speech.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hustler_Magazine_v._Falwell)

To prove libel against a public figure like a celebrity or politician in the US is incredibly difficult.  You have to show what's called ["actual malice"](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Actual_malice) which means that the person knew they were lying, as well as having to show that others took their speech seriously.

&amp;gt;Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Google doesn't actively choose to list sites, an algorithm just finds all sites and lists them unless their robots.txt says not to.  Sites can be manually delisted, but asking them to automatically never list pirating sites would be basically impossible.  And even delisting would have to go through a court order showing that the site in question is engaged in illegal activity.  Since the order would be to engage in a prior restraint of Google's speech, the highest standards would apply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524796415.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding libel laws, this is obviously not something I understood that well. It should be noted though, that I am not writing from the USA, and I understand that this adds a whole other dimension to enforcing any laws such as this. It may boil down to not more than a personal feeling, but I believe people should be meaningfully liable for the content they choose to create.

Regarding Google's algorithms, etc. I still do believe that they bear responsibility. Even if such a change in law damaged them immensely, it is not something I have a problem with in principle. I find the defence of "but we just pull together the things people like" to be a poor one, and I believe if you are acting as a gateway to the internet, as Google often is, that you are liable for the part you play when you oint someone in the direction of illegal activity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524810114.0" user="abortionsforall" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.vg247.com/2013/07/12/league-of-legends-player-jailed-in-texas-over-facebook-rant-released-on-bond/

You are extremely misinformed.  People can and often are "held accountable" for things communicated over the internet.  I can give you many examples like this one of people having their lives wrecked over essentially nothing; I can't take you seriously unless you give me a real example of internet communication you think should be regulated that currently isn't.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524817191.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;that I am not writing from the USA, and I understand that this adds a whole other dimension to enforcing any laws such as this

Can you tell us what the laws are in your country regarding libel?  I think your example regarded Ted Nugent - what would have happened to a person who wrote those kinds of comments about him in their school paper or on a poster on a wall?

&amp;gt;I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Is that really illegal in your country?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524833468.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>As I mentioned, unfortunately I have to go out, so I'll write a little more about libel tomorrow when I return.

I don't believe this is illegal, it just makes me feel queasy and doesn't feel right. To be honest, this might be getting at something fundamental about why my view is changing as it is. It seems so easy to divorce online reality from physical reality, and I feel that the "online" person should be treated the same as a public citizen. That's an inelegant way for me to communicate my thought very quickly, but I feel that it is somewhat accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524839990.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>I guess my question is: isn't the online person already treated the same as a public citizen?  What's the key difference you see in the treatment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524850959.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure; I think I probably haven't expressed myself clearly. I will try harder tomorrow!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27525098531.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't believe this is illegal

It definitely isn't illegal.  There may not be an employee following you around with a camcorder.  But, there are security cameras which record what happens in the store.  This is basically the same thing.  

I'm sorry, but unfortunately, you're going to be filmed in most stores.  This has been the reality for a while now.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27525088075.0" user="PlatinumGoat75" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Even if such a change in law damaged them immensely, it is not something I have a problem with in principle. 

You may not object to this in principle.  But in practice, this would mean we couldn't have search engines anymore.  

The people who run search engines don't manually examine every single web page on the internet.  That would be impossible.  Search engines can only work if they're allowed to use computer programs which quickly scan web pages for key words.  If they're banned from doing this, then they won't be able to exist.  

When proposing a law, you have to think about its practical implications.  You're proposed rules might sound ok philosophically.  But if we implemented them, we'd have to get rid of Google, Yahoo, Facebook, Reddit, and any other website which allows users to post information or that provides links to websites which they don't control.  

Are you really ok with giving up all these things?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27525245965.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Regarding libel laws, this is obviously not something I understood that well. It should be noted though, that I am not writing from the USA, and I understand that this adds a whole other dimension to enforcing any laws such as this. It may boil down to not more than a personal feeling, but I believe people should be meaningfully liable for the content they choose to create.

This isn't really an issue with internet regulations then.  If what that person said was illegal in the jurisdiction where they said it, then it would still be illegal for them to say it on the internet.  I used the US because Nugent is in the US and would be suing here, where he'd lose, even if it were in a newspaper or magazine.

If your country's libel laws make such conduct unlawful, then they apply online as well; if they don't, then your problem isn't with internet regulation.

&amp;gt;Regarding Google's algorithms, etc. I still do believe that they bear responsibility. Even if such a change in law damaged them immensely, it is not something I have a problem with in principle. I find the defence of "but we just pull together the things people like" to be a poor one, and I believe if you are acting as a gateway to the internet, as Google often is, that you are liable for the part you play when you oint someone in the direction of illegal activity.

It would be a ban on all search engines.  Search engines compile more information than a human can look at in advance and do so via algorithms.  If all sites had to be pre-screened by a human being, then it would mean the end of all search on the internet.  I think that would be a disaster.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
