<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="165660639.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2qmokf/cmv_activity_on_the_internet_should_be_much_more/">
    <title>CMV: Activity on the internet should be much more heavily regulated</title>
    <original_poster>e05bf027</original_poster>
    <original_post>Before I begin, I understand how unpopular the following will be on a site such as this, but I really want to hear opinions. I have, over the last little while, gone from feeling that essentially unregulated and uncensored activity on the internet is a good thing, to believing the opposite. Here are my reasons, though not in a particularly lucid or well-structured form. Also, I understand that the gap between principle and practicality is vast, so I offer my points only as ethical ones.

Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

Data protection: Despite the above, I think companies should be extremely limited regarding what data they are allowed to store about people. The fact that millions of lines of code in various places churn through my online activity and that Google, Amazon, etc. have a virtual model of me should not be allowed. For example, Amazon should not be allowed to record the history of what I browse. I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Now, I understand that there are a great deal of complicated parts of this, especially when it comes to things like expressing dissident political views, government surveillance, etc. and I know how ill-formed my point is. I suppose that by offering these views for criticism and rebuttal I want help clarifying what I truly think.

TLDR: Unregulated, anonymous activity that is largely without personal consequence is not a good thing. People should be as liable for what they do online as if they did it on TV or in the middle of the street. 

Edit 1: let me be explicit in saying that I am not claiming innocence of any of these things, but that recently I have been asking myself ethical questions and an uncomfortable with answers I find myself giving, and my beliefs are changing because of it.

Edit 2: I have to go out for the rest of the night, but I will reply tomorrow and give more thought to all points made. Thanks for taking the time to reply, I already have a lot of food for thought.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27524730651.0" user="FaerieStories" delta="False">
    <text>About the libel point:

The internet is not just a publishing platform, it's a communication platform, and it is currently probably the best tool we have for regular citizens to voice their opinions about things. Are you saying that you want to treat regular people as if they had the same influence and responsibilities as national newspapers? If so, then you are actively seeking to destroy the most important principle of our media-saturated world: the idea of free speech. 

In any case, why do you think the whole idea of libel is a good idea for *anyone* - paper or person? Far, far more important than stopping people who say things we don't like from saying those things is preserving the right for them to say them. Censorship is a slippery slope because it means that our opinions have to be filtered through a regulating system. This system can potentially be the very system that the speaker wishes to criticise - which of course can lead to the circular trap of totalitarianism.

Nothing good ever comes of stopping people from expressing views that they hold. Understanding each other is far more important than trying to limit communication.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524815330.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting way to put it. However, I feel that malicious lies or unresearched conjecture that may damage a person should be punished. A person should not be able to identify me personally and say I robbd an old woman if it is not true. I do agree that understanding is key to free speech.

While I do accept that different sources have different levels of impact, I think the ethics of a libellous act must surely be the same no matter the power of the source. I acknowledge that in practical terms this means that the New York Times should get hit harder for libel than my racist grandmother, but I feel the essence is very similar.

I feel that almost all laws can surely be viewed as part of a continuum of a "slippery slope". Surely part of what laws do is try, imperfectly, to create boundaries of what we accept and don't as a society. Is it your opinion that anyone should be able to say anything at all about anyone or anything at any time and any place?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524887284.0" user="FaerieStories" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Interesting way to put it. However, I feel that malicious lies or unresearched conjecture that may damage a person should be punished. A person should not be able to identify me personally and say I robbd an old woman if it is not true.

We currently have no way of telling undeniably whether someone is lying or not. In some cases we have evidence that points one way or another, but in many cases, we simply do not have enough to go on. Education will grind to a halt if we exert our efforts into preventing people from simply being wrong. Censoring what we think are lies will not change the ways of liars, but it will throw a spanner in the works of free discourse and critical thinking: two things which are absolutely fundamental to free and equal society.

&amp;gt;  I feel that almost all laws can surely be viewed as part of a continuum of a "slippery slope". 

All laws have grey areas, but I don't see how preventing people from killing and raping each other could lead to a slippery slope whereby a government can take totalitarian power over a country.

&amp;gt;Is it your opinion that anyone should be able to say anything at all about anyone or anything at any time and any place?

No. If someone came into my house and started insulting me, I should have the right to tell them to leave. However, it is my opinion that we should have a platform to be able to share and discuss views openly, and the internet is that platform. The key to getting along with one another is listening to what views people hold and responding to them: not preventing the views from being said in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
