<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="165660639.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2qmokf/cmv_activity_on_the_internet_should_be_much_more/">
    <title>CMV: Activity on the internet should be much more heavily regulated</title>
    <original_poster>e05bf027</original_poster>
    <original_post>Before I begin, I understand how unpopular the following will be on a site such as this, but I really want to hear opinions. I have, over the last little while, gone from feeling that essentially unregulated and uncensored activity on the internet is a good thing, to believing the opposite. Here are my reasons, though not in a particularly lucid or well-structured form. Also, I understand that the gap between principle and practicality is vast, so I offer my points only as ethical ones.

Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

Data protection: Despite the above, I think companies should be extremely limited regarding what data they are allowed to store about people. The fact that millions of lines of code in various places churn through my online activity and that Google, Amazon, etc. have a virtual model of me should not be allowed. For example, Amazon should not be allowed to record the history of what I browse. I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Now, I understand that there are a great deal of complicated parts of this, especially when it comes to things like expressing dissident political views, government surveillance, etc. and I know how ill-formed my point is. I suppose that by offering these views for criticism and rebuttal I want help clarifying what I truly think.

TLDR: Unregulated, anonymous activity that is largely without personal consequence is not a good thing. People should be as liable for what they do online as if they did it on TV or in the middle of the street. 

Edit 1: let me be explicit in saying that I am not claiming innocence of any of these things, but that recently I have been asking myself ethical questions and an uncomfortable with answers I find myself giving, and my beliefs are changing because of it.

Edit 2: I have to go out for the rest of the night, but I will reply tomorrow and give more thought to all points made. Thanks for taking the time to reply, I already have a lot of food for thought.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27524712828.0" user="_OccamsChainsaw" delta="False">
    <text>Taken together, I feel that your views are not necessarily on the acts themselves, but on the accessibility of said acts. Which is an interesting distinction ethically, because limiting these facets of the internet will not eliminate these problems, they will simply put them away from public limelight. I'll address each point as you do:

Libel: Your stance that the internet is a publishing platform is one interpretation of many. Others can simply view it as a communication tool. When you have a discussion with a friend or a colleague in your living room, you're not "publishing" your views on a topic to them. You're having a conversation. The internet could simply be seen as a means of having this conversation thousands of miles apart, as opposed to the proximity of your immediate surrounding space. You could argue that it is both a publishing platform and a communicating tool. That would account for the difference in, say, news sites vs forums. You can keep your stance that *published* material follows certain standards to avoid libel under the law, this is limited to companies or individuals who operate under a public entity, such as a newspaper or a media outlet online. But forums are largely where "individuals" on the web congregate, and this would be no different to speaking to people in your living room, it's just a larger crowd. You, at a social gathering for work, can talk smack about Sally in HR who is a total bitch and it's not considered libel. It gets kind of murky when you say a person can't talk in forums in similar manners. Even reddit isn't "worldwide public consumption." reddit has it's own population, target audience, and is a fraction of the total world population. Where do you draw the line between friends in your living room, a group of like-minded forum posters, etc? 

Data Protection: I think people personify the idea of "virtual model of myself" when it comes to these online algorithms. Like it's some white collar office jockey who personally browses through your online shopping history and makes his own suggestions, or like you said, some retail clerk who follows you around as you shop in person, then making suggestions. The reality is that it just boils down to a math equation. They're just cross referencing what other people bought as well and make the assumption it has value and immediate need/want as well. Another human being likely has never seen your purchase history. It's just attempting to make your shopping more efficient. And when I look at some of its suggestions, they're completely off. Their "virtual model" of me isn't "me", it's merely a generalized guess. To make a Fight Club joke here, "I am not my shopping history." Maybe a reasoned middle ground is that individuals should have the choice to have these algorithms applied to their shopping? Make it extremely transparent and prompt them from the beginning, rather than require them to understand that's likely hidden in some distant settings on their account?

Piracy: Well, are you more interested in enforcing the illegality of obtaining copyrighted material? Having Google link to them can store the "paper trail", so to speak, of an individual's online presence, which can be used to prosecute or penalize them more efficiently and accurately. By simply not linking to them will not reduce piracy, it will only move it back to communities, such as the "invite-only" Demonoid-type community. Maybe it'll make it harder for the layperson to find this material, but again, it won't really address the issue, it'll just hide it from public sight. So I'm at a loss as to what your view on piracy really is. I guess you could "block" sites with illegal material in their entirely, but this is getting dangerously close to the whole debate of net neutrality and the idea that your ISP can choose what they can show you. Such restrictions would limit piracy, but at what cost. This is again, similar to the NSA debate. Do we monitor each and every citizen at the cost that one *might* do something wrong (e.g., pirate media)? It's a steep cost. 

So what is your core ethical dilemma here? The accessibility, or the act itself? Because your suggestions would essentially cripple the internet at the cost that a fraction of the current users would no longer engage in the acts you are "against" but you have no means of assessing how effectively it would actually limit said actions. And it certainly wouldn't eliminate them.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27524815956.0" user="e05bf027" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for taking the time here. I actually have to go out, but I will look at this tomorrow and reply properly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
