<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="165660639.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2qmokf/cmv_activity_on_the_internet_should_be_much_more/">
    <title>CMV: Activity on the internet should be much more heavily regulated</title>
    <original_poster>e05bf027</original_poster>
    <original_post>Before I begin, I understand how unpopular the following will be on a site such as this, but I really want to hear opinions. I have, over the last little while, gone from feeling that essentially unregulated and uncensored activity on the internet is a good thing, to believing the opposite. Here are my reasons, though not in a particularly lucid or well-structured form. Also, I understand that the gap between principle and practicality is vast, so I offer my points only as ethical ones.

Libel: Essentially the internet is a publishing platform. If a newspaper or other media outlet has to obey the laws of libel and defamation, should an individual who is publishing things publicly not have to do the same? As an example, earlier I read a comment in a thread about Ted Nugent. The comment made a fairly strong statement regarding his sexual preferences. If this was on TV or in a newspaper, the outlet would be in seriously dodgy territory. In this case, an anonymous person can say anything and gets to live by different rules, despite the intention being to publish their view for worldwide public consumption. I think this is wrong.

Data protection: Despite the above, I think companies should be extremely limited regarding what data they are allowed to store about people. The fact that millions of lines of code in various places churn through my online activity and that Google, Amazon, etc. have a virtual model of me should not be allowed. For example, Amazon should not be allowed to record the history of what I browse. I see this as akin to having a shop assistant follow you round a store with a camcorder as you browse and believe that companies who do this should be heavily prosecuted.

Piracy: I understand that the issue of piracy is a complex one, but I feel that a growing attitude treats all information in digital form as almost a right. I think this is wrong, and that all copyright laws should be equal regardless of whether someone sells fake DVDs from their car boot, or runs a torrenting site. I believe that Google should not list any sits that link to illegal copyright infringement, and that they are complicit in the violations of law.

Now, I understand that there are a great deal of complicated parts of this, especially when it comes to things like expressing dissident political views, government surveillance, etc. and I know how ill-formed my point is. I suppose that by offering these views for criticism and rebuttal I want help clarifying what I truly think.

TLDR: Unregulated, anonymous activity that is largely without personal consequence is not a good thing. People should be as liable for what they do online as if they did it on TV or in the middle of the street. 

Edit 1: let me be explicit in saying that I am not claiming innocence of any of these things, but that recently I have been asking myself ethical questions and an uncomfortable with answers I find myself giving, and my beliefs are changing because of it.

Edit 2: I have to go out for the rest of the night, but I will reply tomorrow and give more thought to all points made. Thanks for taking the time to reply, I already have a lot of food for thought.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27525286445.0" user="Alterego9" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is when you say things like "Essentially the internet is a publishing platform", or compare it to a system of distributing DVDs. 

Which are definitely true, but other than all of these, the internet also happens to be the nervous system of our entire society, where we study for college, create art, buy groceries, pay taxes, criticize the government, find partners,  etc. And it's getting more and more vital. 

As one good article has put it:

&amp;gt;The internet is important, but the copyright wars treat it as a triviality: like cable TV 2.0; like the second coming of the telephone; like the world's greatest pornography distribution system. Laws such as the Digital Economy Act provide for disconnecting whole families from the internet without due process because someone in the vicinity is accused of watching TV the wrong way. That would be bad enough, if the internet were merely a conduit for delivering entertainment products. But the internet is a lifeline for families, and giving some offshore entertainment companies the right to take it away because they suspect you of doing them wrong is like giving Brita the power to turn off your family's water if they think you've been abusing your filter; like giving KitchenAid the power to take away your home's mains power if they think you've been using your mixer in an unapproved way.

&amp;gt;The internet is the best – and often the only – place to publish all sorts of information, and yet England's high court judges have decided that the entertainment industry can compile blacklists of sites they don't like and get court orders demanding that service providers block them without a hearing, much less a trial. 

&amp;gt;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/blog/2013/mar/28/copyright-wars-internet?CMP=twt_fd 

(recommended to read the rest of it, it's good stuff.)

It's a fact of modern life, that the same Internet, (and often the same websites), that serve as our main publishing platform and DVD distributor, also happen to be platforms of our our most intimate discourse, of a billion vital practical utilities,  and securing civil liberties. You can't regulate all facebook posts as news articles, and all Google links as cable channels, because there are billions of them, mingled with our entirely innocent, (and often vital) means of communication. 

Even now, these supposedly too lax laws regularly lead to hobbyist artists' Fair Use creative works being censored away from the net through DMCA takedowns without due trial, or people losing their private data because it was on a file storage system that apparently didn't take down pirated files agressively enough. Corporations like Google can choose between these two options: censoring innocents with agressive takedown systems, or getting censored for being too slow. The third option would be to supervise all data transmission manually, that would take millions of employees and drive them to bankrupcy.  

You say you care about the principle, not practicality, but when practically executing your principles is physically impossible, and attempting to do so involves casually demolishing much more important principles, then your principle sucks. 

Ultimately, libel laws and copyright laws were written because they made sense at the time. It's not just that the theory behind them could have been phrased to sound vaguely fair, but their results **were evidently fair**. When spreading news was in the hands of a handful of journalists, then a handful of unintrusive regulations that limited very few people in very minor ways, could have a great net social benefit. 

Likewise, when a handful of factories could mass prduce books, casettes, CDs, etc., then it made sense to give printing monopolies over individual works to their authors, to maximalize their profits. 

 But when everyone has a printing press in their pocket, insisting on upholding the same benefits at the price of breaking our civilization's nervous system, messing with large numbers of innocents, just for the sake of keeping the status quo and protecting a few relatively trivial special interests, exactly that kind of balanced fairness is sacrificed on the altar of "Following the Principle". 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
