<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1660398859.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/rgk3yj/cmv_web_30_is_just_a_zoomers_realization_that/">
    <title>CMV: Web 3.0 is just a Zoomer's realization that "Punk" was a subculture that existed before they did.</title>
    <original_poster>Defiant_Dickhead</original_poster>
    <original_post>All Web 3.0 is a call to decentralize the digital ecosystems that were built in Web 2.0. Instead of using Google and Facebook, users will create their own digital ecosystems. Hmm sounds a lot like the punk subculture that rejected postmodernism and consumerism in the 80s and 90s. 

Don't buy CD's. Make your own vinyl records! Don't buy music. Make your own music! Don't buy food. Grow your own food! I swear, Bill Maher is right when he accuses Zoomers of being the generation that thinks nobody ever lived before they did. 

Web 3.0 is just catchy nonsense that explains how YOU CAN TOO build your own digital ecosystem away from the prying eyes and centralized control of BIG TECH. Well, sure, you could do that. IF you were a programmer that was so inclined AND had a lot of disposal income to build your own digital ecosystems. There's a reason why Google and Facebook exist and most people use them: because they can't or don't want to create their own products all the time. 

Web 3.0 just seems to be a scammy premise that promises that people can "decentralize" the internet and own their own data and blah blah blah. That's not how it works. You're never going to "own" your personal data unless you essentially become a digital version of an Amish person who never uses the internet unless it's in their own homemade ecosystem. 

Also, as more and more actors move into the space to create their own ecosystems disconnected from "big tech", there will be a power law distribution on who consolidates power and influence with those new ecosystems. In effect, you're trading Google or Facebook for another 3rd party...a 3rd party which will STILL have centralized control over your data and use of their system as a customer. And no, blockchain (which is just a lame version of SQL) isn't going to solve for this. There will always be a party that acts as a controller for the data and systems that make up the ecosystem. Doesn't matter if it's Google, Facebook, or your whatever new Web 3.0 platform becomes the next player.

Again, this all just sounds like the Punk subculture that advocated a DIY ethos. Tell me the difference between the punk subculture and the Zoomer's wet dream of a "decentralized internet" a la "Web 3.0".

Go ahead and change my view but please spare me any lofty generalized nonsense about how Web 3.0 will cure cancer and save the whales.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38494931131.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>How many zoomers or millennial or people in other generations know what Web 3.0 is? I’m a very online “zoomer” and I have no idea.

Most people including gen Z don’t interact with cryptocurrency, even fewer do stuff with NFT, and WTF is Web 3.0? Because these things depend on shared value, people who have bought into it are trying to hype these things to limited success</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38494951463.0" user="Defiant_Dickhead" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone that I know that is into crypto, NFTs, and web 3.0 is a Zoomer. Or on that figurative line between millennials and zoomers. Anecdotal sure but your example is anecdotal too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38495022176.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>Most men aren't Shakespeare, but Shakespeare is a man.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/11/11/16-of-americans-say-they-have-ever-invested-in-traded-or-used-cryptocurrency/](https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/11/11/16-of-americans-say-they-have-ever-invested-in-traded-or-used-cryptocurrency/)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

16% of Americans, 31% of those 18-29, 43% of 18-29 edit: OF MEN have i**nvested in, traded or used a cryptocurrency**. That doesn't mention NFTs or Web 3.0 which are probably much smaller, nor does it ask how involved they are using crypto. Did they buy a little bit or are they hardcore?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38495129537.0" user="Defiant_Dickhead" delta="False">
    <text>Still a heavy distribution in Zoomers / tail end millennials. Interesting that it seems to be predominantly asian and hispanic young men that are buying crypto. For matters of definition I consider 23 year olds and younger to be zoomers because zoomers were born 1998 or later. So I'll concede the point that there are plenty of late millennials that are part of this trend. Not just zoomers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38496185089.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>but it is Gen Z people who use cryptocurrency, which is a couple notches more accepted above Web 3.0. I could not find polling from a gold standard polling firm about NFTs or Web 3.0

above I dropped "of men" from 43% of 18-29%. Even if we assume everyone who traded crypto is involved in Web 3.0 (which is obviously not true) that less then a third of the 18-29 yr old cohort.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
