<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1669442084.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/rlxxr8/cmv_kim_potter_is_guilty_of_2nd_degree/">
    <title>CMV: Kim Potter is guilty of 2nd degree manslaughter</title>
    <original_poster>StoopSign</original_poster>
    <original_post>The facts of the case aren't really disputed. She thought she grabbed her taser but grabbed her gun instead and shot Daunte Wright while he attempted to flee. Potter knew that it wasn't a lethal force scenario by *intending* to grab her taser and yelling "taser." If her years of experience taught her to use lethal force she would have not attempted to draw the taser, and she wouldn't have cried on the ground knowing she'd made a mistake. That's what it was. A mistake. A deadly mistake. 

"A person who causes the death of another by any of the following means is guilty of manslaughter in the second degree and may be sentenced to imprisonment for not more than ten years or to payment of a fine of not more than $20,000, or both:

(1) by the person's culpable negligence whereby the person creates an unreasonable risk, and consciously takes chances of causing death or great bodily harm to another;"

 
https://www.revisor.mn.gov/statutes/cite/609.205

Culpable negligence includes mistakes. Even honest mistakes. She's not charged with murder. She didn't need have to have criminal intent to commit 2nd degree manslaughter by way of culpable negligence.

Explained online:

"Examples of culpable negligence might include a healthcare professional giving a patient a medication that they are allergic to; a teacher leaving a class unsupervised, resulting in a child getting hurt; a car driver injuring someone in an accident that occurred while the driver was texting – the list goes on, but the most infamous example of culpable negligence concerns firearms."

https://www.centralflalaw.com/culpable-negligence.html

Edit: Just wanna point out how I'm totally part of a new stereotype of liberals/civil libertarians, who remember the incident, then get all confused by media portrayals of events and the possible mistrial. MSM is indeed bullshit. They never get down in the weeds. CourtTV is a bit better. I've amended my view to have some doubt on the jurisprudence side. I dunno if its a reasonable doubt. Some quantify reasonable doubt as a 10% doubt but every legal professional I've met says that's bs.

I do think everyone in that room except the jury has a pro-police bias. I think DAs were a bit eager to overcharge both Rittenhouse and Potter. This muddies the waters for jurors. I suppose there's something to be said for complaints about "actavist DAs." I want them to focus more on releasing non-violent offenders and not bow to public pressure and end up charging the woman with two crimes that are substantially similar. The key difference is whether she recklessly intended to injure and didn't care if he died (man 1) or whether she acted with disregard for any possible injury he could sustain (man 2). These states of mind are contradictory. Even though they are substantially similar. So the defense can easily assert a state of mind that falls short of culpability

I don't believe in lengthy sentences. 3yrs on the protective cop n snitch block is enough if convicted</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38551412093.0" user="MrCappadocia" delta="False">
    <text>She's not guilty of anything.

"(1) by the person's culpable negligence whereby the person creates an unreasonable risk, and consciously takes chances of causing death or great bodily harm to another; or"

&amp;amp;#x200B;

The "and consciously" part is what matters. She didn't consciously reach for the gun. She unconsciously did.

She intended to use the Taser. She shouted that she was going to use the Taser. All EVIDENCE shows \*her conscious choice\* was to reach for the Taser.

Her reaction, however, was to reach for her Gun. That was her acting unconsciously. She wasn't even \*aware\* the gun was in her hand. This is why she called it a Taser.

"I'll taze him! I'll taze him. Tazer Tazer Tazer!" Right in the video.

This was an unconscious "decision" and therefore does not meet the requirement of the law.

No reasonable person can think she CONSCIOUSLY chose to shoot that man with a gun in the face of OVERWHELMING evidence that she did not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38551712108.0" user="Matinee-Idol" delta="False">
    <text>The defense argued your point - that to be guilty she had to be aware she was holding her gun.  The prosecution argued that she did not have to be aware she was holding her gun. The judge did not resolve this dispute leaving it to the jury to figure out. From a certain point of view it seems that the judge left it up to the jury to figure out what the law is - which is never the jury’s job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38573935438.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;She wasn't even *aware* the gun was in her hand. This is why she called it a Taser.

Do you really belive this? Tazers and guns feel very differently in the hand, on top of the huge weight difference.

&amp;gt;No reasonable person can think she CONSCIOUSLY chose to shoot that man with a gun in the face of OVERWHELMING evidence that she did not.

She reached for the tool on the opposite side of her body from the other tool. This shit is drilled into cops. Saying tazer was just to cover her ass.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
