<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1669442084.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/rlxxr8/cmv_kim_potter_is_guilty_of_2nd_degree/">
    <title>CMV: Kim Potter is guilty of 2nd degree manslaughter</title>
    <original_poster>StoopSign</original_poster>
    <original_post>The facts of the case aren't really disputed. She thought she grabbed her taser but grabbed her gun instead and shot Daunte Wright while he attempted to flee. Potter knew that it wasn't a lethal force scenario by *intending* to grab her taser and yelling "taser." If her years of experience taught her to use lethal force she would have not attempted to draw the taser, and she wouldn't have cried on the ground knowing she'd made a mistake. That's what it was. A mistake. A deadly mistake. 

"A person who causes the death of another by any of the following means is guilty of manslaughter in the second degree and may be sentenced to imprisonment for not more than ten years or to payment of a fine of not more than $20,000, or both:

(1) by the person's culpable negligence whereby the person creates an unreasonable risk, and consciously takes chances of causing death or great bodily harm to another;"

 
https://www.revisor.mn.gov/statutes/cite/609.205

Culpable negligence includes mistakes. Even honest mistakes. She's not charged with murder. She didn't need have to have criminal intent to commit 2nd degree manslaughter by way of culpable negligence.

Explained online:

"Examples of culpable negligence might include a healthcare professional giving a patient a medication that they are allergic to; a teacher leaving a class unsupervised, resulting in a child getting hurt; a car driver injuring someone in an accident that occurred while the driver was texting – the list goes on, but the most infamous example of culpable negligence concerns firearms."

https://www.centralflalaw.com/culpable-negligence.html

Edit: Just wanna point out how I'm totally part of a new stereotype of liberals/civil libertarians, who remember the incident, then get all confused by media portrayals of events and the possible mistrial. MSM is indeed bullshit. They never get down in the weeds. CourtTV is a bit better. I've amended my view to have some doubt on the jurisprudence side. I dunno if its a reasonable doubt. Some quantify reasonable doubt as a 10% doubt but every legal professional I've met says that's bs.

I do think everyone in that room except the jury has a pro-police bias. I think DAs were a bit eager to overcharge both Rittenhouse and Potter. This muddies the waters for jurors. I suppose there's something to be said for complaints about "actavist DAs." I want them to focus more on releasing non-violent offenders and not bow to public pressure and end up charging the woman with two crimes that are substantially similar. The key difference is whether she recklessly intended to injure and didn't care if he died (man 1) or whether she acted with disregard for any possible injury he could sustain (man 2). These states of mind are contradictory. Even though they are substantially similar. So the defense can easily assert a state of mind that falls short of culpability

I don't believe in lengthy sentences. 3yrs on the protective cop n snitch block is enough if convicted</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38548745109.0" user="robdingo36" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with you in your understanding and application of the law in this situation, the primary argument is more about whether her actions were negligent or intentional.  Tasers and firearms are kept on opposite sides of their duty belts to specifically help prevent such mix ups from happening.  This is a universal training practice with basically every department that carries both.  They also feel completely different in your hands and have a totally different weight.  They are very obvious which one you have in your hand.  Because of how much training goes into making sure you KNOW which tool you're grabbing from your duty belt, the argument is being made that there's no way it could have been an accident.

That said, I don't know how many times I've walked into a pull door because I tried to push it open, and that's about on the same level of stupidity of the mistake made.  The only difference is misusing a door makes me look like an idiot, while mistaking your taser for your gun people wind up dead, or, 2nd degree manslaughter as you stated.

Ultimately, I have a feeling this is where the trial is going to land, and it's going to piss a lot of people off because they believe it was an intentional act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549434569.0" user="zuluportero" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't she yell "taser" before firing? Pretty strong evidence that it was unintentional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549554155.0" user="robdingo36" delta="False">
    <text>Which is one of the reasons why I think they'll find it as 2nd degree manslaughter.  But the fuck up is still pretty monumental, and police have a real bad wrap right now for shooting suspects when they shouldn't have, thus why I think there will be a huge public outcry if the jury goes that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549547201.0" user="StoopSign" delta="False">
    <text>2nd degree manslaughter doesn't require intent. People who don't read the post comment on the post, then other people vote it to the top without reading the post. 

The underlying mindsets involved in criminal law goes like this

Simple Negligence---&amp;gt; Culpable Negligence---&amp;gt; Recklessness --&amp;gt; Intent.

The mindsets for charges she faces are the middle two.

You picked the two that aren't involved in the case at all.

Edit: Gross negligence and Criminal Negligence are synonyms with culpable negligence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549605904.0" user="robdingo36" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're the one who didn't read what I wrote.  I was agreeing with your assessment that 2nd degree manslaughter is the appropriate charge in this case, and will likely be found guilty of it.  As far as I can tell, Ofc. Potter showed no intention of using her gun.  She was intending to use her taser and made a horrible, tragic mistake.  However, she was culpably negligent because there are so many obstacles set up to differentiate between a taser and firearm, and yet she still accidentally grabbed the firearm instead.

That said, there are plenty of people out there who are claiming that because there are so many obstacles between the two, that the only way she could have used her firearm instead of the taser was if she did so on purpose, or intentionally, which would be 2nd degree murder.  I believe that she will be found guilty of 2nd degree manslaughter, but the people who believe it was intentional are going to complain that there was intent to harm with the pistol, and it wasn't an accident, are going to be very upset, and this is what they are arguing about.  I don't know anyone who's saying she's innocent in this matter.  It's all a matter of to what degree she's guilty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549693648.0" user="Forthwrong" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 2nd degree manslaughter doesn't require intent.

I'll quote the relevant parts from the [State's proposed jury instructions](https://www.mncourts.gov/mncourtsgov/media/High-Profile-Cases/27-CR-21-7460/Proposed-Jury-Instructions_1.pdf) (emphasis added).

True, the Instructions provide that:

&amp;gt; It  is  not  necessary  for  the  State  to  prove  any  intent  on  the  part  of  the  defendant  to  kill  anyone.

Intent to kill is not required, true, however, she must have intended to do what she did:

&amp;gt; Second, the Defendant caused the death of Daunte Wright by culpable negligence, whereby the  Defendant  created  an  unreasonable  risk  and  ***consciously  took  a  chance***  of  causing  death  of   great bodily harm.

&amp;gt; “Culpable  negligence”  is  ***intentional  conduct***  that  the  Defendant  may  not  have  intended to be harmful but that an ordinary and reasonably prudent person would recognize as involving a strong probability of injury to others.

How does she engage in "intentional conduct" and "consciously take a chance" at shooting someone when she didn't intend to shoot him?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549834794.0" user="StoopSign" delta="False">
    <text>Oh i thought you meant to kill. My bad on that. She intentionally reached for her belt and fired. She consciously reached for her belt and fired *something* so she took a chance. She would have been just as liable for any injuries he could've sustained from the tasers.

Were these instructions part of the trial?

Just how i see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38550012725.0" user="Forthwrong" delta="False">
    <text>I do emphasise the "consciously took a chance" part, but it's important to note, "consciously took a chance" doesn't mean she consciously took _any_ chance – it's that she "consciously took a chance of causing death of great bodily harm." As in, that she consciously and intentionally drew her gun.

1 . If you regard Tasers as deadly force, you run into problems in another part of the Instructions:

&amp;gt; Minnesota  law  provides  that  no  crime  is  committed,  and  a  police  officer’s  actions  are  justified, only when the police officer uses deadly force in the line when necessary to: 

&amp;gt; (1) Protect the police officer or another from apparent death or great bodily harm; 
 
&amp;gt; (2) Effect the arrest or capture, or prevent the escape, of a person whom the peace officer knows or has reasonable grounds to believe has committed or attempted to commit a felony involving the use or threatened use of deadly force; or  

&amp;gt; (3) Effect the arrest or capture, or prevent the escape, of a person whom the police officer knows or has reasonable grounds to believe has committed or attempted to commit a felony if the police officer reasonably believes that the person will cause death or great bodily harm if the person’s apprehension is delayed. 

&amp;gt; As to each count or defense, the kind and degree of force a police officer may lawfully use in protecting themselves or another, effecting arrest or capture, or preventing escape, is limited by what a reasonable police officer in the same situation would believe to be necessary. To determine whether or not the actions of the police officer were necessary, you must look at those facts known to the officer at the precise moment she acted with force.

Where there are arguments to be made for points 1 and 3. For point 1, she had to prevent the other officers from being dragged (i.e. great bodily harm). For point 3, it is a felony for an individual to flee police officers while those officers are engaged in the performance of an official duty.

2 . If you regard Tasers as less-than-lethal weapons, it's problematic to say that Taser usage is an unreasonable risk and involves a strong probability of injury.

3 . Regardless of how lethal you think Tasers are, there still remains an argument to be made about whether a reasonable officer in her position would have used the Taser.

---

Yes, jury instructions are an integral part of jury trials, and everything I've quoted appeared in the final jury instructions, although that hasn't been publicised in PDF format yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38551549161.0" user="GravitasFree" delta="False">
    <text>If fleeing an officer is a felony in this situation, would this event be considered a felony murder (suicide)?  It looks like the wisconsin statute for felony murder includes a section for battery against officers of the state,  so maybe the fleeing part isn't as important as the possible harm that could have come about as a result of the scuffle beforehand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38551343694.0" user="openyoureyes505" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The only difference is misusing a door makes me look like an idiot, while mistaking your taser for your gun people wind up dead, or, 2nd degree manslaughter as you stated.

I wholeheartedly agree with this, however, had the "victim" not tried to flee, we wouldn't be talking about this, and that needs to be factored into the situation. 

We a society that agrees when the criminal escalates the issue, they take on the responsibility for the added violence. 

She made a mistake, and needs to suffer consequences, but they should be light considering he was the reason she had to reach for a weapon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38551476464.0" user="robdingo36" delta="False">
    <text>For anything a suspect may do, there is what's known as a 'reasonable response.'  Using a taser to stop and detain a fleeing suspect is a reasonable response.  The use of force, whether it's as simple as merely being present, all the way up to use their gun to shoot a suspect, is 100% the responsibility of the officer.  Hell, anytime my hand touched any weapon on my duty belt, I was writing out a use of force report to justify my actions.  And if my actions exceeding the justifications, then you better believe I was going to be held accountable.  It doesn't matter if a suspect was goading me, or trying to get a rile out of me.  It doesn't even matter if they escalate the situation to a 5, you do not respond with a 10.  THAT is on the officer, not the suspect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38551651398.0" user="openyoureyes505" delta="False">
    <text>Did I imply in any way the officer shouldn't be held accountable? 

I'm sorry, but I don't think it is OK fight back when you are being arrested, and that should very much be a part of the evaluation. We have two very good examples from Minneapolis to discuss here.

Philando Castile was killed by a police officer and the officer was 100% in the wrong.  Philando did absolutely nothing wrong. That person should go to jail, that was murder.  Where as this situation is different because the "victim" caused the situation by trying to run. That is the difference between murder an manslaughter. By trying to evade arrest you just gave permission to the police to be violent in order to apprehend you. Up until that point, the police need to be respectful that is their job. As long as the officer is doing everything right up until the suspect tries to run, we back the police, period.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38553031042.0" user="MyGubbins" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;By trying to evade arrest you just gave permission to the police to be violent in order to apprehend you.

I feel like this is a giant leap in logic. Do you personally believe that shooting a gun at a fleeing suspect is a reasonable escalation of force?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
