<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="167467659.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2rpevf/cmv_the_events_in_paris_suckbut_the_comic_creator/">
    <title>CMV: The events in Paris suck...but the comic creator wasn't some great martyr or anything.</title>
    <original_poster>anotheranotherother</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please leave the footnote below the following line, but remember to delete this sentence by replacing it with the body of your post. Thank you!

_____
Almost none of his comics were actually relevant or topical in any way.  They were basically just shock-jock level of "oh hey look how insulting I can be, come at me bro."  If he hadn't just been killed by a terrorist, this was basically 4chan level of trolling. Not even that really. 

"I don't have a wife or children or credit" etc, sure that applies to him, but not the other people killed. And, frankly, his comics were awful, pure 100% trolling, but now they're "genius" because he's dead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27542483398.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>The entire magazine is shock jock level stuff so it doesn't really matter that this particular cartoon was shock jock level stuff. The point is they "satire" everyone and everything. Why should Islam be treated special? That was the point. 

He wasn't trolling he was doing his job. You may not like his job and never buy the magazine but obviously there were people who did like his cartoons and that style of humor. He was willing to risk his life to show that Islam isn't special. Whether you agree with that or not that's what free speech is about. Expressing opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27543001395.0" user="DwarvenPirate" delta="False">
    <text>He was a troll. Satire is trolling. Presenting a false or exaggerated narrative to evoke a reaction is what satire and trolls are all about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27543343925.0" user="AgentMullWork" delta="False">
    <text>That's an extremely broad and rather useless definition of a troll.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27546094429.0" user="babacorneliu" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. You may want to check your definitions and examples. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27547368490.0" user="Chronicthehedgebong" delta="False">
    <text>No, no it's not...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
