<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="167467659.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2rpevf/cmv_the_events_in_paris_suckbut_the_comic_creator/">
    <title>CMV: The events in Paris suck...but the comic creator wasn't some great martyr or anything.</title>
    <original_poster>anotheranotherother</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please leave the footnote below the following line, but remember to delete this sentence by replacing it with the body of your post. Thank you!

_____
Almost none of his comics were actually relevant or topical in any way.  They were basically just shock-jock level of "oh hey look how insulting I can be, come at me bro."  If he hadn't just been killed by a terrorist, this was basically 4chan level of trolling. Not even that really. 

"I don't have a wife or children or credit" etc, sure that applies to him, but not the other people killed. And, frankly, his comics were awful, pure 100% trolling, but now they're "genius" because he's dead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27542755547.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>I'll use the most extreme example I can think of.

Let's look at Rush Limbaugh.

Rush isn't merely a shock jock, he (or at least his public persona) stands for everything I think is fouling the political life of this country. I think his speech plays a role in the hatred and fear and insane partisan climate of current right wing politics. He's not just someone I disagree with, but someone I find actively harmful.

However, his actions are speech, and any attempt to silence him through violence would be even more abhorrent to me.

If Rush were subject to the same consistent and credible threats of violence as Charlie Hebdo, and he kept up his work because he did not want to give them power, that is an act of strength and will against an adversary who must not be bowed down to.

There have always been places in the world where people must bow to the violence of the mob. There are places where non governmental "morality police" patrol the streets ready to throw a teenage girl into the back of a van if they catch her wearing makeup.

Right now, in this instance, and maybe in this moment in the world, much of that mob is Islamic defending their religious beliefs. In the 1930s in the US, it was often the mafia, out for material gain. In the past it has come from other beliefs, in the future it will be different yet.

But one thing is consistent. The more we bow to the mob, the more power we give it. Knowingly risking one's life by refusing to bow to this force will always be noble regardless of how frivolous or even terrible the specific action is that one is standing up for, because one will always be above all standing against the power and rule of mob violence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
