<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="167467659.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2rpevf/cmv_the_events_in_paris_suckbut_the_comic_creator/">
    <title>CMV: The events in Paris suck...but the comic creator wasn't some great martyr or anything.</title>
    <original_poster>anotheranotherother</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please leave the footnote below the following line, but remember to delete this sentence by replacing it with the body of your post. Thank you!

_____
Almost none of his comics were actually relevant or topical in any way.  They were basically just shock-jock level of "oh hey look how insulting I can be, come at me bro."  If he hadn't just been killed by a terrorist, this was basically 4chan level of trolling. Not even that really. 

"I don't have a wife or children or credit" etc, sure that applies to him, but not the other people killed. And, frankly, his comics were awful, pure 100% trolling, but now they're "genius" because he's dead.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27542383960.0" user="Will_Im_Not" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;mar·tyr
ˈmärdər/
noun
1.
a person who is killed because of their religious or other beliefs.

You can claim that he wasn't a "**great** martyr", or that has cartoons were irrelevant or not topical. But he was killed because of his beliefs which objectively makes him a martyr.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27542390906.0" user="anotheranotherother" delta="False">
    <text>Hm I guess I made the OP incorrectly.  The main point was meant to be he created a bunch of random/semi-irrational posts and, simultaneously, said he had nothing to fear because of the above/often-reposted comments...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27543704139.0" user="SOLUNAR" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; random/semi-irrational posts 

Could you elaborate on this? or at least show some examples. Every comic ive seen by the media (which im sure they have a bias on) as made sense, and been rational.

which ones do you refer to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27544925277.0" user="slf1452" delta="False">
    <text>Also, the term martyr in 2015 can be interpreted to mean that someone died as a representative of a contemporary debate or issue. In 2015, part of the international conversation has to do with Islamic extremism, especially with regards to their treatment of criticism. Someone who is murdered by islamic extremists for insulting Islam acts as a martyr for that international conversation, regardless of the merit of their artistic content.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
