<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38697407855.0" user="TempestVI" delta="False">
    <text>You tend to use your substitutions wisely or tactfully, having them unlimited would completely ruin that aspect.  Of course you also use them if someone gets injured but mostly teams will play subs smart and not just pick 3 random players and switch them off for 3 more.

Teams also have only a set number of players who can play in certain positions.

There is also a limit to how many players you can have on the bench not to mention all the extra time added on for constant switching players about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38697500552.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!

I think No. 1 does not outweigh the benefits. Substitutions can be used wisely regardless of the number, it simply requires a different strategy.

No. 2 is true in sports with unlimited substitutions

No. 3 doesn’t have to be true. Substitutions could happen without stopping the game, similar to how it’s done in hockey.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38697785037.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>Would you have a changing zone, could you run off the field and another player is able to join from any place?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38698843951.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Probably only through midfield and maybe with other restrictions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38698132777.0" user="shoelessbob1984" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like you're saying soccer would be better if it was a different sport</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
