<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38697383775.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Youre completely reinventing the sport. Its like saying the NBA would be better with 5 point shots. Maybe. But it would be a different game with different kind of players. Unlimited substitutions would cause the players to become far more bulky. Right now they need to last a while. If you can just sub them in and out you can just put a fast strong dude in for 10 minutes then sub him out as soon as he runs out of breath. Maybe that would be fun to watch who knows. But it would be a different game. Most people are happy with the current version.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38697539083.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!

I’m sure people are happy enough with the current version, but that can be said about almost anything until one day things change, people initially hate it and then they can’t fathom the fact that the thing was different before.

I see your point about players become more bulky or similar effects. This has happened in other sports (eg. basketball). However, I see that as a natural evolution and something that benefits the sport.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38697831262.0" user="ImaginaryInsect1275" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a natural evolution it would drastically make it a different game. Like currently you'd have substitutions only on a resting ball situation. If you can exchange players while the game is running you mess with a whole bunch of tactical situations, how does for example off-side work if you can just let an offensive player leave the field while a defender joins somewhere else. 

You'd make it much more fast paces and less technical like idk handball or basketball. However given that soccer has a rather large field and lots of players I'm not even sure that could work like that this easily without changing up almost anything that currently makes the game. In which case one could simply make a different game with that rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38698840313.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>I can still imagine a version of soccer that allows for substitutions happening at midfield under certain additional restrictions.

I don’t think this counts as an entirely different sport, but I see why you’d see it that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38699175046.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>I only played soccer in leagues to before highschool, but I am curious from a professional league standpoint what the level of stamina for players is.  Take marathon running for example.  if you could swap marathon runners out halfway through the race, the pair would have a faster time as the player could go harder knowing they only have half the distance to cover, but for many it wouldn't be that much faster as they have trained their body to sustain a certain level for a certain time, and you can't simply ramp up twice as hard for half the time.

If you were a team that could afford essentially 2 first string quality sets of players, you could swap them out throughout the match and basically have fresh players the whole game.  They could train to take advantage of this new system and emphasize high speed sprinting as they could take more all out blasts knowing they can swap and cool down the moment its over.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
