<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38698947881.0" user="theskyisnotthelimit" delta="False">
    <text>you are profoundly misunderstanding pretty much everything about soccer.  If you don't like soccer, fine, but there are hundreds of millions of people who love the sport just as it is. Better for you personally does not mean better for everyone. If you want soccer to be more like basketball, then just watch basketball.

American leagues are closed off, they have drafts, salary caps, and a single league that controls every aspect of the game. Soccer is decentralized, every league has its own structure, and every country has multiple leagues that promote and relegate between each other (except the US). So the gap between the top teams and bottom teams in terms of spending power is HUGE compared to American leagues. The ONLY leverage that smaller teams have to increase their competitiveness is being able to offer promising players more playing time.

Not to mention that stamina is another huge aspect of soccer strategically. Strength and speed aren't the only hallmarks of athleticism, stamina is important too. Seeing which team will last longer, which team is fitter, and how the game evolves because of that is a massive part of any team's tactics. The need to preserve energy adds a different dimension to the game; a patience and subtlety that simply doesn't exist in American sports. Instead of just constantly running at full tilt, you have to calculate when and where you put the energy in.

Why does the speed need to increase at all? What's the hurry? What do you even mean by "higher quality"?

I'm willing to bet that the average soccer player has a longer career than the average NFLer or NBA player, the constant intensity of those sports wears down a player's body faster. In soccer, top players can keep going well into their 30s if they take care of themselves.

I personally like the reliance on the starting 11, you feel more attached to the players that way. Those are your 11 warriors for the day, it's their opportunity to prove themselves, to show what they can do and how well they work together. You can still come up with creative tweaks and changes without changing players.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38699170968.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>As much as value as I see in your ideas, I find it hard to consider them when the opening statement is that I “profoundly misunderstand pretty much everything about soccer”.

My intention here is not to make the sport better for me, who cares about me? I’m posting a question to learn from what I’m missing.

That said, I already awarded a self based on the idea that soccer is like the marathon of team sports. I like the analogy and makes me think that subs would change the game too much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38699222407.0" user="theskyisnotthelimit" delta="False">
    <text>yeah I saw that after I posted, and I realize I was kind of a dick in my post, so I'm sorry.

As a North American soccer fan, I've grown up hearing how "boring" or "slow" soccer is or how it's not a "real sport" or whatever, so I get kind of defensive, especially since billionaire soccer team owners/investors recently have been trying to change the game to appeal to "new markets" (like the US) while taking existing fans for granted, but that's not your fault!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38703032641.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks stranger, apologies accepted.

I was born and raised in Mexico, so I have no natural interest in ways to make the game more appealing to a US audience. I'm just generally curious about parts of the game that could be improved. Apparently, subs don't fall in this category.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
