<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38865003433.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are already getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

&amp;gt; So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

Yes, sometimes prisoners today are subjected to cruel treatment by their fellow inmates... doesn't make it any less cruel or appropriate to prescribe as something that should happen.

Even if it weren't cruel, it's just not a good punishment.  It's going to traumatize some people and other people might just have a good time with it. If your goal is to disincentivize criminal activity and rehabilitate criminals, it's just not a good idea even if you had no issues giving cruel punishments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865090216.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't matter if they enjoy it. The point is it would additionally provide a public good using people who revoked their bodily rights anyway if their crimes justify it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865361799.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't encouraging prisoners to act out their impulses to rape and abuse on other "acceptable" prisoners result in a net negative for society? The prisoners doing the raping would be pushed further and further into a disordered state.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
