<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38865005004.0" user="mcgucketmcsuckit" delta="False">
    <text>So they’re committing crimes because they can’t get laid so the best way to stop it is to rape them? I feel like this punishment would work better for people who falsely accuse others of rape.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865085270.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>I do see how that follows, but I think despite how damaging rape accusations can be, in my opinion false accusations don't require quite the level of criminal thought to warrant being sentenced to be the public's sex slave.

Also it would make rape victims less likely to accuse real rapists. But this is kind of a separate topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865248360.0" user="mcgucketmcsuckit" delta="False">
    <text>It still seems that this could get blown out of proportion really easily and would be way to hard to properly regulate and control. Also are you saying that while in prison other inmates can rape them whenever or like with sex offenders that can be tracked by the public and just raped whenever after their sentence is done? Because the first one I can see as somewhat kinda ok the second one is just not cool at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38871461319.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't follow that it would blow out of control. Countries have legalized weed and prostitution thereby making it safer without it blowing out of control.

Other inmates would be able to rape inmates who were declared by a judge and jury to deserve it. However if there's a large demand they have to get in line like everyone else, unless they don't mind gangbanging. Only an orderly process would be allowed.

Jumping the line would still be illegal. The analogy for exactly how illegal would be something like if someone made arrangements with a prostitute to have sex but then showed up at a different time than agreed upon, then prostitute refuses because she's busy but the customer rapes her anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
