<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38867070495.0" user="sunlight_gaps" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like the plot of a dystopian society movie. Im really struggling to see how allowing the rape of prisoners would help the incel problem? Correct me if ive misunderstood but..are you suggesting incels would stop being incels because they are ‘allowed’ to legally rape people? Like a reward? Because no sane decent person would want to rape anyone. Instead of saying that ‘oh maybe prisoners shouldnt get raped in prison’ you suggest its actually *encouraged*? I wouldnt wish rape on anyone. I can understand wanting to torture criminals who have committed the *absolute worst* crime imaginable with indisputable evidence but I cant even see the logic in this one. How on earth can you say “prison sex slave” and still not question yourself</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38871535593.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>I am questioning myself; that's why I wrote this CMV.

Prison would be encouraged only on the prisoners who deserved it *beyond a reasonable doubt*, as overseen by the legal system through judge and jury. This normalization and regulation of prison rape on the worst criminals would I think stop the illegal prison rapes on inmates who don't deserve to be raped. All the rape would be directed to only to prisoners who legally deserve it anyway.

I agree that no well adjusted decent person would rape anyone anyway, but none of those incel terrorists ever stopped killing people or inciting murder online because it wouldn't be decent, so I think giving them an orderly and regulated access to not be celibate might be a way to get through to them, since clearly, common sense and decency doesn't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38871562320.0" user="sunlight_gaps" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not see how it would be a reward to those “incels” or anyone who would be even open to the idea of raping someone? No one deserves rape. If anything there are other forms of torture that do not include rape or *rewarding rapists*. It’s concerning you would have to think even twice about this tbh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38871632767.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a reward so much as an optional privilege. Once they expend all that pent up anger on prisoners hopefully they'll go do something else that isn't plotting to kill people.

No one deserves rape? What about pedophiles, fathers who locked their children in basements to keep as sex slaves, mothers who electrified their children and stuffed them in the freezer? Absolutely no one could do anything to deserve rape? I find your statement puzzling.

*rewarding rapists*

They wouldn't be rapists because assuming they follow the legal process, the state is revoking the prisoner's ability to withhold consent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38872020642.0" user="sunlight_gaps" delta="False">
    <text>a rapist is a rapist, doesnt matter if its “legal”. Your logic is so flawed. What evidence is there that being ‘allowed’ to take out disgusting desires would stop them from doing it to innocent people? Serial killers dont stop at one murder and normally rapists dont stop at one victim. If people are having thoughts about wanting to kill or rape they need psychological help, not encouragement and feeding their ideas. “Optional privilege” *privilege*? Still not making your argument sound any less like its a little reward or treat for terrible people. They are still terrible people even if they are committing disgusting acts on other terrible people. Rape is so horrific I dont think anyone deserves it. I would rather someone be put into isolation for life or another punishment that they are hurt physically. I dont think rape should ever be considered okay and i cant imagine the trauma it  would cause people who have to even watch- almost sounds like that one SCP</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
