<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38864964950.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Aside from this being a clear violation of the 8th amendment, what happens when someone is wrongfully convicted, and now you’ve subjected them to state-mandated rape?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38864970477.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>The state murders innocents all the time. I don't see this as worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38864984034.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good argument to ban the death penalty. It's not a good argument to do something equally bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38864998095.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like we should get rid of the death penalty then, and not add something even more heinous and problematic.

I’m sure you think it’s a great idea until *you’re* the one who’s wrongfully convicted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865114755.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>How would the damage from wrongfully sentencing innocent prisoners to rape be worse as a whole for society compared to stopping mass shooters and lowering prostitution? Wrongful conviction is quite rare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865136338.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>And how would you feel if *you* were the one wrongfully convicted?

You should be okay with losing your rights and body autonomy end endure repeated physical trauma so some fucking incel can get laid?

And what does prostitution have to do with this? Prostitution should be legalized.

Seems like that would be far better solution to the problem that you think legalized rape will solve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865170617.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>If I was wrongfully convicted I wouldn't be okay with being imprisoned either. And especially, as I pointed out still happens, not in solitary.

Legalizing prostitution might actually solve that problem somewhat, obviously no one knows, but I think it would be too expensive still and incels would still be able to justify that they are incels due to the high cost of regularly seeing prostitutes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865275526.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>And just because it happens doesn’t mean that state needs to sanction it and encourage more it.

You seem to have this really twisted view that just because bad things happen, we should go out of our way to cause *more* bad things to happen.

Also, I love how you claim that legalizing prostitution won’t work, but legalizing prison rape will.

One of those is far less problematic and doesn’t involve inflicting extreme trauma on potentially innocent people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38871553908.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>There are plenty of examples where we have to do bad things to stop more bad things from happening. Any time we have to go to war and kill people on a massive scale to defend ourselves is one example.

The prison rape would be free whereas prostitutes aren't is a key difference to converting incels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38868194715.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>What if some incel claims you're discriminating against that group because you're assuming every one of them is a mass shooter waiting to happen? Let me guess, the penal system already makes some similar assumption about some other group and that justifies this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865017215.0" user="mcgucketmcsuckit" delta="False">
    <text>But they only have to die once, not be raped repeatedly for however long the sentence is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38867394529.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>Hmmm.... this kind of seems to be stretching it? You're saying that getting raped repeatedly is worse than dying, but then we wouldn't see inmates choose to be raped over being killed, but when presented with that option I've never heard anyone choosing to be killed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
