<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589731500.0" user="fanningmace" delta="False">
    <text>What about stemless wineglasses that are made of relatively thick class? Are you against all wineglasses or just a certain ilk?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589781659.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>Primarily the stemmed ones. I own a set of stemless wine glasses and they work excellently.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
