<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589673144.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a wine drinker, but my girlfriend loves wine and grew to understand it for quite some time after living in France for four years.

From my limited understanding based on what I remember from her knowledge, the shape of the glass is specifically to help breathe the wine. Part of the full joy of drinking wine is drinking it properly. One of the ways to do that is to let the aromas collect in the glass, which is the reason you shouldn't pour more wine in a glass than half (usually even less) and why the opening at the top of the glass is usually a certain dimension.

As to the rest of the wine glass, it goes toward the entire "mood" of wine. It is more *sophisticated* and perhaps considered to be more "delicate" than other alcoholic beverages, and the glass used reflects as much.

So much about drinking alcohol is about the setting, mood, etc. and wine is no different. I'm not going to drink beer out of a sippy-cup so I'm certainly not going to drink wine out of a normal glass (especially since it loses some of those characteristics I mentioned earlier).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
