<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589663159.0" user="AnonForSenate" delta="False">
    <text>Wine glasses have a long stem so that when you hold it the heat of your hand doesn't warm the wine. The cup also exposes the wine to more air, which enhances the flavor. 

Also the fragility and impracticality is a show that you are doing something special. Wine is over 50%"the experience". It's a show of wealth. 

Also it is much easier to tell if a wine glass is clean.

If you just want to put alcohol in your mouth, there are easier ways. But then why are you drinking wine at all? Instead you can put on a bib and drink swill out of a plastic cup. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589682518.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>I'm skeptical that heating wine with your hand is sufficiently noticeable of flavor enhancement to pass in a blind test. The same applies to it exposing the wine to more air. Shows of wealth are still impractical but even so, can be done in other ways such as by varying quality of wine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589687794.0" user="EmptyOptimist" delta="False">
    <text>Try it.  Pour some wine into a thick-sided glass, and some into a proper wine glass.  Try them both.  See if you can tell the difference.

If you can, drink from whichever you prefer.  If you can't, drink from whichever you prefer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589741647.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>Temperature and air exposition will almost certainly affect the substance and it's taste. No way around it. It works with water, which is much more simple than wine. Same with coffee or beer. I don't know how you could deny that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589795457.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>I certainly would not deny it in the case of large temperature differences, but in the time it takes me to finish most other drinks, even if I am sipping, and keeping my hand on the glass the entire time does not produce a sufficient temperature change such that I can notice a difference in taste compared to when I only put my hand on the glass to get a drink.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589832083.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>Depends a lot on the amount of liquid, time, and the temperature of your hands. You must also consider that the quantity of liquid will be decreasing and that some wine and served chilled. 

The fact remains that it will undoubtedly affect taste overtime. Seeing as the liquid is expensive, why not limit this possibility as much as possible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589754426.0" user="riggorous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but even so, can be done in other ways such as by varying quality of wine.

Every time you come up with rhetoric like this, you should ask yourself: why? Why should other people, who probably live a life so different from yours that it is to you incomprehensible, conform to your ideas of practicality and luxury? Why do you think that you know better than millennia of tradition and lived human experiences? Fundamentally, why should a person who wants to and can afford to spend their life however they want, whether by drinking out of champagne flutes or by chugging straight out of the bottle or by hunting foxes or by going to college and majoring in gender studies, turn around and conform to the beliefs and expectations of some lone rando they've never met? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589787102.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>I apologize about the way my CMV is worded. What I meant to say is that I should not be expected to have wine glasses for business meetings or parties. It should not be an expectation for me to not have those things, nor should it be frowned upon if I do not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589801787.0" user="riggorous" delta="False">
    <text>That's still very vague. A business meeting about wine would reasonably involve wine glasses if you're going to be tasting the wine, for reasons outlined to you by others. A party specifically designed to show off wealth or erudition would also need wine glasses, for the purpose of being luxurious. A party that is not designed to this purpose gets away with red plastic cups, in my experience.

Basically, if your purpose requires wine glasses, duh you're gonna get criticized if you don't have them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589820334.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>I guess my issue is that I'm skeptical that the wine glass actually adds to the experience but is mainly something that society arbitrarily decided people should drink wine out of. I wouldn't expect someone to have a fancy car, even if they could easily afford it, just because it shows off his or her wealth. Furthermore, as a college student, these expectations are placed on me by my peers, even for events such as casually playing video games.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589839800.0" user="riggorous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I guess my issue is that I'm skeptical that the wine glass actually adds to the experience but is mainly something that society arbitrarily decided people should drink wine out of.

I mean, does wearing nice clothes add to the experience, or is it something society constructed? Does proposing to your girlfriend in Venice add to the experience, or is it something society constructed? The raw experience of life is pretty boring: you are born, you eat, you breathe, you excrete, you procreate, and you die. Everything around that husk of human existence - art, science, traditions, the rituals (birthdays, graduations, marriages) that you find important, even the people you love - are mostly social constructs. That doesn't mean social constructs aren't as real as natural laws - indeed, it's not like whole nations kill each other and people spend lifetimes in prison because of natural laws - it just means they can change, and natural laws can't. In regards to your specific question, a number of studies have been done on whether people value the taste of wine more than the ritual of wine, and the conclusions point overwhelmingly towards the reverse ([wine economics is a real thing] (http://www.darkcoding.net/research/wine%20economics_Robin%20Goldstein_vol%203_1.pdf))

&amp;gt; these expectations are placed on me by my peers, even for events such as casually playing video games.

Do you go to fucking Dartmouth? Tell them to BYOB or GTFO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589905760.0" user="UncleMeat" delta="False">
    <text>Thin rims in wine glasses enhances the flavor of the wine because it allows you to more easily get a little air along with the wine in your sip. This helps you to taste the wine better (a huge amount of taste is actually smell). 

Other people have pointed out that the stem helps keep you from affecting the temperature of the wine with your hands. The shape of the glass also helps expose a large amount of the wine to air (vaporizing aromatic compounds) as well as focus those compounds towards your nose. 

These effects are not major. If you are drinking mediocre wine and don't really care about tasting it seriously then it isn't a big deal. But a wine glass **does** have an effect on how the wine tastes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590375667.0" user="happybarfday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;mainly something that society arbitrarily decided people should drink wine out of.

As you can see by all the posts in this thread the reasons for the glass's shape are numerous. Whether or not those reasons have validity in enhancing the experience is up for debate but I don't think you can say the design is completely "arbitrary".

Why else would they take the time to design a special glass though if it didn't really make a difference? Is it all a conspiracy to make people buy more glasses?

&amp;gt; Furthermore, as a college student, these expectations are placed on me by my peers, even for events such as casually playing video games.

Lol, is this really a serious issue? Are your bros complaining that you don't have wine glasses available for the cabernet sauvignon they brought to the deathmatch?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590091237.0" user="SanSerio" delta="False">
    <text>Do you take issue with wearing semi-formal/formal clothing at business meetings and parties?  Do you see dressing in a presentable manner day to day is pointless?  

Even if you don't want to buy into the whole temperature/taste argument, I think it's hard to deny that in a lot of cultures (yours probably included) a wine glass is a very visible symbol of refinement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589762171.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Most wines are best served chilled. And you don't drink them, you sip them, slowly.

It does not take long for warm hands to turn delicious 40 degree wine into disgusting 70 degree wine.

I really don't have much to say for allowing the wine to "breathe" as I am not a wine connoisseur, but my opinion is that while wine glasses may be "lesser glasses", wine is a "lesser drink".

It is not as refreshing as water, delicious as grape juice, nor alcoholic as liquor. Wine is a drink for show, so the glasses should reflect that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589773780.0" user="MrF33" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Wine is a drink for show

You had it going up until that point.

If all you care about is getting drunk or getting hydrated then it would be nothing but grain alcohol and water for you.

&amp;gt;delicious as grape juice

Some people would disagree, I find grape juice to be unpleasant, but a good wine has a much more complex and delicious flavor than a simple grape juice.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27591129115.0" user="Grammatical_Aneurysm" delta="False">
    <text>Man I think wine is super nasty. But I love some grape juice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590300274.0" user="AWildEnglishman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you just want to put alcohol in your mouth, there are easier ways.

I must admit, I'm quite partial to a tankard of absinthe every hour or so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590707911.0" user="SalamanderSylph" delta="False">
    <text>Cheap wine is our standard predrinks, it's not necessarily a show of wealth. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
