<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589735876.0" user="___OccamsChainsaw___" delta="False">
    <text>Of course there's the standard argument that the shape of a wine glass is physically important and improves the actual quality of the wine. But even assuming that it doesn't, who cares? It's part of the experience. It's the same reason I bought a set of copper mugs^1 specifically for Moscow Mules,^2 or a set of Martini glasses just for that drink. The experience isn't just the actual liquid. I'm happier using the appropriate glassware and so are most other people. The why of it doesn't matter at all. 

____________________________________________________

^(1. Cleaning copper is an ordeal, and if you don't do it right your drink will taste like car keys.) 

^(2. One of my favourites. 2 oz vodka and 1/2 oz lime juice poured into an ice-filled copper mug or collins glass, topped with ginger beer and stirred. One of the drinks that popularized vodka in America along with the Vodka Martini &amp;amp;c.) </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
