<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="172456552.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2uocbs/cmv_wine_glasses_are_impractical_inconvenient_and/">
    <title>CMV: Wine glasses are impractical, inconvenient, and should not be used for the purposes of drinking when more convenient glasses/cups are available.</title>
    <original_poster>RobbityBobbity1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wine glasses are incredibly impractical and inconvenient tools for the purposes of drinking. First, they are tall and top heavy. This makes them easier to knock over and spill than ordinary glasses. While their wider base alleviates this a bit, they have the additional problem of being very easy to break, so that if they do fall over, there is a good chance that they will shatter, leaving a mess that is difficult and potentially harmful to clean. On the subject of cleaning, their shape makes them difficult to clean and their fragility makes them difficult to clean well. You cannot get your hand inside them to apply pressure to certain stains, and even if you could, you still can't apply the pressure needed to clean some stains without risking breaking the glass. Furthermore, the stem of the glass is also brittle and serves no practical purpose. For these reasons, wine glasses should not be used or be expected to be used.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27589669904.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>The design of a wine glass most definitely serves a purpose.  The shape of the bowl is designed to trap the vapour and funnel it to your nose when you drink (you know how they say smell is 70% of taste, or something like that?).  The stem is so your hand doesn't warm the drink up too much.  A good wine glass isn't that brittle, that's just the cheap ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589687991.0" user="RobbityBobbity1" delta="False">
    <text>Similar to my response to u/AnonforSenate, I am skeptical that people would notice the difference in taste in a blind taste test comparing a regular glass to a wine glass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589702922.0" user="deadaluspark" delta="False">
    <text>You're not the only one skeptical.  There are major studies which assert that professional wine tasters really have no idea what they are doing and have often rated cheap wines as some of the best tasting, when doing blind tests.

I am also completely skeptical that the design of the wine glass actually does any of the things claimed when we have evidence that the people most knowledgeable about wine really don't know shit about it (at least in terms of flavor).

http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2013/jun/23/wine-tasting-junk-science-analysis</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589729615.0" user="nevrin" delta="False">
    <text>As a test try using a brandy glass (designed such that the heat from your hand warms it, resulting in stronger scent from vapor) and a wine glass. I don't actually know what your results will be as I don't drink wine, but the difference of a degree or two certainly has an effect on beer, and I would be surprised if it didn't also have one on wine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589750970.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree that this kind of thing can easily be applied to tasting and comparing wine, I'm much more interested by the effect of the glass on a single bottle of the same wine. 

I know, from being an heavy drinker, that air exposition and temperature will affect the taste. I don't pretend to be an expert, but I can tell a single wine will taste different under certain conditions. As such, the shape of the glass isn't useless, although the whole snobishery surrounding it very well might. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589769980.0" user="deadaluspark" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As such, the shape of the glass isn't useless, although the whole snobishery surrounding it very well might. 

Oh well all right then, I didn't know that the wine glass was a scientific endeavor.

Oh, except it wasn't?  Wine glasses originated from similar clay goblets, and the thin-stemmed glass ones became a symbol of wealth and aristocracy.  These early wine glasses arrived in around 500AD.  Hardly sounds like a history of invention vested in the *science* of flavor.

I'm not disputing temperature doesn't affect the taste of a drink, it vastly affects the flavor *of any number of drinks, not just wine.*

Considering the history of the wine glass starts in the B.C. era, when we first began to see clay goblets with stems on the bottom, I find it *very, very hard to believe* that any science or true knowledge of how the wine glass affected flavor *ever, at any point* went into the design of modern wine glasses.

Just saying, history paints a picture of the shape coming from the basic type of goblet that was used by pretty much everyone in ancient societies, and not being some kind of scientific endeavor to enhance flavor.  Yes, it's as much snobbery as wine tasters.  We just live in a world where glass fashioned into fancy liquid holders is something almost everyone can afford, not just the aristocracy.

From the Wikipedia entry for ["Wine Glass"](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wine_glass)

&amp;gt;The effect of glass shape on the taste of wine **has not been demonstrated by any scientific study and remains controversial.** It is however believed by some that the shape of the glass is important, as it concentrates the flavour and aroma (or bouquet) to emphasize the varietal's characteristic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589839790.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>That's all very interesting, but completely irrelevant. You've managed to empty three clips in that straw-man, but I've never argued that wine glasses were scientifically engineered or somehow enhanced the taste. 

I simply said *they'll affect the taste* and were, therefore, not necessarily useless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590419795.0" user="aardvarkious" delta="False">
    <text>Wine is a matter of preference. 

No, there is no way to scientifically show that wine kept cold or exposed to air tastes better than warm, non-aerated wine.  That isn't a scientific question.

However, people like what they are familiar with. Most people who enjoy wine learnt to do so using a traditional glass so they could have cool, aerated wine. Most of these people will prefer what they are used to, and so a traditional wine glass would be preferable. 

If you are introducing wine to someone, I doubt it matters. But if you are serving wine to someone who already appreciates it, then it probably does. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27589924080.0" user="UncleMeat" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't what your link says. 

The first study shows that wine *scoring* is bunk, not wine tasting. Everybody knows that scoring is bullshit. Its only done because consumers demand it. But scoring for movies and music and games is also bullshit. The fact that a professional wine taster gives a wine a 91 one day and a 94 the next day doesn't mean that he is a fraud.

The job of a wine taster isn't to score wines, but to *explain* them. He needs to be able to tell a somm or a client that a wine is representative of a certain style or that it diverges from the accepted style in a certain way. He'll be able to do this no problem.

The second study was done on *students*, not experts. It also showed that the participants were fooled (somewhat, I'll get to this) by coloring the wines. No shit. You don't just taste wine blind. You don't expect to white wines to be red. I can trick your eyes into seeing the wrong colors with the proper priming but you wouldn't then say that seeing colors is bullshit. The participants also weren't asked if the wine was red or white. They were asked to *describe* the wine and they used terms associated with red wines when given the dyed white wine. The study found that visual information can override olfactory information, not that you don't get any olfactory information from wines. This study has been widely misinterpreted by popular media trying to drum up views.

The third study finds a link between price and enjoyment. Again, *no shit*. Perception affects actual experience. This isn't controversial. But it doesn't mean that cheap wines and expensive wines are identical or that all wines taste the same. It just means that perception outside of the pure taste of a wine also affects your enjoyment. This isn't just true of wine. Its true of hamburgers, and vacations, and concert tickets, and a million other things you can buy. 

The next study appears to be done on random university students, not experts. Great, undergrads can't tell the difference between wines. This says nothing about experts.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27590662608.0" user="Snafu_Coaxer_2013" delta="False">
    <text>Professional wine tasters are actually incredibly skilled. There's competitions where everyone is given a wine and then asked to say the grape variety, followed by the region, followed by the vineyard, followed by the year, and professional wine tasters, or indeed anyone who is very knowledgeable about wine, do *considerably* better at this. There are quite a lot of people who will consistently get all of those correct, as well, for pretty much any wine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
