<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173157689.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2v3dbt/cmvthe_media_turns_us_into_what_we_consume/">
    <title>CMV:The media turns us into what we consume</title>
    <original_poster>ExploreMeDora</original_poster>
    <original_post>Marshall McLuhan coined the term "the medium is the message." This means that the form of a medium (cell phone vs newspaper) embeds itself in the message, creating a symbiotic relationship by which the medium influences how the message is perceived. McLuhan proposes that a medium itself, not the content it carries, should be the focus of study. He said that a medium affects the society in which it plays a role not only by the content delivered over the medium, but also by the characteristics of the medium itself.


With this concept in mind I ask that you challenge these statements:


1. Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.
2. Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.
3. Watching television makes us less social.
4. Life online gives us popcorn brain.


Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.


I welcome you to come up with other statements to challenge or to develop other counterarguments. Essentially, I believe that our media consumption strongly affects our identity. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27596341021.0" user="deadaluspark" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's hard to disprove, because you're wrong in respect to violent video games, there's a multitude of studies (including long term studies) which show that there is no connection between game violence and real life violence.

And while you're wrong in that respect, you're also right, because you've eaten up this bullshit that the media fed you.

http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/gaming/longterm-us-study-finds-no-links-between-violent-video-games-and-youth-violence-9851613.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596352410.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>But I could probably find an article that attacks claims made by articles like that one. And it will probably sound pretty concrete and valid. It comes down to which you choose to believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596363203.0" user="deadaluspark" delta="False">
    <text>I'll be honest, I think you're fully misunderstanding McLuhan's work.  He didn't ever say we could define how changing communication mediums changed society.  Rather, he even went so far as to argue that we still didn't understand early human writing systems and how they changed society.  He focused on a lot of research of early human communication, and I think that is likely why.

I mean, your argument isn't about what you "choose to believe" it's about whether or not the way we communicate changes how we interact in other, unexpected ways.  Which is not in question, it *always* does.  Everything in the world is changing, all the time.  Nothing is static, everything is in flux.  The question is *how* it changes things, which is rarely able to nailed down to an exact reason.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
