<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173157689.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2v3dbt/cmvthe_media_turns_us_into_what_we_consume/">
    <title>CMV:The media turns us into what we consume</title>
    <original_poster>ExploreMeDora</original_poster>
    <original_post>Marshall McLuhan coined the term "the medium is the message." This means that the form of a medium (cell phone vs newspaper) embeds itself in the message, creating a symbiotic relationship by which the medium influences how the message is perceived. McLuhan proposes that a medium itself, not the content it carries, should be the focus of study. He said that a medium affects the society in which it plays a role not only by the content delivered over the medium, but also by the characteristics of the medium itself.


With this concept in mind I ask that you challenge these statements:


1. Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.
2. Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.
3. Watching television makes us less social.
4. Life online gives us popcorn brain.


Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.


I welcome you to come up with other statements to challenge or to develop other counterarguments. Essentially, I believe that our media consumption strongly affects our identity. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27597243916.0" user="BolshevikMuppet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.

Why would that be true?  Even accepting that the medium is involved, are we really arguing over whether 50 Shades of Gray makes someone more educated than Shindler's List?  Even if you *do* want to make that argument, how are you defining "educated"?  Dimes to dollars I'm both more informed and more educated than most of the population, and I rarely read anything in print.

&amp;gt;Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.

There is no evidence to suggest that.  And there is no significant correlation between the rise of film or video games (the the violent versions of them) and increased violence in society.

&amp;gt;Watching television makes us less social.

Why would it?  Because it's a solitary activity?

&amp;gt;Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.

Maybe, but would that be a bad thing?  Someone able to, and accustomed to, thinking on multiple things at once.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
