<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173157689.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2v3dbt/cmvthe_media_turns_us_into_what_we_consume/">
    <title>CMV:The media turns us into what we consume</title>
    <original_poster>ExploreMeDora</original_poster>
    <original_post>Marshall McLuhan coined the term "the medium is the message." This means that the form of a medium (cell phone vs newspaper) embeds itself in the message, creating a symbiotic relationship by which the medium influences how the message is perceived. McLuhan proposes that a medium itself, not the content it carries, should be the focus of study. He said that a medium affects the society in which it plays a role not only by the content delivered over the medium, but also by the characteristics of the medium itself.


With this concept in mind I ask that you challenge these statements:


1. Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.
2. Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.
3. Watching television makes us less social.
4. Life online gives us popcorn brain.


Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.


I welcome you to come up with other statements to challenge or to develop other counterarguments. Essentially, I believe that our media consumption strongly affects our identity. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27596330182.0" user="hellohellizreal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  a medium affects the society in which it plays a role **not only** by the content delivered .

"not only". It means that both medium and content should be taken into account to estimate the message perceived.

I think the relevant questions are 

* What is the respective influence of the medium and the content on the message perceived?"

* For a given content, What is the influence of the medium used on the message perceived?
 


&amp;gt; Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.

In your first point, you make a statement about the message delivered by a medium **totally** regardless of its content. I think i get you point but i'm not sure it is possible to back up that argument in every case. We can probably agree that reading Cosmopolitan on a print media doesn't make you more educated than reading a serious newspaper on your smartphone.

&amp;gt;Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.

In this statement you are giving information about the content (violence) of the medium (video game) so i am not sure how it could prove your main point. Anyway that is a big question. Many studies are done on that subject but their is no consensus as far as i know.

&amp;gt;Watching television makes us less social.

Your point is that it makes us less social than what? You are not comparing 2 media. Could your statement be "Watching television makes us less social than if we were watching the exact same content on your smartphone?"? That statement is debatable. (people tend to overuse their phone in social situations, etc. )

&amp;gt;Life online gives us popcorn brain.

To relate to your main point, I feel like it is always about comparing media for similar content. The problem is that online life provide content which can't be compared to other traditional media. The constant stimulation of electronic multitasking you are talking about can't be compared to what is provided by newspaper, radio or even TV. About the statement itself, i feel like you are quite pessimistic about the brain ability to adapt.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596433601.0" user="ysl51" delta="False">
    <text>Great analysis</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596478588.0" user="Kaique94" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just gonna add to your post.

* [Long-term US study finds no links between violent video games and youth violence](http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/gaming/longterm-us-study-finds-no-links-between-violent-video-games-and-youth-violence-9851613.html)
* [Video games are not making us more violent, study shows](http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/nov/10/video-games-violent-study-finds)
* [Long-term study finds zero link between violence in video games and real life](http://www.sciencealert.com/definitive-study-finds-zero-link-found-between-video-game-and-youth-violence)

No, violent video games do not make us more violent. And yes, OP, I saw your post where you say "But I could probably find an article that attacks claims made by articles like that one. And it will probably sound pretty concrete and valid. It comes down to which you choose to believe."

Surveys show that over 70% of youth in the XXI century play video games. Do you see that many people acting agressively in the world?

Furthermore, that same argument is used with music, film and television in general. But we were way more violent in the middle ages, or even in the 50s-60s, before all that technology existed, than we are today. Developed countries are far more civilised than those with no access to those things (I don't see ISIS playing Call of Duty).

Media doesn't make anyone anything. It doesn't make us *lazy*. We have gyms! If you're sitting on your couch on twitter instead of working out, it's because *you are lazy*. Nothing to do with technology. If it wasn't twitter, it would be something else. If there was none of that, chances are they'd still be on the couch doing nothing at all but taking a nap.

*You* choose how to live your life. You can use technology and media to your favor, learn and grow as a person, or stay on facebook all day and take naps. That's you. Not media. People just like to use those as an excuse for their piss-ass poor personality, behaviors and to cause sensationalism.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
