<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173157689.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2v3dbt/cmvthe_media_turns_us_into_what_we_consume/">
    <title>CMV:The media turns us into what we consume</title>
    <original_poster>ExploreMeDora</original_poster>
    <original_post>Marshall McLuhan coined the term "the medium is the message." This means that the form of a medium (cell phone vs newspaper) embeds itself in the message, creating a symbiotic relationship by which the medium influences how the message is perceived. McLuhan proposes that a medium itself, not the content it carries, should be the focus of study. He said that a medium affects the society in which it plays a role not only by the content delivered over the medium, but also by the characteristics of the medium itself.


With this concept in mind I ask that you challenge these statements:


1. Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.
2. Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.
3. Watching television makes us less social.
4. Life online gives us popcorn brain.


Popcorn brain can be defined as a brain so accustomed to the constant stimulation of electronic multitasking that it becomes unfit for life offline, where things pop at a slower pace.


I welcome you to come up with other statements to challenge or to develop other counterarguments. Essentially, I believe that our media consumption strongly affects our identity. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27596259876.0" user="bubi09" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your clarification! 

&amp;gt; Reading print media makes us more educated, as opposed to the digital media we revel in today.

Can you explain this? Why does one make us more educated than the other? If anything, with digital media we have access to...well, the whole Internet. On the other hand, a newspaper or a book has a limited amount of data and if it's the only thing we have, then we're limited to what's written in it. 

&amp;gt; Playing violent video games and watching violent films makes us more violent.

While connections have been drawn in some cases, I think this is an unfair generalization. Video games and movies (regardless of their genre) have one thing in common: their main task is entertaining us. If this statement were true, we would have all killed or injured others by now, simply because we've all seen a violent movie (or 100). 

&amp;gt; Watching television makes us less social.

What if we're socializing while watching tv? Movie dates (whether at a cinema or in front of the tv/computer) are a fairly common way to pass the time and bond over shared interests. Not to mention that just because I choose to watch something for several hours, doesn't mean I would have been out socializing if I hadn't been in front of the tv. There's numerous other things that I could choose to do other than socialize, tv or not. 

&amp;gt; Life online gives us popcorn brain.

Can you give me examples or sources for this? Just because you know how to multitask, doesn't mean you feel the compulsion to do so all the time. I would say that any multitasking abilities gained would be beneficial in life offline, as well.    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596284393.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why does one make us more educated than the other? 

With print media we were able to sit and focus on what we are trying to learn. We can read with purpose. Now, with electronic media there is so much distraction (notifications) that we can hardly sit and read an article without scrolling through it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596290469.0" user="bubi09" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; we can hardly sit and read an article without scrolling through it.

Scrolling through a document or article doesn't mean it's distracting. It's so automated at this point that it doesn't even register. Sure, with people who aren't familiar with technology, I can see how it might seem complicated and distracting, but for the vast majority of users it's not an issue at all.

We're used to it. We're used to scrolling, ads, and all those other little things. I would go as far as to say that it's a valuable ability because, contrary what you said in your post, we are able to sit and focus without getting distracted by all the shiny things. We have adapted to this new form of media. 

Do you perhaps have any comments to my other arguments?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27596305907.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>Here is a good article on popcorn brain!

http://www.cnn.com/2011/HEALTH/06/23/tech.popcorn.brain.ep/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27599186464.0" user="NuclearStudent" delta="False">
    <text>It's somewhat of a faux pas to ask somebody to chase around an article, or a video, or any other source without telling someone what they ought to be looking for. This is particularly true on the internet, where you can easily waste an hour or more of the combined time it takes for many people to sift through information.

I can't speak for everybody, but if I don't have a reason to trust a source and a quick scan doesn't reveal any relevant information, I'm not reading the whole thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
