<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27601010060.0" user="nebalia" delta="False">
    <text>I want to represent the other, in that I use twitter mostly for reading and hardly ever tweet.  

I follow people who communicate local or breaking news, and use their links to read outside long reports rather than just piecing it together from tweets.  A quick duck out of twitter and I'm back in with. He connect to understand the tweets.

If a comedian is sprucing their show, I scroll past if they are not in my area. The cost of this being annoying is offset by seeing the announcement that they will be near me, and being able to get tickets before they hit the mainstream press and sell out.

Good twitterers writing over several tweets will make it clear they are doing so, eg 1/3,  if it is not clear, it is the fault of the writer.

You can search by topic. Indeed that is the whole point of hashtags. Click on one of those and it immediately narrows the tweets to that topic.

Ultimately, if you are expecting it to be Facebook or Reddit, you will be disappointed. If instead you look at what it does differently and appreciate that, the features start making sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
