<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27600146137.0" user="not_very_social_guy" delta="False">
    <text>I'll answer you from the position of my own experience. 

I use Twitter as a substitute for RSS feed (RIP Google Reader). Every online newspaper or news site has its account in Twitter where they post links to new articles etc. So basically Twitter provides you links to the information you need, not necessary the information itself.

If you want to separate your feed, you can create various lists, in fact you don't even have to be subscribed to someone to add him to your list. 

Also, living in Ukraine, I want to have reliable information about conflict in the east of my country. I am disgusted with both Russian and Ukrainian mass media and their covering the war in east in particular and international political events in general.

With Twitter, I am able to follow people who'll deliver lots of info at first-hand, and what is more important - it happens instantly. People who I follow are all different people with various (sometimes completely opposite) views on the situation, but hence comes the main advantage: having 20 opinions is definitely better than one. With that amount of info, I usually can distinguish reliable info from utter bullshit (believe me, it is really hard thing to do in Russian-language web nowadays).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27601092605.0" user="electrostaticrain" delta="False">
    <text>If you are using Twitter like an RSS, you might love Nuzzel (http://nuzzel.com). They scrape the links from your feed and put it into a more RSS-y format, but with the context of the tweets as well - there's a feed from friends, as well as friends of friends. You can also set it up to trigger email alerts if more than X number of people tweet a link, or (and this is something I enjoy) to send a digest of the most tweeted stuff from your feed once a day. 

It won't replace the informational tweets that don't contain links, but if you're reading a lot of news via Twitter you really might love it. I'm a huge fan - I follow a lot more designers and people from my industry who post good links because I know I'll get them via Nuzzel. I was a big google reader user and never did get into feedly or any of those - this is my replacement. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
