<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27600883076.0" user="optimum234" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure how to counter this without explaining in very fine deetail how Twitter works which I don't think will be appropriate. But like any other website, Twitter is very efficient and user friendly once you have used it for a while.  

It is like Reddit - in the beginning, I had no idea what any of these inside jokes were. I had no idea what /r/ or /u/ meant. I had no idea why millions of users are on here but most top posts only had 3000  upvotes. What differentiated "Top" and "Best"? and why do I have to open new tabs for every article on here, when it would be far easier if it opened within the page? Now that I am familiar with everything, it is possibly the best website I have ever used to categorise all of my information and sort it from best to worst. 

Twitter is similiar. Most of the problems you list are basic navigation issues which you will figure out with a few hours of use (Honestly I'm pretty surprised you hadn't figured it out sooner, but not everyone is familiar with website design so I'll have to forgive you). The other problems you list are just bad users, and not Twitters fault. 

Once you get used to it, you will begin to see all the little signs that indicate the parameters around each tweet that jumps up. You'll be able to distinguish whether it is someone sharing another users tweet or whether it is their own work. You will be able to see if it is a reply to another tweet. You will be able to notice how many people have shared it or simply liked it, all without doing a thing but looking at it. 

Once you click on it, you will be able to see all of the immediate replies or other replies in the conversation. You will be able to see date, time, who liked it, and even give you the option to reply yourself. 

You can share (Retweet) other peopels work. You can share external links and the Tweet itself will give the details of the link. You can share pictures. You can see which tags are trending and use those tags to get your tweets to a relevant audience. People have even adopted the tagging method as a means of summarizing their tweets, an internally developed tendency that Reddit does so often.

There is so much more that Twitter offers. And I haven't even begun to scratch the surface because I haven't discussed different things people have figured out to do with these options. Once you lockdown the basics you will have a world of options at your finger tips - almost anyone you can think of has a Twitter themselves, or at least their fans do to keep up updated. Once you figure out all of the inside jokes and jargon, it will become even better. It is totally worth putting in a few hours to get used to, just as Reddit is. You'll be amazed how funny some complete strangers can be in 160 characters. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
