<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27600201785.0" user="midnight_thunder" delta="False">
    <text>This is interesting, because I could not disagree with you more, with respect to how I use twitter. 

For me, I'm on twitter almost all day, with it on in the background. However, I don't think I've ever tweeted only but a handful of times. Instead, I follow my favorite sports journalists, athletes, sports teams and the like. I find that twitter is the best way of disseminating news quickly and concisely. If a trade is breaking, I want to know it right away, without having to actively search out an article and read through an entire piece. All journalists tweet their breaking news before releasing the article.


This function of twitter likely extends to all media niches. 

TL;DR twitter has the news you want to know before any other website, and has it concisely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27601243078.0" user="coldfrontin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If a trade is breaking, I want to know it right away

Is there a reason for this? Maybe I'm old but I'm happy to just read about it the next day in local paper.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27601275053.0" user="midnight_thunder" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it comes down to the modern impatience that comes with the ability to communicate instantly. Say the Patriots trade Tom Brady at 3:59pm. At 4:00 it's on twitter. At 4:01 that tweet is on reddit. At 4:05 it's on ESPN with the talking heads. At 4:30 the journalist that broke the news uploads his article. At 6:00am it's in the Boston Globe.

When I see it on twitter, I jump to reddit so discuss the deal. By the time 6:00am rolls around, it's already been analyzed a million times, and is old news. 

I'm a millennial. I need information now, and I need it quickly. I think that's the new normal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27601278952.0" user="coldfrontin" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I disagree. #Deflategate was going strong about 2 weeks after it should have been old news. I'm usually late to the party and I still get bored before people stop talking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
