<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27600678930.0" user="DarnLemons" delta="False">
    <text>It takes a good amount of social infrastructure to start getting into twitter imo. Thats why it appeals mostly to high school and college students. Twitter is designed mostly to keep you in touch with friends or acquaintances you already know in a quick to the point way, and maybe crack some jokes along the way. Trying to make one blind is difficult, and while some people can get a raise out of trying to follow certain subjects or trying to get into the pandering style twitter humor subculture, in my experience its mostly a tool to see what your friends are doing or laugh at some of the jokes they make.

Celebrities are pretty notoriously bad at twitter, I can't really get into most of them. I think a lot both have better things to do, and would rather use material when they need it.

As for symbols, @ is the same as /u/ and having a hashtag is kind of dumb, but is essentially highlighting an important subject or contributing to a large topic a lot of people are discussing, but its become so meaningless that its mostly just used as a buzzword system #blessed</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
