<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173572831.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vc9nj/cmv_twitter_is_nearly_unreadable_and_people/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter is nearly unreadable and people mostly only use it for posting</title>
    <original_poster>aurochs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have tried many times to get into Twitter but I am always astounded by how visually unfriendly the experience is. 

Problems:

* There are so many out-of context sentences with people replying to each other but I can't see what they're replying to unless I click around for a while. Couldn't the replies be grouped with the original tweet without having to click on the name and then click 'details?'

* Some people are writing paragraphs spread out over multiple tweets so this leaves their rant broken up by unrelated tweets from other people. 

* I try to follow some comedians, but their tweets are usually something like "I'm in Chicago tonight, come my show. Now I'm in Minneapolis..."

* No categorization. Subjects are all over the place and common topics are not grouped together.

* Too many weird @symbols and #hashtags and http://links just creates a fatiguing reading experience.

I understand the reasons for all of these issues but they are all problems that have been solved by other platforms like reddit and Facebook. I can't understand why twitter is so popular despite all of these points. It could easily be so much better.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27600040642.0" user="AsaKurai" delta="False">
    <text>You sound like my Dad. It takes time getting used, just like any social media site. Even Reddit is confusing for any new user (it was for me), but you just have to understand that many of the people on Twitter are there to just interact with friends in their own personal lingo and occasional tweet at a celebrity. Limit the people you follow to a manageable amount so your feed doesn't seem so cluttered,and just follow tweets and replies to people more before you start using twitter yourself so you can understand what is going on better. Everything is subjective so hashtags, jokes, memes etc. are all things people use on Twitter that *they* think makes sense. 

The reason Twitter is popular is because it allows people to say things on their mind to try and connect with others who feel the same way. Also the chance to connect with those who are famous, rich, etc. are things that people want since it is much easier than bumping into them in a crowded city for an awkward hello. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27600057747.0" user="aurochs" delta="False">
    <text>Does your dad use reddit? 

As I said, all of the pros and cons you mention are issues that other platforms have dealt with better. Sure, reddit is overwhelming at first but links to web pages and user names are formatted for readability and replies are grouped with the original post. Imagine every reddit comment appearing as a live stream in twitter form... Yikes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27600083336.0" user="AsaKurai" delta="False">
    <text>It's all different because it has to be. I mean if Twitter was like Reddit, why would you use one over another? Twitter is very fast-paced and if you don't use it often you tend to miss out on things. It's why kids have their phone in their hand every 2 minutes because they're constantly tweeting, updating etc. Also i'm not saying you *have* to like it, not everyone likes it for their own reasons, but I don't think it is a bad platform for social media.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27600059022.0" user="appropriate-username" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Even Reddit is confusing for any new user

Wasn't confusing for me. I like this layout.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
