<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173814707.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vhgab/cmv_focusing_too_narrowly_on_the_plot_of_movies/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing too narrowly on the plot of movies is a shallow way of experiencing and critiquing them</title>
    <original_poster>sloggz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often when I see movie criticism, either on Reddit or in person, I see people focusing on critiquing the plot of films. They'll say things like "the story was great, up until *blank* and then it totally ruined it for me". There is also a general focus on spoilers, plot holes, etc.


Now, I don't think there is necessarily anything wrong with people viewing film this way, I just think it's shallow. And I don't mean shallow in a wholly negative way, I just mean it as exactly as it is, shallow, close to the surface, without depth.


Films, as an art-form are an immensely complex and intriguing form of entertainment. They combine all the aspects of music, photography, writing, performing, digital effects and art, set design and sound production into an end result that can often be greater than the sum of its parts. To reduce all of these aspects of film to just the narrative of the story and the literal events of the movie is to ignore and not appreciate a massive part of the experience.


Not that plot isn't an important part of movies. I love movies with complex, interesting plots, but I also love movies without them. A complex narrative is in no way, a pre-requisit to a good movie. Just as it's not a requirement for a good novel or anything. It helps, and it can add to or make a good film even great, but it is not all there is.


Basically, my view is that modern mainstream critiquing of movies - what your family members discuss after leaving the cinema, or what people say around the water-cooler at work, (or what is often said in discussion posts of films at /r/movies, is far too focused on the plot of movies. Movie fans everywhere are doing themselves a disservice and would enjoy the movies they watch more if they changed the way they thought about them.


I equate it to people judging music solely on the lyrics.


So! please, try to change my view, as I am clearly in the minority. Why would it not be better for general audiences in general to be more well-rounded film viewers?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27602267599.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between being a film critic, and having an opinion about a film. If something in the plot interrupts one's suspension of disbelief, that's a legitimate criticism. If the criticism has merit, what does it matter if you consider it "shallow"? 

Not everyone goes to film school, and not everyone views criticizing movies as an academic exercise. If a movie doesn't make a connection with a viewer does it really matter if the viewer didn't like it because of the plot, or casting, or if a viewer didn't like it because it ripped off Battleship Potempkin? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602280599.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I don't think there' anything necessarily wrong with people criticizing the plot, or having issues with it. I love watching people mercilessly take apart the plot holes in bad movies, or in getting caught up in the complexities of a great plot. 


My issue is that this seems to be far too large of a focus for many film-watchers.


If you say that, who am I to judge them for not liking it? It's not that I judge them, I feel bad for them, and I wish that more people challenged this way of thinking more often.



I already used this example in my OP, but I feel like I'm living in a world where everyone judges music primarily on the lyrics, and not the sound of the song. (Except replace music with movies, and plot with lyrics). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602289886.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>Its a subjective thing. For some people things like plot holes, inconsistencies, or irrational behaviour [not supported by the films context] can ruin movies - even if they find the movie otherwise generally enjoyable.

For other people its much easier to suspend disbelief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602304424.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it is subjective. I don't think people are wrong for being so influenced by the plot, I think that audiences in general would find more enjoyment in films if they learned to stop watching them while focusing on the plot. I think film critiques would be doing the general public a service by stressing this point more often.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602352869.0" user="kwprules" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that people go to watch films to escape from reality and to become engrossed in a believable universe. If something happens that makes no sense, this immediately causes viewers to think, "Well damn, this is just a movie and isn't real. My problems still exist and will continue after the end of the movie" rather than continue to be immersed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602365332.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that something that takes you out of the experience is a bad thing, and can ruin the experience. 


I'm not saying that people should ignore their problems with the plot of movies, what I'm saying is that they should also try to broaden their view of what aspects of movies they enjoy. I get the feeling that for some people the plot is 90% of the enjoyment, and the rest is just sprinkles on top. Yes, there are some movies where this is appropriate, but applying this judgement to all movies is narrow-minded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602917527.0" user="ignotos" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that people necessarily derive most of their enjoyment from the plot when watching a good movie.
 
Rather, serious plot problems can be a "dealbreaker", and ruin enjoyment of a movie. Some people are not able to "forgive" plot holes, because the plot somehow provides part of the essential "framework" which allows them to enjoy the movie as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27603224267.0" user="armanioromana" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to differentiate between writing a movie off because of the plot, and not enjoying it because of the plot. To use a cliche example, I completely recognize that the film Avatar was visually stunning, and I appreciate that. But I also thought the plot, and dialog was extremely sub par and I didnt actually enjoy the film *despite appreciating the visual aspects of it*. Similarly, there are some authors that I find to be wonderful writers, but poor story tellers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27603607202.0" user="bgaesop" delta="False">
    <text>I think that splitting up into "90% of my enjoyment comes from the plot, 5% from characterization, and 5% from cinematography" or whatever isn't the best way to look at it. Instead, while all of those things contribute to the quality of the film, it's possible for any of them to be bad enough that it keeps you from being able to enjoy the movie. 

Compare "the plot made no sense" to "the characters were all boring and unlikable" or "the shakycam made me puke".

Which is not to say that a movie might not excel so much in one area that the others can be ignored. I really enjoy kung fu movies for their cinematography and choreography, even when their plots and characterization are completely forgettable.

Overall, I'm not sure I disagree with you, I just hope I can point out another way of looking at the issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602465239.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I think that audiences in general would find more enjoyment in films if they learned to stop watching them while focusing on the plot

The plot is *integral* to the enjoyment for many people of a movie. Yes, these people also recognise awesome effects, great acting, dramatic soundtracks and the like aswell, but... having a realistic plot is necessary to tie those things together and enjoy the movie as a greater whole.

Keep in mind someone with such views is not going to hold a fantasy animation to the same standards as movie that presents itself as a realistic interpretation of some story. And most movies fit on a continuum somewhere in the middle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602477805.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>But why is the plot integral? 

For example, a James Bond or Christopher Nolan movie will tend to have a very complex plot. These movies can also be really good. Now, something like, Under the Skin, or Koyaanisqatsi are also really good films, with minimal (under the skin) or almost no plot (Koyaanisqatsi). 


For this reason I see the plot as being a component of movies, and an optional one at that in some cases. Just as how sound can be a *huge* aspect of some films, even though silent movies exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602496014.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>Because not everyone has the same taste in movies as you, its subjective, you arent going to convince anyone because its just how their brain is wired. Its kinda like trying to convince a lover of one music genre that another is much better.

As I mentioned, the importance of the plot depends on how big a part it is expected to be in a movie. Its all about context. If you portray your movie to be at least a somewhat realistic interpretation of events, then obviously it should be at least somewhat realistic, its really that simple. These people arent actively trying to pick plot holes as they watch - that would ruin a movie in itself, but instead their mind may subconciously interrupt if it notices something that doesnt quite add up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602506740.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that peoples minds are just wired that way.  I used to think in a way that very heavily focused on the plot while discussing or thinking about movies,  this idea to try to focus on other elements has grown in the past few years as I've tried to broaden my film going experience and become a better film watcher. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602515048.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>Dont assume thats all they focus on. Some people just require (depending on the movie and how realistic it should be expected to be) a realistic plot to allow enjoyment of movie as a greater whole. You can still enjoy the musical score or visual effects from a movie with an irrational/broken plot for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602805879.0" user="Panaphobe" delta="False">
    <text>I think movies in general are broadly perceived to be first and foremost about telling a story. Yes, there are many intricacies that can each be considered art in their own right, but the primary goal is to tell a story. There are movies without sound, movies without special effects, movies even mostly without performers - the only thing that *every* movie has in common is that they tell a story. I don't think it's shallow at all to judge a movie if it has a major failing in performing its primary function.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602823786.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>Man, remember that scene where they were all running from the dinosaurs, and the extremely low-resolution, solid turquoise T-rex slid across the screen and the movie started flickering and cut out for 10 seconds and then the T rex turned purple and the characters started screaming, and then it was a different time of day because they reshot the scene later?

That is the VFX analog of plot hole / stupid story / inconsistent behavior etc.  You'd probably not take as much issue with someone saying "I was enjoying the movie but that part really fucked it up for me".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602353570.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>I think your point has some merit, but there's another factor involved: investment of time. The first time you see a movie, you have to pay attention to the story if you're going to understand the movie. Thus, the plot of the movie is going to be a primary focus. If you didn't like the movie, there's a good chance that you didn't like the plot. And if you didn't like the movie, there's very little incentive to watch it *again* and have a chance to notice the symbolism, or the cinematography or the set design, or how well the score enhances the atmosphere. 

There's very few movies I see where I don't notice something new when watching them a second or third time. But if I didn't like the plot, there's a good chance I'm not going to see it again. The time investment for a song is typically three to four minutes. The time investment for a movie is an hour and a half to two plus hours. So maybe criticizing the plot is *shallow*, but I think it's unreasonable to expect someone to watch a movie *they didn't like* again, just to have a deeper critical understanding of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602369595.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not suggesting that everyone who has an issue with a movie just needs to watch it with "plot-blinders" over their eyes and focus on the rest of the movie. 


I'm suggesting that in the initial viewing of a movie, while following along with the plot, they could also be noticing the symbolism or enjoying the cinematography and the set design. These things are just as important to the movie as the plot, and aren't something only to be noticed on a 2nd or 3rd viewing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602391984.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>And your evidence that people don't do this is what exactly? That people don't complain about these things enough? People, generally speaking, watch movies to get engrossed in the universe and the story. Symbolism and nice cinematography and set design are nice things to have, but ultimately the purpose of a movie is to tell a story. I also take objection to your comment on 2nd or 3rd viewings. If you noticed all the symbolism in a movie on the 1st viewing, the movie is probably either absolutely dreadful or just has very little to begin with. The beauty of good symbolism is in its subtlety, so that the viewer can continue to get enjoyment from a work by realizing its presence even after they have finished actually viewing the work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602403758.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I don't exactly have any hard evidence that people don't do this. My view is based on my anecdotal experiences as a redditor, a film review  lover, and general twenty-something year old pop-culture lover.


As to your objection, I'm not trying to say that all aspects of a movie should be clear on first viewing, of course there exist subtlety to films that you might not get until you've seen it for the 50th time, or after you've had kids, or after a near death experience, or for a limitless number of different reasons.


What I don't understand is exactly what you just said "The purpose of a movie is to tell a story". Yes, most films tell stories, and telling a really good story is a sure-fire way to start off on the right foot of also making a really good film, but it's not all of it. Just like painting a picture of a really awesome looking mountain is a great first step in making a really good painting, but it's not the most important, or the most vital.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602421116.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't exactly have any hard evidence that people don't do this. My view is based on my anecdotal experiences as a redditor, a film review lover, and general twenty-something year old pop-culture lover.

You haven't really given any anecdotal evidence either. All you've said is that you often see people complaining about the plot.

&amp;gt;What I don't understand is exactly what you just said "The purpose of a movie is to tell a story". Yes, most films tell stories, and telling a really good story is a sure-fire way to start off on the right foot of also making a really good film, but it's not all of it. Just like painting a picture of a really awesome looking mountain is a great first step in making a really good painting, but it's not the most important, or the most vital.

A movie is not a painting, because a painting is not a medium for storytelling while a movie is. You would never talk about "a painting *about*" something, except perhaps to talk about the themes and ideas conveyed by it, but certainly not when referring to what happens in the picture. Similarly, you would never talk about "a movie *of*" something, except perhaps to talk about things that recur in the movie, but not to talk about the background or scenery. Paintings are about the visuals. Movies are about the plot. These are obviously not the only elements, or even necessarily the most important, but they're the *points* of the media, the reasons why these media exist at all. Everything else is just a framework to help better get across these elements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602437794.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like we're reaching a point where we fundamentaly disagree about something. You state multiple times that the "point of movies is the plot", or that "everything else is just the framework to help better get across [the plot]". This is exactly the view I disagree with. 


I think that everything else about the movie is the point, and that the plot is the framework to get across those elements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602453149.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, keep in mind here I'm using the word "plot" very loosely. I don't mean just the general storyline, I use it to refer to the entirety of the events that happen over the course of a movie.

Secondly, I don't think this is fundamental; we can go deeper. The point of a painting is the visuals. Without the visuals, what do you have? A blank canvas. Take away everything but the visuals, what do you have? A beautiful scene. People make paintings of a beautiful scene, but a painting of a blank canvas would be utterly pointless.

Applying this to movies, what is a movie without a plot? A still frame where nothing happens. What is a movie with only a plot, without cinematography, actors, or soundtracks? I would argue that the closest thing we have to this are books and oral stories. Movies are made based off books and stories all the time; I have yet to see a movie based off of a still frame where nothing happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602462357.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that having some sort of plot (in the loose sense of- things occur) is going to be integral to the making of something which, in the end, can be called a 'movie'. 


My view is not that plots are unnecessary, only that the importance of them is propped up. I've talked to many people with whome it seems their entire enjoyment (the only thing they took away from a movie) is the literal events that took place on screen.


Now, there is nothing *wrong* with this, I just think that they would be a more well-rounded movie watcher, if they opened up their experience of the film to taking in much more than just the plot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602875004.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I don't understand how you can be so sure that these people only take away the plot. What did they say or do to indicate this? All you've said so far is that you hear people complaining about the plot, yet you also deny that you're saying people complaining about the plot is bad. What is it that you are complaining about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602379722.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>So the music is the movies, and the lyrics are the plot, but what is the sound of the song? You criticize people for focusing on the plot without giving any suggestions as to what should be focused on more. The acting? The scenery? The soundtrack? What is it that you think people under appreciate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602393058.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>The plot of a movie is the events that happen within it. I guess I think that people should focus more on how these events are told. 


I'll try to fit my music analogy better to what I'm saying.

Music= Movies

the story of the lyrics= the plot of the film

the prose of the lyrics = the dialogue of the film

how the lyrics are presented (singing/rapping/ spoken word) = the acting

the production of the music = the production design of the film, the costumes, the sets, the CGI, etc.

How the song is cut together = the editing of the movie
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602960699.0" user="Cosmologicon" delta="False">
    <text>Do people routinely discuss songs' production quality or editing? I only hear about that kind of stuff from people who are musicians themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27603169630.0" user="riggorous" delta="False">
    <text>I think the fact that there exists a popular market for the kind of nebulous melodrama filmed by Woody Allen or Wes Anderson et al. is testament that a substantial proportion of casual movie fans does indeed watch films for things other than plot. i.e. I think you may be suffering from confirmation bias.

I agree with you, the 16-year-old Youtube film critic market seems to be cornered by people obsessed with plot holes. However, there are also hard-core (and less hard core) academic film critics, who focus on all sorts of esoteric things, plus people who like talking about characters (such as ships and the bulk of stuff that happens on fandom subreddits), people who focus on the actors, people who focus on the business side of things... Besides, even reviewers who tend to focus on plot (such as a lot of people who review horror or thriller, which is often all about the plot) will discuss non-plot elements if these elements are noticeably exceptional. It's just that a lot of commercial genres rely on plot. There is no hard statistic describing the makeup of the film buff market, so your view may stem from the bias of the environment you are in as much as from any kind of truth about general reality.

Plus, I suspect that the very act of discussing movies attracts a specific kind of person. I don't think that most casual movie-goers discuss the things they see. They watch a film, they say, "I liked that", or "I didn't like that", and they move on with their lives.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
