<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173814707.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vhgab/cmv_focusing_too_narrowly_on_the_plot_of_movies/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing too narrowly on the plot of movies is a shallow way of experiencing and critiquing them</title>
    <original_poster>sloggz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often when I see movie criticism, either on Reddit or in person, I see people focusing on critiquing the plot of films. They'll say things like "the story was great, up until *blank* and then it totally ruined it for me". There is also a general focus on spoilers, plot holes, etc.


Now, I don't think there is necessarily anything wrong with people viewing film this way, I just think it's shallow. And I don't mean shallow in a wholly negative way, I just mean it as exactly as it is, shallow, close to the surface, without depth.


Films, as an art-form are an immensely complex and intriguing form of entertainment. They combine all the aspects of music, photography, writing, performing, digital effects and art, set design and sound production into an end result that can often be greater than the sum of its parts. To reduce all of these aspects of film to just the narrative of the story and the literal events of the movie is to ignore and not appreciate a massive part of the experience.


Not that plot isn't an important part of movies. I love movies with complex, interesting plots, but I also love movies without them. A complex narrative is in no way, a pre-requisit to a good movie. Just as it's not a requirement for a good novel or anything. It helps, and it can add to or make a good film even great, but it is not all there is.


Basically, my view is that modern mainstream critiquing of movies - what your family members discuss after leaving the cinema, or what people say around the water-cooler at work, (or what is often said in discussion posts of films at /r/movies, is far too focused on the plot of movies. Movie fans everywhere are doing themselves a disservice and would enjoy the movies they watch more if they changed the way they thought about them.


I equate it to people judging music solely on the lyrics.


So! please, try to change my view, as I am clearly in the minority. Why would it not be better for general audiences in general to be more well-rounded film viewers?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27602636240.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>Could you give an example of a movie you think got bashed by its plot, but deserved a deeper analysis? A couple movies immediately come to mind as counterexamples. Inception/Interstellar are both movies that come to mind as having plots that are heavily critiqued, but these films are still widely viewed in a positive light on account of their style and performances. Pacific Rim has a pretty dopey plot, but folks love it because of its music and robot vs monster action. A lot of Tarantino films barely have plots at all, but are easily supported by sharp dialog and amazing acting in scenes that basically stand on their own. So at first glance, I kind of reject that the premise of your view is even true, let alone if its justified. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602699787.0" user="TooMuchPants" delta="False">
    <text>What about the two front runners for best picture this year?  *Boyhood* and *Birdman*?

Neither has a great story in my opinion, but I would still consider them both great films.

And I've seen *lots* of criticism of both movies' plots.  I remember in particular on Adam Carolla's podcast, he said that while appreciated the art of birdman, he didn't need to know what happened next.  The people I saw the movie with walked out of the theater saying basically the same thing.

But there's so many great things both movies made me think and feel that had nothing to do with the plot whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602706432.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know anything about Boyhood. Birdman is on my queue, but almost everything I've heard about it has been positive from critics and friends who have seen it. And like you said, its a frontrunner for best picture. Is it really a good example of a film that has received narrow/shallow criticism of its plot without being sufficiently appreciated for its other qualities? Even the critique you described had the critic knock it for its plot, but still "appreciated the art", so I don't think that really fits what OP was describing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
