<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173814707.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vhgab/cmv_focusing_too_narrowly_on_the_plot_of_movies/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing too narrowly on the plot of movies is a shallow way of experiencing and critiquing them</title>
    <original_poster>sloggz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often when I see movie criticism, either on Reddit or in person, I see people focusing on critiquing the plot of films. They'll say things like "the story was great, up until *blank* and then it totally ruined it for me". There is also a general focus on spoilers, plot holes, etc.


Now, I don't think there is necessarily anything wrong with people viewing film this way, I just think it's shallow. And I don't mean shallow in a wholly negative way, I just mean it as exactly as it is, shallow, close to the surface, without depth.


Films, as an art-form are an immensely complex and intriguing form of entertainment. They combine all the aspects of music, photography, writing, performing, digital effects and art, set design and sound production into an end result that can often be greater than the sum of its parts. To reduce all of these aspects of film to just the narrative of the story and the literal events of the movie is to ignore and not appreciate a massive part of the experience.


Not that plot isn't an important part of movies. I love movies with complex, interesting plots, but I also love movies without them. A complex narrative is in no way, a pre-requisit to a good movie. Just as it's not a requirement for a good novel or anything. It helps, and it can add to or make a good film even great, but it is not all there is.


Basically, my view is that modern mainstream critiquing of movies - what your family members discuss after leaving the cinema, or what people say around the water-cooler at work, (or what is often said in discussion posts of films at /r/movies, is far too focused on the plot of movies. Movie fans everywhere are doing themselves a disservice and would enjoy the movies they watch more if they changed the way they thought about them.


I equate it to people judging music solely on the lyrics.


So! please, try to change my view, as I am clearly in the minority. Why would it not be better for general audiences in general to be more well-rounded film viewers?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27602518369.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Films, as an art-form are an immensely complex and intriguing form of entertainment. They combine all the aspects of music, photography, writing, performing, digital effects and art, set design and sound production into an end result that can often be greater than the sum of its parts. To reduce all of these aspects of film to just the narrative of the story and the literal events of the movie is to ignore and not appreciate a massive part of the experience.

Yet all of those things are *dependent* on a good plot.  The complexity of the work of does not imbue it with the magical properties of overcoming it's innate flaws.

It kind of reminds me of the Tacoma Narrows Bridge.  There was a huge effort from hundreds of disciplines that went into it's construction.  It was a thing of beauty but failed because it collapsed, much like the plot line of Battlefield earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602530319.0" user="sloggz" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree completely about them all being dependant on the plot.  What is it about the plot that makes it the King of movie? Many comedy,  or experimental films could have a very simple plot or lack any story,  and they could still be a good movie. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602557271.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an example of a good movie with a bad plot?

Pointing out movies that are good with a simple plot only indicates that a simple plot is not necessary a requirement for a good movie.

&amp;gt;What is it about the plot that makes it the King of movie?

Because presumably a movies intent is to tell a story and/or relate events.  If it fails to do this in an entertaining way the *whole* reason for making the movie fails.

Sure it can have beautiful vistas, compelling actors and jaw breaking CGI but if it fails impart a successful story it has failed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27602691194.0" user="TooMuchPants" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP actually has a point that film isn't primarily a story-telling medium the way, for example, novels are.  In a book, you are reading a story about a guy in a bar.  In a movie, you are seeing a specific guy, who looks a specific way, in a specific bar.  So there's an ontology to it that writing doesn't have.

A good example from this year is *Boyhood.*  I would consider it a great film, but what makes it great isn't the story it tells.  It's the ideas in it.  And Linklater communicates those ideas using characters and dialogue, but I have the feeling that if you read boyhood as a story it wouldn't be very good at all.

Now, you can use film to tell a story and it can be effective, but that doesn't mean that's what film is best at or that's what all movies are trying to do.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27603682831.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And Linklater communicates those ideas using characters and dialogue, but I have the feeling that if you read boyhood as a story it wouldn't be very good at all.

Which are components of the *plot*....

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604013366.0" user="Bufferton" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you have an example of a good movie with a bad plot?

Avatar.

The experience was why I was there, the plot was completely meh/bad. Still consider it a great movie, would not consider it 'failed', if its goal was to show a 'world'. I would also put Prometheus in that same mold.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604041604.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The experience was why I was there, the plot was completely meh/bad.

Avatar?  The movie that had 83% of 292 professional critics give it a positive review with Roger Ebert giving it 4 stars in the Chicago Sun-Times calling it "extraordinary".

The same for Prometheus  It had a 74% approval rating from 269 critics according to Rot ton Tomatoes.

Avatar had generally positive references in regards to the plot while Prometheus wasn't exactly hammered for the plot by critics.

I don't think I would call either good movies with bad plots.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604087731.0" user="Bufferton" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Avatar? The movie that had 83% of 292 professional critics give it a positive review with Roger Ebert giving it 4 stars in the Chicago Sun-Times calling it "extraordinary".

Hardly any of that praise is related to its plot. Just look at its rotten tomato page again. Hell, most of the reviews actively say it was brought down by its plot in some form or fashion. It's no surprise it was called extraordinary, and it was exactly my point that it was, while still having a derivative and formulaic plot at best.

"The film received mostly positive reviews. Review aggregator Rotten Tomatoes reports that 83% of 292 professional critics have given the film a positive review, with a rating average of 7.4 out of 10.[223] The site's consensus is that "**It might be more impressive on a technical level than as a piece of storytelling**, but Avatar reaffirms James Cameron's singular gift for imaginative, absorbing filmmaking."

I bolded the part you left out. As for Prometheus:

"Reviews frequently praised both the film's visual aesthetic and design, and Fassbender's performance as the android David received almost universal acclaim. **However the plot drew a mixed response from critics, who criticized plot elements that remained unresolved or were predictable,** tempered by appreciation for the action and horror set-pieces"

The fact that these movies still have high reviews, as you've shown, gives credence to my point that a movie can still be considered good while having a meh/bad plot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604116345.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>Not at all.

They didn't have *bad* plots at all.  Read those reviews again.  The plots were *criticized* as not being unresolved, predictable.  

&amp;gt;"It **might** be more impressive on a technical level than as a piece of storytelling, but Avatar reaffirms James Cameron's singular gift for imaginative, absorbing filmmaking."

It *might* be more impressive on a technical level.  This isn't really that big of a complaint as there seeing how it *was* impressive on a technical level:) 

No amount of CGI could have helped Battlefield earth, or production value could salvage ShowGirls:)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604141836.0" user="Bufferton" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yet all of those things are dependent on a good plot. The complexity of the work of does not imbue it with the magical properties of overcoming it's innate flaws.

The plots were heavily criticized, and thus not 'good'. Therefore the success of Avatar and Prometheus with critics, even if we accept your premise that critics thought the plots were only meh instead of 'bad', show that well-received movies can overcome innate flaws in plot.

&amp;gt;They didn't have bad plots at all. Read those reviews again. The plots were criticized as not being unresolved, predictable.

Often unresolved plots with holes that are predictable are considered 'bad'. I would point to overwhelming focus of critics of Prometheus on stupid plot decisions characters make, and the large amount of quantifiers people use to say "I like Prometheus in spite of...".

&amp;gt;No amount of CGI could have helped Battlefield earth, or production value could salvage ShowGirls:)

Because Battlefield Earth didn't just have a bad plot. The writing was bad, the effects were bad, the performances were bad, the cinematography was bad, the whole package was bad. Production value is only one aspect, just like plot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604145685.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>Then it dawns on me.

You are just arguing a subjective point.  To you a solid plot is not an important element, to me it makes a movie worth watching again or not at all.

meh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604164664.0" user="Bufferton" delta="False">
    <text>Well of course we are arguing subjective points, the overall CMV is subjective, your original point is subjective, it's subjective statements all the way down...

&amp;gt;To you a solid plot is not an important element

Bit of a reach. Sure I'll watch Tree of Life or Avatar for the beauty of it rather than the plot, but I'll pour over the details of Primer, 2001, or Memento too. I find it's more fun to simply find the aspect the film is stressing, what it is really going for, and try to see if I can enjoy it on that level. Which is why I adore Prometheus for the world and atmosphere it creates, without focusing on the nitty-gritty plot details that seem to bug a lot of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604235465.0" user="sunburnd" delta="False">
    <text>To me I need to have a cogent and compelling plot.

The other elements are employed to help convey that message.

I don't necessarily see a distinction between the atmosphere in Prometheus and the plot as a whole.  They are interconnected and interdependent.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
