<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173977724.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vky2k/cmv_i_shouldnt_get_lasek_surgery/">
    <title>CMV: I shouldn't get LASEK surgery.</title>
    <original_poster>nazedayo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't have any current ocular issues (aside from astigmatism). They are L: -9.5, R: -9.0. This means that I can't function without my glasses or contacts– for all intents and purposes I'm blind without them. As an active rock climber and runner, I'd find replacing my contacts (which I hate) convenient, but have my skepticisms.

I've been hesitant to indulge because most LASEK surgeries will cost $2500/eye, according multiple evaluations at 4 different laser surgery centers. My insurance will only pay for 15% (pre-tax $). I'm saving up to go to MBA in about 4 years, and am not sure getting LASEK now would be a wise investment.

I'm also hesitant because I've heard anecdotes from friends who've had LASEK (not LASIK) that, about 2 months~1 year after their surgery, they went from an average 1.0/1.0 back down to about 0.2/0.3 ish. Still pretty damn good, but makes me suspicious about the quality of the treatment.

I've heard that people experience dry eyes constantly, and am afraid that it may imply bigger problems when I get old.

Lastly, I heard LASEK (not LASIK) hurts like a mother the first day or two.

CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27604979303.0" user="Mannbearpiggg" delta="False">
    <text>I had LASIK 8 years ago and I can say without a doubt, it was the best $3,000 I have ever spent.  Granted, I was about the perfect candidate in terms of nearsighted vs. far sighted, no astigmatism etc. so the doctors said that my surgery would be about as routine as it gets.  Your situation is a bit different in that you have astigmatism, but man, it is so worth it to never have to worry about glasses / contacts anymore and being able to wake up every day and just see perfectly. 

Yes, I thought the surgery sucked, it was a shitty 20 - 30 minutes or whatever it was, but oh so worth it (for me).  I still have 20-20 vision now, and accept that later in life I will probably have to get cheater glasses, but that's a fact of life.  As for dry eyes - yeah it can happen, but having some visene with you is a quick and easy fix.  

If you choose to go with the surgery, good luck with it.  If you don't get the surgery I get it as it's a big financial and life decision that shouldn't be made lightly.   </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
