<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173977724.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vky2k/cmv_i_shouldnt_get_lasek_surgery/">
    <title>CMV: I shouldn't get LASEK surgery.</title>
    <original_poster>nazedayo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't have any current ocular issues (aside from astigmatism). They are L: -9.5, R: -9.0. This means that I can't function without my glasses or contacts– for all intents and purposes I'm blind without them. As an active rock climber and runner, I'd find replacing my contacts (which I hate) convenient, but have my skepticisms.

I've been hesitant to indulge because most LASEK surgeries will cost $2500/eye, according multiple evaluations at 4 different laser surgery centers. My insurance will only pay for 15% (pre-tax $). I'm saving up to go to MBA in about 4 years, and am not sure getting LASEK now would be a wise investment.

I'm also hesitant because I've heard anecdotes from friends who've had LASEK (not LASIK) that, about 2 months~1 year after their surgery, they went from an average 1.0/1.0 back down to about 0.2/0.3 ish. Still pretty damn good, but makes me suspicious about the quality of the treatment.

I've heard that people experience dry eyes constantly, and am afraid that it may imply bigger problems when I get old.

Lastly, I heard LASEK (not LASIK) hurts like a mother the first day or two.

CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27604551252.0" user="I_Have_Dementia_" delta="False">
    <text>If you have had lasik you can become an astronaut, now why does that matter? Because the safety regulations to become an astronaut are ridiculously stupid, if you have ever had a kidney stone you can't be an astronaut. So I kinda consider that being a stamp of approval from a third party organization with strict regulations that could only lose by approving of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
