<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="173977724.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2vky2k/cmv_i_shouldnt_get_lasek_surgery/">
    <title>CMV: I shouldn't get LASEK surgery.</title>
    <original_poster>nazedayo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't have any current ocular issues (aside from astigmatism). They are L: -9.5, R: -9.0. This means that I can't function without my glasses or contacts– for all intents and purposes I'm blind without them. As an active rock climber and runner, I'd find replacing my contacts (which I hate) convenient, but have my skepticisms.

I've been hesitant to indulge because most LASEK surgeries will cost $2500/eye, according multiple evaluations at 4 different laser surgery centers. My insurance will only pay for 15% (pre-tax $). I'm saving up to go to MBA in about 4 years, and am not sure getting LASEK now would be a wise investment.

I'm also hesitant because I've heard anecdotes from friends who've had LASEK (not LASIK) that, about 2 months~1 year after their surgery, they went from an average 1.0/1.0 back down to about 0.2/0.3 ish. Still pretty damn good, but makes me suspicious about the quality of the treatment.

I've heard that people experience dry eyes constantly, and am afraid that it may imply bigger problems when I get old.

Lastly, I heard LASEK (not LASIK) hurts like a mother the first day or two.

CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27603842245.0" user="flynavy88" delta="False">
    <text>I had Wavefront-Guided PRK (essentially LASEK) and it cost $2000/eye

For me, it has been worth EVERY single cent I spent.

I used to have terrible eyes too: around the -7.00 range in both eyes.

My life has been changed completely.

I no longer worry about bringing glasses or contact lens solution - if I go drinking and crash on a buddy's couch, I don't have to worry about any of that anymore.

It was also a huge boost in self confidence - both superficially in terms of not having to wear glasses but also in just feeling good about not having to wake up and look for my glasses.

The cost isn't a big deal - sure, I paid for it out of pocket, but I'd rather pay more for the best doctor than go cheap and have complications from the surgery. My eyesight is too valuable to risk.

Dry eyes do happen in the first year or two - they went away for me after about 2 years and I rarely if ever need eye drops anymore. And the eye drops come in little disposable vials which are convenient to carry if you ever need to.

My eyes started at 20/15 and are now around 20/20 after 5.5 years. Again, compared to where I was before where the 20/400 line was a pipe dream, and it's a world of difference.

Other complications? Well it allows me to fly high performance aircraft</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27603922923.0" user="nazedayo" delta="False">
    <text>This would be exactly why I want to do it. Good to hear the dry eyes go away after about 2 years– I've heard it lasts indefinitely, but guess that's a case-by-case thing. Lucky you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27604526525.0" user="MIBPJ" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to second ALMOST everything he said. Lasik was one of the best decision I ever made. Before getting lasik I dealt with glasses and contacts for years. This meant losing/breaking glasses, spending time in the morning putting contacts in and out, worry about contacts before going to into a pool, etc. The cost of lasik well justifies getting rid of those hassles not to mention that the actual monetary savings. 

I remember for the first few weeks after lasik I would be just so thankful to wake up each morning having crystal clear vision. Its now become normal to me but even several years later it will pop into my head and I would think about how awesome lasik is. Cannot recommend it enough.

The one part of my experience that differed from the commenter above is that I never experienced dry eyes. Actually I differed a little from your post in that I really didn't have any pain either. Maybe lucky? I also paid significantly less than you stated (about half) but that was in part because I was referred to doctor by my sister. If you happen to live in Southern California I recommend the doctor. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27606261047.0" user="sas318" delta="False">
    <text>Just curious, what was your prescription? It's usually low prescriptions who praise it to death and experience little to no dry eyes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27607321686.0" user="MIBPJ" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't low but I also didn't have extremely poor vision. I can't actually recall what my prescription was. I want to say I had 20/70 vision but I could totally be missing the mark. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
