<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27618274852.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>There are a lot of problems that pop up when you switch to 24/7 service.

For example, a lot of transit systems will use nighttime closures to do maintenance work.  If you run 24/7, you need to do re-routings on train lines.  This is a huge issue for the NYC subway (which is 24/7) and results in every station having like 3 posters about train route changes for maintenance work.

Likewise, with busses, if you have them come in every night, you only need one shift of maintenance workers to do all the busses.  If they're going 24/7, you need multiple shifts to get them all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618280876.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>So we will slow down the transit a little during the slower hours. 

Mechanics i agree could be an issue but it is another job created. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618288059.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So we will slow down the transit a little during the slower hours.

It's a lot harder than that.  When the whole system is shut down, you can be very aggressive about doing stuff that you can't do when a train is whizzing by on the next track.  What took 4 hours in a closed system can take a full weekend on a single closed line.

&amp;gt;Mechanics i agree could be an issue but it is another job created.

And another tax and/or fare hike.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618362679.0" user="Clark_Savage_Jr" delta="False">
    <text>This whole CMV seems to ignore that public services aren't optimized based on their personal preferences and that increasing service increases the cost to someone.

Nothing is free and running an empty train isn't an efficient use of public funds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619214151.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>It is if that means you can be guaranteed a train at any time of the day or night.

Furthermore, it can be free; cash in the peace dividend and take it out of the military's budget.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619222410.0" user="Clark_Savage_Jr" delta="False">
    <text>Without some specifics on usage and availability for a specific location, it's hard to talk about whether a schedule is efficient or feasible.

I would love to cut military spending. Diverting that money to other projects isn't even remotely free, it's just shuffling money we don't have into other pockets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619232170.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>It is, though. It's recovering money that is currently simply going to waste, and putting it to productive use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619249863.0" user="Clark_Savage_Jr" delta="False">
    <text>If I borrow $100 a week gambling, I'm being very wasteful. If I stop gambling and use the money for better tasting meals, that money wasn't free, it's reallocated to something less wasteful.  

If I invest it and earn 8%, that 8% is "free" but the $100 isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619279386.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>A personal budget is not comparable to a government, or even moderately sized organisational budget.

We already have the income streams in place. Any reorganisation of spending is, itself, still spending. Even if it is to reduce taxes or pay down debt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619275905.0" user="frotc914" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it can be free; cash in the peace dividend and take it out of the military's budget.

First of all, this is the real world's transit, not the bus system of Candyland. And second "we can find the money" doesn't mean "it's free". I could come up with 10,000 better uses of military spending, and about 9,900 of those are better than running empty buses and trains. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619281235.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Yet you have not yet done so, and thus the military budget is still there for reallocation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619314819.0" user="auandi" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but it can be reallocated to many many things. For example building a new line. I think building a new line/expanding an existing line is probably a better use of funds than switching to the costly practice of 24/7 operation. Building a new line could bring in hundreds of thousands of new users, expanding hours would only add hundreds. 

And once again, the military budget is FEDERAL. Cities and states can not cut the military and so they can not use the money going to the military.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619371239.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Money can be transferred between levels of government. In fact I've never heard of new rail lines being built _without_ federal contributions.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619673243.0" user="SoMuchMoreEagle" delta="False">
    <text>But what about the day-to-day operation of the trains?  And of bus lines?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619413709.0" user="frotc914" delta="False">
    <text>So what is your point? There is a cost to running public transit 24 hrs. It's not free. The fact that we *might* reallocate money from elsewhere is meaningless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619464965.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>It is free. We do not have to raise funds. We have existing funds that are currently going to waste.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619492432.0" user="frotc914" delta="False">
    <text>If you buy a surf and turf dinner instead of flushing $100 down the toilet, that doesn't mean it's free. You could have had 10 other meals or 3 tanks of gasoline or something else that was more useful or enjoyable. This ridiculous logic is borderline trolling. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619556926.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Again, a government's budget is not compatible to an individual's. The structure of that flushing is entrenched, and will not stop until it is reallocated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619278906.0" user="auandi" delta="False">
    <text>Transit money comes out of city budgets.. cities tend not to have a military budget to cut. If they need to find the money, it will more than likely come out of education as that's generally the largest city expenditure. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619280052.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27622110030.0" user="Bratmon" delta="False">
    <text>Are you trying to tell me that money is not finite?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27622133442.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it isn't, but no, I was pointing out that transit funds come from all three levels of government.

Also, what dystopia funds education municipally? That's absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618626455.0" user="pipocaQuemada" delta="False">
    <text>In Boston, there's only one set of tracks per line for the T.  In order to do any sort of inspection or work, the train can't be running.  So actually getting 24/7 service would necessarily require them to build a parallel set of tracks for each line, so inspection and repairs can happen.

That's not going to happen, particularly because of how underfunded the T is and how unwilling the state government has always been at actually funding it.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619066810.0" user="Tullyswimmer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's not going to happen, particularly because of how underfunded the T is and how unwilling the state government has always been at actually funding it.

Also it's be like the big dig, only worse. And on that note, I don't even know if there's anywhere underground left to put the T...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619098901.0" user="skatastic57" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Mechanics i agree could be an issue but it is another job created.

This is the broken window fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618626393.0" user="kapparoth" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to run the same network as in the daytime. Most European cities that do have nighttime services have a separate night network with longer headways and fewer routes, often converging to the same central stop in order to make the transfer easier. I agree, though, that metro is poorly fit for the 24/7 services, but there is mostly no need for it, with the smaller amounts of the passenger traffic that can be handled with busses and trams just as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618846388.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>Either way, a 24/7 system is going to be expensive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618888035.0" user="kapparoth" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's obviously not that expensive if some of the cities I'm thinking of are the Czech ones (Prague, Brno, Plzen...), and the Czech Republic is not the wealthiest country of the EU. 
It's something of a cultural difference between the US where a bus is a looser cruiser, and the EU where a semi-decent mass transit system in any large-ish city or town is something natural.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618899647.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>Those are big cities, and the system is still probably greatly reduced during off-peak usage. Remember also that transit ridership is typically much higher in poorer countries, so they might see more (not fewer) fares off-peak.

I'm not saying it can't be done. Or even that it's necessarily a bad idea. I am saying that having 1 passenger on a bus or train is ridiculously inefficient, and if a typical city wants to expand its service to times when usage is very low, it has to find the money somewhere.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27622676419.0" user="rnisly" delta="False">
    <text>I live in the Denver metro and it costs $2.25 for local. If they raised it to $5 after 10p it would make it worth it to stay open and keep the bums off the 15 which does run 24/7 </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
