<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27619054519.0" user="eNonsense" delta="False">
    <text>This whole thread is why I moved to Chicago. There are 24 hour buses on most all of the main streets and the Red &amp;amp; Blue trains are also 24 hours. Sure they're on a less frequent schedule, but it's the future so I can stay in the bar until my phone says the bus is about to come.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
