<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27618262198.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>Except in NYC most buses would be empty. It would be cheaper to get a cab for the occasional person traveling late at night.

For trains, you also need to shut down lines periodically for maintenance. It would be much harder to get that done if you couldn't do it at night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618267803.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Cheaper than $6 to get home? In NYC? 

Also lines would be slowed down to meet lesser demand if need be. But they would still always be running </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618629013.0" user="briguy57" delta="False">
    <text>He means it would be cheaper for the city to buy you a cab to yor destination than it would be to spend all night driving around with Jo one on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618717988.0" user="imagineALLthePeople" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;they would still always be running 

Cheaper than $100,000/hr to keep everything running</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619057365.0" user="fanningmace" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also lines would be slowed down to meet lesser demand if need be. But they would still always be running

This is exactly how it works now. Lines are "always running" and are slowed down when there is lesser demand (like, say, from 2am to 5am.) They are still always running, though. Just instead of 30 minutes between buses to meet demand, there is now 3 hours between buses to meet demand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618326532.0" user="TulasShorn" delta="False">
    <text>I do not think NYC is a good example for you to bring up, since the trains run 24/7. And it is super useful, and I am glad to live here.

Its in the second paragraph:
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_City_Subway</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618411363.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>The MTA also have [more debt than many entire countries](http://nypost.com/2015/02/11/subway-costs-leave-mta-34-1-billion-in-debt/), and the service changes required for regular maintenance are chaotic to say the least.  I love the subway too, but it just isn't feasible for most cities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618518714.0" user="CantabKBH" delta="False">
    <text>Transit debt is as financial a problem as it is political. Taking the MTA as a basis of comparison, funding comes from highways tolls, fares, and real estate taxes. Tolls and fare are never going to be enough to support the MTA (which I'd argue is public good) and real estate taxes are notoriously volatile. However, we know that mass transit, particularly subways, have immense ancillary economic benefits - higher property values, increased economic activity at transit hubs. Many transit agencies just are not able to ascertain funding that stems from these benefits. For example payroll taxes, property tax levies earmarked for transportation, specific 'transit taxes', etc.. would all be better ways to fund subways because they reflect the real benefit of the service - the reason the MTA doesn't have them (outside of RE tax) is because they are politically unsavory, not financial unfeasibility. Also, afaik, Albany has been turning the screws on the MTA budget for a while which doesn't help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618524770.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>All of this is true.  But it doesn't change the point I was making, which was that there are, at most, maybe half a dozen transit agencies in the world than could possibly pull off what the MTA does every single day.  Even if you fix the funding, other agencies simply don't have the talent, the infrastructure, or the customers who know how to deal with a new service change on their commute every other week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618542133.0" user="CantabKBH" delta="False">
    <text>I'm in 100% agreement. Was less responding to your points, but to the notion (kinda a straw argument) that because Transit Agency X runs a deficit and has debt that it is therefore not feasible and should be tanked. Most areas in the US, as you say, just don't have the adequate density (the "permanent market") for subways. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619115547.0" user="skatastic57" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; which I'd argue is public good

It's a publicly provided good but it is most certainly not a public good.  
A public good has two characteristics:

1.  It is non-rivalrous in consumption which means that my using it doesn't impede anyone else from using it.  This might be true on a close to empty car but for all those instances where you're pressed up against someone while standing it is definitely the case.

2.  It is not excludable.  This means that there's no good way to keep people from using it.  It's quite easy to keep people from using public transportation.

Classic examples of true public goods are lighthouses, military defense, street lights, and clean air.

I'm not saying transportation doesn't provide positive externalities for which a subsidy makes sense but that doesn't make it a public good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618518442.0" user="klparrot" delta="False">
    <text>Not all of them run through the night. And if you count limited service, well,many larger agencies already have a night network of routes providing sparser coverage and reduced frequency, so if OP wants that, he's already got it in many cities. If he wants full service, well, that's just a ridiculous waste of money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618646269.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>I meant that literally. 24/7 makes sense in NYC and maybe 2 or 3 other cities in the world, but not in the vast majority of places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618525042.0" user="the_omega99" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean "cheaper"? Cabs are pretty expensive. It's very easy to get a cab fair $20+. Bus fair for the same distance might only be a couple of bucks and the kind of person who would use a bus late at night probably uses a bus regularly and thus pays for monthly passes.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618731350.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>they meant in terms of spending. running a bus cost more money to the economy than taxi-ing everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
