<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27618254098.0" user="ulyssessword" delta="False">
    <text>How many riders would they get?  How much would the additional trips cost?  What does that work out to, in terms of cost per passenger?  Are people willing to pay that much?

I trust that the people running public transit have thought of those questions, and have decided that it isn't worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618256791.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I trust that the people running public transit have thought of those questions, and have decided that it isn't worth it

This is the government, they can't do anything right. 

I think they would get a fair amount of riders, however, even if money is lost, it would employ more people and be a general public good. Perhaps fares could increase past 1am if they need to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618266821.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is the government, they can't do anything right  

Yet here you are asking "them" for more of what "they" do.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618269025.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Making ways to improve it </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618551877.0" user="Wehavecrashed" delta="False">
    <text>That quote really sums up OP. He really has no idea what he's talking about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618269129.0" user="Crooooow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is the government, they can't do anything right.

He says while riding on a train provided by the government, and asking for them to give him more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618301528.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is the government, they can't do anything right.

Yet you're using a government funded form of transportation and are advocating for the expansion of the hours that this service is provided. It seems like the government has done something right by offering public transportation that you're obviously using. Anyways,

&amp;gt;I think they would get a fair amount of riders, however, even if money is lost, it would employ more people and be a general public good. Perhaps fares could increase past 1am if they need to

What makes you think there would be a fair amount of riders, especially during weekdays? I'm not sure how late public transportation runs in your city, but where I live trains and busses are virtually empty late at night which is why they don't run 24 hours a day. If they're losing money, you say that it would employ more people and "be a general public good". Well, if the public transportation system is losing money, then where is the money going to come from to pay these extra employees? Even if fairs were increased, with such lower ridership late at night they would have to be increased to the point that people wouldn't bother using public transportation unless they absolutely have to in order for the public transit system to break even, or the extra money would have to come from taxes which then means that people are paying for a service through taxes that really isn't needed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619140099.0" user="Smooth_McDouglette" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; even if money is lost, it would employ more people

No, if money will be lost it would never go forward in the first place. Are you saying they would just hire more people to make up for the lost revenue? Huh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619281208.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree with OP, but I believe the point is that government programs don't have to be independently profitable, and have a stimulus impact by employing people which is independent of whether they are or are not profitable.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
