<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27618376775.0" user="Herculian" delta="False">
    <text>One of your arguments was "if people want it". I don't want it. Not only do I not want it, I would be opposed to it. Here's why:

The government has limited funds, if you spend more on public transportation it has to come from somewhere else. I would rather the money go to schools or to cleaning up the environment, than helping drunk people get home at 2am. I realize it wouldn't only be drunk people using it, but they would be a large portion of the people who would be using this service. 

I am also opposed to this because it would encourage drunk people to stay out later at night, which has no benefit to society, other than employing the people who will now have to manage them (sounds like a great job, huh?). Drunk people staying out later means we need more police officers. Police officers get paid even more than bus drivers, where does this money come from? If taxes would be raised to pay for this I would vote against any politician who was in favor of it. The other alternative is taking money from another government program. Which one is less worthy? 

One last point. Given that the government has limited funds they need to try to spend them to provide the maximum benefit to the most people. People who would use public transportation outside of current operating hours are a very niche group so most of the populace would not benefit from this at all. Furthermore, there are already services that cater to this group. Heard of Uber? People who stay out late aren't forced to walk home. There are functional businesses already in place, so why should the government get involved? Especially since the government is notoriously inefficient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619032908.0" user="tangowhiskeyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Youre really mad at drunk people and fail to see the enormous number of people that work low paying jobs like servers and bartenders and retail and stocking that cant afford a car that need transportation home when they get off at 2am</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619279085.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Youre really mad at drunk people and fail to see the enormous number of people that work low paying jobs like servers and bartenders and retail and stocking that cant afford a car that need transportation home when they get off at 2am

Those people exist, but there are far more people who need transportation during the day than there are who need transportation in the middle of the night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619696239.0" user="Herculian" delta="False">
    <text>Actually I'm not mad at drunk people at all. I'm one of those people who goes out drinking in the city at night. 

My position is that it isn't the government's responsibility (at the cost of taxpayers) to take care of people who make the decision to stay out late drinking. I also mentioned that I realize it would not only be drunk people using this service, but based upon the demographics I see when I take public transportation late at night, I don't see the benefit of providing this service outweighing the cost that would be required to provide it.

Main point: the money would be better spent elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619049136.0" user="eNonsense" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am also opposed to this because it would encourage drunk people to stay out later at night

This sounds like a similar argument to sex education will encourage teenagers to have sex. One of the points of this thing is giving people who drink at night an alternative to driving.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619708638.0" user="Herculian" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with your first point but partially agree with your second. 

In response to your first point, I don't believe my argument is akin to sex education as sex education does not provide people the means to have sex. At a very young age we all have a basic sense of how it goes down, whether or not we understand all of the details, where as if we don't provide public transportation late at night it simply isn't an option.  Additionally, I base this off of discussions I have with people I know in their 20s (I am 25 myself). "How are we going to get home?" and "When does the metro close?" always come up. If the metro ran 24/7 we wouldn't have to worry about how late we stayed out. There would be no preset time limit on how late we were out, and I can see this encouraging people to push their limits further.

In response to your second point, I agree that providing more public transportation later at night would reduce drunk driving which is unquestionably a good thing. The issue I come back to is the cost. Is the amount of money WE (taxpayer dollars = our money) would have to spend worth the reduction in drunk driving incidents? My position is that the money would be better spent elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
