<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="175548882.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2wimdu/cmv_public_transportation_should_run_247/">
    <title>CMV: Public transportation should run 24/7.</title>
    <original_poster>Keep-reefer-illegal</original_poster>
    <original_post>We live in a world that is no longer 9-5. Businesses stay open later, friends can reach us with a portable device simply by typing on a mini keyboard. It doesn't make sense that public transportation isn't 24/7. Here are some reasons why it should be 24/7:

1. Very few buses run at 2 am for last call, I feel like if nothing else, running buses later let's responsible drunk people take public transit instead of driving home. 

2. It would benefit the working poor who may work night shift 

3. As mentioned before our world is now 24/7 

Those are my arguments. 

I encourage you all to change my view 

Edit: by transit I am including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation, not just buses. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27618249985.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>Where's the money going to come from? The vast, VAST majority of the workforce do indeed work 9-5 or thereabouts. To pay for drivers that late at night would require enough passengers to negate the extra you'd have to pay them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618259019.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>I think that if it didn't bring in money it would still be a public good. 

The money could come from increased fares past a certain time or it could come from additional grants. I believe money wouldn't be too major of an issue because people would want this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618261093.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;additional grants

You can't just magic money out of the air. Do you mean taxes? Will the taxpayer want to fund a public transport system that hardly anyone uses?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618264095.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Hardly anyone uses? I'm on public transit right now! The train is 3/4 full! I'm in a major city and public transit is full of $6 a ride paying people as I'm typing this! 

The money can be justified in just about any budget, if people want it </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618265569.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>And outside of your major city?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618269771.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>It would still serve as a way for the working poor and drunks to get home or to work </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618271530.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>The working poor who will have to pay more to take the later bus?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618272594.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Cheaper than driving/maintaining a car. 

Also cheaper than paying for parking. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618277707.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Parking is generally not charged for outside of cities. We have space. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618284241.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Many places make you pay for parking with meters. 

Again though, insurance, maintaining the car ect. More pricy than the bus  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618287866.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>But these people will still see an increase in taxes, surely, to pay for the extra buses?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618300811.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Not outside of the city. Very few places in rural areas and small towns use parking meters. There is also seldom bus services, taxis, or commuter trains outside of the city as well. 

Remember we switched to talking about rural areas and small towns several posts back on this sub line of posts but you seem to be ignoring that and think that they have bus services too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618544040.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you even arguing about night bus service in areas too small to have *any* bus service?

My town is on the cusp. We have buses (new over the past decade). But we've also charged for parking greater than 2 hours for 3 decades.

The size of our town is smaller than the size of the Dallas/Fort Worth Airport.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618714320.0" user="imagineALLthePeople" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The size of our town is smaller than the size of the Dallas/Fort Worth Airport

Why dont you use a real measurement like sq/ft or population? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619542398.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>We're about 80k people in 33 mi^2, but how many ordinary people can visualize square miles or even know how many their own towns have? People know how big an airport is because they've had to navigate the places to find a terminal and/or a sbarro. :P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618716285.0" user="imagineALLthePeople" delta="False">
    <text>Small hometown here. Bus service. Check. Free parking. Check. Their bus system only costs $1 for a ride too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618780772.0" user="FlamingTelepath" delta="False">
    <text>Other good points have been made, but in addition, your premise that riding public transit is cheaper than owning a car is flawed.

Where I live, we have busses, light rail, and trains available.  Getting almost anywhere you are not very close to requires you to take a bus to the train station, then get on a train or light rail, then taking another bus to your destination.  This usually costs about $10-$12 each way.

This cost is much, much higher if you are taking it every day when compared to the cost of a cheap car, gas, and bad insurance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618850464.0" user="isleepinahammock" delta="False">
    <text>Parking is never free. The cost of maintaining a parking lot is simply rolled into the price you pay for goods and services at at business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618342942.0" user="just_foo" delta="False">
    <text>So.... There's 25% unused capacity on your coach... Sounds like your public transit is appropriately scaling service to the demand.

Or would you rather they ran enough coaches overnight to have each of them half full? What about only 25% full? What about with 1 passenger each? 

Any service has to optimize for supply and demand. Every public utility has to optimize for public goods vs. responsible use of taxpayer money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618439026.0" user="252003" delta="False">
    <text>Full trains are less comfortable. Usually shorter trains run at night but they still aren't as full. People still need to get home so trains still have to run even if the cost is slightly higher. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618549104.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody optimizes public transport to 100% capacity, and even 75% is pushing it. These are not sardines, they are human beings and they require room to move about and to enter and exit, which 25% space barely gives them leeway to do.

Also, this is a government service not a for-profit business. The family who does not get run into and murdered by a drunk driver because the drunk took a night bus home instead of driving pays for this beneficial externality via taxes. Public transportation enriches all of our lives, and not just the ones riding the bus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618674294.0" user="Silver_kitty" delta="False">
    <text>In the NYC transit system, "capacity" is defined as the number of people that could fit in the car filling every seat and with 2 square feet of standing room. That's not "sardine" territory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618711938.0" user="imagineALLthePeople" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nobody optimizes public transport to 100% capacity

You're wrong. Japan crams their public transit to 100% and on cold days out here in Boston there are plenty of buses and trains and subways filled to capacity.

I also disagree with this: *family who does not get run into and murdered by a drunk driver because the drunk took a night bus home instead of driving pays for this beneficial externality via taxes*

If someone has the respect to take a bus, they have the respect to call a taxi. People who lack the respect and would drive drunk would still do that anyway given an alternative. People get killed in daytime drinking accidents all the time, busses or no</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619554521.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're wrong. Japan crams their public transit to 100% and on cold days out here in Boston there are plenty of buses and trains and subways filled to capacity.

My argument speaks to mens rea, not outcome. Please demonstrate that said cramming happens on purpose, EG: that these municipalities explicitly prefer 100% capacity to an utterly attainable 50% or less capacity, as opposed to "they just can't keep up with demand".

&amp;gt; If someone has the respect to take a bus, they have the respect to call a taxi. People who lack the respect and would drive drunk would still do that anyway given an alternative. People get killed in daytime drinking accidents all the time, busses or no

So your argument is that absolutely zero inebriated individuals will take a bus if one is made available? This also benefits from some citation. As long as *somebody* does, then whomever they aren't running into benefits, and that benefit (being an externality) falls upon taxes to finance instead of fares.

Besides, I think a drunk person who owns a bus pass will find it a lot easier to be "respectful" by simply climbing on board a bus than they would shelling out $30-$50 for a taxi every time they get shitfaced.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618983349.0" user="IndependentBoof" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Nobody optimizes public transport to 100% capacity, and even 75% is pushing it.

That is true, but there is definitely a cost/benefit to the public transportation availability. If the buses are often empty (or close to it), not only are you providing a service that is largely unused, but you are also being inefficient with gas/energy. Public transportation is a (relatively) environmentally-conscious way to travel... until you get to the point where you're not transporting enough people to make it advantageous.

Not only is running public transportation more often than is necessary a waste of taxpayer money, but it is also a waste of enery</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619536417.0" user="jesset77" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so multiply the energy efficiency (mpg or mpkwh, converting as needed) of often hybrid gas-electric or full-electric buses per mile with the number of rider-miles they transport, and compare that with 1.5-2x the same number rider-miles time the average fuel efficiency of personal vehicles (scaling factor because personal transportation normally eats a lot more miles, as passengers would drive from home to destination instead of bus stop to bus stop, do a lot more circling for parking spaces, more idling to warm up vehicle, more trivial trips, etc).

You'll find that buses are already more fuel efficient with an average of perhaps 3-5 passengers riding, even if they have a 50 passenger max capacity.

As far as taxpayer value, every one bus replaces roughly number of passengers x car of road space. Night buses help keep dangerous drunk drivers off the road. Public transportation in general offers mobility to the impoverished helping to both enrich the job market and undermine crime rates.

Through both the increased energy efficiency note above and the increased centralization of energy usage (it's much easier to make and keep 1 bus more green than 100 personal vehicles) public transportation protects our environment.

And all of this is equally true at night.

Really, if complaints focus on "not enough business at night" then the best approach is to mildly subsidize businesses which stay open 24/7 and work on shift schools so that a larger percentage of the population has incentive to live and work at late hours. Trying to focus 100% of business and social activity into 16 hours of the day is where many of these inefficiencies begin. :P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618738271.0" user="xtfftc" delta="False">
    <text>Public transport doesn't need to be at 100% capacity to be efficient. Even 50% average capacity can be very good.

And also, cars tend to be at 25% capacity most of the time.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618853805.0" user="Slinkwyde" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;And also, cars tend to be at 25% capacity most of the time.


Do you mean 20%? 2 front seats + 3 back seats = 5 seats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619109240.0" user="BMRGould" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, but some cars have more, so average it out at 25% :~)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619221105.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>More seats would reduce, not increase, the capacity average.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619247973.0" user="BMRGould" delta="False">
    <text>I was not talking about seats, but people within the 5 seats. Usually 1, but sometimes more people per car. So easy to say 25%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619273824.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>I'd wager there are more no passenger high occupancy vehicles than there are multi-passenger vehicles of any type.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619305660.0" user="xtfftc" delta="False">
    <text>Some have five or six, some have four or two, some have more than the driver inside. Should that really be the focus on discussion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618550065.0" user="Wehavecrashed" delta="False">
    <text>The train won't be 3/4 full at 3AM.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618690198.0" user="sonofaresiii" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The train is 3/4 full!

This is because it runs rarely late at night, or you're on the last one of the night. If it was as regular as during the day, there would be far fewer people on your one bus/train.

PS Even in NYC public transportation runs 24/7 (which is awesome by the way) but we're one of the most densely packed places in the country, almost no one has a car, *and* it's still very infrequent at night with not many people riding the trains.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618866506.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>So, let's say the transit is 3/4 full and $6/rider make it work. Say there are 100,000 people using the transit (I don't know where you live) and the daily revenue is $600,000.

Now you expand operating costs by perhaps 50%. But during those wee hours, there will be, perhaps, an extra 1,000 riders.

So now, operating costs have doubled, and revenue has gone up by maybe 1%.

Your fare needs to be ~$11 to make that work.

Not that any of that math is real, but also, it isn't unreasonable.

Alternatively, you could charge nighttime fares in the neighborhood of $50, $100, maybe even $200.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618270732.0" user="ulyssessword" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;people would want this. 

There is a very easy way to test that:  Are they willing to pay for it?  If they want it enough, money is never an issue.

If the taxpayers want it enough, a politician could gain popularity by proposing a tax hike linked to better service.

If the users want it enough, they would be willing to pay higher fares.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618276047.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, so let's put it to work for 6 months. If people like it, they will pay for it. I think that it at least deserves a trial run </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618284799.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of geography are we talking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618287169.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry I don't understand what you are asking me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618289135.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>Where will this 24/7 public transport run? In cities? Between cities? Between states? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618292140.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>Like it is now but 24/7</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618297724.0" user="thenewlove" delta="False">
    <text>So the 739,482 inhabitants of North Dakota, who will not use 24hr transport on any real scale, are going to prop up a system that will benefit the 8.4m inhabitants of NYC? You really can't see any sort of problem with this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618440052.0" user="252003" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a city with 150 000 inhabitants and 24/7 bus service. Commuter trains run 19.5 hours a day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618616546.0" user="pipocaQuemada" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you assuming this would be a federal tax?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618678532.0" user="Silver_kitty" delta="False">
    <text>NYC transit already runs 24/7. But more importantly, transit is generally paid with state and city taxes, and in NYC, the subways are partially funded through the bridge fares to allow cars into the city. I don't think they're suggesting that we issue higher federal taxes, I think they're suggesting state and local tax increases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618309652.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize that most of the country does not have any type of public transit right? Why are those without a system at all suppose to pay for making the system in other places run 24/7</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618613609.0" user="pipocaQuemada" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why are those without a system at all suppose to pay for making the system in other places run 24/7

Why would they?  Most public transit is paid for by fares as well as local and state taxes.  A lions share of state taxes tends to come from the cities, so even if someone on the wrong side of the state is paying some tax to public transportation, they're likely getting some other service subsidized by taxpayers in the city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618548730.0" user="Wehavecrashed" delta="False">
    <text>So everywhere on the planet? Because that's what you just said. He's asking where you would want to do the trial. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618991099.0" user="IndependentBoof" delta="False">
    <text>This might be practical for a select few cities.

Most localities simply don't have enough demand to be worth the extra cost. Running public transportation when there isn't much (or any) demand for it is a waste of money (driver, fuel, etc) is bad for the environment (use of energy that's not needed, added emissions for any gas-fueled buses), and adds unnecessary noise at night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618549587.0" user="Wehavecrashed" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think OP is very clever if he didn't understand that simple question. I don't see the point of a wide scale trial. You would select key areas with large amounts of late night activity on certain days to cater to the needs. Which is the sort of thing most governments already do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618707080.0" user="imagineALLthePeople" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If people like it, they will pay for it

I thought this was for the working poor? Now you're forcing them to cover extra cost of these services? 

&amp;gt;**I believe money wouldn't be too major of an issue** because people would want this

Money is a HUGE issue especially for "including trains, buses, all forms of public transportation". Trains are operating at a profit practically never even when they are packed full. They are massively expensive to fuel, maintenance and staff. Money is the reason why its not done in the real world, and money shouldn't be an issue that you simply shrug off.. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618788973.0" user="trophymursky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is a very easy way to test that: Are they willing to pay for it? 

That logic makes one major assumption, they can pay for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618456390.0" user="littlesoubrette" delta="False">
    <text>False. My county passed a bill last year that cut all buses on evenings and weekends due to budget cuts. People didn't want a higher sales tax so we lost public transit outside of the work day. The is not nearly enough money for these services and they are being slashed left and right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618482947.0" user="Keep-reefer-illegal" delta="False">
    <text>I think it would still work in many larger areas </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619104511.0" user="littlesoubrette" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a major metro area with thousands of people who use public transit as their only means to get around. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618713873.0" user="efhs" delta="False">
    <text>government spending is limited at the moment, so they can't really start taking on extra losses.

If you increase the fares people will be less likely to pay for it, possibly reducing usage/ profit.

Additional grants would come from the government which i pointed out are broke.

This is a prime example of a gap in the market that would be filled if it was profitable. some cities have it, and these are the ones with sufficent population density/ amount of people active at night. most places simply don't have enough people doing stuff at night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618844233.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>Assume for the sake of argument that a bus costs $100/hr to operate. At 4am let's assume there are 2 passengers.

Does a $50 bus fare sound reasonable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618944255.0" user="Glitsh" delta="False">
    <text>Thats a pretty terrible argument though. Its like how costco does business with their food court. I forget the term used, but they have acceptable losses to do business. If they had late night buses and such here, I would absolutely invest in a bus pass. They make money during the day quite well. Maybe a small hike in the cost of the bus pass or a minuscule increase in the rate, and it covers that period of time that is sort of being ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619024148.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt very much that the increase would be small. Keep in mind, Costco also closes at 8pm, while most retailers close at 10pm, in order to keep prices down.

And the loss leader(?) Costco might experience with the food court is perhaps necessary for doing business. But whatever loss their food service operates on, it's probably very minor. The loss involved in running a full-service transit system with only a few riders is probably absolutely enormous.

Sometimes, it does make sense for a city to do it. But in medium-sized US cities, it probably doesn't, and that's why they don't do it. I'm not really sure how much of Europe operates a 24/7 transit system, or what their reduction in service is, but I'm sure similar arithmetic figures into it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619052267.0" user="Glitsh" delta="False">
    <text>fair enough. You are probably right, but it would be nice to see a metro area at least run the numbers publicly. I would like to see what kind of costs it really does incur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619109227.0" user="CanisImperium" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I hear you... I'm generally supportive of increased transit spending, but personally I'd rather expand service area than expand operating times.

We're still a year or two away from getting a train to the airport. I'm wondering whether that will have a late-night schedule, since the airport is 24/7-esque.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619710266.0" user="Glitsh" delta="False">
    <text>Now that makes me thing you are talking about the denver area. Stupid light rails are so slow to put up and making I 36 a toll road is totally not helping traffic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618432454.0" user="omegashadow" delta="False">
    <text>At first I was agreeing with all the CMVing posts but then it dawned on me that in my city we do have all night transport and have for ages in the form of the nighbus (a limited streamlined secondary service with greater intervals between buses) and the new 24 hour underground on weekends. 

It provides a key utility in my city and would provide a key utility everywhere. The key utility is that it reduces the absolute necessity of owning a personal vehicle. In many places in the world even with a semi robust transport system, small weak links make personal transport necessary, such as the fact that on weekends everyone is constrained to 12 AM or 1 AM or whenever for staying out without a vehicle, this kind of quality of life difference is what causes people to start using personal transport over public transport even when the public system is robust. 

Having all night services means you don't worry constantly about being stranded by missing the last bus/train if you are dependent on the public transport system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618804981.0" user="quinn_drummer" delta="False">
    <text>The night the tube goes 24 hours I'm going to be riding that thing all night, it'll be such a novelty to be able to go about town without having to dick around with night buses, especially where I live, that part of the tube will be 24hours, where as the closest night bus stops a good 25min walk from my house.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618822060.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think there's a lack of utility to all night transport. Your post brings up an advantage, other people bring up other advantages.

The question is whether the advantages rise to the costs. I could name a million great possible programs that would have even bigger, more tangible advantages! But will we be able to pay for them and will it be worth it. Your city seems to think it's worth it and that's great, but the model may not work everywhere.

I live in Boston, and it would be fantastic to have an all-night subway system. But our system is already underfunded and breaking down. We don't know where we'll get the money to keep it running as is, much less to add ~33% more service time.

In the extra running time, we'd have to pay more employees, the power bills for keeping the lights and trains running. We'd have that much more wear on our already old and failing machinery, even if they aren't running very full. And while I'm sure people would use them, the fares (which wouldn't even increase for people using monthly passes) won't be a drop in the bucket to paying for it.

Which means that taxpayers would have to subsidize it. Right now, if people want to stay out late, they may have a car, or they may just call a cab. Right now people pay their own cost for staying out late. Extending service would make everyone else pay for that.

While I'm all for the public interest in transport, the late night interest is niche, and at least in some cities, better directly paid for by the people who need it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619017656.0" user="teefour" delta="False">
    <text>The MBTA is far from underfunded. They just blow money with wreckless abandon and give in to every singe whim of the public sector unions. Do you know what a bus driver starts at in the MBTA? $65,000 per year plus full benefits and a pension. For a job any half wit with a semi clean driving record can do. If you want a comparison, I'm a chemist with a big fancy degree, and I started at $38k. And then there's overtime. There were bus drivers last year that took home over $120k. Welders make upwards of $120k *base* salary. There were multiple people last year that retired who are under 50 and are now receiving up to $85k per year pensions for the rest of their lives. You can look these numbers up, it's all public record online.

And yet the MBTA continues to cry underfunding and wanted the state to raise taxes by a half billion dollars. That ridiculous number aside, why should people out in Adams or Pittsfield be taxed *at all* to prop up bostons insanely inefficient and wasteful public transportation system?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619094872.0" user="skatastic57" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The MBTA is far from underfunded.

It is, a quick google search confirms it.  

&amp;gt; They just blow money with wreckless abandon and give in to every singe whim of the public sector unions.

This may be the *reason* that they're underfunded but it doesn't make them any less underfunded.  I guess maybe your argument is that they have sufficient funds but that they're forced to spend them in a way that you see as frivolous.  Unfortunately unions aren't going away anytime soon so this isn't going to go away just because you want it to.

&amp;gt; Do you know what a bus driver starts at in the MBTA? $65,000 per year plus full benefits and a pension.

I tried to look this up on their webpage but they don't have any openings for bus driver but other positions were below $20/hour.  [Another website](http://www.careerbliss.com/mbta/salaries/bus-driver/) says they make on average $63k and doesn't mention a pension at all.  So while we could attribute the difference in the number to a rounding error, the fact is that is what you claimed bus drivers *start* at.  It's quite likely that they start at the $20/hr that the positions they have available start at and with seniority they've risen to $63k/yr.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619119483.0" user="Freeze__" delta="False">
    <text>I live in New York City where public transportation does run 24/7 albeit slower during nights and weekends and fares have gone up 3 times in the last 6 years. Then again it's only 2.75 so it's so bad but costs so rise over time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619205064.0" user="DashingLeech" delta="False">
    <text>At some point of minimal ridership, I imagine a few drivers stationed at key points of the city with a mini-van or small bus, combined with an Uber-like app to call them, would be cheaper and more convenient than running mostly empty buses on fixed routes. 

Many cities already have this with handicapped buses that do point-to-point deliveries on demand even during daytime.

I wonder if it'd be self-defeating though. If such a publicly funded program existed due to the low rider demand overnight, would rider demand increase simply by undercutting paid taxis services than many people use for trips at that time of night.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619508883.0" user="B0pp0" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't Montreal do this with the taxi colectif services?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618636747.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>Virtually no public transport runs at a profit. We operate it because it's important that people who don't own cars can still be part of society.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618689278.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>And so with that in mind if they are already operating at a loss or break even, how will they afford to stay in business if they were to run 24/7 without the extra income to support it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618739408.0" user="CoffeeKazee" delta="False">
    <text>Just like water treatment plants; we keep dumping money into them because the effect of having people getting to drink water and get to their jobs is pretty nice (and a net positive).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618746806.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>And like water treatment plants, we have found a pretty decent equilibrium between cost and providing the service...what we have now is the product of that. Increasing transportation at night will yield very little benefit imo as not enough people will use it to justify the cost increase. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618790894.0" user="CoffeeKazee" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno. I've lived in other countries with a completely different view of 'decent equilibrium' regarding water treatment (don't drink the faucet water!) and transportation at night.

Look at the justification for things like the Big Dig and see how easily one could extend that to a few buses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619260427.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know how much we spend on the military?  We can absolutely, 100%, easily afford it, it's merely a matter of our priorities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619264455.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>And that differs from what I said how? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619434210.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>How could an equilibrium of cost and service not be affected by how much money you have to spend?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619445162.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>Because they aren't going to pull military funding for 24/7 public transportation? Therefore my point stands: The benefits will be negligible enough where the cost increase is not justified. Or in other words, it's a matter of priorities and night transportation is very low on that list. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619488981.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's a matter of priorities and night transportation is very low on that list

That's exactly what this CMV is about.  You're putting the cart before the horse and justifying your argument with itself.  You don't seem to disagree that the money is there, contingent upon the willpower, so we must first establish what we SHOULD do before we can discuss at all what we CAN do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619506449.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's exactly what this CMV is about. 

No, the CMV is that he thinks it should happen, and is asking people to change his view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619516619.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>Right.  And I'm arguing that you can't make that argument by discussing funding, which presupposes that we SHOULD do it, but are restricted by the money.  If you aren't first refuting that it SHOULD be done, the door is wide open to the possibility that it COULD be done, given an appropriate realignment of priorities.

So, you can't demonstrate that we COULDN'T shift priorities without first demonstrating that we SHOULDN'T.  I don't know how else to phrase this for you, could you elaborate on what exactly you're disagreeing with here instead of repeating what I've said seemingly incredulously?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619644999.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure what you aren't  understand. We shouldn't because it wouldn't be worth the time or funding to do so. If we were to realign our priorities and increase taxes I feel that money should go towards more important things than getting a few drunks home. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619678477.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We shouldn't because it wouldn't be worth the time or funding to do so.

Why?  This is exactly the case I'm saying you need to present here.

&amp;gt;If we were to realign our priorities and increase taxes I feel that money should go towards more important things than getting a few drunks home.

I agree, but there's enough money to go around and still have the largest military in the world several times over, and again, this isn't the main issue here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619327944.0" user="Trillen" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair military is the feds money and public transportation is local</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619674978.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>The federal government subsidizes a great many things for states when they're deemed important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618741349.0" user="Shorkan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm all for increasing taxes. I think it is beneficial for everybody:


* Better service, which would both attract new users and benefit the current ones. 

* Reduced emissions, which benefits everybody. 
* Less traffic, which would improve driving times for non-users and maybe (I'm speculating here) reduce the number of accidents. 

I think that making public transport more convenient is beneficial even at expenses of increased taxes. But I know this is the kind of debate that people never agrees on (education, health care, etc.).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618787322.0" user="trophymursky" delta="False">
    <text>They don't have to make a profit, they're in the public sector. The goal of public transportation isn't to make money, it's to provide a service. They'll get the money from taxes but that's fine because the service would reduce the number of drunk driving, of people stranded in situations they don't want to be in, ext.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618851964.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>I am not talking about profit in the slightest.  

&amp;gt;how will they afford to stay in business if they were to run 24/7 without the extra income to support it?

If they are already operating at a loss or break even, how can they afford to operate at even more of a loss?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618885060.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>They'll afford to operate however they've afforded to operate at a loss until this point.  And more taxes.  Are you trying to be difficult?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618914690.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They'll afford to operate however they've afforded to operate at a loss until this point.

Contrary to popular belief, money doesn't grow on trees. Good luck getting everyone on board to increase taxes to implement something like this. Without that, they most likely won't be able to even fund something like this. 

It seems you are being difficult considering you can't understand the fact that while it seems like a good idea on paper, that something like this isn't realistic as the benefit would not outweight the increased cost. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618931250.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>You asserted that they could be operating at a loss already.  In that case, to answer your question of "how will they go on at a greater loss", they'll go on by whatever means they somehow already operated at a loss.

If they're not operating a loss (which they are, unless you count taxes), and would be operating at a loss after, then yes, it requires budgeting more tax money to it.  But since that has *already happened*, your arguments like "Good luck getting everyone on board to increase taxes to implement something like this" don't really hold any water.

Since some cities do have 24/7 transit, we know for sure that this is false:

&amp;gt; something like this isn't realistic as the benefit would not outweight the increased cost

and that there's more to it than some paper pusher adding up numbers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618939950.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>As you stated they can do this because of taxes. Unless taxes are raised, then no they cannot "just go on operating at a loss however they were". Yes it very much does hold water. All because people have had taxes raised in the past and are ok with paying X amount now, does not mean they are ok with paying more for something they perceive to not be worth it. 

Some cities do sure, but as you may know not everyone (or every community) values the same things. If that were the case and everyone thought the same way, then we would have no differences between different cities. They would all operate the same way and this would already be implemented everywhere. Obviously since it is not, logic leads us to believe there are people (such as me) who do not think it is worth the money or time to invest in something like this. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618949802.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>They won't necessarily be OK with paying more now, but you said they wouldn't, which you can't know, so that's bullshit (since we have proof that they have in the past - we're not going from no taxes to taxes, we're going from taxes to taxes+1, which we've done for various things including previous improvements to transit!)

Yes, there exist people who, like you, hold a belief that it isn't worth it, even though they have not done the work to determine what that even means.  It's probably not even true that those people are the bottleneck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618993664.0" user="Hyabusa1239" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I see. So the whole crux of your posts are just because you want to be pedantic because I said they wouldn't, instead of *they wont right now*. Good to know. I am done discussing with you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619133046.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; we're not going from no taxes to taxes, we're going from taxes to taxes+1, which we've done for various things including previous improvements to transit!)

which may or may not be popular among the population. they may be willing to pay for it, but they may not be. there won't be 24/7 transit if there's no tax increase approve. assuming that "since they have paid tax anyway, they wouldn't mind an increase" is a big fallacy.  

if you like to buy coffee for $1 in a coffee shop, then they increase the price to $2, you may reduce your frequency of buying the coffee, since it'll cost twice as much. same with tax, people will not be take increase of cost just bcos they already paying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619384317.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say that they would therefore not mind it, I was using it as proof that taxpayers have paid for things like that in the past, so it would be "more of the same" rather than "nobody would approve of this" which was the guy's claim that I was responding to.  In other words, if nobody would approve of such a thing, then we wouldn't have transit in the first place: obviously, he is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619169878.0" user="birchstreet37" delta="False">
    <text>He's not being difficult at all. What do you mean "however they've afforded to operate at a loss until this point"? It's not magic, the difference is made up for by taxes. That's it. Any public service that operates at a loss uses public funds to pay for whatever its revenue doesn't cover. So an increase in service would necessitate an increase in taxes. That's not necessarily a bad thing, but it is hard to get people to vote for tax increases. Besides, there are many things that would be more beneficial to spend tax money on, like schools and healthcare. I would love to have 24/7 public transport, it would make my life so much easier. But that doesn't mean it would be a good use of public funds over something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619941632.0" user="trophymursky" delta="False">
    <text>they get it from federal/local government's budget. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618716437.0" user="mcbane2000" delta="False">
    <text>... And so that the many businesses and services can enjoy having a robust and varied workforce to make profits with.  And so that businesses which have late night options can have a larger customer base.

It's as much (or more) a service to local businesses as it is to any individual.

The language of your post *seeeeemed* to ignore that, so I just wanted to add it.  If you've got thoughts on it, I love a healthy discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618854784.0" user="isleepinahammock" delta="False">
    <text>No transport PERIOD runs at a profit. All forms of transportation are heavily subsidized by the government. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619134712.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>depends on the country, some transit services in some countries are private. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619238250.0" user="HalfADozenOfAnother" delta="False">
    <text>There's not running a profit then there is wasting resources.  I'm ok with my city running a bus with 30 people on it for a bit of a loss.  I'm not ok with my city spending money running buses all night long with virtually nobody riding them.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618673979.0" user="taw" delta="False">
    <text>The buses already exist and stay idle at night, so that would cost nothing, and bus drivers are pretty close to unskilled labor which is plentiful and cheap (if you avoid union nonsense).

A lot of cities have night buses and they are a fucking huge deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618831356.0" user="cleansoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The buses already exist and stay idle at night, so that would cost nothing

Coach-class vehicles depreciate overwhelmingly on miles, not years.  A coach used during the day has a marginal cost approaching zero while sitting idle.  

The reverse is far from true.  Not only do you have the entire operating costs of running it at night, you have non-linear increases in maintenance costs due to the increased duty cycle and the need for off-peak emergency maintenance availability.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618949304.0" user="taw" delta="False">
    <text>You have much fewer buses operating at nighttime (like 25% or so, or even less compared with what you need to have at peak hours), so operational costs are small, and capital costs as I mentioned are zero. If some of them break down during the night, you can use another bus and wait until morning to deal with it.

It basically fucks up everyone who doesn't have a car or can't use one really hard for very small amount of money saved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619087276.0" user="cleansoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  and capital costs as I mentioned are zero

This is the mistaken point I originally replied to.  They are not zero.  Depreciation of the asset is real and can not be ignored.

&amp;gt; If some of them break down during the night, you can use another bus and wait until morning to deal with it.

More handwaving.  If you break a coach during the night *and delay repairs* it can't be used during the day, meaning you need to own more coaches to meet peak demand (and thus yet more capital costs).


I'm in favor of 24h bus service, but making incorrect arguments does not work.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  and the need for off-peak emergency maintenance availability.

And notice the words of mine you chose to ignore.  You talked about maintenance.  I talked about emergency maintenance.  A bus tends to break down on the road, where it can not be left until the morning shift shows up.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618708400.0" user="elperroborrachotoo" delta="False">
    <text>They don't necessarily need to run with the same frequency and coverage. 

Public transport is an infrastructure service, as such it's likely making a loss on the books anyway, since it's benefits - while significant - are not readily expressed ind dollars and cents. 

*Potential* benefits of night service in particular are: Increased safety, less drunk drives, higher attractiveness for tourists and people moving in, making the town more attactive for events and businesses. 

Whether they make up for the cost of additional night service is hard to say. 

Yet if the PT network expands beyond the "shuttle running up and down main street", it will naturally service routes that, individually, make a loss on the book. Yet they makes using PT regulary more attractive, they support development of that area.  

Similar reasoning can be applied to night service: why not use the existing infrastrcture to make this town a better place?


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619140853.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Public transport is an infrastructure service, as such it's likely making a loss on the books anyway, since it's benefits - while significant - are not readily expressed ind dollars and cents.
&amp;gt; Potential benefits of night service in particular are: Increased safety, less drunk drives, higher attractiveness for tourists and people moving in, making the town more attactive for events and businesses.
&amp;gt; Whether they make up for the cost of additional night service is hard to say.

when government looks into increasing service, they should quantify those potential benefits into some dollar estimate, to see if it's worth it or not. they can't just say "the intangible benefits will be great", but they need more concrete proofs when making decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619509451.0" user="Panda_BearCat" delta="False">
    <text>I acually think that that's a terrible way of thinking. If everything has to be argued in dollars, you aren't running a country, you are managing a company. In a profit orientated company it clearly isn't about the people. But this would lead to a whole other discussion.

I just wish people would
1. look into WHY public transport is so bad in the US (rich men saw their profits going and decided to destroy a working and growing public transport system)
and
2. look a little further and realize, there are cities worldwide with 24/7 public transport. How come others could overcome the problems?!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619568218.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>1. though it is true that government should be different with companies, but they share similar thing: they have to make the most beneficial benefit from the amount of tax dollar spent (e.g. spending $10M to increase local economy by $5M is a bad move); many people (including some users ITT) said that government is inefficient, which is bcos they weren't run like a business in the past, too little benefit for tax dollar spent. the difference with business is that the benefit may not go to government, but to local business or community.  

2. it's really based on demands. if it's NY, with &amp;gt;10M people in the area, and it's very active even at 3AM, it's logical to operate 24/7 because there will be demand. if it's small community with barely any activity past midnight, it's not logical to operate empty buses at late night.  

24/7 is not an impossibility, as long as it's demand driven, and not because "it's nice to have and be great for a few drunks" 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27620401440.0" user="elperroborrachotoo" delta="False">
    <text>Well, of course they need to evaluate the pros and cons, similar projects etc. 
And of course ho much - if any - public transport is good depends on a lot of factors. 

But what value do you assign to a safe trip home 3 in the morning?   
To enabling someone to have a job and get an education who can't afford a car?  
A family that see each other 1 hour more per day because both their commutes got just shortened?   
A kid that can take the ballet lesson she wants even though her parents can't drive her?   
Someone able to take a job on the other side of town even though they can't afford a second car?   
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27618994294.0" user="jnethery" delta="False">
    <text>My ideal would be to have such a good public transportation system that people use their money instead of buying a car to pay a premium for an unlimited pass (people can still pay for one-way passes, of course, but you're incentivized to buy a long-term pass). Then we get higher salaries for happier drivers and people don't have to worry as much about traffic, because ideally there would be more public transit units on the road than private transit units, so we'd have higher throughput of transportation. 1 bus carrying 20 people to a common location is much more efficient and environmentally-friendly than 20 cars carrying one person, in my mind. 

Of course, the details of implementing this are hazy at best, but I think it's a good idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619145400.0" user="feb914" delta="False">
    <text>it's the ideal situation, but it's still not achievable for a lot of places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619224987.0" user="jnethery" delta="False">
    <text>That's the unfortunate truth, but I envision a future in which this is viable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619234854.0" user="RadiantSun" delta="False">
    <text>Taxes? The state isn't supposed to be running a profitable business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27619506077.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>I live in Tokyo, which almost all transportation stops from 1-5 AM.  Even assuming only 1% of people go to or from work in that time that is still 350,000 people in the metro area.  Maybe it's impractical for small towns but for major cities there is no excuse not to have 24/7 public transport.  

In addition people go to places other than work.  Late night is a prime time to go drinking, which leads to drunk driving.  This can be prevented by having easy and cheap alternatives to driving.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
