<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="176180921.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ww62h/cmv_i_think_atheism_is_the_better_path_than/">
    <title>CMV: I think atheism is the better path than religion, as it can cause less conflicts</title>
    <original_poster>theraiderofreddit</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups. People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior. People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective. If one is not driven by religion, there would be less chances of conflicts. I don't mean no conflicts at all. 

Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27624154354.0" user="Casus125" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups.

The world is filled with conflict, period.

&amp;gt; People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

Wars are about resources and power.  The justification's change, but the end result is always the same: Resources, and power.

What's the difference between Charlie Hebdo and the Aurora Theatre Massacre? Crazy people do crazy things.

&amp;gt; I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

Very much doubt so; a world without religion would be a world without religious conflicts, that is all.

'My atheism is better than yours. Lets fight.'

&amp;gt; There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective.

This should be a clue for you.  Humans are very nuanced, and love to find and create nuanced views.  The various sects and divisions of religion have very little to do with religion's various underlying philosophies - generally: 'Don't be an asshole.' - and mostly do to with Humans wanting to do very Human Things - generally: 'Be an asshole.'

&amp;gt; Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?

Because religion is not the primary motivational factor for violent conflicts.

People don't resort to war and violence until they run out of easier options. But once they near that precipice, they need find justifications, reasons, to motivate the rest of their society to jump off the ledge and into War.

But the end goal of every war is securing resources, and establishing political power. The justifications are many, but the goals are always the same.

Worldwide Atheism wouldn't change anything. People would just use different justifications for violence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
