<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="176180921.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ww62h/cmv_i_think_atheism_is_the_better_path_than/">
    <title>CMV: I think atheism is the better path than religion, as it can cause less conflicts</title>
    <original_poster>theraiderofreddit</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups. People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior. People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective. If one is not driven by religion, there would be less chances of conflicts. I don't mean no conflicts at all. 

Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27624050698.0" user="Patjay" delta="False">
    <text>Atheism =/= non-religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624052482.0" user="theraiderofreddit" delta="False">
    <text>Wait...what? Care to elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624061666.0" user="Toane" delta="False">
    <text>I guess he could mean that there is agnostisism as well, though I am drawing a blank as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624357866.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>Most self-described atheists are agnostic atheists</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624401727.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Agnosticism is a modifier of philosophy, not a philosophy on its own. It is the belief that you cannot know things for certain and so must place faith in some place. Most Christians, and many other theists are agnostic as they are faith based. Many atheists are agnostic, but many are also gnostic believing that you can scientifically prove the existence of a deity or the lack there of.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624451818.0" user="Toane" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't the whole point with Agnosticism is that it's the middle ground, you don't know whether or not there is a god, and do not believe anyone can prove or disprove it at this time. How can someone believe that you can disprove/prove that there is/isn't a while still being an agnostic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624476677.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>No. 

As I said it is a modifier of an existing philosophy. Gnostic means knowledge, as is something can be know. Agnostic means it cannot be known. Agnostic does not exist on its own but only in tandem with other philosophies. In the terms of what we are discussing there are Gnostic-Theists, Agnostic-Theists, Agnostic-Atheists, and Gnostic-Atheists. The "middle ground" as you put it is split between the Agnostic-Theists and Agnostic-Atheists so in that regards you can say that the Agnostics have the middle ground, but there are still leanings. 

&amp;gt; How can someone believe that you can disprove/prove that there is/isn't a while still being an agnostic?

I am not sure what you are asking here, but I will try to answer. If you believe something can be proven then you are not agnostic. You are gnostic. Many Atheists (particularly the vocal anti-theists on the internet) fall into this category. Gnostic Christianity was deemed heresy in the 4th century, and while there are some modern denominations with more Gnostic leanings the majority of Christianity is still Agnostic and faith based. 

Once again there is no fully neutral category, the things are on two axis. One is the Theist/Atheist axis, and one is the Gnostic/Agnostic axis. Each axis has only two categories without a neutral point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624497035.0" user="Toane" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the explanation, it was very informative, though I would like to ask you one more thing though.  

Neil Degrasse Tyson describes himself as an agnostic, in what aspect of agnosticism would that imply? Would he then be an Atheist-agnostic or and Atheist-gnostic? I'm asking because you done confused me, and I'll like to clear it a little up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624516465.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Most people who say they are Agnostic without including the theist/atheist axis descriptor mean they are Agnostic-Atheist. It is kind of like a short hand. If they are a person trained in philosophy or otherwise highly educated then it is very safe to assume that they know the difference of things and are just saying Agnostic for brevity's sake. But your standard layperson is generally as confused as you seem to be and uses it incorrectly.

You should also put the modifier before the term (so agnostic before atheist or theist) to reduce confusion. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624530751.0" user="Toane" delta="False">
    <text>Right, thanks for explaining. I'll make sure to remember that, it's some good info.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624068518.0" user="Patjay" delta="False">
    <text>Atheism is lack of belief in gods

Religion is just kind of a loosely defined word meaning a collection of beliefs and views, usually involving life/the universe/morality/etc.

Buddhism, Taoism, Scientology are all religions but no god is necessary to believe them. Some people even consider humanism a religion, in which case even people like Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris would be 'religious'. I'm a very strong atheist and detest most religions, but your premise is false because it doesn't really make sense.

I assume when you say 'atheism' you mean atheistic, materialistic, secular humanism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624317206.0" user="butsicle" delta="False">
    <text>I think arguing over terminology here is missing the point of this discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
