<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="176180921.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ww62h/cmv_i_think_atheism_is_the_better_path_than/">
    <title>CMV: I think atheism is the better path than religion, as it can cause less conflicts</title>
    <original_poster>theraiderofreddit</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups. People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior. People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective. If one is not driven by religion, there would be less chances of conflicts. I don't mean no conflicts at all. 

Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27624158517.0" user="ljak" delta="False">
    <text>Every ideology claims that if only the entire world adopted it, there would be no more conflict. This is of course true. The problem is that the rest of the world *does't* want to adopt it, and forcing them to do so is precisely what causes conflicts.

[Atheism is not different from Islam or Christianity in this regard](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USSR_anti-religious_campaign_%281928%E2%80%9341%29).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624246630.0" user="catastematic" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that while there have been wars between Islamic states over both material interests and religion, and wars between Christians states over both material interests and religion, and wars between religious and non-religious states over religion, so far as I know there never have been and never will be wars between atheist states over religion. 

Do you follow the logic? We know there would be conflicts over religion in a world ruled solely by Christian governments, because this has happened in the past so it could happen in the future. Since the claim that there could not be grounds for conflict between Christian governments is false in this specific case, we can conclude that the broader claim is groundless. Ditto for Islam. Atheists might hypothetically have grounds for conflict with religious neighbors, but no one has yet explained any grounds on with atheists could fight religious wars with other atheists.

An atheist government removing privileges from a previously state-sponsored church doesn't mean much. The executions of priests during the process is a drop in the bucket during a purge with one million killed by the NKVD. I wouldn't blame a new atheist government for dismantling state-sponsored religious infrastructure, just like I wouldn't blame a new Protestant government for dismantling state-sponsored Catholic infrastructure. The goal, however, should be not to replace with anything new. The fact that every Soviet social policy had to be accomplished with machine guns can't really be blamed on atheism.

A better example would be China invading Tibet, except that China has been so careful to cultivate and support a state-sanctioned Buddhist hierarchy. It's fairly clear that China's invasion was not really motivated by Tibetan religion so much as an obsessive concern with defending an absolute claim to all Qing Dynasty territory. I'm sure you can find some good examples of religious countries picking religious fights with less-religious countries, though. The problem will be finding religion-free countries that had religious conflicts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624288940.0" user="ljak" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to believe that countries fight over religions, but I don't think that this is accurate. Wars start over material interests, and ideology. Ideology may be related to religion, culture, philosophy, race, and many other factors. The 21st century clearly demonstrated that secular ideologies can be just as harmful as religious ones (Communism vs. capitalism vs. fascism). 

Of course you don't see atheist Sweden starting a war with atheist Norway, but this is not because they are both atheists but because they both have the exact same ideology. If they both Christian states, they wouldn't be at war either. On the other hand, a secular capitalist state may very well go to war against a secular communist state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624583579.0" user="catastematic" delta="False">
    <text>Well, how exactly would you explain the wars of religion in Europe in the 15th and 16th century? I wouldn't claim that there were *no* material interests involved on any side. The world is a complicated case. But it seems very clear that the Catholic states began using violence against the evangelicals *for religious reasons*, and that the Protestant Princes who joined the Schmalkaldic League (eg) did terrible damage to their purely material interests by doing so, but thought that religiously it was important. Likewise with the conflicts between Catholics, Anglicans, Presbyterians, and Congregationalists in England; it's rather difficult to identify actual material motives that aligned all of the Catholics against all of the Anglicans, etc., especially when the rewards for adhering to the party that controlled the state seemed so great. Likewise with the religious wars in France: and there we see an exception probing the rule, where Henri IV continued to fight to uphold his religious interests *up to the point* that he was actually guaranteed the monarchy if he converted, at which point his material interests outweighed (some of) his religious interests. Or again, look at the Low Countries, where the Hapsburgs (once again) destroyed their own material interests, and the Protestants were more or less slaughtered indiscriminately, over religious questions; and it happened all over again a generation later, when there was a civil war in the UP over a schism within Protestant theology. 

It's extremely hard to explain the motives of all the parties to these disputes unless you genuinely credit the idea that they thought they were going to heaven and their opponents were inspired by Satan.

Similar points can be made about several religiously-inspired rebellions in Chinese history. Say what you will about what other motives the rebels might have had, but you don't gather an army around yourself with the claim that you are Jesus' little brother unless you take your religion seriously. 

These examples can be multiplied indefinitely. There are really only two alternatives: a "naive" theory of religious ideology, according to which people really did believe the crazy things they said and acted accordingly, or a completely "suspicious" theory, according to which the powerful *acted exactly as though they believed the things they said*, but only in order to control the masses who made up their war machine. Under the naive theory, either one of the religious dogmas is actually correct, in which case that one is worth dying for and the others are trash, or they are all false and any religious dogma breeds unnecessary conflict...... Or, under the suspicious theory, even though apparently religious conflicts are only elaborately staged because they help cynical, powerful people manipulate the masses into fighting for them, thus keeping them in power and enjoying the fruits thereof. In that case even though the people who chose the conflicts weren't really interested in dogma, religious dogma is necessary to warmongering liars so they can hold onto power.

I don't really see that either of these is compatible with the belief that religion doesn't promote conflict. The only way to defend that is a reductionist view, where everyone does exactly what they would have done if they were atheists but use their religious beliefs to justify it, which simply doesn't fit at all with how these conflicts start, how they develop, or how they (fail to) end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27625637339.0" user="ljak" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree with you about conflict over religion being a real thing. I just think that it's best viewed as an instance of conflict over competing ideologies or beliefs. If religious ideology falls out of favour, people are going to find other ideologies or beliefs to fight over. If it's actively suppressed by another ideology, it will just add another source of conflict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27625706521.0" user="catastematic" delta="False">
    <text>But you seem to assume that ideological conflict is a zero sum game, in several senses.

First, ideology can stack. There can be conflict between people who think the father and son are the same substance and those think father and son are different substance. And there can be conflict between those who support the dynastic claims of Theodosius and those who prefer a competent leader like Belisarius. But there is nothing prevent someone from having *both* the homoiousias ideology *and* the dynastic ideology at the same time, and being in conflict with both groups at once.

Further, in the weak sense of "ideology" in which it is actually true that all people have ideological motives, not all ideological motives are as pernicious as religious motives. A few problems with religious motives:

1. People tend to believe that the costs of ignoring the motives are infinite. That means that any time your religious rivals agree to peace, you know that it is in principle only a strategic ceasefire, so that they can attack successfully later. This leads to conspiratorial and paranoid thinking, since both sides are on the look-out for signs that the other side is about to strike, leading to preparations for conflict that the opponent reads as part of the conspiracy. Other ideologies tend to be conditional, so you can get to a point where it is no longer worth fighting to achieve your goals.

2. People tend to believe that adherence to the dogma (faith) is more important than any particular goal the dogma encourages. This means that toleration for other ideologies is always shaky, because simply by *publicizing* his ideology your rival undermines faith, which is an intrinsic goal; many religions compare undermining the faith of a believer to murder. Other ideologies tend to assume the project is what's valuable, and the project is only valuable if the ideology is correct, so it's possible for them to *welcome* ideological challenges.

3. Further, religious ideologies are the least sensitive to logical and empirical analysis. It is almost the definition of a traditional religion that it remains barely changed in the face of incredible pressure on its dogma: the flexible ideologies of 600AD no longer exist! Non-religious ideologies harmonize over time as they adapt by poaching each other's best ideas and minimizing/abandoning their blunders.

4. Finally, while this comes closer to something that needs to be argued case-by-case, on the whole religious ideologies are nonsensical and fights over them are almost pure loss to society, whereas nearly all non-religious ideologies that people are willing to fight for have *some* underlying insight, even when they come into conflict. This means when non-religious ideologies triumph, they are able to do something that makes the world a better place and leads to less conflict down the road. (For example, whether or not WWII would have been less violent without the Western Allies' democratic ideology, the fact that they set up constitutional governments in all the countries they occupied, funded the Marshall Plan, and started the EEC certainly contributed to peaceful relationships between those democratic countries.)

I hope these points aren't too controversial. I would clarify, though, that I see the first half (ideology stacks, it isn't zero-sum, less religious conflict means less conflict overall) as straightforward and obvious; the separate claim that religious ideologies (if any doctrine is an "ideology") have undesirable features is true overall, but not as a universal law; and that the first point is the most certain whereas later points are less so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
