<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="176180921.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ww62h/cmv_i_think_atheism_is_the_better_path_than/">
    <title>CMV: I think atheism is the better path than religion, as it can cause less conflicts</title>
    <original_poster>theraiderofreddit</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups. People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior. People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective. If one is not driven by religion, there would be less chances of conflicts. I don't mean no conflicts at all. 

Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27624119122.0" user="looklistencreate" delta="False">
    <text>I've got an even better idea: let's get rid of countries. They've caused plenty of conflicts on their own. Sure, there are some wars that don't have anything to do with national identity, but on the whole it's a safer world without them.

Saying that it's better for humanity to get rid of religion because it causes wars is kind of insulting to everyone for whom religion has had a personal positive effect. There's more to culture than violence. You're saying that we should throw the baby out with the bathwater.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
