<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="176180921.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ww62h/cmv_i_think_atheism_is_the_better_path_than/">
    <title>CMV: I think atheism is the better path than religion, as it can cause less conflicts</title>
    <original_poster>theraiderofreddit</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups. People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior. People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion, and the recent Charlie Hebdo massacre was done on the grounds of religion.

I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective. If one is not driven by religion, there would be less chances of conflicts. I don't mean no conflicts at all. 

Conflicts are bound to happen, but religious conflicts are one of the major factors. So why not remove religion from the equation and unlock a more peaceful world?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27624103942.0" user="cmv12a" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Today, the world is filled with conflicts between religious groups.

Today's world is filled with political conflicts that often take a religious tint. Issues like Charlie Hebdo are often more to do with the political histories between Europe and the Arab World than with the actual teachings of any religion.

&amp;gt; People rush to defend their religion, and think of other's religion as inferior.

These people are a minority as ~2 Billion Christians have ignored inflammatory comments of Charlie Hebdo along with ~1 Billion Muslims and ~12 Million Jews. Very few people responded to the cartoon in a violent method.

&amp;gt; People are fighting wars sorely on the basis of religion

There has seldom been a war where religion has been the sole factor and most wars today are not fought on those lines.

&amp;gt; I am here with an alternate proposal: That of no religion at all, aka atheism. Of course, I don't mean eradication of Religion. That would be impossible. I am just saying that a world without religion would be a world with less conflicts.

Atheism has been the inspiration for some of the most destructive ideologies known to man, frequently involving the eradication of religion.

&amp;gt; One may pose the argument that the institution of religion unites people under a single umbrella, but that ship has passed. There are too many sects, too many divisions too many views for this to be effective.

Religion is still a great unifying force in various areas of the world. It has a major role in cohesion among Arabs, Indians, Latinos, etc. Most of these major religions have evolved into increased levels of ecumenism with their rival sects, just look at the non-denominational movement within the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624340386.0" user="Crewman-Chu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Atheism has been the inspiration for some of the most destructive ideologies known to man, frequently involving the eradication of religion.

Any examples? Because I'm pretty sure that atheists have never massacred people for being religious. Or tortured them for it. Whereas atheists (and people of the "wrong" faith) have been subjugated, tortured, and massacred by religious people since forever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624354117.0" user="thekeemoman" delta="False">
    <text>[Really?](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anders_Behring_Breivik)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27625707812.0" user="Crewman-Chu" delta="False">
    <text>From that link you provided:

&amp;gt;He summarizes his goals, stating "I believe Europe should strive for: A cultural conservative approach where monoculturalism, moral, the nuclear family, a free market, support for Israel and our Christian cousins of the east, law and order and Christendom itself must be central aspects (unlike now)."

So yes, really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624355928.0" user="sausageroller" delta="False">
    <text>He's probably referring to the Soviet repression of religion, not a theocidal venture, but certainly tasked with eradicating religion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624365846.0" user="GregBahm" delta="False">
    <text>The USSR and China are the obvious, massive, overt examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27625710342.0" user="Crewman-Chu" delta="False">
    <text>Those governments may repress religion, but do they actually *kill* people for practicing religion? I haven't heard of that happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27626064606.0" user="GregBahm" delta="False">
    <text>It was grounds for being thrown in the [Gulag](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gulag) in the USSR. Likewise, in China it was grounds for [Re-education through labor.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Re-education_through_labor). 

When famine befell both countries, the prisoners in these systems were the first to die, with death tolls exceeding the holocaust. So while you can argue only a few people were specifically killed for being religious leaders, it'd probably be pretty cold comfort for all the clergy and outspokenly religious people who were rounded up, shipped off to camps, and then left to die of starvation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27627032902.0" user="Crewman-Chu" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I stand corrected. I'll amend my statement, and simply say that it's much, much less common for nonreligious people to target religious people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27627185120.0" user="GregBahm" delta="False">
    <text>But nonreligious people themselves are much, much less common than religious people. In terms of proportionality, we've done quite terribly for ourselves so far.

The problem is that religion is just a thing people make up. So any conflict "caused by religion" was really "caused by people, who then invented a religious justification." Taking away the religious justification doesn't take away the root cause of the conflict. 

There have only been a few atheist nations in the history of the world, but every one of them has engaged in just as much conflict as their religious peers. It is dumb to try and use atheism as a solution to conflict. A hundred years ago it was a worthwhile experiment to conduct, but now we know. Thanks history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624395305.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Communist Russia and Communist China are two major examples of atheist lead religious persecution and killings. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624654938.0" user="DangerAwar" delta="False">
    <text>Why are these considered religious killings and not political, while you consider the Charlie Hebdo shooting political?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624677207.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>They were killed specifically for having a religion by a atheistic government seeking to eliminate religion within their borders. That makes it both a political and a religious killing. The two are seldom mutually exclusive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624689430.0" user="DangerAwar" delta="False">
    <text>That's my point. Perhaps I'm misunderstanding but you seem to be insinuating that theists killing others is more political than religious, whereas atheists killing others is more religious than political. I would contend that they're both political with religious undertones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624843580.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Crewman-Chu was the one who claimed that Atheism has never prompted people to kill based on religion. I was giving examples of how that was false. I never claimed that they were not political and religious, just that they were the religious based examples he asked for. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624851112.0" user="DangerAwar" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, fair enough. I misinterpreted your statement then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624450350.0" user="cmv12a" delta="False">
    <text>Communist ideology is at its core atheistic and antitheist, as such when its two most powerful iterations were developed they expressed both values. The USSR and China heavily persecuted religious individuals in their country, and made it their active mission to eventually eliminate religion from the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27624636382.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm pretty sure that atheists have never massacred people for being religious.

To put it bluntly, you're wrong. [You can find some relatively recent examples here.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Criticism_of_atheism#After_World_War_II) After World War II, Albania declared itself to be an atheist state and closed down any religious institution while imprisoning, torturing, and executing religious leaders. China allowed some religious practices, but suppressed others that were considered a threat. The Khmer Rouge banned any religious practice during the Cambodian Genocide and persecuted those who practiced religion. No one's hands are clean when it comes to persecuting others based on their religious, or lack of religious beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
