<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1780416108.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tg0hv0/cmv_the_west_does_not_understand_russia_and_its/">
    <title>CMV: The West does not understand Russia and its efforts to make it capitulate won't come into fruition</title>
    <original_poster>Tasogare80s</original_poster>
    <original_post>Russia and Russian politics in general is vastly different from the long-standing democratic societies of Western countries. The perception of western countries that Russia will ultimately capitulate due to economic pressures is presumptuous, primarily because it assumes that Russia operates on the same status quo that western countries do.

If and when a democratic country enters a war, public pressure and change in leadership ensures a war's end so long as the public deems it unworthy of continuation. Russia is a non-democratic society, to which the constraints of public opinion do not bind the Russian state to the opinions of its people due to it not caring about what the people think and its irrelevance to the decision-making process.

In some parts of Europe, parliaments have existed since the medieval ages, which eventually became our models for modern parliamentarianism and republican democracy. Russia never experienced these developments and hence from Tsardom to Soviet to the modern era, the public opinion of your average Russian is irrelevant. The only parliament that Russia ever had was the Zemsky Sobor, which only approved the line of succession for Tsars whose sole and only purpose and power was taken away by Tsar Peter I. This is important because Russian society did not experience the same thing that western democracies did, and hence assuming that they function in a similar way is flawed.

One important thing to note is that because of this, every time the Russian state and country underwent hardship they willingly outsourced their hardships on their people. Knowing full well that the people are incapable of rebellion and the nobility being so weak, as a result of their deprivation of rights and strengths to even affect anything. When Soviet Russia was undergoing economic hardship during the 20s Stalin blamed the kulaks. When Peter the Great went to war against Sweden, he incentivized nobles with tax breaks if they taxed their peasants effectively. I am willing to bet that Putin does not care about the average Russian pensioner and if shit hits the fan he will outsource the consequences of his war, to his people.

Additionally, when Stalin purged the kulaks, he also purged the Soviet military and politicians, replacing his power base anew. When Ivan the Terrible's power was being questioned by the nobility and boyars, he engaged in a political purge that executed most of the Russian aristocracy. Putin's support when he rose to power were former KGB agents and when he consolidated his power, he was backed by the oligarchs. There are now rumours that Putin has surrounded himself with right-wing ideologues like Alexandre Dugin and the military elite. The Russian nobility is interchangeable and they aren't cemented within the political system. Hence if the oligarchs feel that their profits are going dry due to sanctions, all Putin has to do is arrest them, shoot them or sack them to fall in line. 

If history tells us anything Russia is going to crackdown hard on its own people and engage in another political purge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39244282047.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>As a Russian, there are a lot of things that you don't understand about Russia.

When west started to make sanctions that hurt ordinary people, like companies that stopped supplying cars, or when essential drugs disappeared from the shelves(glad a lot of them have Russian-made alternatives, somebody prepared). Like, I would be fucked right now if we weren't doing our own insulin. Those sanctions are clearly targeting the people.

Also stuff like harassment and expulsion of Russian students abroad. Or companies refusing to service Russians. Or facebook officially allowing calls for violence against Russians.

This is a huge mistake that the western media did.

When there were tensions with China, there was a huge campaign called 'Stop Asian Hate'. And it said that people shouldn't hate ordinary Chinese people for what their country does. Like even if Chinese government commits a genocide against Uighurs, or prepares to invade Taiwan, it's not a reason to hate ordinary citizens.

But with Russians, it was very different. Now everyone in Russia says:

Okay, you see now that the west is Russophobic as hell. Lots of governments and lots of companies, independently of each other, are attacking ordinary Russians. They always made us villains in their games, they harassed our athletes on Olympics, they deny them the right to play under our national flag. They hate us. Furthermore, they even hate the students in Czechia who majorly are pro-western(like, why would they study abroad).

It's a pure animalistic nazi-style hatred. They want all of us dead, they want to see is starve, they want to see ur people dying and suffering. Btw, your takes on Russian history, and that Russia was always 'bad, backwards, evil' is a clear signature of that.

I was initially against the war, but now I don't mind seeing the world burn. Reading reddit almost makes me wish for a nuclear winter</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39245531880.0" user="Professional-Menu835" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody in my life (from United States) hates Russians. Nobody thinks that the suffering of Russian citizens is a good thing. Certainly those people may exist, ignorance is everywhere. But who is telling you that we hate you and we want you to suffer? 

I am rethinking my assumptions about how my government has approached this. We’re not innocent; we illegally invaded Iraq with false cause in 2003. 

But we weren’t taking Iraq as a territorial possession. The “neocons” like Bush and Rumsfeld legitimately thought Iraqis would become a pro-US democracy if only we killed Saddam for them. To the West, it appears that Putin wants to recreate the Soviet Union’s territory.

I would say, if we want peace and we can’t directly attack Russian military or Putin or your oligarchs, this is the option. We want the oligarchs to hurt, we want Putin to hurt. I honestly don’t know if there is a better way and I’m listening if you think there is.

I say all this in good faith and I hear the pain in your words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39246611012.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I got emotional because I took historical analysis of the OP guy too personally. I shouldn't have, it's internet. There are trolls here.  

And when I say the west hates Russian, I mostly talk about the elites. Owners of big business, politicians, etc. Ordinary people don't play a huge part here. 

Nobody knows what Putin or anyone in charge wants in the end of the day, but occupying Ukraine and adding it to Russia would be very stupid and ineffective. Crimea was a different matter, Crimea was given to Ukraine by USSR because the USSR government used to change interstate borders as crazy. They thought the Union would stay forever, and that ethnicity as a concept will be forgotten. USSR wanted everyone to become 'soviet', rather than Russian or Ukrainian. This is one thing that the movie Red Heat got right. And Crimeans are Russians. Armenia and Azerbaijan fight for the same reason. Karabakh(aka Artsakh) is totally Armenian and always was. USSR give it to Azerbaijan to appease the Turks. 

As for the rest of Ukraine, Minsk agreements that everyone signed and nobody followed were designed to peacefully reunite Ukraine and people's republics. But Ukraine was supposed to federalise, have two state languages and autonomy. The same way Canada has two state languages. But Ukrainians don't want that, they want absolute total control of Ukraine. Why? Because they armed a lot of nazis and radical who would chop their heads off otherwise. Ukraine is a country where different oligarchs have their own armed gangs. This is hilarious.

Americans didn't, of course, add Iraq to their territory(would be weird), but American troops are still there. For all things and purpuses, this is occupied land. Making them a state would be too generous, gives too much rights. 

Putin tried diplomacy first, no nato bases(with guarantees) in Ukraine. I understand that people make arguments that 'a sovereign nation can join whatever it wants', but oh boy this is bullshit. America would never tolerate a huge Chinese base in Cuba.  And military alliances aren't supposed to work that way. Plus, after Victoria Nuland confirmed presence of 'biological research fascilities' I think those might be a problem as well. 

Sanctioning Russia or oligarchs won't help. Russia has been preparing for it for years in advance. And oligarchs aren't exactly Putin's friends. Putin said that those oligarchs who ended up having wealth abroad weren't Russian enough to begin with and deserve it.

My solution would be neutral status for Ukraine, federalization of Ukraine(ethnic nationalism is not the western way, lol). LDNR negotiates its status with Ukraine and peacefully integrates back over time. Like literally, Russian negotiated with Chechens who chopped of heads and took children of hostages(School in Beslan). And Ukraine can't make peace with people who didn't do anything like that. LDNR soldiers allowed Ukrainian soldiers to leave encirclements. And Ukraine called them terrorists who are beyond negotiations. And I think Russia should help rebuilding Ukraine. That's it. This would be acceptable terms for everyone. 

Putin made an ultimatum that was actually reasonable(considering that NATO promised to not accept ex-USSR states anyway), and he wrote an official document and got an official reply. Russia had two options, to shove it or to act. That's it. People say that invasion was unexpected, but Putin clearly warned about this. 

Western politicians pretend that Russia is beyond negotiations, but Russia still supplies Germany with gas through Ukraine. Because Germany signed a long term contract with Russia and breaking promises leads to chaos.
I understand why the western elites declared an information/sanction campaign against ordinary citizens. They want citizens to rebel and overthrow the government. I don't blame them. Politics is politics. 

I blame stupid sheep people who wanna harass Russians, hack websites, expel them from universities, etc. This is harmful and stupid. There are many scientific programs(like ExoMars) that are being sabotaged for no reason. Why can't astronomy be outside of politics? Scientific cooperation is what holds this planet together, and findings are public knowledge. Hope this all ends soon and well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39250836127.0" user="MrRabbit7" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention, when Russia was treated as a lapdog and incessantly mocked by the West under Gorbechav and Yeltsin, the people had enough elected Putin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39257350698.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Well, not exactly. Oligarchs appointed Putin as Yeltsin's successor to continue what he did, but Putin turned out to be different, and it was a surprise.

And many things Putin did in the early 2000s were only appreciated post fact. All the oligarch own so called free media criticized him for continuing the war in Chechnya, showed interviews with inexperienced conscripts who were "thrown into slaughter" just because Putin couldn't let Chechnya be free. People started to appreciate things later. He was always a 'do as I say and thank me later' kind of guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39246848253.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>upd: It might have looked that I am biased and support Putin and stuff, but I've done too much research in life to feel love, or even hate towards politicians. I just benefit from the absence of the NATO base as much as Putin does. Our interests align here. 

Plus, your government, no matter how bad or corrupt, will care for you more than any other government on the planet. There are exceptions, but not many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39247492734.0" user="Professional-Menu835" delta="False">
    <text>Nah you had a human response I appreciated. I do believe we are getting completely different information about the situation and it’s very hard to objectively sort out what is real. I’m sure you see tons of propaganda just as I do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39257273261.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>As they say, if you don't pay for the product, you are the product. Media isn't free because it's charity, it's free because it's designed to condition you in a certain way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39246025437.0" user="hellokitty694201984" delta="False">
    <text>Short of the entire western world going to war with Russian, and Russia potentially using nuclear arms, what do you propose should be done to stop Putin from invading a sovereign nation? No one hates the Russian people, but I can see how the tools being used to stop Putin may be perceived that way. The message the world is trying to send is "play nice" or be removed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
