<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1780416108.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tg0hv0/cmv_the_west_does_not_understand_russia_and_its/">
    <title>CMV: The West does not understand Russia and its efforts to make it capitulate won't come into fruition</title>
    <original_poster>Tasogare80s</original_poster>
    <original_post>Russia and Russian politics in general is vastly different from the long-standing democratic societies of Western countries. The perception of western countries that Russia will ultimately capitulate due to economic pressures is presumptuous, primarily because it assumes that Russia operates on the same status quo that western countries do.

If and when a democratic country enters a war, public pressure and change in leadership ensures a war's end so long as the public deems it unworthy of continuation. Russia is a non-democratic society, to which the constraints of public opinion do not bind the Russian state to the opinions of its people due to it not caring about what the people think and its irrelevance to the decision-making process.

In some parts of Europe, parliaments have existed since the medieval ages, which eventually became our models for modern parliamentarianism and republican democracy. Russia never experienced these developments and hence from Tsardom to Soviet to the modern era, the public opinion of your average Russian is irrelevant. The only parliament that Russia ever had was the Zemsky Sobor, which only approved the line of succession for Tsars whose sole and only purpose and power was taken away by Tsar Peter I. This is important because Russian society did not experience the same thing that western democracies did, and hence assuming that they function in a similar way is flawed.

One important thing to note is that because of this, every time the Russian state and country underwent hardship they willingly outsourced their hardships on their people. Knowing full well that the people are incapable of rebellion and the nobility being so weak, as a result of their deprivation of rights and strengths to even affect anything. When Soviet Russia was undergoing economic hardship during the 20s Stalin blamed the kulaks. When Peter the Great went to war against Sweden, he incentivized nobles with tax breaks if they taxed their peasants effectively. I am willing to bet that Putin does not care about the average Russian pensioner and if shit hits the fan he will outsource the consequences of his war, to his people.

Additionally, when Stalin purged the kulaks, he also purged the Soviet military and politicians, replacing his power base anew. When Ivan the Terrible's power was being questioned by the nobility and boyars, he engaged in a political purge that executed most of the Russian aristocracy. Putin's support when he rose to power were former KGB agents and when he consolidated his power, he was backed by the oligarchs. There are now rumours that Putin has surrounded himself with right-wing ideologues like Alexandre Dugin and the military elite. The Russian nobility is interchangeable and they aren't cemented within the political system. Hence if the oligarchs feel that their profits are going dry due to sanctions, all Putin has to do is arrest them, shoot them or sack them to fall in line. 

If history tells us anything Russia is going to crackdown hard on its own people and engage in another political purge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39241299801.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not sure you are considering the modern economics involved here. This isn’t WW2 when they can just throw poorly built tanks and millions of soldiers at a problem.

They face an enemy their logistics cannot easily get to. Their doctrine involves many older and poorly protected tanks and attack helicopters against an enemy who has been provided modern Western Javelins and Stingers perfect for the job. 

In addition Russian doctrine uses ground based SAMs for air defense, where the West uses fighter aircraft for air defense. And the SAMs are cheap and potent, but don’t move anywhere near as quickly.

Then we have Russia’s method of moving its military, by a robust rail network. A network that stops at the Ukrainian border with Russia and Belarus now after Ukraine blew it up, now Russia has to use trucks, something they haven’t focused on in their military doctrine.

Then Ukraine painted over or destroyed their road signs, as Russia uses power maps instead of GPS, so the Russian soldiers are getting lost. And Ukraine sent out pictures of Russian fuel trucks to target, as stopping the fuel trucks stops everything else in a military that is hyper focused on mechanized transport.

Then you add the vehicle losses, many from destruction and many abandoned when out of fuel:

https://www.oryxspioenkop.com/2022/02/attack-on-europe-documenting-equipment.html?m=1

233 tanks, 143 armored fighting vehicles, 208 infantry fighting vehicles, 68 armored personnel carriers, 13 lost aircraft, 32 lost helicopters and many more vehicles and weapons.

To keep the war effort going, they need to replace the losses.

And then cruise missiles, many have been launched, and no nation keeps as vast a stockpile as they would like to for budgetary reasons. They will need to be replaced.

All of that to make this point:

Replacing those weapons and vehicles won’t just be expensive, it will require materials Russia might not have access to with the sanctions in place.

What happens when Russia can’t pay plant workers? Or when food gets harder to come by?
I’m talking about the workers who build the weapons of war that are domestically produced.

This war is going badly for Russia, compared to their goals, and replacing the losses so far will be costly. And the farther West Russia goes, the worse the losses will become.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39241368127.0" user="Tasogare80s" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying Russia will win this war or anything about the military aspect of the war in general, I have stated no opinion regarding whether Russia will win or lose. I'm saying that western analyses of the Russian regime is flawed, it is rooted through a western context because to some political scientists Russia is European. Which I contend, it is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39243048945.0" user="Jebofkerbin" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've missed the point u/TheMickyMac was making.

The sanctions placed on Russia do not need to topple Putin, or create pressure from the civilian population to work. The sanctions can work by making it economically impossible for Russia to replace the equipment it's losing. If for example Russia's production of cruise missiles depended on a supply chain that has been cut off due to sanctions, it's going to take years to build the infrastructure to domestically to build them. More likely they will never build that infrastructure as the economy is crashing and there is a war Russia needs to fund right now. That means no more cruise missiles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39243059738.0" user="jamerson537" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t understand this response. Your view is that Russia “won’t capitulate,” but now you state that you’re not saying Russia will win their war against Ukraine. If you don’t believe that Russia will capitulate, and Russia also doesn’t win, what does that look like? It seems to me that not winning and not capitulating means that they will wage an eternal war in Ukraine, which is absurd. If they do not win then eventually, whether it’s next week or in 20 years, Russia will lack the financial means to continue their war effort and will thus be forced to abandon it, and that is the definition of capitulating due to economic pressure.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
