<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1780416108.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tg0hv0/cmv_the_west_does_not_understand_russia_and_its/">
    <title>CMV: The West does not understand Russia and its efforts to make it capitulate won't come into fruition</title>
    <original_poster>Tasogare80s</original_poster>
    <original_post>Russia and Russian politics in general is vastly different from the long-standing democratic societies of Western countries. The perception of western countries that Russia will ultimately capitulate due to economic pressures is presumptuous, primarily because it assumes that Russia operates on the same status quo that western countries do.

If and when a democratic country enters a war, public pressure and change in leadership ensures a war's end so long as the public deems it unworthy of continuation. Russia is a non-democratic society, to which the constraints of public opinion do not bind the Russian state to the opinions of its people due to it not caring about what the people think and its irrelevance to the decision-making process.

In some parts of Europe, parliaments have existed since the medieval ages, which eventually became our models for modern parliamentarianism and republican democracy. Russia never experienced these developments and hence from Tsardom to Soviet to the modern era, the public opinion of your average Russian is irrelevant. The only parliament that Russia ever had was the Zemsky Sobor, which only approved the line of succession for Tsars whose sole and only purpose and power was taken away by Tsar Peter I. This is important because Russian society did not experience the same thing that western democracies did, and hence assuming that they function in a similar way is flawed.

One important thing to note is that because of this, every time the Russian state and country underwent hardship they willingly outsourced their hardships on their people. Knowing full well that the people are incapable of rebellion and the nobility being so weak, as a result of their deprivation of rights and strengths to even affect anything. When Soviet Russia was undergoing economic hardship during the 20s Stalin blamed the kulaks. When Peter the Great went to war against Sweden, he incentivized nobles with tax breaks if they taxed their peasants effectively. I am willing to bet that Putin does not care about the average Russian pensioner and if shit hits the fan he will outsource the consequences of his war, to his people.

Additionally, when Stalin purged the kulaks, he also purged the Soviet military and politicians, replacing his power base anew. When Ivan the Terrible's power was being questioned by the nobility and boyars, he engaged in a political purge that executed most of the Russian aristocracy. Putin's support when he rose to power were former KGB agents and when he consolidated his power, he was backed by the oligarchs. There are now rumours that Putin has surrounded himself with right-wing ideologues like Alexandre Dugin and the military elite. The Russian nobility is interchangeable and they aren't cemented within the political system. Hence if the oligarchs feel that their profits are going dry due to sanctions, all Putin has to do is arrest them, shoot them or sack them to fall in line. 

If history tells us anything Russia is going to crackdown hard on its own people and engage in another political purge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39241187878.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>crackdowns on their own people and political purges inflict costs.

fears of getting purged inflicts costs, too.

the people face more consequences than the elite during any crisis or conflict.  That's true everywhere, not just in Russia.

The Russian government may be more insulated from the problems of the people than the US or western Europe.

But, pushing all of the consequences on the people is impossible.

There is no foreign policy action, for any country in the world, that exclusively targets a foreign head of state.  The idea that our government should restrict itself to such an empty set of policies is absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39241407444.0" user="Tasogare80s" delta="False">
    <text>I never said all the consequences of the war would be delegated to the people. What I am saying, as you have pointed out, that they are more insulated from public pressure. 

&amp;gt;empty set of policies is absurd.

I agree and in the normal realist and liberal world view, states are not beholden to a singular ruler figure or its regime. But I suggest re-evaluating that analysis when examining states such as Russia, which never really incorporated modern western thinking into their political system. I cannot recall right now but a historian stated that Russia is not country ruled by laws but ruled by men. This is exemplified in the need for a central autocratic figure in distributing patronage in politics. Which is unlike most dictatorships around the world that are in some way reliant on a singular, cemented power base. Such as in the Philippines, essentially relying on kinship ties and local politicians for patronage or in Thailand which relies on legitimacy from the monarchy to justify the coup regime. 

Although, my theory isn't necessarily paradigmatic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39241464505.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a central autocratic figure in distributing patronage in politics

that patronage is necessarily harder to distribute when your financial system is in ruins.

Putin needs people under him to run his government.  They in turn need people under them to keep things functioning.

When there is less money to pass around at the top, and less ways to spend it abroad, these key people are going to be less happy.

Not likely unhappy enough to rebel (the possibility of that seems like a delusion of the west to me), but enough to put some pressure on Putin to find a resolution to the conflict for which he doesn't lose face.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39241489909.0" user="Tasogare80s" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;that patronage is necessarily harder to distribute when your financial system is in ruins.

Patronage doesn't need to take the form of hard cash or even anything material. Being the next FSB official or a cushy military appointment can be considered patronage. Even then, it's too early to tell whether the Russian Federation could adapt to the crisis so I'm pretty open to your opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
