<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1780416108.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tg0hv0/cmv_the_west_does_not_understand_russia_and_its/">
    <title>CMV: The West does not understand Russia and its efforts to make it capitulate won't come into fruition</title>
    <original_poster>Tasogare80s</original_poster>
    <original_post>Russia and Russian politics in general is vastly different from the long-standing democratic societies of Western countries. The perception of western countries that Russia will ultimately capitulate due to economic pressures is presumptuous, primarily because it assumes that Russia operates on the same status quo that western countries do.

If and when a democratic country enters a war, public pressure and change in leadership ensures a war's end so long as the public deems it unworthy of continuation. Russia is a non-democratic society, to which the constraints of public opinion do not bind the Russian state to the opinions of its people due to it not caring about what the people think and its irrelevance to the decision-making process.

In some parts of Europe, parliaments have existed since the medieval ages, which eventually became our models for modern parliamentarianism and republican democracy. Russia never experienced these developments and hence from Tsardom to Soviet to the modern era, the public opinion of your average Russian is irrelevant. The only parliament that Russia ever had was the Zemsky Sobor, which only approved the line of succession for Tsars whose sole and only purpose and power was taken away by Tsar Peter I. This is important because Russian society did not experience the same thing that western democracies did, and hence assuming that they function in a similar way is flawed.

One important thing to note is that because of this, every time the Russian state and country underwent hardship they willingly outsourced their hardships on their people. Knowing full well that the people are incapable of rebellion and the nobility being so weak, as a result of their deprivation of rights and strengths to even affect anything. When Soviet Russia was undergoing economic hardship during the 20s Stalin blamed the kulaks. When Peter the Great went to war against Sweden, he incentivized nobles with tax breaks if they taxed their peasants effectively. I am willing to bet that Putin does not care about the average Russian pensioner and if shit hits the fan he will outsource the consequences of his war, to his people.

Additionally, when Stalin purged the kulaks, he also purged the Soviet military and politicians, replacing his power base anew. When Ivan the Terrible's power was being questioned by the nobility and boyars, he engaged in a political purge that executed most of the Russian aristocracy. Putin's support when he rose to power were former KGB agents and when he consolidated his power, he was backed by the oligarchs. There are now rumours that Putin has surrounded himself with right-wing ideologues like Alexandre Dugin and the military elite. The Russian nobility is interchangeable and they aren't cemented within the political system. Hence if the oligarchs feel that their profits are going dry due to sanctions, all Putin has to do is arrest them, shoot them or sack them to fall in line. 

If history tells us anything Russia is going to crackdown hard on its own people and engage in another political purge.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39242595067.0" user="ahtemsah" delta="False">
    <text>I assure you the west understands Russia just fine, with their primary focus on the red neighbour. Their efforts are a combination of bleeding Russia dry economically without actually risking themselves by going to war. To be cruelly blunt, Ukraine is hardly a footnote on EU radar and even if it's taken completely it won't make a difference except the added risk of Russia being ever closer. Ukraine is simply not worth the effort of actually sending the troops to defend it against a nulcear power. The russian invasion is pretty small scale as of yet, further diminishing the motivation to go.

On the other hand, Russia can't get away with it to prevent them from trying this again, and to deter others from doing the same. So Practicing soft power punishments is , for now, the way to go. All the economic measures will hit the people first and hardest, which will prompt them to protest the war and sway the public political will against Putin, with both against him, he will be forced out or risk instability in his house, and the west get to save face without playing with nuclear fire</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
