<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1798869912.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tr00wo/cmv_we_should_be_focusing_on_toxic_masculinity/">
    <title>CMV: We should be focusing on toxic masculinity when talking about Will Smith's slap.</title>
    <original_poster>Izawwlgood</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, Will Smith was responsible for his actions, which were inappropriate. This CMV is not meant to justify or exonerate him of his choice to slap Chris Rock. 

The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time, and this toxic masculinity is an example of the myriad and conflicting pressures men are under in society. Men are constantly told they need to be strong, to man up, to beat up anyone who steps to their women/family/property, etc, and at the Oscars, Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

Something I want to emphasize here - Chris Rock was not merely making an offhand lol ha ha funny joke: he is the driving creator behind this film [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good\_Hair](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Hair) , which was about the importance of hair in the black community. This was a movie Chris Rock decided to make after his daughter indicated she had internalized social bias around black hair. Chris Rock \*knew\* how impactful his comments would be, and this was not the first time he had made these comments to Jada about her disability - [https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/](https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/)

Comedy is about poking and exposing and making light of things. Comedians \*should\* make fun of stuff, and particularly at an event like the Oscars, people \*should\* expect to get poked. Physical violence is not the appropriate response, and Smith definitely gave up a very profound opportunity to stand up for his wife without physical violence and make a mature and impactful statement about Rocks choice of jokes. Rock passed up an opportunity to make a joke that wasn't punching down on someone's disability, someone who is part of a community for whom that particular disability is really impactful. This is absolutely an example of people weighing their personal perception of how inappropriate a joke is *for someone else*, and deciding how *someone else* should have responded. 

HOWEVER, I also think had Smith stood up and made such a statement, the media would be lambasting him for "not being a man". We so very regularly hear people goading a dude into a fight ("You gonna let him say that to me?!" or "Don't be a pussy, do something!", etc). Now, we obviously cannot argue a hypothetical, so the point I am making is that the deeper discussion behind Smith slapping Rock is not whether the slap was appropriate (it was not) or whether the jokes were acceptable (they were not), but **why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.**

tl;dr: I believe the real issue to discuss from this event is the internalization of toxic masculinity, not whether Smith or Rock were acting appropriately.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39338257818.0" user="Yuu-Gi-Ou_hair" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time

They almost never hear it, and almost no one would resort to similar actions as Will Smith did in this situation.

All this gender politics speaks as though things that rarely happen be common. It's a small minority at best that buys into all this gender nonsense and time and time again gender identity politics acts as though the pressures a small minority of people feel with regards to gender are universally felt, probably because the people who are interested in identity politics are more often the persons that feel such pressures, along with their friends they meet in such circles.

&amp;gt; the black community

There is no such unified “community”.

&amp;gt; black hair

There is similarly no such thing. It's a marketing gimmick at best.

Verda Byrd was also sent to a “black hairdresser” specializing in “black hair” which supposedly needs “different care” and at the age of 70 found out being adopted, and having “white” biological parents, and this “black hairdresser” who specialized in it somehow did not notice that it was actually “white hair”, showing how much of a hoax it is, deeply entrenched in the very same identity politics that wishes to create distinctions where none exist.

Only the greatest of fools buys into it, wise men live their lives everyday, unhindred by these supposed “gender” and “race” pressures that only fools would feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39339058612.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know. At least speaking personally, I would feel very tempted to use violence on someone who insults my girlfriend or my family. I *probably* wouldn't punch them, but I also would probably feel bad about it, if I do it or not.

What would a woman do if she or her friend gets insulted (assuming it's not something trivial)? Probably try to hurt them in a non-physical way? Shame them?

Are you allowed to slap someone if they sexually harass you (or a friend)? I read it reduces trauma for victims of sexual harassment, if they are able to retaliate when they are made to feel helpless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39339983165.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;black hair
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;There is similarly no such thing. It's a marketing gimmick at best.

You're saying you believe there is nothing different about black hair when comparing it to white hair?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39342958808.0" user="Yuu-Gi-Ou_hair" delta="False">
    <text>I believe there is no consistent hairtype that these “races” have, specially in the U.S.A., which is about the only country where this gimmick exists, where many “black” persons are 99% Indigenously European, and 1% indigenously Subsaharan African due to how the “one drop rule” functions, but they still are called “black” and visit these “black hairdressers”, as the example I gave demonstrates.

A specialist cannot be given a strand of hair and judge from it what “race” the person it grew out of was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39343019212.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so you took this in a completely different direction than I expected. I wasn't assigning any sort of racial identity or anything to the hair. I literally used "black hair" to mean "hair of the extremely curly variety that is the norm for dark-skinned people of African origin". That type of hair requires completely different care and handling than my fine, very slightly wavy hair.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
