<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1798869912.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tr00wo/cmv_we_should_be_focusing_on_toxic_masculinity/">
    <title>CMV: We should be focusing on toxic masculinity when talking about Will Smith's slap.</title>
    <original_poster>Izawwlgood</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, Will Smith was responsible for his actions, which were inappropriate. This CMV is not meant to justify or exonerate him of his choice to slap Chris Rock. 

The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time, and this toxic masculinity is an example of the myriad and conflicting pressures men are under in society. Men are constantly told they need to be strong, to man up, to beat up anyone who steps to their women/family/property, etc, and at the Oscars, Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

Something I want to emphasize here - Chris Rock was not merely making an offhand lol ha ha funny joke: he is the driving creator behind this film [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good\_Hair](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Hair) , which was about the importance of hair in the black community. This was a movie Chris Rock decided to make after his daughter indicated she had internalized social bias around black hair. Chris Rock \*knew\* how impactful his comments would be, and this was not the first time he had made these comments to Jada about her disability - [https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/](https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/)

Comedy is about poking and exposing and making light of things. Comedians \*should\* make fun of stuff, and particularly at an event like the Oscars, people \*should\* expect to get poked. Physical violence is not the appropriate response, and Smith definitely gave up a very profound opportunity to stand up for his wife without physical violence and make a mature and impactful statement about Rocks choice of jokes. Rock passed up an opportunity to make a joke that wasn't punching down on someone's disability, someone who is part of a community for whom that particular disability is really impactful. This is absolutely an example of people weighing their personal perception of how inappropriate a joke is *for someone else*, and deciding how *someone else* should have responded. 

HOWEVER, I also think had Smith stood up and made such a statement, the media would be lambasting him for "not being a man". We so very regularly hear people goading a dude into a fight ("You gonna let him say that to me?!" or "Don't be a pussy, do something!", etc). Now, we obviously cannot argue a hypothetical, so the point I am making is that the deeper discussion behind Smith slapping Rock is not whether the slap was appropriate (it was not) or whether the jokes were acceptable (they were not), but **why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.**

tl;dr: I believe the real issue to discuss from this event is the internalization of toxic masculinity, not whether Smith or Rock were acting appropriately.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39337187224.0" user="UArugby" delta="False">
    <text>There is nothing toxic about standing up for someone you love. The defense of loved ones is an instinctual drive that exists in all humans. It’s why women run into burning buildings for their children, it’s why men push themselves to the front of a dangerous system. We shouldn’t argue your hypothetical, so I’m gunna argue against your bolded statement. 

There is nothing toxic about using physical violence to protect loved ones. One of the primary biological urges all humans are born with is to defend one another, and this is stronger in men than in women. The idea that there is no place for violence in society is contrived at best and outright dangerous at worst, because some function of violence or the threat of violence is necessary for the function of society. While I’m not advocating people go around punching one another, a man’s “worth” to society is based around his contributions to society. One of those being his ability to defend himself and his loved ones. 

Let’s look at another scenario: I’m a 6’3, 255lb former rugby player, and im still built like someone who plays. I have a girlfriend who has a handful of characteristics that society deems attractive, and as a result she gets a fair amount of attention when she goes out. When I met her, she had plenty of horror stories regarding experiences she had while she was out in public where people, usually men, would harass her in some way or another. However, when I am with her, she never gets harassed. This is because there is an implicit threat of violence to other men if their behavior crosses a line.

There is a larger conversation to be had here, specifically whether the entire concept of “toxic masculinity” is a fallacy created to stigmatize traditional male behavior, but we can save that for another time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337235879.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>Your last paragraph seems to be an admission that this is the bigger issue and is worth discussing? I'm not sure what 'another time' would be - I specifically raised the issue here.

Regarding your points, I think you've basically just repeated all the issues I outlined. You have stated that a man's worth is defined in part by his ability to defend his loved ones. That view contributes to a mans propensity to rise to physical violence when he should not.

You outline examples of how the \*threat\* of violence you present is sufficient to curb other peoples behaviors - that indicates that society recognizes that you may rise to violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337256096.0" user="UArugby" delta="False">
    <text>Hey I’m all for discussing it, I just didn’t want to go outside the scope of your view. Fire away, by all means. 

And yes, our points are similar, our outcomes are different. You’re saying it’s wrong for society to stigmatize someone who refuses to use violence to defend loved ones. I’m saying it’s not wrong, because using physical violence as a means of defense is an inherent trait to humans and should not be viewed negatively. I’m saying there are plenty of benefits to violence or the threat of violence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337284788.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>This is admittedly getting off the scope of my initial post, which I am not faulting you for because you start the comment saying as much, but I feel the point of society is continually rising above our base instincts and survivalist needs. My value to society is not how many antelope I can chase down and kill, it is how I can apply my specific knowledge set to help a specific element of societies activities. Men, and everyone really, has value beyond hunter-gatherer paradigms. Toxic masculinity has not risen above that.

To circle back to why toxic masculinity is the underpining issue here, and why this is important - Rock and Smith are both distinctly people whose value to society is NOT in their physical capacity to commit violence, but their capacity to communicate (comedian and actor by way of trade). In this case, Rock was not utilizing his capacity appropriately, and Smith did not respond appropriately, both making bad choices influenced by toxic masculinity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337340993.0" user="UArugby" delta="False">
    <text>Right, and I agree. Society as a whole has progressed away from the days where families need to be isolated in huts to prevent violence. However, my question is simple: as a society, we still have people who are willing to use violence de to get what they want. There are men who harass women, who assault other men and women for no reason, who make piss poor decisions that are predicated on their ability to do violence. If society had progressed beyond the point of needing violence to maintain order, these people would not exist. The only thing that keeps them in check is that other people might meet their aggression with action in kind. 

Let’s dive deeper into the second paragraph. Why was what Rock did toxic masculinity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337825717.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>I think it can be both - society can have progressed past this point, and also still have it be a problem for some. Physical violence is significantly less common today than at various points in the past.

That said, as a spitball, do you believe there can be more things holding violent people in check than violence? Legal consequence or social ostracization for example?

I'd hold that Rock was influenced by toxic masculinity insofar as he was fulfilling a need to bully someone he feels is weaker. Comedians have a lot of material to choose from, and choosing to punch at someone's disability is not a particularly justifiable one in most contexts, particularly this one. While I accept that celebrities are so wealthy and sheltered as to be somewhat in a class of their own, I also believe that intersectionality matters - she is still a woman, a minority, and suffering from a physical disability that is impactful to her. Poking at that specifically is pretty bad form, though, I think could have been done in an appropriate manner (turning the jab into a compliment for example). 

In my view, a comedian who punches down isn't particularly funny. Pete Davidson was absolutely raked over the coals for making a joke about a combat vets missing eye. Here, people are making a lot of excuses around Rocks choice of jokes, likely in part because the reaction to it was so wildly inappropriate, but also maybe because he's a dude making fun of a woman in a way that most dudes don't understand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39338905540.0" user="Konfliction" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is nothing toxic about standing up for someone you love.

There is if it's done with the mindset of infantilizing women and acting like they also aren't adults who can handle their shit themselves. 

This is an often ignored part of this conversation, and the uncomfortable part of all the people who seemed to support Will and him defending her. Jada is an adult;. There's a weird acceptance of this mentality from men where they don't even realize what they're mindset is doing. Defending your women's honor is fine in theory, but it's also often done at the expense of the women's own freedom to do it herself. The problem is that more often then not this mentality is perpetuated by both men and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39339941137.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; While I’m not advocating people go around punching one another, a man’s “worth” to society is based around his contributions to society. One of those being his ability to defend himself and his loved ones.

This is a regressive view as far as I'm concerned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39346466454.0" user="ericoahu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There is nothing toxic about standing up for someone you love.

Until you respond to a verbal insult with violence. 

&amp;gt; There is nothing toxic about using physical violence to protect loved ones. 

Unless you are "protecting" them from nothing more than words. This is not the Middle ages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40586683394.0" user="Top_Chance_2735" delta="False">
    <text>OP would have done well in the middle ages, so a part the mindset is ingrained in him.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
