<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1798869912.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tr00wo/cmv_we_should_be_focusing_on_toxic_masculinity/">
    <title>CMV: We should be focusing on toxic masculinity when talking about Will Smith's slap.</title>
    <original_poster>Izawwlgood</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, Will Smith was responsible for his actions, which were inappropriate. This CMV is not meant to justify or exonerate him of his choice to slap Chris Rock. 

The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time, and this toxic masculinity is an example of the myriad and conflicting pressures men are under in society. Men are constantly told they need to be strong, to man up, to beat up anyone who steps to their women/family/property, etc, and at the Oscars, Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

Something I want to emphasize here - Chris Rock was not merely making an offhand lol ha ha funny joke: he is the driving creator behind this film [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good\_Hair](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Hair) , which was about the importance of hair in the black community. This was a movie Chris Rock decided to make after his daughter indicated she had internalized social bias around black hair. Chris Rock \*knew\* how impactful his comments would be, and this was not the first time he had made these comments to Jada about her disability - [https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/](https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/)

Comedy is about poking and exposing and making light of things. Comedians \*should\* make fun of stuff, and particularly at an event like the Oscars, people \*should\* expect to get poked. Physical violence is not the appropriate response, and Smith definitely gave up a very profound opportunity to stand up for his wife without physical violence and make a mature and impactful statement about Rocks choice of jokes. Rock passed up an opportunity to make a joke that wasn't punching down on someone's disability, someone who is part of a community for whom that particular disability is really impactful. This is absolutely an example of people weighing their personal perception of how inappropriate a joke is *for someone else*, and deciding how *someone else* should have responded. 

HOWEVER, I also think had Smith stood up and made such a statement, the media would be lambasting him for "not being a man". We so very regularly hear people goading a dude into a fight ("You gonna let him say that to me?!" or "Don't be a pussy, do something!", etc). Now, we obviously cannot argue a hypothetical, so the point I am making is that the deeper discussion behind Smith slapping Rock is not whether the slap was appropriate (it was not) or whether the jokes were acceptable (they were not), but **why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.**

tl;dr: I believe the real issue to discuss from this event is the internalization of toxic masculinity, not whether Smith or Rock were acting appropriately.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39337541783.0" user="josephfidler" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

First, I don't think an ailment is intrinsically a disability. Much like "toxic masculinity", "disability" has become a convenient and popular label to apply even where it isn't appropriate. A disability is something that prevents you from doing the normal things a human does to work, travel or care for oneself. Now, having a mental illness caused by being ashamed of being bald might be a disability.

&amp;gt;why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.

Seems to be a chicken and egg scenario. Humans evolved into what they are. "Society" is not separable from genetic design in this regard. Men are designed to protect women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39338915530.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>The term "disability" is actually more of a legal term than a medical one. Doctors don't really talk about disabilities, they talk about diseases, conditions, signs, symptoms, function, injuries, etc.

In the USA, under the ADA, a disability is a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more major life activity. This includes people who have a record of such an impairment, even if they do not currently have a disability. It also includes individuals who do not have a disability but are regarded as having a disability.

That is, under the ADA, a person is "disabled" for the purposes of the law if they are perceived as disabled by another even if there is nothing medically wrong with them. This is a necessary legal condition because the ADA is protecting people from being discriminated against based on disabilities, and since the discriminator has only their perceptions and limited awareness to base their own actions off of, and not perfect knowledge, sometimes people will be discriminated against for being disabled when they have no disability at all. So the ADA protects them in such cases.

So, oddly enough, a disability isn't really what you think it is. Now, colloquially it may mean that to many people, but that use doesn't align to the legal use at all.

To the extent that the medical community defines the term, it gets defined pretty broadly. The World Health Organization defines it as any medical condition results in any  lasting impairment in a person's body structure, function, or mental functioning.  As the skin is an organ, and Jada's ailment results in a lasting impairment in the function of her skin to produce hair -- that is, a body structure's function is impaired. It's a medical disability. A mild one to be sure. But still.

As someone who has a significant disability, and who spends my days pretty much trying to make sure that no one notices, I kind of think this is the wrong front to have this discussion upon. It doesn't really matter.   


In my mind, the simple response to this should be nothing beyond this: Smith committed the two separate crimes under the California code of simple assault and simple battery and instead of being arrested by the numerous police who were no doubt present there to enforce the safety of the participants of that show, he was given an award and a standing ovation.   


His privilege protected him in the face of an overt action that would have gotten most other people in America arrested, jailed, and maybe worse. It was a gross and humiliating display of the power of privilege and the lack of accountability to not only simple human decency but also the legal norms that the aristocratic class is held to. The Academy should be ashamed for not having had him arrested and removed immediately. Any other discussion, in my mind, is bowing to the privilege afforded him by his wealth and fame and is a symptom of the lack of standards we expect from the famous and entitled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39344295407.0" user="josephfidler" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The term "disability" is actually more of a legal term than a medical one.

It can be.

&amp;gt;Doctors don't really talk about disabilities, they talk about diseases, conditions, signs, symptoms, function, injuries, etc.

The psychiatrists who wrote the DSM-V would be surprised to hear you say that because they use that very word for the definition of mental illness.

&amp;gt;In the USA, under the ADA, a disability is a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more major life activity. This includes people who have a record of such an impairment, even if they do not currently have a disability. It also includes individuals who do not have a disability but are regarded as having a disability.

That's one law in one country and as you say, it creates a legal fiction where people who admittedly don't have a disability are considered to have one.

&amp;gt;In my mind, the simple response to this should be nothing beyond this: Smith committed the two separate crimes under the California code of simple assault and simple battery and instead of being arrested by the numerous police who were no doubt present there to enforce the safety of the participants of that show, he was given an award and a standing ovation.

&amp;gt;His privilege protected him in the face of an overt action that would have gotten most other people in America arrested, jailed, and maybe worse. It was a gross and humiliating display of the power of privilege and the lack of accountability to not only simple human decency but also the legal norms that the aristocratic class is held to. The Academy should be ashamed for not having had him arrested and removed immediately. Any other discussion, in my mind, is bowing to the privilege afforded him by his wealth and fame and is a symptom of the lack of standards we expect from the famous and entitled.

That does not appear to directly respond to the CMV, but instead be what you want to say on the topic of the slap.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
