<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1798869912.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tr00wo/cmv_we_should_be_focusing_on_toxic_masculinity/">
    <title>CMV: We should be focusing on toxic masculinity when talking about Will Smith's slap.</title>
    <original_poster>Izawwlgood</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, Will Smith was responsible for his actions, which were inappropriate. This CMV is not meant to justify or exonerate him of his choice to slap Chris Rock. 

The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time, and this toxic masculinity is an example of the myriad and conflicting pressures men are under in society. Men are constantly told they need to be strong, to man up, to beat up anyone who steps to their women/family/property, etc, and at the Oscars, Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

Something I want to emphasize here - Chris Rock was not merely making an offhand lol ha ha funny joke: he is the driving creator behind this film [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good\_Hair](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Hair) , which was about the importance of hair in the black community. This was a movie Chris Rock decided to make after his daughter indicated she had internalized social bias around black hair. Chris Rock \*knew\* how impactful his comments would be, and this was not the first time he had made these comments to Jada about her disability - [https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/](https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/)

Comedy is about poking and exposing and making light of things. Comedians \*should\* make fun of stuff, and particularly at an event like the Oscars, people \*should\* expect to get poked. Physical violence is not the appropriate response, and Smith definitely gave up a very profound opportunity to stand up for his wife without physical violence and make a mature and impactful statement about Rocks choice of jokes. Rock passed up an opportunity to make a joke that wasn't punching down on someone's disability, someone who is part of a community for whom that particular disability is really impactful. This is absolutely an example of people weighing their personal perception of how inappropriate a joke is *for someone else*, and deciding how *someone else* should have responded. 

HOWEVER, I also think had Smith stood up and made such a statement, the media would be lambasting him for "not being a man". We so very regularly hear people goading a dude into a fight ("You gonna let him say that to me?!" or "Don't be a pussy, do something!", etc). Now, we obviously cannot argue a hypothetical, so the point I am making is that the deeper discussion behind Smith slapping Rock is not whether the slap was appropriate (it was not) or whether the jokes were acceptable (they were not), but **why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.**

tl;dr: I believe the real issue to discuss from this event is the internalization of toxic masculinity, not whether Smith or Rock were acting appropriately.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39337270063.0" user="ThePickleOfJustice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time

I think that focusing on toxic **masculinity** is off base here, as it frequently is.  While you are correct that people use that term to refer to the type of situation we're discussing, the term itself has semantic issues and shouldn't be used in this case (and possibly ever).

By using the term toxic **masculinity**, it puts the focus on men and masculinity.  But that isn't the problem here.  The problem is that when men defend their woman in a situation like this, **women find that attractive**.

Straight men are *always* going to do what women find attractive.  In the broad sense, they'll do what the majority of women find attractive.  In the narrow sense, men will do what a specific woman (in this case, Jada) finds attractive in order to impress that woman.

So if you want men to stop the behavior, you have to focus on **women's expectations, not men's actions**.  I think most would agree that telling men "behave in a manner that does not attract women" to be a losing preposition.

 And by focusing on "masculinity", you're doing jus that.  You're sending the message "men have a problem and need to fix it".  When in reality, it's the *women* who need to change, not the men.  And by focusing on "toxic masculinity", you're completely missing the mark by focusing on men, while letting women off the hook.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337327144.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>Semantically I agree with your issues regarding the term, but I don't think that changes the nature or topic of the discussion. You are right - the term "toxic masculinity" is inherently problematic insofar as it shifts the blame on men and masculinity. While masculinity is a social construct that everyone contributes towards, solely blaming men here for the existence of this social construct is not the right approach.

That said, I don't think going the opposite direction and solely blaming women is a valid approach either. This is not something for women to fix. This is something for society to fix.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337360681.0" user="ThePickleOfJustice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I agree with your issues regarding the term, but I don't think that changes the nature or topic of the discussion. You are right - the term "toxic masculinity" is inherently problematic insofar as it shifts the blame on men and masculinity.

So then it seems that you're saying that "focusing on toxic masculinity" isn't going to be effective, so why should we be focusing on it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337533264.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm saying I concur there are issues with the term, and agreed that the term used to talk about the thing has issues which should be acknowledged. You understood what I was talking about, and agreed that the thing I was talking about was a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337615119.0" user="ThePickleOfJustice" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how you think we agree when the title of your post is, literally, "we should be focusing on toxic masculinity" and my response is "we should absolutely **NOT** be focusing on toxic masculinity; we probably should even mention toxic masculinity".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337837637.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is not that toxic masculinity is a non-issue, but that the term is flawed. I am not debating the semantics of the term, or the utility in using it to identify the thing I wish to speak about, because A ) I don't care for a semantic argument, and B ) you correctly identified what I wanted to talk about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337953601.0" user="ThePickleOfJustice" delta="False">
    <text>Everything is a semantics argument though!

You say that we should be focusing on "Toxic Masculinity", but yet agree that we should really be focusing on societal, especially women's, expectations of men.

But **words matter**!

If they didn't, you could post a CMV saying "We should be focusing on oil changes when talking about Will Smith's slap" and then just explain that "well, by "oil change" I'm talking about societal expectations of men and challenging that term is just semantics".

No!  We shouldn't be focusing on oil changes.  We shouldn't be focusing on toxic masculinity.  We should be focusing on what attracts women to men, whether any of it is problematic and what, if anything, should be done to change the problematic aspects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337471528.0" user="Eleusis713" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While masculinity is a social construct that everyone contributes towards, solely blaming men here for the existence of this social construct is not the right approach.

Using that phrase *at all* is not the right approach and you seem to be agreeing with that. Every time this phrase pops up, there's always confusion about it and people always have to clarify what they're talking about. If there is such confusion around the phrase, then why should any well-intentioned person continue to use it? 

&amp;gt;That said, I don't think going the opposite direction and solely blaming women is a valid approach either. This is not something for women to fix. This is something for society to fix.

And yet the very phrase "toxic masculinity" inherently puts blame on men and ignores the role women play and most people who use it seem fine with that. Toxic masculinity frames this as an issue "with men" and not a societal issue. Even if this isn't how it's meant to be used, it is how it's generally used by many people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337582946.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>Respectfully, I think the confusion comes from people who have a knee jerk reaction and presume that the term solely blames men. I agree that the term can seem to imply as much, but do not believe that it what it is typically meant to convey.

Toxic masculinity does not solely blame men, nor exculpate women from their role in perpetuating the social pressure. It is a societal issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337823848.0" user="Eleusis713" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Respectfully, I think the confusion comes from people who have a knee jerk reaction and presume that the term solely blames men.

Are you actually denying that there are many people who use the phrase "toxic masculinity" to demonize and blame men? Do you not think that these people can contribute towards the confusion? These people absolutely exist and they're quite visible. If you haven't seen them, then you can't be looking very hard.

&amp;gt;I agree that the term can seem to imply as much, but do not believe that it what it is typically meant to convey.

So you admit that the first reaction many people have with this phrase is a negative one. Isn't this an obvious sign that this phrase is inherently problematic? And the negative connotations and confusion isn't going away, this phrase has been politicized on both sides of the isle.

This term has little practical purpose that cannot be better served by simply describing what you are talking about. If you continue to use catchphrases and buzzwords that are problematic and confusing, then the person who misunderstands or is confused isn't the one at fault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337869509.0" user="Izawwlgood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Are you actually denying that there are many people who use the phrase "toxic masculinity" to demonize and blame men? Do you not think that these people can contribute towards the confusion? These people absolutely exist and they're quite visible. If you haven't seen them, then you can't be looking very hard.

Of course not. I simply hold that their views are as useful or informed as those who claim that feminism seeks to undermine men.

&amp;gt;So you admit that the first reaction many people have with this phrase is a negative one. Isn't this an obvious sign that this phrase is inherently problematic? And the negative connotations and confusion isn't going away, this phrase has been politicized on both sides of the isle.

I admit that *some* may have that reaction. I think that is an obvious sign that *some* people are misinformed.

&amp;gt;This term has little practical purpose that cannot be better served by simply describing what you are talking about. If you continue to use catchphrases and buzzwords that are problematic and confusing, then the person who misunderstands or is confused isn't the one at fault.

Or it allows me to filter for people who would rather have a semantic or knee jerk response than discuss the actual matter at hand. In some ways, it seems to serve as a litmus for those who are well informed on the matter at hand.

If you want to argue the semantics of the term, that's a useful signal to me.

Now, since the term seems to be eliciting such a strong response in you, it seems perhaps you may understand why this social pressure on men is so problematic and worth discussing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39338119163.0" user="Eleusis713" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Or it allows me to filter for people who would rather have a semantic or knee jerk response than discuss the actual matter at hand. In some ways, it seems to serve as a litmus for those who are well informed on the matter at hand.

It depends on what you mean by "well-informed". Many people are aware of the problems that others refer to when using the phrase toxic masculinity, but they don't use that phrase themselves, some have never even heard the phrase before.

Those who are well-intentioned, and who also unironically use the phrase toxic masculinity, are only a portion of the people who care about these issues. So using this phrase could easily filter, not for people who understand the issues, but for only people who exist within the same ideological sphere that you do.

Feminist thinking does not have the monopoly it thinks it does on addressing issues like this (and it shouldn't). Not everyone frames issues the same way feminist academics do or use the same phrases and terminology they do. Filtering only for these people will likely create an echo chamber which will impede progress on actually solving the issues.

&amp;gt;If you want to argue the semantics of the term, that's a useful signal to me.

I'm not arguing semantics about what toxic masculinity means. I'm arguing about the usefulness of such a politically charged phrase to address the issues you supposedly care about.

&amp;gt;Now, since the term seems to be eliciting such a strong response in you...

I don't know what you mean by "strong response". Is this a veiled attempt at an ad hominem?

&amp;gt;...those who claim that feminism seeks to undermine men.

I'm addressing this last because it's not directly relevant to the topic at hand but I still feel it's necessary to address some confusion that you seem to have.

The idea that feminism undermines men is not an unsupported belief. There are a wide variety of things feminists and influential feminist organizations have done to intentionally negatively impact men as a demographic. I will give two examples with wide reaching consequences.

Feminists created the Duluth model of domestic violence. This is the feminist model of DV that describes it as something that men do to women because men are inherently violent and abusive. This model is blatantly sexist and not scientifically supported. And because of feminist lobbying power and influence, it has been used to train police and inform law and policy for decades across the US and other countries.

Popular mainstream feminists like Mary P Koss and feminist organizations like the NOW (National Organization for Women, the largest feminist organization in North America as far as I'm aware) are also responsible for redefining rape specifically to exclude male victims and female perpetrators. A thorough explanation of this can be found [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/greentext/comments/k30ui0/anons_ex_girl/ge0koa0/?context=3) (well worth a read).

Some of the most influential feminists and feminist organizations are responsible for some pretty horrendous things and they've all used feminist beliefs and ideas as justification for what they do. The idea that feminism as an ideology undermines or disadvantages men is a valid concern. I wouldn't dismiss this out of hand if I were you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337547407.0" user="SennoEktoGammat" delta="False">
    <text>The patriarchy runs deep with this one. Oh it’s tooooootally women’s’ fault.  /s

It’s crazy how well thought out your reply was, but hinging it on the perceived effect of women’s expectations of men is like saying Chris Rock made a poor joke because that’s what his wife finds attractive. 

How about…everyone is solely responsible for their own actions no matter the influence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39337709811.0" user="ThePickleOfJustice" delta="False">
    <text>Men want women to suck their dicks.  If men are behaving in a way that reduces the chances of some woman sucking their dick, they're going to stop that behavior.  If  men are behaving in a way that increases the chances of some woman sucking their dick, they're going to continue that behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39338288462.0" user="SennoEktoGammat" delta="False">
    <text>I’m pretty sure there is a subreddit for you somewhere.

r/virginsofreddit</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
