<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1798869912.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tr00wo/cmv_we_should_be_focusing_on_toxic_masculinity/">
    <title>CMV: We should be focusing on toxic masculinity when talking about Will Smith's slap.</title>
    <original_poster>Izawwlgood</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, Will Smith was responsible for his actions, which were inappropriate. This CMV is not meant to justify or exonerate him of his choice to slap Chris Rock. 

The point I would like to make is that 'attacking another man for disrespecting your woman' is rhetoric that men hear all the time, and this toxic masculinity is an example of the myriad and conflicting pressures men are under in society. Men are constantly told they need to be strong, to man up, to beat up anyone who steps to their women/family/property, etc, and at the Oscars, Chris Rock punched way down on Jada's disability.

Something I want to emphasize here - Chris Rock was not merely making an offhand lol ha ha funny joke: he is the driving creator behind this film [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good\_Hair](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Hair) , which was about the importance of hair in the black community. This was a movie Chris Rock decided to make after his daughter indicated she had internalized social bias around black hair. Chris Rock \*knew\* how impactful his comments would be, and this was not the first time he had made these comments to Jada about her disability - [https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/](https://www.salon.com/2022/03/28/chris-rocks-history-of-jada-pinkett-smith-jokes-hair-commentary-and-disability/)

Comedy is about poking and exposing and making light of things. Comedians \*should\* make fun of stuff, and particularly at an event like the Oscars, people \*should\* expect to get poked. Physical violence is not the appropriate response, and Smith definitely gave up a very profound opportunity to stand up for his wife without physical violence and make a mature and impactful statement about Rocks choice of jokes. Rock passed up an opportunity to make a joke that wasn't punching down on someone's disability, someone who is part of a community for whom that particular disability is really impactful. This is absolutely an example of people weighing their personal perception of how inappropriate a joke is *for someone else*, and deciding how *someone else* should have responded. 

HOWEVER, I also think had Smith stood up and made such a statement, the media would be lambasting him for "not being a man". We so very regularly hear people goading a dude into a fight ("You gonna let him say that to me?!" or "Don't be a pussy, do something!", etc). Now, we obviously cannot argue a hypothetical, so the point I am making is that the deeper discussion behind Smith slapping Rock is not whether the slap was appropriate (it was not) or whether the jokes were acceptable (they were not), but **why society has taught men that their worth as men is tied to their propensity to commit physical violence to defend women/family.**

tl;dr: I believe the real issue to discuss from this event is the internalization of toxic masculinity, not whether Smith or Rock were acting appropriately.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39337486519.0" user="TitanCubes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and this was not the first time he has made these comments to Jada about her disability 

Did you actual just make a “claim” from a source you didn’t read? Because if you did read the Salon article you would know it says Chris Rock has made jokes about Jada in the past, jokes about her “boycotting” the oscars years before she came out about her alopecia.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
