<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391269057.0" user="Bake_Miserable" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of speech but not hate speech. I see people make jokes about controversial topics all the time with no major repercussions. When it's not a joke and can be seen as threatening... that's when it becomes an issue and shouldn't be taken lightly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391293301.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>What is hate speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391319271.0" user="Major_Lennox" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is one of those CMVs where we need to make clear which countries we're talking about here. In the UK (which I'm presuming OP is from), there are several clear statutes e.g the Racial and religious hatred Act of 2006, which amended the Public order Act of 1986:

&amp;gt; A person who uses threatening words or behaviour, or displays any written material which is threatening, is guilty of an offence if he intends thereby to stir up religious hatred

Is there a legal definition in the US, or wherever you're from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391343086.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>So it’s speech combined with intent to stir up hatred? Presumably more than just religious hatred, which is another term that could use defining. 

There’s no legal definition of hate speech in the US because it doesn’t exist in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391364965.0" user="Major_Lennox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So it’s speech combined with intent to stir up hatred?

Yes. The Crown Prosecution Service has a [summary here](https://www.cps.gov.uk/crime-info/hate-crime):

&amp;gt; The law recognises five types of hate crime on the basis of:

&amp;gt; Race
    
&amp;gt; Religion 
    
&amp;gt; Disability
    
&amp;gt; Sexual orientation 
    
&amp;gt; Transgender identity

&amp;gt; Any crime can be prosecuted as a hate crime if the offender has either:

&amp;gt; *demonstrated hostility based on race, religion, disability, sexual orientation or transgender identity*

&amp;gt; Or

&amp;gt; *been motivated by hostility based on race, religion, disability, sexual orientation or transgender identity*

Where it gets kind of murky is here:

&amp;gt; The police and the CPS have agreed the following definition for identifying and flagging hate crimes:

&amp;gt; "Any criminal offence which is *perceived by the victim or any other person*, to be motivated by hostility or prejudice, based on a person's disability or perceived disability; race or perceived race; or religion or perceived religion; or sexual orientation or perceived sexual orientation or transgender identity or perceived transgender identity."

So essentially it's enough for someone to *believe* you're committing a hate crime for you to be *charged* with a hate crime. Now whether or not you'll actually be jailed for this is a different matter - but there you are. Sorry for the wall of copy/paste and so on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391390069.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks very much. However I was asking about hate speech not hate crimes. They’re two separate legal concepts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391421603.0" user="Major_Lennox" delta="False">
    <text>The legal distinction is not so clear in the UK - in my understanding, "Hate Crime" is more of an umbrella term that "hate speech" falls under. So from the aforementioned public order act, it's an offence to use:

&amp;gt; threatening, abusive or insulting words or behaviour that causes, or is likely to cause, another person harassment, alarm or distress

or the communications act (2003):

&amp;gt; A person is guilty of an offence if he-

&amp;gt;(a) sends by means of a public electronic communications network a message or other matter that is grossly offensive or of an indecent, obscene or menacing character; or

&amp;gt;(b) causes any such message or matter to be so sent.

So these laws are all bundled together as "laws on hate speech" when we're talking about the UK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391493578.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between Hate Crimes and Hate Speech, at least in legal systems derived from the English common law tradition, don’t know a whole lot about purely statutory systems, is that a hate crime is a preexistent crime that is punished more harshly because it’s motivated in fact or has the appearances being motivated by hatred towards a legally protected group. Hate speech would probably, again I don’t know because it doesn’t exist in the legal system I have the most familiarity with, be speech that by its very nature is legally sanctioned. For example when the Public Order Act 1986 prohibits “insulting words or behavior” that “intends thereby to stir up racial hatred” or “having regard to all the circumstances racial hatred is likely to be stirred up thereby.” It’s not illegal prima facie to insult someone it only becomes illegal when it’s done or perceived to be done because someone is a member of a protected group. Another example would be The Football Offences Act 1991(which as an aside, having an entire statute devoted to banning speech specifically at soccer games is about as peak British as you can get) which bans indecent or racialist chanting at football matches. Obviously it’s not illegal to chant at a soccer game it only becomes illegal when the chant is deemed indecent or racialist. 

But now I’ve done what I was trying to avoid. Namely having to research British law. 

Anyway, I think the assumption I had, that these hate speech laws would be so broad and vague as to mean basically whatever those in power want them to mean and thus don’t serve the purpose they nominally exist to prevent has borne out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391507700.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Pedophilia is a mental illness and a disability, the same goes for psychopathy but that's not well defined in psychology. Hating people for these two traits is commonplace, and you will not be arrested for hate against them.

Hatred against Christianity is common, racism against white people is common too. The thing with values is also that they do necessarily go both ways. If a Muslim is reported to have killed a homosexual by throwing them off a building, then wouldn't both criticizing that, *and* defending that, be considered hate speech?

Modern law really is a joke, you'd have to not take it literally in order to follow what's intented, but a subjective law is even worse than a flawed law, because then the meaning is "implied" and made subjective, which will mean that you can hate and be hostile all you want as long as you're "punching up", which is another term which is just as dishonest and subjective, since it's based on whatever groups the left currently considers "victims" and "oppressors", which, by the way, is just as dishonest and subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393901131.0" user="Gnarly-Beard" delta="False">
    <text>With the any other person standard, wouldn't you just need to find someone, anyone who claims to be offended and therefore any crime can have a hate crime enhancement? And at that point, aren't all crimes then "hate crimes" and we've just increased penalties without any change in law or action?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391405884.0" user="GoddessHimeChan" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever the people in charge want to be silenced</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391435416.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>right because racism is a good thing we need to hear more of</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391570627.0" user="Kung_Flu_Master" delta="False">
    <text>No one said that, the issue is mainly left wingers calling anyone who disagrees with them racist, if they were in power anyone right of Stalin would be arrested. Using their definitions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391583847.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>except OP is in the comments using racism as an example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391626741.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think we need more racism, I dislike every comment I've sent hats lead to an arrest, I dont believe this is an arrest able thing tho. I believe social consequences are okay, like maybe your boss sees and fires you or you are insulted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391346423.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>That's not hate speach though I believe that would be threaghtening behaviour or threaghtening violence. Those are different things as one is a lot easier to define than the other. 

A judge can deside something is not a joke, or they maybe feel personally attacked ect and can charge with a hate crime, there has to be a believable threat for the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391838907.0" user="Thatniqqarylan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that would be threaghtening behaviour or threaghtening violence. 



You maybe think there's a reason you're not the one in charge of that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391846898.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm here for people to change my oppinion as I'm looking for a reason to believe it's okay and not a risk to others who wont have as much freedom of speach as that isnt even a thing here I believe. 

I am talking about a specific thing, hate speach laws, yes I've got some wrong but now I'm just being questioned on every speach law there is like ive done a++ level research as a 19yo high school drop out.


And I dint want to be in charge, thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391855120.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393279663.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Thatniqqarylan – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Thatniqqarylan&amp;amp;message=Thatniqqarylan%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3gw5xs/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395269289.0" user="ChopinCJ" delta="False">
    <text>If you make an argument about laws, and you complain when people with actual law backgrounds correct your (common) misconceptions, then do you really have any interest in changing your mind? Genuine question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392658164.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe they were just lucky?

https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/arrests-for-offensive-facebook-and-twitter-posts-soar-in-london-a7064246.html?amp</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392659620.0" user="AmputatorBot" delta="False">
    <text>It looks like you shared an AMP link. These should load faster, but AMP is controversial because of [concerns over privacy and the Open Web](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot).

Maybe check out **the canonical page** instead: **[https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/arrests-for-offensive-facebook-and-twitter-posts-soar-in-london-a7064246.html](https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/arrests-for-offensive-facebook-and-twitter-posts-soar-in-london-a7064246.html)**

*****

 ^(I'm a bot | )[^(Why &amp;amp; About)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot)^( | )[^(Summon: u/AmputatorBot)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/cchly3/you_can_now_summon_amputatorbot/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396250871.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>"hate speech" is just speech</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
