<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391776775.0" user="OpenByTheCure" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe in libel laws?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391858394.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly dont know what that means for sure. Is it not sort of like slander but different? Or is it actually slander or deffimation. I get confused easily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391923670.0" user="OpenByTheCure" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe defamation/libel/slander should be illegal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392292501.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Illegal, no; unlawful, yes. Defamation/libel is and should remain a civil issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392486050.0" user="OpenByTheCure" delta="False">
    <text>That means illegal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392987790.0" user="throwaway2323234442" delta="False">
    <text>pst, you aren't op, so them asking for clarification on points to op to change their view doesnt work if you respond, being not op, and not who they were asking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
