<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391684026.0" user="poprostumort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

And how do you distinguish joke, bad take, insult from threatening violence, doxing and defamation? It can be that hate crime is masked as one of those?

Especially considering the fact that there are many causes where anti trans comments, insulting soldiers, ,nazi jokes, racist remarks or jokes - are not prosecuted.

In fact when they get prosecuted it's specifically because they crossed the hate crime line. There are anti-trans people who are active in public and don't get arrested, those who do wusually crossed the line and started voicing themselves in a way that is actually harmful either to trans people or society. Similar thing happens with people who insult soldiers - if they are just voicing their oposition to institution or to ideo of what being a soldier is, they aren't having problem. As for nazi jokes - there is a thin line between nazi joke and promotion on nazi ideology presented as a joke.

And that is the issue - topics you mentioned are on border of hate crimes, so it's easy for people expressing their views to actually go into hate crime territory and pull "freedom" card when confronted for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391741886.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; how do you distinguish joke, bad take, insult from threatening violence, doxing and defamation?

Its effect. Doxxing is easily distinguished from jokes, bad takes and insults though.

&amp;gt; there is a thin line between nazi joke and promotion on nazi ideology presented as a joke.

Depends on the joke. It could be miles apart from promoting nazi ideology. Ever seen "are we the baddies?" it's a nazi joke that is clearly pointing out that nazi ideology is bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391775167.0" user="poprostumort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Its effect.

Exactly. And those who did have problems due to jokes, bad takes and insults are ones who did have an effect on people thir words targetted.  


&amp;gt;Depends on the joke. It could be miles apart from promoting nazi ideology. Ever seen "are we the baddies?" it's a nazi joke that is clearly pointing out that nazi ideology is bad.

And that is great example, as "are we the baddies" is not something that were crossing this line, as it still painting nazism in negative way just in joke form. But there are other "jokes" that do cross the line and actually make victims of nazism a joke. Those are walking on the line and they may be passable in specific circumstances, but as soon as they are taken into public, they are crossing the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392068462.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Having a problem with someone saying something isn't the same as them encuraging violence. Violence - or attempt of violence - has to happen as an effect.

Me going "that girl said 'all men should be killed' and is thus encuraging violence" would not be sufficient to prove she did.

OFC, social media doesn't work off of proving something to be the case, but rather their own rules, and so a lot of people conflate social media's handling of cases to legal cases. Can see this reflected in how many people didn't (and to this day don't) understand how Rittenhouse could possibly be defending himself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400393617.0" user="poprostumort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Having a problem with someone saying something isn't the same as them encuraging violence.

Yes, but it can be used to encourage violence. That's the gist of the problem. We don't want to arrest innocent people for saying a joke or having an opinion, but at the same time we cannot allow for actuall hate and violence encouragement to be alowed if it is dressed up as a joke or opinion, right?

That is the big problem with persecuting something that is a hate crime, as it needs to be judged case by case. There is no way of having foolproof law that would be able to immediately specifically target the correct one. We need actual humans to judge the content and intent.

&amp;gt;Me going "that girl said 'all men should be killed' and is thus encuraging violence" would not be sufficient to prove she did.

Of course, and don't believe that this would end with any punishment - unless there are other proof that your claim.  


&amp;gt;OFC, social media doesn't work off of proving something to be the case, but rather their own rules, and so a lot of people conflate social media's handling of cases to legal cases.

Yea, that seems to be ongoing issue - people conflate hate crime laws and social media cancelling and treat them as one and the same. Which makes discussion about the topic hard as they mentally prop their view by irrelevant examples. So they are f.ex. against hate crime laws becasue someone they know was banned from FB for a bad taste joke</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
