<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="61" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39394120032.0" user="OmNomDeBonBon" delta="False">
    <text>In the entirety of human civilisation, there has never been a society with absolute freedom of speech. It simply does not exist. Every society has rules for speech which restrict what you can say to varying degrees.

As you go up the authoritarian ladder, more and more speech gets you killed by the government, jailed, ostracised, etc. Western society is the freest in the history of the world. The speech that has legal consequences is tiny in comparison to what used to be forbidden.

Self-described "free speech advocates" are either misinformed or disingenuous about what free speech actually entails, or its history.

* In the 50s, saying "Jesus was gay" would get you jailed.
* In the 40s, saying "Hitler was right" would get you jailed.
* In the 20s, saying "Empire must end" would get you jailed.
* In the 1900s, saying "women must be given the vote" would get you jailed.
* In the 1800s, saying "Christianity is nonsense" would get you jailed, or killed
* In the 1700s, saying "The King is a terrible huntsman" would get you jailed, or killed.
* In the 1600s, saying "The King is not divine" would get you jailed, or killed.

And that's just the UK. We've never had absolute free speech, but we've progressively whittled away at the things that can get us jailed.

Right now, pretty much the only speech that *can* get you jailed are:

* Abusive statements made on the basis of someone's membership of a protected characteristic. E.g. you can't call a black man an N-word, you can't call a transwoman a tr*nny, you can't call a Down's Syndrome sufferer a "m*ng".
* Expressing support for terrorism, whether privately or publicly, on the grounds that you're a danger to society
* Grossly offensive speech e.g. expressing delight at British soldiers dying (a la Captain Tom's abuser)
* Threatening violence against an individual or group
* Inciting hatred against an individual or group on the basis of their membership of a protected characteristic

The last one is the problematic one, because it's been used to, for example, prosecute people who criticise the militant trans movement.

But in general, we are the freest we've ever been.

And I repeat, there's been no society in the history of human civilisation which has had absolute free speech. There have always been consequences for forbidden speech.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
