<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="91" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39395905665.0" user="MightyBoat" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who's gone through bullying this argument makes my blood boil.

A kid bullies another kid every day for years. There's no violence, just words. Words that get progressively more and more extreme, to the point of jokingly threatening. Teachers will tell you to just ignore it. Just ignore it and they will stop they say.

The reality is it doesn't stop them. They keep doing it because BECAUSE they are bored. 

If it gets bad enough your parents and teachers might be able to do something about it but if not, it's very difficult to do anything about it.

This situation applies in real life outside school too.

We live in a society that only functions because of a fragile balance we've managed to create thanks to laws and regulations. Laws that limit freedom of speech among other things are designed to stop cases like I described because in real life your parents can't come and save you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396858345.0" user="NewyBluey" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry to hear that you were bullied. Sad that you didn't fight back. I have personal memories of being bullied and the consequences of both not fighting back and of fighting back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400288525.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Bullies being treated far far far too leniently by schools is not part of my argument at all. I was also verbally bullied till I left school, yes I'm upset by it and I do certain things because of it. But I feel like with genuine in school teaching about behaviour and punishments they would learn to be better people, they've just got to wait for someone to punch them in the face rn it seems. And some people are just like that, and they usually end up lonely tbh. And they should also teach victims of bullies better coping mechanisms for how they feel. 

But I'm still alive and I know that I am safe, these peoples comments stopped at the door of the school and any time I got something online it was very simple to block the person. And tbh even if bullies actually do result to violence there is still nothing done so it's not like a law really stops them.

In work places ect it would be taken seriously and if not theres probs more reason to move job than just the bully</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403612917.0" user="MightyBoat" delta="False">
    <text>I just think that your argument is not well defined enough. You seem to imply you want freedom of speech at all costs. By your logic it would mean anyone would be free to harass others because "the world is big enough and they can just move". It would mean people would be able to lie in adverts or political campaigns etc because the government shouldn't be getting involved in speech right? We should be able to do our own research about politics right?

Other than that I totally agree with education, teaching people coping mechanisms etc but until we have a perfect society, do we just give up and let them suffer? I'd rather have imperfect laws that attempt to reduce harm than nothing at all.

We're a far cry from 1984. I don't think any of the so called censorship warrants any drastic changes to the way we deal with free speech.

Also how is any of the censorship going on now worse than the antivax, Brexit, and trump campaigns? Those things are all full of total lies that do real world damage. More damage than the censorship you seem to think is so prevalent. IMO at least I haven't seen anything that bad. 

I don't know where you are politically speaking, but you living in Scotland should be very aware of the damage Brexit has done to the union and all of it was based on lies because of lack of regulation on speech. No regulation means no accountability. Are you happy to just accept that people can do that with no repercussions?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
