<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39392550040.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>So Scotland got a new hate speech law in 2021, which I suspect is at least somewhat related to this post. 

The thing is, is that the new law doesn't actually impact free speech. Stating ones views, stating ones views with vigor, even if some people get offended - don't violate the new law. It isn't the stating of an opinion which is illegal, but intentionally causing offense. 

Saying something for the sole and only reason being to make others aggregated at you is what is illegal now. Stating a view that you genuinely believe isn't illegal. 

Isn't the point of free speech to be able to say what you believe? Is there a point to speech which doesn't relate to what one believes?? Yes, enforcement of this requires policing intent, but the legal system has been analyzing intent for centuries, this isn't new territory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395514537.0" user="YARNIA" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Saying something for the sole and only reason being to make others aggregated at you is what is illegal now. 

And who decides what your reasons are? This requires mind-reading. Thus if the person in power decides that your private mental state was wrong (regardless of the content of your message) you are a criminal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395802332.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>The legal system has been determining intent since it's inception. This isn't new.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395826925.0" user="YARNIA" delta="False">
    <text>That it isn't new doesn't mean that it is a good idea. If the whole of the crime is the intention, then the whole of the proof is a private mental state. If we're talking about "murder" then we have a dead body, means, opportunity, and behavior from which we infer to motive. This is quite different from the whole of a crime being an inference to a private mental state, especially in a polarized political environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396301012.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>What's your stance on perjury? 

Telling a false statement vs knowingly telling a false statement makes all the difference? 

I don't see how distinguishing perjury from "trying to tell the truth but simply being wrong" is any harder than this??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397797990.0" user="YARNIA" delta="False">
    <text>Even here there are differences. Perjury involves the claimant making a claim that is false in objective terms relevant to the facts of the case. This does not involve "wrong think" or speculating about that which is not known, or contradicting an official narrative with is asserted with little or no evidence by mainstream sources (e.g., Clinton did not have sex with that woman, the Iraqis have weapons of mass destruction, Mueller telling congress that the FBI is not spying on Americans, Fauci remarking that masks don't work, just before claiming that they do).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397927212.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>But simply being factually inaccurate isn't a crime. If you believe what you say, you aren't committing perjury. 

Therefore proving perjury requires all the same "mind-reading" that this does, since it's the intent that makes it criminal. 

Yeah, perjury and this are different crimes, so there will be differences, but just boiling it down to "you cannot prove intent" is contrary to how the rest of the legal system works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398075596.0" user="YARNIA" delta="False">
    <text>But being "factually inaccurate" in other domains is NOT limited to be wrong about flat facts of the case which are direct and empirical. The domain of wrongness is MUCH wider for public speech, which means that the mind-reading has to be much more expansive, speculative, and, therefore, troubling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
