<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="41" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39393057613.0" user="OromisElf" delta="False">
    <text>Hey, German here.

I'm not really here to change your opinion but rather give you some perspective. You see, I am all for freedom of speech. We had a time here where you would get into a lot of trouble with the government when you criticized said government. However, we also had a time here, where you would get into a lot of trouble with the government when you *didn't* criticize people from other countries, people with non-binary gender identities, people with non-straight sexualities, people with disabilities...

I think what's important about banning certain topics/things from freedom of speech: the targets or rather victims of said speech. 

Like for example if I were to talk publicly about the incompetence of my government, then that will likely harm nobody. If I were to talk publicly about the incompetence of all, let's say, my own neighbors. Then this might draw people in. They might think something like "they wouldn't speak in public if they weren't incompetent", or maybe they would want to get to know my neighbours to see if they are really THAT incompetent, or they might not believe me at all.

Only one of these 3 reactions I thought of wouldn't harm my neighbours in one way or another. Obviously they could do something against this. But also speaking in public would require charisma, time and maybe money. Moving would require a lot of money and also a lot of time. Now your average neighbour might have charisma, but in times like these they will likely lack time and money to get out of my way.

Depending on how available my "speech" is, moving within the country might not even solve the issue.

Now you might say "hey, wait a second. You left plenty of other reactions out that also wouldn't bother your neighbours"

To which I say that is a) not the point and b) why focus on the options that don't hurt someone and not on those that **do**?

Let's get back to your examples: anti trans jokes, insulting soldiers, racist remarks, nazi/racist jokes. I'm gonna leave the soldier one out because it doesn't fit in that list.

So now my neighbours to the left are trans people, my neighbours to the right have roots in a different country. And I publicly tell a joke about how incompetent my trans neighbours are. And to follow it up I tell a joke about how incompetent my culturally different neighbours are. And to top it off, I tell a joke about how a certain someone had a solution for that.

Some people might laugh about it. Some people might ignore it. Some people might find it disgusting. But there's always at least one more group of listeners that will do neither of that. Instead they will shout about how "right" I am and that it is "brave" of me to speak "truths" like these.

And then I really hope that these people don't know me or where I live. Because if I really told jokes like that, I might've just sold out my neighbours to a group of people who believe in an ideology that *should* be prohobited. That should *not* be getting track again. But most of all an ideology that, about 100 years after it last happened, is again hiding under democratic foundation pillars like "freedom of speech"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
