<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391323545.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>There is line between verbal threat of violence and free speech.

Once someone encourage people (including themselves) to attack other other people, give them advice or hints how to perform act of violence or even mentally abuse people, then they should be stopped. People shouldn't need to live in fear or take abuse just because someone else have "opinions" about them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391377169.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Mental or physical abuse, threats of violence and defamation are needed to be policed, but racist jokes or "I dont agree/ like these people because of this" I dont think do. When it's more an insult or a stereotype sort of thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391391076.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. So there is level of suppression of freedom of speech you are comfortable with. Now it's just finding some level that majority of people agree upon.

You said that abuse, threats and defamation should be policed but jokes not.

What is the line between defamation and a joke? Legally speaking defamation is false statement that hurts the subject. But most jokes are also factually false or otherwise fictitious in nature.

I personally say "let the courts (and juries) decide." I don't want to hurt anyone feelings or support violence in anyways even if someone might find it humorous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391404485.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Deffimation has a lot more clearly defined lines for what should and shouldn't be considered, hence why people joke about someone but when speaking will often use allegedly about stuff. It's a lot clearer what effect it has to have aswell, people have to be able to believe the person who has said about the other. 

For hate crimes it just has to upset someone, and you would be at risk of arrest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391442989.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;For hate crimes it just has to upset someone, and you would be at risk of arrest.

But isn't this almost the same as "few people getting offended"? Can you see how blurry the lines become once you try to nail them down. And if you think line between between defamation and a joke is clearly defined, can you please tell what it is? Because I think that line is murky at best and highly subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391524012.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>"the remark must be false, against a living person and have the effect of lowering their reputation. "

It's at least more defined than hate crime laws, and it's got to be proven to have a negative affect unlike hate crime law</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391542867.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>What about jokes?

Jokes are often factually false or otherwise fictitious in nature. They can be about living person (or group of people). And we wouldn't be here if jokes weren't meant to make their target a laughing stock ergo lowering their reputation.

Certainly lot of jokes that are targeted by these laws fill all the requirements of defamation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391556078.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>There has to be proof it damages the other person as far as I can tell. Even if though joke about bisexuals like they cheat or they do X isnt affecting peoples lives at all its treated the same because its upsetting to read to some people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391584077.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly there has to be proof. That proof have to be bought in front of court after accused person is arrested. They might be found not guilty or not. That's courts purpose but before it this person needs to be arrested (or sued because there is no reason to keep these people locked upped).

I don't support mobs or vigilance but that we have laws in place and those laws are enacted by the police and the court. Those laws are to protect (mental) safety of people against threats of violence or defamation. And lot of jokes could fall into definition of defamation but that's again courts job to look at the proof.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396009630.0" user="b3l6arath" delta="False">
    <text>So, a racist joke

1. Is false
2. Is aimed against living persons
3. Lowers their reputation

Why should they be allowed?

Why should verbal abuse be allowed when physical abuse isn't? Is psychological damage irrelevant?

Disclaimer of my bias:
I got bullied for a decade when I went to school. My personality, my emotions and my understanding of my emotions is still majorly fucked up and I'd happily give a foot or leg if that'd fix these issues. Most of the trauma won't heal, I'll have to somehow live with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397912491.0" user="Farfour1985" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry you were bullied. I was bullied a lot for my race. Bullying is not freedom of speech, there are anti-bullying laws in a lot States and all schools and private places.

However, where do we draw the line to what’s offensive and harming psychologically? What if I speak against war and hurt the feelings of soldiers? What if I speak against religion and harm the feelings of followers of a certain religion? You get my drill. Freedom of speech is essential for our moral and cultural progress. If we didn’t have it, we would’ve never accomplished what we have so far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400080602.0" user="Acerbatus14" delta="False">
    <text>i think it depends on what the joke purports. if the racist joke purports "x black man is a ape" i doubt you can get a defamation suit because you can't reasonably expect people to believe a human is a animal, and thus hurt their reputation in that way. now if it was "x black man stole a bike" you could then get a defamation because its a action that people can believe happened, and the onus of presenting proof fell on the victim

needless to say the comedian would have to demonstrate that the part about stealing a bike is not part of the joke, and is a factual statement by the comedian</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392644503.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Defamation requires a false statement of fact. Jokes tend not to be factual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392748388.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Joke is a statement and that statement is often false ergo jokes can be seen as defamation. Some jokes have even been trialed as defamation so we have precedent for this. Biggest problem is that most jokes are not directed to single person and cannot therefore be prosecuted as defamation. You can't have one person representing all gays or all black people. But just because joke makes fun of lot of people don't make it any less defamation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393018955.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Which jokes have been treated as defamation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393107311.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Just Google "Comedian sued for defamation". There are countless cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393156665.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>I’m aware of the case in Canada, but that wasn’t for defamation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393880149.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>And if you dig around you will find that "it was a joke" is not legal defense for defamation. At least not a good one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396584015.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>are you not familiar with the [*hustler magazine v falwell*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hustler_Magazine_v._Falwell)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393881711.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>And if you dig around you will find that "it was a joke" is not legal defense for defamation. At least not a good one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393303850.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>What is the difference between "not factual" and "false statement of fact"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393735210.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Not factual could be an opinion - it’s broader than a false statement of fact. “I think Joe is a condescending asshole” isn’t factual and is not defamatory. “I think Joe robbed that bank” is a false statement of fact that could be defamatory if false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393754343.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think offensive jokes can easily cross the line by implying/assuming false statements of fact? For example, a joke that implies Jews manipulate the media.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393759932.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>You can’t really defame a race, at least not legally. Who is going to bring the suit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393865373.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>OK, fair enough. Let me rephrase the question. Do you think you can make false statements of fact as part of a joke?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393872455.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>All right, fair enough; let me rephrase my question. Do you think it's possible for a joke to contain a false statement of fact?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393875976.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>All right, fair enough; let me rephrase my question. Do you think it's possible for a joke to contain a false statement of fact?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393878584.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough; let me rephrase the question: do you think it is possible for a joke to contain a false statement of fact?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394156411.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391392143.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize though that other people have their own freedoms? You can say what you want but don’t get upset if you get fired because of that. For example, I’ve yet to see the Catholic Church hire a vocal atheist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391413275.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Consequences for peoples actions are legal, if I say "Jak is a b****" and jak does the same back that's fine. If I go to work and say my coworker is and she reports to the boss and I'm fired that's fine. 

But the law shouldn't be involved, governments shouldn't have so much freedom to bend the definitions of a law around peoples speech. The more we give them that control the more ability they could have to limit other forms of speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391420646.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but most examples of “censorship” that Conservatives complain about is ultimately just private entities just using their freedom of association</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391450891.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but what? I know that, I'm not caring about that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391498792.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. Still relevant when assessing legitimacy of outrage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397319488.0" user="Blackpaw8825" delta="False">
    <text>I still don't follow op's position, 'CMV this thing that doesn't happen shouldn't be allowed to keep happening.'

Then agrees that the thing isn't happening? There's no view to change there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398973028.0" user="Quail_eggs_29" delta="False">
    <text>Report the post and move on, perhaps they’ll resubmit with better clarity</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396558028.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>like kapernick not getting a job in the nfl or joe rogan not being fired?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397237247.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, right wing people are usually really hypocritical about it aswell</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397358262.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>they are, but let's not pretend left wingers aren't also. they are the ones complaining about my 2 examples, obviously, but it is the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398325346.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>Fair</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397016822.0" user="KindaNotSmart" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give examples of people getting arrested or in legal trouble due to racist jokes or insults? Because that’s the basis of your argument yet any comment that asks you who you’ve seen get arrested has no response from you

You aren’t wrong that racist/insulting jokes should not result in legal trouble. But that’s more of a ‘no shit’ than anything else because nobody is getting into legal trouble for racist/insulting jokes yet you think they are for some reason</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392641359.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Social consequences are fine. Being arrested? Not really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392680293.0" user="drakethatsme" delta="False">
    <text>Vocal athiest currently working for the Catholic Church as a singer. 

It's honestly kinda nice taking their money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393474957.0" user="neonfuzzball" delta="False">
    <text>atheist who works for a church here too! Love living a sitcom premise</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394112599.0" user="antlerchapstick" delta="False">
    <text>OP isn’t talking about Social consequences. They are from Scotland where you can (apparently) be arrested for speech deemed hate speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396061793.0" user="Interesting_Mood_124" delta="False">
    <text>Than she is free to prove that is something that actually happens there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393455472.0" user="steadyatbest420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Mental or physical abuse, threats of violence and defamation are needed to be policed,

Who decides what constitutes abuse, threats, or defamation? The government? Individuals? You?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393805649.0" user="thatbish345" delta="False">
    <text>But you can’t be arrested just for saying racist things unless it’s also a crime</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399079373.0" user="Muad_Dib_PAT" delta="False">
    <text>Except that's not what your post said. You're moving the goalpost, at least give a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39557808175.0" user="zgcolyar" delta="False">
    <text>when the speech is used as a tool to spread hate and misinformation about a certain demographic of people, it doesn't deserve protection. This includes those "harmless jokes" because, in reality, they aren't harmless, it's spreading bigotry to whatever group the joke is making fun of. And you know exactly which kind of jokes I'm referring to. Currently, in the USA, there is a lot of anti-trans rhetoric being spewed by conservatives, which is only amplified by these jokes and harmful media portrayals. And if you really don't think that a famous comedian making jokes calling trans people pedophiles and perverts etc is harmful, then why are politicians saying the exact same thing as a reason to take away our rights and privileges. "it's okay to take trans people's rights away because they're grooming the children, and are mentally unstable perverts, etc." and these "harmless jokes" are just adding fuel to the fire. Just because it isn't directly harming someone in particular, like a threat or defamation, doesn't mean it isn't harmful indirectly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391473268.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>That reasoning quickly becomes absurd. What if I think that your values will lead the world towards a state which is dangerous for me? Can I then treat you maliciously in "self defense"?

I've been told before that everyone who votes for Trump is a nazi, and that nazis are inherently dangerous and malicious, and that they're impossible to reason with (and that trying is validating their views, making any attempt at communication and rational discussions equivalent to supporting nazism). I've also been told that nazis have no human rights, that they don't deserve them, and that it's a moral *obligation* to assault them on sight. These ideas are not uncommon, and I've been told that I (along with almost half the American population) deserve to die many times here on Reddit. Hopefully this is unreasonable to you.

Another issue is how you say that "Those who encourage people to attack others should be stopped", especially since "stopped" often means that they should be attacked. To make matter much worse, it has recently become a popular idea that offensive speech and discrimination is "fighting words", that you're allowed to attack people in self defense for what they say. And it doesn't even stop at speech, all symbolism and *perceived* behaviour is included. If I do the OK hand symbol because I'm a diver or whatever, then I'm suddenly responsible for the emotional reaction of whoever misunderstands my intentions, and at risk of being assaulted for it.

"Innocent until proven guilty" should not be infringed for reasons like these.

By the way, holding opinions is a human right. You may hate me, and if you do, I don't think it's your choice in the first place. We're not entitled to other peoples approval, even if we "deserve it", or if we're "minorities" or "underprivileged". It's illegal to act on such feelings, and recently it seems to be a trend to make it illegal to *show* such feelings too, but you don't solve a problem by hiding its symptoms from yourself, and there's no solutions to other people holding negative opinions which doesn't go against their inherent human rights, except communication. This is why censorship and the resulting echo chambers is a danger which only worsens the problem that it claims to solve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391566997.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>When I say "stopped" it means they should be arrested by the police and prosecuted by the court. They should be proven guilty and punished. It doesn't mean we should become vigilantes and attack people.

People shouldn't need to live in fear because you have hateful opinions about them. Deal with that hate in private and don't spread it around. Your right to opinion doesn't supersede others right to safety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391612217.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>How is it unsafe to read or see something racist/sexist/homophobic ect, unless actual threats are made to people. But at that point its threats of violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391642128.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Depending on content it can be defamation, threats of violence or it could be just free speech. Most cases are clearly one of the two formar and in any case it should be brought to court to figure out which if any damage was caused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393315489.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>When I see nazis saying nazi things in public more and more without consequences, I feel incredibly unsafe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394397334.0" user="O_X_E_Y" delta="False">
    <text>it's a blurry line because you should always place these jokes in their current social context. Every now and then I see transphobic posts trending on the frontpage of reddit, I see news stories of anti-trans violence, I see politicians banning trans people's right to exist outright. This means that a transphobic joke can't really be seen in a vacuum anymore but rather as possible furthering the sentiment people already might have. Seeing countless [r/cringetopia](https://www.reddit.com/r/cringetopia) users make apache helicopter jokes in that context can seem just as threatening as them outright calling for violence. Any of the people participating might be ones from future news stories of anti-trans violence, even if that's not realistic, the psychological damage is very similar. Just like 'I didn't know that was a law' isn't an excuse, I don't think claiming you're oblivious of the damage you're doing shouldn't be an excuse either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391641511.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Arrested by the police and prosecuted by the court

That imples that they've done something illegal. The free speech that people tend to be punished for is not illegal. Reddit is against free speech and often censors and deletes things, with a worrying amount of support, based on a "left" political bias making itself out to be morality itself.

Of course, when about half the population is against human rights in favour of their own opinions, and in favour of changing the law to incorporate their political biases, it becomes a danger that I'll experience legal harassment and prosecution for speaking my mind. I feel like that is still a few years away for now.

&amp;gt;People shouldn't need to live in fear because you have hateful opinions about them.

Does that include racists and those who don't want the vaccine? If so, you need to be more precise so that you mean what you say.

&amp;gt;Your right to opinion doesn't supersede others right to safety.

Opinions do not cause harm. There's no such thing as "thought crimes", that would go against human rights. When they're inside my head, they're private in that manner.

Suppose that groups of black people scared me when walking around at night, I'm totally justified in changing sidewalk, even if it's an irrational fear. Like this, we're all entitled to out own lives, and our own choices, including our mistakes. You, however, don't have the right to govern the actions of other people. For this reason, being a racist is a human right, you can do whatever as long as you don't infringe on the rights of those that you hate.

Speaking of hate, that's not an honest word at all. It functions on a whitelist. You're not allowed to be hateful against certain groups, but you're certainly allowed to be hateful in general, and most of politics is hateful. What you're trying to say is probably that "spreading hate" means going against your biases and values, rather than being hateful in general. It could also mean that one should follow the law, but distasteful jokes are not against the law, and neither should they be.

Finally, you say "opinion", but what about truth? People communicate what they think is true. What if I say something which offends you, but which you know is true? What if it offends you, but is quoted from a scientific article (whenever or not you agree with it)?

What if an offensive or controversial statement results in less danger in the long run? Like telling a fat person that they need to lose weight for the sake of their health, or defending things that the majority might consider dangerous (drugs, alcohol and sex were such things in the past, but we now know that banning them and making them taboo topics was a mistake)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391747015.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Let's find some common ground because most of what you said comes out as random rant about non-existing fears about non-existing issues.

If person says that "Black people are genetically inferior and should kill all of them! Arm yourself and attack their houses! I will lead the charge!". Do you think that black people would be justifiable afraid and should this person be arrested by the police and prosecuted for something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396022975.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Every single thing I've said is reasonable, and I can back it up.

Your example consists of threats of violence, which is already illegal. I'm not sure what you want me to conclude here, is it that we should respect the law? My issue is with people saying "fuck the law, we need to get rid of these people at all costs".

Do you want to make argumentations about moral correctness, or in defense of the law? You're attemping to do both at once, and implying that it's good when you do it and bad when others do it, because you're good and they're bad.

I could say "Threats of violence are bad", but would you even agree? It would mean that we should arrest people for threatening nazis.

The entire ideal of "Equality" has flipped on its head in less than 10 years, and you don't see the issue? Against equal rights (no rights for bad people), equal opportunities (instead, we should interfere to restore balance), well-defined laws (we need to break the law to stop people from breaking the law), etc.

This is why I use "left" in quotation marks, it's more of a mental illnesses thinking that it's an ideology and that there's anything liberal about it.

Here's a question for you, is it alright to imply that all conservatives should be killed? Or an even easier question: Should all sexists be killed? We don't treat even criminals nearly that badly. Theft for under 1000$ is barely even prosecuted anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399213365.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>I started this whole thing by saying

&amp;gt;There is line between verbal threat of violence and free speech.

and you go on random rant about vigilantes and lefthish death patrols. You have truly warped views.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399638715.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>You make nazism itself out to be "verbal threats of violence" even when it's not. Your make it out to be justified to commit self-defense against merely perceived dangers by arguing that your perceived dangers are somehow valid and not merely propaganda.

It's the same with the racist and the race in question. It's actually the same with every movement in existence, and the group that they claim is responsible and dangerous, "the patriarchy" is just another instance of this, incels think it about women, nazis thought it about jews, poor people often think it about the rich.

You're no better, you're just an instance of the same error fighting for itself.

You don't seem to dare to write a lot (why such a defensive way of communication? I don't bite outside of banter), so I won't put words in your mouth, but I have multiple conversations going in this thread and the rest support vigilantism and mass-murder. But it's okay, because it's against "nazis" and "racists", or something, but even here I disagree.

The civilized society is largely against execution of the worst people in society, and fear that they might be innocently accused. Whatever movement is not calling itself left, and taking glee in the idea of assaulting those accused of nazism, and denying human rights to groups it considers undeserving (nazis, but also things like medical help for those who are skeptical of the vaccination), is uncivilized. If you defend them, you're warped yourself. I don't blame you for being human, but you have 104 deltas so I'm a little disappointed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399675411.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>I never used Nazism as example. This (and rest of your rant) is you depositing your delusional views in a straw man argument. You might have this argument with other people but not with me and I don't want to argue on behalf of anyone else.

If you want to discuss with me then discuss about arguments I make not something someone else hypothetically might say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400322652.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>You either support free speech when it's legal, even if it's offensive and in bad taste, or else you do not support it at all. Either you judge people on actions, like the law, or else you believe in the idea of thought crimes.

I support free speech, and I do not believe that anything else than actions ought to be punished. Even being a racist is a right, it's merely a negative association with a personal trait, "learned" from society or by personal experience. You can't overwrite human nature with legislations, at best you can mask it.

Dare say anything concrete? If you're being vague and afraid to stand by anything, there's nothing to really argue about, and I can only guess what part of my statement you disagree with and break it down into details, which I argee seems to be a waste of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400397837.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I support free speech, and I do not believe that anything else than actions ought to be punished.

Well slander or defamation is illegal and it's controlling what people can and cannot say. Or suicide bomber example I gave. That guy hadn't done anything else than just threaten to kill people but they will still be stopped accordingly to law. So either you cannot support the law and unrestricted free speech at the same time. Law already limits free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400456679.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>That's not because free speech isn't a right, but rather because slander is an action which goes against others rights. There's a hierarchy through which we solve conflicts. That's another conversation, though, it doesn't make sense to judge human rights against eachother if you discard them on your own personal whim anyway.

Murder is also wrong, but you might have to kill in self-defence, that doesn't mean that the law is a suggestion, that it's poorly defined, that I'm a hypocrite, or that all self-defense is reasonable, and it doesn't tell us whenever or not murder was or wasn't "excessive force" in the hypothetical scenario.

If support the law in one scenario, and advocate breaking the law in another because some words offend you and you want to punch that person, then you're being inconsistent. I don't even care which you prefer, but if you claim to support both at the same time, how am I supposed to agree with you or argue against you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400486129.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;rather because slander is an action which goes against others rights

So if you agree that slander is action then what's the problem? Speaking is action and speaking can be lawfully stopped.

I have never supported vigilante or violent action of any sort. That must have been some other user.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401515008.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Speech is an action, but it's not up to the listener to judge whenever or not the speaker has the right to continue speaking. The ideal of free speech is to have as much speech as possible which is in good faith, and not merely which is pleasant to listen to or agreeable.

If you just think we should follow the law, I'm not sure the conversation is really about free speech, but it's a good foundation to have.

As for whenever online censorship, social pressure and mob justice can be considered "free speech", it not an easy topic. But the same reasoning applies - online echo chambers are dangerous. Authority which can silence people, be they government or everyday people, are a danger to freedom and scientific truth.

I understood your lack of engagement with some of my points as disagreement, which might have been a mistake on my part! And yeah, I have a lot of conversations going at once, and the conversations are rather plain so I have a hard time staying alert and switch to auto-pilot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401738643.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have a hard time staying alert and switch to auto-pilot

And that's why I am not engaging with everything you write because most of it doesn't apply to my argument.

But back to how currently law prevents free speech or slander. It's listeners duty to inform and sue based on their own feelings. They decide if they are hurt enough to lead to legal dispute.

But honestly. If you feel like you have right to go around insulting people, you might have legal right but that's still makes you morally an asshole. Good people don't want to hurt anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403835772.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They decide if they are hurt enough to lead to legal dispute.

That's incredibly stupid, so I'm guessing it's a newer thing.

As a general rule, I think most emotional pain is received by those that we love, and not strangers. It's also easy to hurt people badly with words, without slander or insults, I'd even go as far as to say that it's *easier*. And you would never have a case against them if they didn't word themselves incredibly stupidly.

&amp;gt;Good people don't want to hurt anyone.

That's not true, and "good" tend to be a code word for "weak", but how can you make a positive difference in the world if you're a wimp? How could you help your loved ones if you're weak because power itself scares you and makes you guilty?

People improve through criticism, so how can you be a good friend if you're too afraid to hurt them to tell them the truth? You'd just be sitting them up for failure.

You're not even a moral person if you've just subscribed to some political set of values, your actual virue will be your own. Your own conclusions, your own good and evil, your own values. You might do your best for others, only to be misunderstood, like how parents tend to be hated by their children when they're teenagers.

The world isn't all that complicated, but it's not all that easy, either! You've read too many news which only covers the worst that humanity has to offer, so now your standards have fallen and you're looking down on those who disagree with you.

I bet most people owe the best things about themselves, and the best thing about their lives, to suffering. To pain that they were forced to overcome and deal with. It forced them to look for solutions, to challenge themselves, to really decide this and that. That these people would stand still if life didn't push them, that still water gets stale and that it pushes you along for your own good. That said, the pain and suffering that a statement inflicts on you is not a measure of its truth, worth, or usefulness, I merely mean that it's not its opposite. We should judge people by how small, petty and narrow they are, because that's a better indicator on their positive and negative effect on the world than whenever or they're "good" or "evil".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39407543936.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's also easy to hurt people badly with words, without slander or insults

If you hurt people it's emotional violence and you can sue for that. Again decided by the victim if they want to press charges like with any other crime.

&amp;gt;That's not true, and "good" tend to be a code word for "weak"

You said it yourself. It's easy to hurt people. Anyone can be an asshole or even violent. It shows true strength to so compassion, empathy or even love to people who have wronged you and forgive them. That what good person does. That what good Christian would do.

Also you don't need to hurt anyone feelings when giving criticism. If you feel that you must insult and break someone into tears in order for them to grow you are borderline sociopath. I feel sorry for you if you think that suffering is good. But not to kink shame if you are into S&amp;amp;M.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395016231.0" user="Soleos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The free speech that people tend to be punished for is not illegal.

If you're talking about arrests and prosecution, then the context is exactly violations of laws related to hate-speech with specific operational definitions--i.e. laws that make such speech illegal. Whether you agree with the law or not, that's a different debate. 

People are not talking about policing thoughts kept privately. That's a strawman. We are talking about how people choose to express their opinions, e.g. through persistent harassment resulting in psychological and mental harm and through threats of physical harm. These are the kinds of things people ought to be arrested for, not for merely feeling offended. There is a difference between being offended by someone calling you a wet bowel movement and a Jew facing someone with a swastika tattoo talking about their "opinion" that Jews are a disease that must be purged from the earth--to give an exaggerated example. 

If you want to talk about cancel culture and social punishment, people saying "They're an asshole, don't trust them, don't do business with them," well I guess that's just people using their freedom of speech to express their own opinions that do not cause harm right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395627893.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>There's no such thing as "hate speech", that's just a silly term for prosecuting people who you find disagreeable.

&amp;gt;Whether you agree with the law or not, that's a different debate.

So should we follow the law? Assault is illegal even if it's targeted against nazism. Well-defined laws that people actually follow is a great idea, taking the law into your own hands is not, especially when it's political extremism.

Getting people fired, banning them, accusing them of bad behaviour, manipulating them, etc. is poor, immoral behaviour. To value silencing people over having rational, calm discussions is extremely poor taste, no?

&amp;gt;Through persistent harassment

That sounds a lot like cancel culture to me.

&amp;gt;Resulting in psychological and mental harm and through threats of physical harm

Harm is received, not given. If I call you stupid-face and that hurts to hear, I really shouldn't be arrested for that. It also hurts to be rejected, that doesn't mean that incels should get their way now does it?

How easy your life must be! If insults and discrimination is on your top-10 list of problems, you're privileged. People have financial problems, they might starve themselves so that they can feed their animals or children, the love of their life won't acknowledge their existence, a friend of theirs committed suicide, another was drafted for war. They're stuck in a dead-end job, their car seems like it might break down any time, they don't have many friends, they spend their free time at the pub. These are regular problems that average people deal with, and your quest for improving the world consists of punishing people for using the wrong pronoun or being wary of black people after some bad personal experiences?

&amp;gt;To give an exaggerated example.

And yet many people will say that exact thing to somebody with a swastika tattoo, if they dare, at least. There's little logic in "Treating people badly is wrong, so lets look for people we think are bad so that we can treat them badly".

&amp;gt;I guess that's just people using their freedom of speech to express their own opinions that do not cause harm right?

It does cause harm. It's also their right - it's just extremely poor taste. Bullying is also not illegal, mental abuse too, treating people poorly, making up rumors at your school, turning your friends against each other - you can do all of these, it just makes you an asshole. Just don't pretend you're virtuous for doing it, that it's the right thing to do, that it's a moral obligation, or that anyone forced you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395906834.0" user="Soleos" delta="False">
    <text>Ummm okay. Well I can recognize a couple worthwhile points to talk about from what you've written, it seems you've missed the point of each of my arguments, so there's not likely going to be any meaningful communication. Goodbye and good luck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39439610463.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That imples that they've done something illegal. The free speech that people tend to be punished for is not illegal. Reddit is against free speech and often censors and deletes things, with a worrying amount of support, based on a "left" political bias making itself out to be morality itself.



Late reply but reddit is a private entity. They have every right to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391701028.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>youre using the tolerance of intolerance paradox. being a nazi isnt a protected class</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392056565.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a paradox, you and everyone repeating "the paradox of tolerance" in defense of leftist ideas haven't understood it.

And what do you mean it's not a protected class? It's not "protected" like sexuality is, but that doesn't mean that you should deny them human rights, which I'd hope is obvious. Finally, not everyone you *accuse* of being a nazi is actually a nazi. People have poor judgement in general, that's why we have court systems, and the people that you're defending abuse against haven't broken the law in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392386091.0" user="nerdyboy321123" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain what part of the paradox of intolerance people are misunderstanding? It seems well applied, usually: a wholly tolerant society that is unreactive to any views/beliefs/lifestyles will give space for intolerant groups to grow and organize until they can potentially inflict their will on the people they're intolerant of.

I.e. the US, in the name of freedom of speech, has allowed white supremacists to make up a note able portion of our public discourse (see:Carlson/Shapiro using 'great replacement' rhetoric for a very easy example). White supremacy is an inherently violent, intolerant ideology. So, then, the options become maintaining 'tolerance' of their white supremacy, at the expense of everyone not white. Or, we become intolerant of that white supremacy and take the necessary steps to remove it from society.

What those necessary steps are is up for debate. Some people think the government should strictly legislate against it, others think that's too easily manipulatable by bad actors in government to be used against political enemies. Others think public shaming should work, like doxxing the Charlottesville protesters to their employers. Others, still,  think the people should do it, this is where the "punching Nazis" thing comes from.  When people are spouting Nazi rhetoric there's no legal recourse, so maybe punching them isn't your preferred method of handling it but would you rather people are just like "I don't respect your view that we should violently create an ethnostate but I'll defend your right to say it?"

So that's the dilemma. White supremacy is at the core of a significant amount of political discourse and we should all find that unacceptable. You may disagree with people's methods of pushing back against it, but some methods are needed. I really don't think it's a stretch to say that anyone that sees white supremacy taking up more space and argues against any attempts to stop it is really just supporting white supremacy. If you deny that white supremacy is growing right now, then you're really just not paying attention or are feigning ignorance for the sake of not wanting to push back against it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395908036.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Karl Popper warned about people who couldn't be reasoned with, and who wanted to fight others instead. Yet I hear leftists say "Don't engage with nazis, that just validates their ideas, it's your moral obligation to punch them instead".

If the problem is intolerance, how could intolerance possibly be the solution? Karl Poppers argument does not choose sides, it's a neutral statement. It might as well have been said by the nazis like "We can't tolerate Jews, because if they get any more power over the banking system and such they'll hurt us", actually, I think they said something like that.

&amp;gt;White supremacy is an inherently violent, intolerant ideology.

And yours isn't? You don't tolerate the right, and you don't see the problem in violence against nationalists.

Here's an inherent violent, intolerant belief system: Islam. It has about 2 billion members (and there's about 140K neo-nazis in the world if I remember correctly). They want to convert everyone else. Disbelievers have to pay them money or face death. They believe that women are worth less than men. Do you think that it's our moral obligation to kill them before they become enough people to convert us by force? This has always been the main argumentation against Islam.

&amp;gt;Like doxxing

You support breaking the law in order to hurt political enemies? They don't have rights like you?

&amp;gt;"but I'll defend your right to say it?"

Yes, unless you want to make exceptions for human rights? That one must deserve them?

The Geneva Conventions make no exceptions. Until recently, at least, we considered it immoral to torture anyone, including terrorists who literally slaughtered civilians, no matter their age or gender, in order to spread their political ideas. It was mainly the left which called it inhumane.

See this? It's Reddits blog from 2014:

https://archive.ph/iylV3

"The philosophy behind this stems from the idea that each individual is responsible for his or her moral actions.
We uphold the ideal of free speech on reddit as much as possible not because we are legally bound to, but because we believe that you – the user – has the right to choose between right and wrong, good and evil, and that it is your responsibility to do so. When you know something is right, you should choose to do it. But as much as possible, we will not force you to do it.

You choose what to post. You choose what to read. You choose what kind of subreddit to create and what kind of rules you will enforce. We will try not to interfere – not because we don’t care, but because we care that you make your choices between right and wrong.
Virtuous behavior is only virtuous if it is not arrived at by compulsion. This is a central idea of the community we are trying to create."

How insane everyone has gotten in a few years, and without noticing!

&amp;gt;I really don't think it's a stretch

So I support inherently dangerous beliefs, which means that I should be killed?

&amp;gt;If you deny that white supremacy is growing right now, then you're really just not paying attention

Extreme changes cause extreme counter-reactions, it's all trivially predictable, and if you try to get people killed I don't think it's a good argument to say "See! They're dangerous!" when they punch back.

White people are actually being replaced. That's purely statistics, I'm not saying that it's a good or a bad thing. Migrants do stress welfare systems, and I'm not commenting on whenever or not that's a worthy price for helping people seeking better lives. White people are doing better, and their values work better too, even if they ought to do everything in their power to help those in poverty. For the sake of quality, we need to discriminate against people in that you can't advance in academia unless you pass the classes, and we generally attempt to establish hierarchies of competence so that you can get the very best doctors to save your life if you get in an accident. The most competent people are rewarded the most, even if they haven't worked as hard, or if their parents had more money which gave them the privilege of better education.

There's valid reasons for holding opinions which go against your own, it's not as simple as people being assholes, they're not just looking for people to discriminate against, and they don't simply believe that they're "better". At least 99% of people are just doing the best with the information that they have, much like yourself. If you ask me though, your knowledge base is propaganda and mediocre news articles by politically biased "journalists". But do you really have to "remove them from society" through illegal or cruel means that we wouldn't even use against serial killers?

I don't blame you, though, all these garbage arguments are probably all you've heard for years now, and you've probably noticed that questioning them is a social danger, and don't we all want to get along with our friends and community?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397619994.0" user="nerdyboy321123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If the problem is intolerance, how could intolerance possibly be the solution? 

You're right, the solution to intolerance being intolerance is paradoxical. Hence, the title 'the intolerance paradox.'

&amp;gt;Karl Poppers argument does not choose sides, it's a neutral statement. It might as well have been said by the nazis like "We can't tolerate Jews, because if they get any more power over the banking system and such they'll hurt us", actually, I think they said something like that.

Funny that you bring up Karl Poppers when, as best I can tell, the original source for him discussing the 'paradox of intolerance' doesn't align with the argument you're making: 

&amp;gt;"Less well known [than other paradoxes] is the paradox of tolerance: Unlimited tolerance must lead to the disappearance of tolerance. If we extend unlimited tolerance even to those who are intolerant, if we are not prepared to defend a tolerant society against the onslaught of the intolerant, then the tolerant will be destroyed, and tolerance with them.—In this formulation, I do not imply, for instance, that we should always suppress the utterance of intolerant philosophies; **as long as** we can counter them by rational argument and keep them in check by public opinion, suppression would certainly be most unwise. But we should claim the right to suppress them if necessary even by force; for it may easily turn out that they are not prepared to meet us on the level of rational argument, but begin by denouncing all argument; **they may forbid their followers to listen to rational argument,** because it is deceptive, and teach them to answer arguments by the use of their fists or pistols. We should therefore claim, in the name of tolerance, the right not to tolerate the intolerant. **We should claim that any movement preaching intolerance places itself outside the law and we should consider incitement to intolerance and persecution as criminal**, in the same way as we should consider incitement to murder, or to kidnapping, or to the revival of the slave trade, as criminal."

Emphasis mine. I feel like the party for whom 'fake news' has almost become a catchphrase may be doing so to forbid their followers from listening to rational argument. In the last sentence he explicitly calls for the criminalization of intolerant ideologies. I honestly hadn't see the full quote before, either, but am almost astonished that he's actually making the exact same argument I am.

&amp;gt;And yours isn't? You don't tolerate the right, and you don't see the problem in violence against nationalists.

But context matters. There's absolutely a difference between being intolerant of someone's identity (non-white, LGBT, etc.) and being intolerant of someone's beliefs and actions. Saying "I don't think the US should allow black people" is different from saying "I don't think the US should allow people who think we shouldn't allow black people." Comparing white supremacists to people that use extreme measures to oppose white supremacists is buck wild. That said, I do tolerate some members of the right; I don't think we should go around punching every republican we see. I'll get to this later, but there are some reasons for voting R that I don't think are rooted in a violent ideology. However, conservatives like Richard Spencer (who started the punching nazis debate) are expressly in support of violent, exclusionary ideas and shouldn't be surprised when they're met with opposing violence.

&amp;gt;Here's an inherent violent, intolerant belief system: Islam. It has about 2 billion members (and there's about 140K neo-nazis in the world if I remember correctly). They want to convert everyone else. Disbelievers have to pay them money or face death. They believe that women are worth less than men. Do you think that it's our moral obligation to kill them before they become enough people to convert us by force? This has always been the main argumentation against Islam.

Another absolutely wild comparison here. You are painting the entirety of a religion as being followers of the most extreme, militant versions of that religion. I think if there was an Islamic uprising in the US that was pushing for legislation limiting the rights of marginalized groups or converting people by force then they should absolutely be met with violence. Thankfully nothing remotely close is happening with any Islamic group in the US since muslims are also just human beings and the militant portion of the religion is a minute fraction. 

Funny enough, though, you could make the exact same argument against Evangelical Christianity: Want to convert everyone else, women are worth less than men, etc. Except the Evangelical segment of the US has a huge influence in politics, is pushing (and passing) misogynistic legislation, and has *very* close ties with the white supremacist branch of our politics. What you paint as reason to fear Islam can be more aptly applied to evangelicals. Even then, though, I obviously don't want to push back on the entirety of evangelical christianity - just those who use it as a cudgel to limit the rights of women and the LGBT community.

&amp;gt;You support breaking the law in order to hurt political enemies? They don't have rights like you?

I may have misused doxxing here - typed that comment as I woke up, but I don't think it's illegal to send video of something someone does publicly to the people that know them. Anybody is welcome to video me in public and send it to whoever they'd like, because there isn't video of me chanting "jews will not replace us" while holding a tiki torch. People suffering the consequences of their hateful actions is fine by me and the only reason it hurts them is because it's shameful.

&amp;gt;The Geneva Conventions make no exceptions. Until recently, at least, we considered it immoral to torture anyone, including terrorists who literally slaughtered civilians, no matter their age or gender, in order to spread their political ideas. It was mainly the left which called it inhumane.

Yeah, and I'm not calling for torture? I'm hardly even calling for violence, just defending the idea that it can be justified. Torture is absolutely inhumane, and I agree that it should never be used even in the case of terrorists. Someone getting cheapshotted because they're giving an interview about white supremacist rhetoric isn't the same as fucking waterboarding. If somebody is giving a speech about ethnic cleansing I think they should be arrested and, if that isn't happening, knocked the fuck out. Not disappeared to gitmo to have their life made a living hell until it ends.

I'm not going to directly respond to reddit's views on free speech because I frankly don't give a shit how reddit feels about free speech. They can run their website however they want, if they allow violent rhetoric to a point I find intolerable, I'll leave. That's not at all at odds with pushing for the criminality of violent, intolerant rhetoric; the change we need isn't going to start with Reddit's TOS.

&amp;gt;So I support inherently dangerous beliefs, which means that I should be killed?

I guess here's where I flesh out my thoughts on this, because no.  You shouldn't. I'm not pro-violence, I'm not hoping for a civil war where leftists wipe out any dissenters, I'm not jumping to force at every opportunity. I enjoy arguing with people (that's why I'm typing this all out, after all :) ), but I think pretending that violent ideologies can be debated into submission is naive at best and blatantly wrong given how things have been in the US for the entirety of its existence. I don't think anyone should be killed for their beliefs, but if you support inherently violent* beliefs like you admit, then you should be stopped if you try and spread those violent beliefs. Ideally by the legal system but, since that legal system is also rooted in violent beliefs, then by the minimum reasonable force necessary. If somebody is screaming nazi rhetoric in the speech I don't think anybody should walk up and shoot them, people should tell them to shut the fuck up and if they don't it's justified to do your best to knock them the fuck out. Knocking someone out is a very visible form of violence, so it's easy to shudder at the thought, but white supremacist rhetoric is violence. Nazi rhetoric is violence. Denying the existence of trans people is violence. For people affected by violent ideologies, punching someone spreading that ideology is self-defence. In that light, my whole stance can really just be summarized that whatever self defence you find reasonable in any violent situation on the street, I find acceptable when people come across someone promoting violent ideals. 

&amp;gt;White people are actually being replaced. That's purely statistics, I'm not saying that it's a good or a bad thing.

You should be able to say it's neither. That's always going to happen considering whiteness is defined as exclusionary - if a black person and white person have a kid together that kid is infinitely more likely to be considered a black kid than a white one. The only way for the white population to not decrease is for white people to only have kids with other white people. The fact that isn't happening just makes sense. That's literally just reality and could not matter less.

&amp;gt;White people are doing better, and their values work better too, even if they ought to do everything in their power to help those in poverty

I was kind of giving you benefit of the doubt, but 'their values work better too' sounds like a pretty blatantly white supremacist talking point. Wondering if you can clarify what that means to you.

(Continued in another comment b/c of character limit)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399959002.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The solution to intolerance being intolerance is paradoxical

No it's not. To begin with, if intolerance makes it to the majority, would it not be "democracy"? And in arguing for the sake of intolerance, have you not already given up on the very ideal that characterized leftism not many years ago?

"For it may easily turn out that they are not prepared to meet us on the level of rational argument, but begin by denouncing all argument"

This is the left. They stand for censorship and violence rather than rational discussion. You can discuss openly on 4chan, you can't on Reddit. 

"And teach them to answer arguments by the use of their fists or pistols"

Have you never seen a sentence like "We should answer nazi rhetoric with a fist"?

&amp;gt;Any movement preaching intolerance places itself outside the law

Intoleance of everyone who's "racist" and "sexist" and "homophobe" and "islamophobe" is intolerance. You can tolerate ideas without accepting them, you're not forced to fight like you might be implying.

"Places itself outside the law" is exactly the vigilantism that I'm against, the trial by public opinion, the cancel culture, the modern witch-burning claiming itself to be moral (and certainly, the Christians thought themselves morally correct as well)

You haven't seen it before because you adopted the argument from another person with values similar to your own. I don't think you've tried attacking it yourself, to see if it really holds out in all cases.

&amp;gt;But context matters.

Hypocrisy is not "context". You just consider yourself correct, as every group does, and this is why you deny objective measurements and rules. Do you think that "You shall not kill" supposes context? That it means something like "Don't kill people unless you think they deserve to be killed"? We must make no exceptions if we wish to go anywhere, to agree on anything, to solve any problems in the world. If every sentence we say implies some specific context, and we disagree with it in the next moment, then everything's vague and useless, and our argumentations become justifications of specific examples that align with out own views.

&amp;gt;Comparing white supremacists to people that use extreme measures to oppose white supremacists is buck wild

Why? After all, this "supremacy" is just an accusation. And you're no less of a supremacist, you just belive that your values and political opinion is better, rather than your culture being better. But all culture is, is a set of values, and all religion is, is a set of values!

The "anti-racist" moment started for real in 2015. In response to mass-immigration to Europe and the terror attacks in Paris. People were afraid of Islam (which is no less of a danger to women and homosexuals than nazism is) and its values. They were afraid of migrants in general, **And uncivilized values which threatened our moral process** not just their skin color and identity. I remember the media defending the terrorists, by the way. The media which is now talking about how terrible mistreatment of LGBT people is. But that is one of the issues with Islam (and also Christianity). But religion is a protected class?

&amp;gt;The most extreme, militant versions of that religion

Their law *is* the Koran. They're either extremists, or not muslims at all. Muslims in the US believe that killing civilians is "often or sometimes" justified, with only 59%  saying that it's never justified:

https://www.pewresearch.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/7/2017/07/PF_2017.06.26_muslimamericans-05-02.png

There's over 14285 times more muslims than neo-nazis, and muslims outside of America are very likely to be more extreme than those living in America. Even if they were the same, you're looking at 280 million supporters of terror against civilians.

Half of neo-nazis live in Russia, but if we assumed that *every* neo-nazi lived in America, that'd still only make for 0.28% of Trump voters.

&amp;gt;You could make the exact same argument against Evangelical Christianity

I don't disagree entirely, Christians haven't advocated violence since the crusades though. They can tolerante non-believers, so I can tolerate them.

&amp;gt;misogynistic legislation, and has very close ties with the white supremacist branch of our politics

No such thing. The left is pushing for extreme, poorly-thought-out changes in society, and calling it "racism" and what not when it doesn't go through. There's also nobody who is really against gay rights and LGBTQ rights. After all, it's all human rights, and they should be inalienable. What people are against is *forced speech*, special privileges for "victim" groups, and unfair treatment done out of pity (like racial quotas for hiring), also things like trans people competing in sports, and can you really not see why reasonable people would worry about that? Just like some LGBTQ groups worry that men might identify as women in order to get access to womens toilets and such.

&amp;gt;I'm hardly even calling for violence

If engaging with nazism is wrong because it validates their ideas, and we must get rid of them and suppress them, then what's left besides murder? You can either convince people, or you can force them. By denying free speech and discussions, and by turning to censorship, you exclude the first. You can't change beliefs through the law, that's not how human nature works. It doesn't even help our cause to call for violence. We should seek to understand people and reason with them, because we're all just humans (this is supposed to be a leftist axiom as well, what happened to it?)

&amp;gt;People suffering the consequences of their hateful actions is fine by me

The media is not exposing people, they're slandering them. Nobody is a fair judge against those they hate. You should take no movements words for the actions of those they're against. Incels aren't right about women, white racists aren't right about black people, communists aren't right about capitalism, the far-right is not correct when they say "our nation is better" any more than a football fan is correct when they root for "their team".

But are you sure you want to make the majority opinion into a judge? Why were gay people prosecuted in the past, if not because a majority was against them? Rights should protect minorities against the many! That's the very opposite!

&amp;gt;I'm not going to directly respond to reddit's views on free speech

Firstly, your views on torture and such are quite rational, and I largely agree. I don't even support nazism, I just think that the mentality against them is a greater danger, and often that it's dangerous for exactly the same reason that nazism was dangerous.

Anyway, I wanted to show you the radical *change*. The liberal Reddit of a few years ago is denounced as nazi rhetoric today. It's quite insane.

&amp;gt;Then by the minimum reasonable force necessary

That's a lot of faith to put in a group of emotional people who has been fed anger-invoking and exaggerated articles by the media for years, and who hold strong opinions about all of these issues despite knowing much less than us on average.

&amp;gt;But white supremacist rhetoric is violence

It's really not. By definition, even. And the most extreme versions of those just don't exist in reality. That which is called nazism and supremacy and anti-LGBT isn't calls for violence and murder. It's people who are against uncontrolled migration, people who want to defend their own culture, people whose understanding of gender rests on biology and not psychology, leading to semantic disagreements, etc.

Can you show any counter-examples? Calls for violence? Dehumanization? Or is it all "implied" somehow?

cont.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415536277.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There's also nobody who is really against gay rights and LGBTQ rights.

[The national GOP platform still opposes gay marriage.](https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/richard-grenell-addresses-rnc-gop-platform-still-opposes-gay-marriage-n1238272) That's not nobody.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415991567.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Marriage is closely tied with various laws complicated laws, it's not just something between two people, the state is involved. It's probably a pain to change it more than anything else, you're just impatient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39423541461.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>It's clearly not. Read the link, it's religious zealots trying to drag our country back. Plus you can't change a SCOTUS ruling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397621317.0" user="nerdyboy321123" delta="False">
    <text>(continued, see other comment)

&amp;gt;For the sake of quality, we need to discriminate against people in that you can't advance in academia unless you pass the classes, and we generally attempt to establish hierarchies of competence so that you can get the very best doctors to save your life if you get in an accident. The most competent people are rewarded the most, even if they haven't worked as hard, or if their parents had more money which gave them the privilege of better education.

Yes, that's fine. The issue is when competence is so heavily dependent on factors outside your control. If your future earnings are best predicted by the zip code you grow up in, it becomes pretty apparent that competence isn't linked to any sort of intrinsic quality but just the opportunities you're afforded in your life. There's a massive disparity in that opportunity and leftists want to push to address that disparity at its roots so that competence is actually a fair reflection of someone's effort/intelligence/whatever and use stopgap measures like affirmative action to both shrink that disparity and account for the impact that someone's upbringing has had on their ability to succeed in school. If we just need people to pass the tests in college, then it makes sense to understand that there are more factors to take into consideration in letting them into college than what their GPA was. Someone working 2 jobs through high school that only has time to get a 3.2 may be just as capable of acing a college exam as someone with multiple tutors and a stable home life that pulled a 4.0. Measures to balance those factors aren't perfect, but are really only necessary as long as we have high schoolers that have to work 2 jobs to help support their family.

All that said, I'm ***still*** fine with more competent people earning more. I just also think that the people that earn the least shouldn't starve in the wealthiest country on the planet. If we want people to afford yachts, fuckin' sure, but everybody should be able to afford the things necessary to survive, at a bare minimum.

&amp;gt;There's valid reasons for holding opinions which go against your own, it's not as simple as people being assholes, they're not just looking for people to discriminate against, and they don't simply believe that they're "better". At least 99% of people are just doing the best with the information that they have, much like yourself. If you ask me though, your knowledge base is propaganda and mediocre news articles by politically biased "journalists". But do you really have to "remove them from society" through illegal or cruel means that we wouldn't even use against serial killers?

I agree, and there are aspects of the republican platform that I can understand the appeal of. I think a lot of it comes from disingenuity about what they're actually pushing (the party of the working class tends to be really bad about shifting tax burdens from the wealthy onto the working class, for example), and a lot of it comes from a failure of the democratic party to propose any good policy. I think the working class is being absolutely shafted by both parties and both parties make phony appeals that they're the ones trying to help. The only reason I vote democrat is because they at least aren't actively making anything worse, while Republicans fight tooth and nail to push back progress on every issue important to me. Like I said earlier, I don't think every Republican is evil. I do think the Republican *party* is rooted in white supremacy and regressive identity politics and the people in charge are evil for perpetuating that, as is anybody that explicitly supports the party for those reasons and/or pushes it farther in that direction.

I do wonder what sources you go to for news that are less biased. I try and find reporting that is only biased in what stories it chooses to run and then dig into the facts of the situation to inform my opinion. I do try and branch outside the liberal and leftist bubbles, as well, and do the same there. The issue is that facts have a leftist bias. The evidence shows that Covid is lethal and vaccines help, that the best way to reduce income inequality is to tax the rich and support social welfare, that most terrorists do so in support of conservative ideologies, that we have extremely limited social mobility, that income disparity in the US is worse than it was in France pre-revolution, that climate change is going to make large swaths of the earth uninhabitable in the next few decades, that police demonstrate a clear racial bias in their use of force. The list goes on. That is all just factually accurate and that is what I base my beliefs on, not the fact that the news sources I use come to the same conclusion from the data. 

Anyways, if you read all this, thanks for giving me the chance to go off like this. Genuinely had a blast typing this all up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398140743.0" user="AlienRobotTrex" delta="False">
    <text>God damn you absolute madlad! Couldn’t have said it better myself. I’m saving this for future reference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400262085.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Denying the existence of trans people is violence

Biologically, boys are boys and girls are girls. Psychologically, it's a spectrum, and about 10% of the population leans more towards the other gender. It's further complicated by our mental states, as we get more emotional and feminine in touching situations, and more masculine in the face of danger. Mental illness is often involved in sexual extremities, but this is not a condemnation, it's a definition we've accepted purely because such people tend to suffer from their problems. Of course, not being accepted by society is a large factor of the suffering, but everyone suffers from insecurities about themselves.

You shouldn't call it "self defense", because it's not. It's not self-defense if a girl knocks out a muslim because sexism is inherent to Islam. It's not self-defense if I knock somebody out for calling me privileged, even though he's making judgements about me based on the color of my skin rather than my character and individuality. When depressed people say that life is suffering, that we should all die, that humans are a virus on the planet, that we're over-populated.. He's really calling for the destruction of myself and everything I love, but that person is merely troubled and speaking his feelings, I'd not be justified in harming him. 

&amp;gt;The fact that isn't happening just makes sense

I'm glad you agree. So why so harsh on other people for saying it or worrying about it? If it's a fact, then why liken it to extremism and dangerous speech because you're worried that they might *imply* something you find to be disagreeable?

&amp;gt;Sounds like a pretty blatantly white supremacist talking point.

If you're making facts out to be statements that people ought to be assaulted for uttering, then you're quite the danger yourself you know. How am I supposed to be assured that you're only against actual nazis when you can't differentiate libertarians and literal neo-nazis?

More civilized civilizations have more money. They have less crime. They have better aid for the poor and the weak. The reason we're against racism is because we've progressed past it, and we consider anyone stuck in the past (conservatism) to hold worse values. A lot of third world countries are less developed, especially when it comes to human rights and general behaviour. We don't believe that might makes right, we're skeptical of traditional gender rules, we find it immoral when the Chinese scam eachother, we find it sad when traditional cultures make mental illness and sexuality taboo topics. In short, these are our values, and we consider them better!

&amp;gt;The issue is when competence is so heavily dependent on factors outside your control

All inadequacy, in all human beings, is excused away. Even when we insult ourselves and say "I'm so stupid", we're really saying "It's outside of my control, I'm not to blame!". Your competence is entirely in your control, but it's not easy, and neither is it fair. That's life. There's a bigger difference between ugly people and pretty people, and yet *this* inequality has not become a social issue. Why?

&amp;gt;So that competence is actually a fair reflection of someone's effort/intelligence/whatever

That's a hiarchy of competence, but the left does not generally support hiarches. They do not stand for equality of oppertunity, but for equality of outcome. That's an extremely dangerous view, as it invalidates the individuals stiving in life, and punishes effort. "Got an A? Must be because of your skin color. Got an F? It can't be helped, you'll never succeed in life, everyone is against you and that's the only reason things aren't better". Want to take a guess at the psychological consequences of sending such a message?

&amp;gt;Everybody should be able to afford the things necessary to survive

I don't disagree. I understand the emotions behind your statements and they're very similar to my own. But the proposed solutions of the left do not work. They're as naive as communism, society will collapse if incompetent people with good intentions are put in charge of a redesign. The problems we're trying to prevent will get worse. Leftism is why racism has gotten worse, they didn't listen when it was said "Judge my not by the color of my skin, but by the contents of my character". Society is fixated on groups, not individuals, and it's judging everyone on trends and patterns. But that's the entire problem of racism and sexism and such! To reduce people with similar traits to a "type" is an error, and it's no less of an error against "groups" that you're skeptical of.

&amp;gt;And there are aspects of the republican platform that I can understand the appeal of.

Given enough time with any belief system, you should come to understand them, even if that means to understand why they're mistaken. As long as you think "they're evil", "they're stupid", "they're bad people", you've not yet understood them. This is why communication is essential, and why you must seek to understand those that you hate, because otherwise, how could you even be justified in hating them?

Free speech as a value is not an accident. We've thought all of these things through. Those who have defended human rights throughout history have been even more aware of the pros and cons than even us, and they took worse things than nazism and discrimination into consideration, and still arrived at the same conclusion!

cont.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400262551.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The issue is that facts have a leftist bias

Not at all. Covid is lethal, but very rarely. Vaccines help, but they're not without side-effects either. We're not even taxing the rich, they're evading taxes through legal loopholes. If you force them to pay more, chances are that they will leave for a country which doesn't do that. That's the main reason we don't push companies harder, it's rather calculated.

The idea that terror is right-wing is a lie. The media just decide that it's terror when done by right-wingers, and something else when it's done by the left. Think about is, was the capitol thing terror? Well, what about looting doing BLM protests and riots?

Income disparity is terrible, I don't think anyone disagree with that. Maybe with the reasons, or solutions, but surely not the issue.

Climate change is legitimate, but also exaggerated, and ultimately just a big roleplay. We recycle, and yet the garbage is later mixed together, or sent to some third world country and dumped in a river. We ban plastic straws, which account for less than 0.1% of all plastics, and make "green" staws whose process is less efficient, resulting in more pollution. Making solar cells and windmills is also a dirty process. Everyone's just pretending to care while the issue is getting worse. In the end, it's all about money, as much as I hate that fact.

The police is biased, but the examples of the media is extremely poor. George Floyd wasn't a good person, and those who attacked Rittenhouse weren't either (one had sexually abused a child), so I don't think criticism is entirely unjustified. If BLM had protested police brutality, I think a lot of people would have supported their cause, but instead they had to make it about racism and speak badly about everyone who didn't support them as they put local businesses on fire (even when they were owned by minories).

Did you know these things? If not, you do consume biased media. I try to avoid all media, news and politics myself, I find it to be gross, even when it  agrees with my conclusions. Not sure where I know these things, I guess I just picked them up. I'm mainly thinking for myself though, and reading old books by great people.

The following is a warning against religion, politics, tyranny and ideology all at once. It warns of nazism and communism and religious faith all the same. It was also written in the 1950s. My ideas are not based on right-wing media or anything mediocre like that.

"What has the West, with its political and denominational schisms, to offer to modern man in his need? Nothing, unfortunately, except a variety of paths all leading to one goal which is practically indistinguishable from the Marxist ideal. It requires no special effort of understanding to see where the Communist ideology gets the certainty of its belief that time is on its side, and that the world is ripe for conversion. The facts speak a language that is all too plain in this respect. It will not help us in the West to shut our eyes to this and not recognize our fatal vulnerability. Anyone who has once learned to submit absolutely to a collective belief and to renounce his eternal right to freedom and the equally eternal duty of individual responsibility will persist in this attitude, and will be able to set out with the same credulity and the same lack of criticism in the reverse direction, if another and manifestly “better” belief is foisted upon his alleged idealism. What happened not so long ago to a civilized European nation? We accuse the Germans of having forgotten it all again already, but the truth is that we don’t know for certain whether something similar might not happen elsewhere. It would not be surprising if it did and if another civilized nation succumbed to the infection of a uniform and onesided idea. America, which – O quae mutatio rerum! – forms the real political backbone of Western Europe, seems to be immune because of the outspoken counterposition she has adopted, but in point of fact she is perhaps even more vulnerable than Europe, since her educational system is the most inﬂuenced by the scientific Weltanschauung with its statistical truths, and her mixed population ﬁnds it difficult to strike roots in a soil that is practically without history. The historical and humanistic type of education so sorely needed in such circumstances leads, on the contrary, a Cinderella existence. Though Europe possesses this latter requirement, she uses it to her own undoing in the form of nationalistic egoisms and paralyzing skepticism. Common to both is the materialistic and collectivist goal, and both lack the very thing that expresses and grips the whole man, namely, an idea which puts the individual human being in the center as the measure of all things."
Also
"The ethical decision of the individual human being no longer counts – what alone matters is the blind movement of the masses, and the lie has thus become the operative principle of political action"

I'm not only against nazism, but all self-serving ideological movements which excuse individuals to act out their suppressed destructive impulses against some target group which is made to be the scapegoat of all the problems in the world. There's barely any unbiased articles, and there's even less honest politicans. There's no selfless actions, and no desire for truth. People fight for their beliefs, and they merely look for things which validate them, and then they discard the rest. This is because we identify with our beliefs, and feel our identity threatened whenver we're argued against. I don't like this game, so I will point out that it's a game and disillusion us for a bit.

I've had fun writing as well! But I'll admit I look down on everything written on this sub, including my own text. It barely scratches the surface of anything which matters, it's a sort of play, not actual problem solving. Our perspective doesn't escape our own role, we're just acting out some collective identity or something. I don't feel like anything is being themselves, or questioning the script they're reading from, they're just carried along with the flow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415559958.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Extreme changes cause extreme counter-reactions, it's all trivially predictable

Who trivially predicted the explosion of white nationalist groups and their violence? 

&amp;gt;and if you try to get people killed I don't think it's a good argument to say "See! They're dangerous!" when they punch back.

They aren't "punching back" because someone threatened them. They're actively attacking people they disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39416023385.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Who trivially predicted the explosion of white nationalist groups and their violence?

There's no such explosion at all. There's a counter-reaction to radical leftism though, and why wouldn't there be? It's obvious. A strong increase in migration leads to a strong criticism of uncontrolled migration.

&amp;gt;They're actively attacking people they disagree with.

That's exactly what you're advocating. I have personally seen zero support of that by right-wing extremists, by the way. The criticism of radical leftism gets people accused of racism and what not, but the accusations are wrong and misunderstood. For instance, there's financial reasons to oppose mass-immigration, not everything is about white people who think they're superior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39423576250.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Who trivially predicted the explosion of white nationalist groups and their violence?
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;There's no such explosion at all.

[Yes there is.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/interactive/2021/domestic-terrorism-data/)

&amp;gt;There's a counter-reaction to radical leftism though, and why wouldn't there be? It's obvious. 

Way to no true Scotsman terrorism bro. 

&amp;gt;A strong increase in migration leads to a strong criticism of uncontrolled migration.

That's not what they're worked up over but OK. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;They're actively attacking people they disagree with.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;That's exactly what you're advocating.

Changing the subject. 

&amp;gt;I have personally seen zero support of that by right-wing extremists, by the way.

I don't care about you're experiences out in bumfuck nowhere, show me data. 

&amp;gt;The criticism of radical leftism gets people accused of racism and what not, but the accusations are wrong and misunderstood. For instance, there's financial reasons to oppose mass-immigration, not everything is about white people who think they're superior.

Stop trying to change the subject coward.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39424221514.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes there is.

Do you never get tired of reading propaganda and seriously biased articles? And  the opinions of random people in general, god, please think for yourself!

Do you know the sources of this bullshit? 

https://www.gao.gov/assets/690/683984.pdf

"Two neo-Nazis and a third associate murdered a local drug-dealer"

"Two white supremacists killed a husband and wife because the husband was a sex offender"

"White supremacist and associate killed a child molester"

"White supremacist murdered his stepfather to gain “street cred” 

"Neo-Nazi killed an African American man"

And so on. None of these are terror!

&amp;gt;Way to no true Scotsman terrorism bro.

BLM is an "explosion of rioting and looting", but you probably consider it a counter-movement? At the very least you don't seem to consider it terrorism, even though it's closer than the above examples.

&amp;gt;That's not what they're worked up over but OK.

How would you know? Many people accused of racism and whatnot simply called for less migration. You just assumed their reasons.

&amp;gt;Show me data.

How would I show you data on a lack of data? Why don't you show me all of these dangerous nazis? People calling for violence, right-wing extremism, racists in positions of power?

And not just people you've assumed to be racist or nazistic, please.

&amp;gt;Stop trying to change the subject coward.

I'm not, I'm accusing you of projection (since your criticism isn't valid, but happens to apply to yourself). And have you read the manifesto of the few actual extremists? They explain their motivations quite well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394710877.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>yes we should deny nazis human rights</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394965708.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>As long as you throw communists in there as well, or any statist for that matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395164718.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>youre comparing an economic system to a racist ideaology that encourages and supports genocide</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395198660.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Communism actively supports genocide, based on almost every historical metric we have of it. Or you could just skip right to the No True Scotsman fallacy if you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395237931.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>its an economic system. it being used incorrectly doesnt suddently change its values and definition to include supporting genocide. nazism does, by definition. supporting nazism means having a belief in genocide. i truly dont understand why this is so hard to understand. why do you want to normalize nazism so much that you think it is as normal as an economic system? all your argument is, is you assuming that because im against nazism, i must be an extreme leftist who supports communism. is your argument then that nazism is a conservative belief and not that bad because others support communism? youre kind of just making yourself look bad. we both know theyre completely different things and youre just comparing them for semantica</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395576666.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Communism is a political system as well as an economic one. Socialism is just an economic system.

&amp;gt;why do you want to normalize nazism

I don't; I just want to de-normalize communism to the same extent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395758143.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>no, its juet an economic system. supporting it or not is a political position. even if it were a political one too, it still does not support genocide and racism, and nazism does. comparing communism to nazism shows that you dont care about ending nazism and that hate, othewise you wouldnt have to say "what about this too!!" it doesnt matter, nazism is still wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396402000.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Communism has led to more genocides in the last century than fascism ever did. 

Both are truly morally bankrupt systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397566126.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>communism is an economic system. it has not led to genocide. facist goverments have. individual oppressive countries are not oppressive because of communism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398063639.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, you're going to argue the No True Scotsman and say that the USSR and Mao's China weren't communist, so their genocides didn't count, right?

Fascism has the Holocaust under its belt. Communism has the Holdomor, the gulags, the Great Leap Forward, the Killing Fields, etc etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398404989.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>im against the USSR and Maos China, just like im against Nazi Germany. very concerning that you cant just outright say your against nazism. correlation does not equal causation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398447236.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>You need me to explicitly state I have a burning hatred for fascism and nazism? I hate all forms of states, with more hatred towards the more totalitarian and authoritarian forms of them. Of course I'm against Nazism, but it and Communism are two sides of a totalitarian coin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398492817.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>you should have been easily able to say youre against nazism instead of providing a whataboutiam about communism. if nazism and communism are two sidesbof the same coin than its telling the right is defined by racism and bigotry</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395488824.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Together with a "Guilty until proven innocent" approach in which everyone right of the center is considered nazi, I assume?

Well, not like it matters. You don't support human rights, as long as you're honest about that I don't really have much to say, it's your choice after all.

It just happens that the main problem with nazism is the lack of unalienable human rights</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395771183.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>you either are one or not. if you are, fuck your rights unless you support rights for everyone as well, which nazis dont. being racist isnt a human right, its the opposite, youre taking human rights from others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396066589.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Fuck your rights unless you support rights for everyone

That is an actual contradiction. I support rights for everyone, you do not.

&amp;gt;Being racist isnt a human right

Yes it is. You're just not allowed to act on it in a way which conflicts with other peoples rights. It's illegal to murder, but it's not illegal to want to murder. If taking rights away from people is bad, maybe you shouldn't base your entire view on the idea of removing other peoples rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397575589.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>nazis do not support rights for everyone, if you support them, you are against rights for everyone. being racist conflicts with other peoples rights. your right to be racist is not important compared to a racist free society. im not sure why you value racism but i personally dont and i dont value people who support racism either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396576794.0" user="Dragolins" delta="False">
    <text>The point of human rights is that all humans get them. I'm pretty far left but this is a fucking garbage take, if you're actually serious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397560669.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>right which is why nazis shouldnt get the right to remove the human rights of others</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400157587.0" user="blaepic" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue instead of flat out banning the speech, action should be taken to disprove it at recognise it. It saves time effort money and a lot of trouble. As long as it is implemented as an actual anti-disinformation campaign as opposed to flat out propaganda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400289407.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>The "fact-checkers", with their ministry of truths plagiarized from 1984, are paid to spread propaganda and influence public belief. Corrupt politicians pretending to be journalists, acadamics, activists and intellectuals.

They label their own biased takes on things as "debunked" or "settled" and employ censorship against everything which questions it.

Communication works, when it's allowed to work, and people can read it and judge for themselves. But that requires that no sides of the argument gets deleted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400752988.0" user="blaepic" delta="False">
    <text>Allowing a single team of people selected by a few people to verify or denounce every opinion the government considers dangerous is in itself, indeed dangerous. I am not suggesting that. I am suggesting a common initiative to disprove groups and rationales that are widely seen as dangerous, setting up an entire group to do this has great flaws i think it should be taken case by case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401544410.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed, and I agree! But there's little demand for the correct answers, people will rather want answers which conform to their feelings, even if they cause more damage in the long run. An example is the hatred of pedophiles, to the extent that non-offenders don't feel safe about seeking professional help. Another issue was the war on drugs, but science and rationality seems to be winning that.

Truth is considered mean, and the lies that people make up are full of spite and malice, so I can't even consider it a good kind of nonsense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415470496.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>Here's a fun fact for you, white people will no longer be the majority in the US in a few decades. How does that make you feel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39416096949.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>I've known that since like 10 years ago</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415479928.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The "fact-checkers", with their ministry of truths plagiarized from 1984, are paid to spread propaganda and influence public belief. Corrupt politicians pretending to be journalists, acadamics, activists and intellectuals.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;They label their own biased takes on things as "debunked" or "settled" and employ censorship against everything which questions it.

The concept of fact checkers really has you triggered huh? 

&amp;gt;Communication works, when it's allowed to work, and people can read it and judge for themselves. But that requires that no sides of the argument gets deleted.

Are you aware of this thing called "propaganda"? Are you aware that some people don't debate in good faith?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39416089137.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Are you aware of this thing called "propaganda"?

Your "fact checking" is propaganda, you just don't realize it. Making some agent authorities of truth is so stupid that I think it might be the first time in human history that it's being attempted. We seemingly agreed that everyone should just throw their ideas out there, and that people would judge by themselves. That's no longer possible if you censor anything. It doesn't matter much if one argues in good faith or not, and it can't be helped that people generally don't.

I shouldn't need to tell you all these things, you should know them. Just like I'm perfectly aware of propaganda and how it works, it's actually one of the reasons that I support free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39423580393.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>They literally cite their sources. Stop making the truth out to be a boogeyman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39410977132.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39412518653.0" user="methyltheobromine_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Are you a nazi?

I said with half the US population. Is half the US population nazis to you? Because that'd prove my point.

I don't think nazis should be killed on sight, especially since more than 99 out of 100 accusations of nazism are false (including yours). Somehow, this makes me a "nazi apologist" in some peoples eyes, and thus my human rights are apparently revoked.

&amp;gt;This isn't a popular idea at all.

It's quite similar to your idea that Nazis do evil just by existing, and that they don't need to harm anyone to be guilty of harm.

&amp;gt;Blame the alt right for coopting a symbol.

What if a handsign that you had used for 20 years was suddenly deemed offensive? Wouldn't that be stupid?

&amp;gt;This isn't a court of law.

You think we should just discard the law and take matters into our own hands whenever we get emotional, then?

&amp;gt;Pointing out that your opinions are shit is also a human right.

Do you support human rights or not?

&amp;gt;Why would we hate you unless you have shitty opinions?

All opinions look shitty to those who disagree, your own political bias is not an objective measurement of correctness.

&amp;gt;word salad.

Reading comprehension

&amp;gt;There are plenty of legal ways of setting you straight.

I mean, it's legal to hate people, but illegal to act on it in ways which conflict with their rights. If you force people to hide their feelings, do you really think you've removed the hate, though?

&amp;gt;Some problems you solve by destroying the cause.

That's more extreme than shunning. You're essentially begging them to kill you.

&amp;gt;Are you saying we should allow racist rhetoric in all spaces?

If it's not illegal, sure. You wouldn't be able to judge if something is racist or not anyway.

&amp;gt;How about we get rid of racist echo chambers

People like you created the echo chambers in the first place. And in chasing people away, you also mae your own community an echo chamber. You might not realize, but you're an extremist yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415447665.0" user="AnActualPerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think nazis should be killed on sight, especially since more than 99 out of 100 accusations of nazism are false (including yours). Somehow, this makes me a "nazi apologist" in some peoples eyes, and thus my human rights are apparently revoked.

I would expect a better argument from Mr. Mensa than making up numbers, but here we are. It's sad. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;This isn't a popular idea at all.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;It's quite similar to your idea that Nazis do evil just by existing, and that they don't need to harm anyone to be guilty of harm.

They are evil by existing, but you have yet to prove that it's a popular idea. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Blame the alt right for coopting a symbol.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;What if a handsign that you had used for 20 years was suddenly deemed offensive? Wouldn't that be stupid?

No, it wouldn't. Plenty of other hand signals for you to use. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;This isn't a court of law.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;You think we should just discard the law and take matters into our own hands whenever we get emotional, then?

Not what I think at all. I was pointing out you're invoking a legal concept when we aren't in court. Sounds like you're the one getting emotional. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Pointing out that your opinions are shit is also a human right.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Do you support human rights or not?

I do not support spreading hate speech. Hate speech is not included under the umbrella of human rights. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Why would we hate you unless you have shitty opinions?
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;All opinions look shitty to those who disagree, your own political bias is not an objective measurement of correctness.

There is no objective measure of correctness where hate speech is acceptable. This isn't up for debate. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;word salad.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Reading comprehension

Awkward weirdo trying to justify their bigotry. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;There are plenty of legal ways of setting you straight.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;I mean, it's legal to hate people, but illegal to act on it in ways which conflict with their rights. If you force people to hide their feelings, do you really think you've removed the hate, though?

There is no reaching them at this point. Best to not let their messages spread. 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Some problems you solve by destroying the cause.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;That's more extreme than shunning. You're essentially begging them to kill you.

Excuse me? That's where your mind went? You think bigots are going to kill me? 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Are you saying we should allow racist rhetoric in all spaces?
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;If it's not illegal, sure. You wouldn't be able to judge if something is racist or not anyway.

That's a super fucked up thing to think, I'm glad it doesn't happen anywhere worth listening to. It's pretty easy to figure out if something is racist, you must be out of practice. Or you are one! 

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;How about we get rid of racist echo chambers
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;People like you created the echo chambers in the first place. And in chasing people away, you also mae your own community an echo chamber. You might not realize, but you're an extremist yourself.

So you've totally lost the subject of the post then. Again, subreddits are all echo chambers. If I'm an extremist anti racist, then I openly embrace it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39416325143.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39416326516.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Fighting words](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fighting_words)** 
 
 &amp;gt;Fighting words are written or spoken words intended to incite hatred or violence from their target. Specific definitions, freedoms, and limitations of fighting words vary by jurisdiction. The term fighting words is also used in a general sense of words that when uttered tend to create (deliberately or not) a verbal or physical confrontation by their mere usage.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39424883184.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>u/methyltheobromine_ – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20methyltheobromine_&amp;amp;message=methyltheobromine_%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3vgn4n/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39423642424.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/AnActualPerson – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20AnActualPerson&amp;amp;message=AnActualPerson%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3sa0ks/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392386834.0" user="hafetysazard" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, you can always charge someone with a crime if you can prove they counselled somebody else to commit a crime.  Precluding somebody from being able to express themselves out of unfounded fear it has the possibility of being a crime is anathema to free speech and due process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392464591.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>It's better to prevent crimes than to figure out who were involved after the damage have been done. It's better for everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392882732.0" user="hafetysazard" delta="False">
    <text>No it isn't, because who gets to decide what's unacceptable, or not?  What you're describing is a thought-crime.  Plus, you're describing something out of minority report, which we don't have the capability to do.  Allowing some authority to ban any, and every, type of speech in fear it might lead to criminality is basically what dictators have done to oppress people.   Free speech is often the only think oppressed people have to fight against oppression, you're advocating that be taken away, because of some cowardly notion of, "protecting," them.

The principle of due process already handles the criminaloty someone's speech might have, pre-empting that is playing fortune teller.  It is always better to let 10
criminals go than imprison 1 innocent person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392930409.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's just stupid. If someone comes here with bomb strapped to the chest screaming they will kill everyone, we cannot stop them until they have killed everyone.

Fact that you want to protect people's right to give death threats means you are immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396548669.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Once someone encourage people (including themselves) to attack other other people, give them advice or hints how to perform act of violence or even mentally abuse people, then they should be stopped

this has already been addressed in america at least, true threats, incitement to imminent violence, etc. 

&amp;gt;People shouldn't need to live in fear or take abuse just because someone else have "opinions" about them.

why would you live in fear of twitter people? twitter people have a very skewed perception of how much twitter people actually matter in real life.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
