<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391412802.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like.

All else aside, I don't understand this particular slippery slope.  Could you explain the logic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391448797.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Scotland has these laws in place for hate crimes it's super lossely defined. Right now I'd say I honestly really do dislike what people are saying and feel they deserve punishment. But I worry it's going to get more extreme. 

Also this government supports rights of LGBTQ+, and inclusion for different races. What if the next government in charge of these laws kinda sque the meanings, like if trump had a law like that I can imagine hed have argued for it being used against those who insulted Republicans ect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391563809.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I don't understand what those have to do with one another.  Hate speech laws (for instance) can't be used against people who don't engage in hate speech as defined in the law.  If people want to make it illegal to criticize the government, they can pass that law whether or not hate speech laws exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391608100.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>But once a laws passed it seems to be easier to change it little bit by little bit, or for example Trump added a republicans one, now the Liberals are back they decide to add a no insulting liberals or political beliefs is added. 

So now political conversation could get u arrested. 

And as its handed back and for it gets worse, but its still protecting people, eventually we have very little freedom and they may be able to start pushing in laws about the government themselves into it, making them difficult to talk about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391843519.0" user="Muff_Divington" delta="False">
    <text>People have a hard time seeing the slippery slope because of the amount of slipping involved. Further to this point, there seems to be a general lack of awareness (more like concern) to the fact media outlets have become mouthpieces of government policy and polity, which then gives the impression that non governmental actors are supporting government standpoints unequivocally. Next thing you know, dissent is not only unpopular but easily becomes illegal.   
  
Easy to see in Canada with the freezing of bank accounts of people who supported trucker protests. Whatever side of the argument you're on, that cannot be portrayed as anything other than a gross departure from the fundamentals of personal liberty - but it all started with government and media working hand in hand to denounce, make unpopular, and ultimately to delilegitimatize the personal right of individuals to speak freely (or to put their money where their mouth is, as it were).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392126517.0" user="258amand34percent" delta="False">
    <text>So you are proving the point that this isn’t a slippery slope. 

The people in Ottawa were not punished for their views on vaccines and Covid, they were punished for their ACTIONS. Big difference.

They have not been punished for their views but for causing disruptions, blocking people from businesses/work, assaults, thefts, and supplying an illegal demonstration, etc. So which of these examples are people sharing their opinions and being punished for it? They tried shoving their opinions on other people, which you can’t do by force, and they were held accountable for it according to our laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392210069.0" user="Muff_Divington" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't demonstrations literally a manifestation of a group *voicing* an opinion or grievance?

Edit: the way things are going, you'll remember this comment when you get censured for supporting a cause *you* believe in :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392227420.0" user="258amand34percent" delta="False">
    <text>You can voice an opinion, sure. Hence peaceful protesting that we have laws for, and again the people demonstrating must follow those set rules. Which does not force anyone else to accept their views, you can go on with your life unimpeded. 

The people you are referring to did not follow the rules or procedures of PEACEFUL LAWFUL protest. They chose to impede on average Canadians lives because they were right, and the rest of us are wrong. Again, night and day difference. And if you can’t see the difference, that’s sort of alarming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392342077.0" user="Matos3001" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The people you are referring to did not follow the rules or procedures of PEACEFUL LAWFUL protest

Not working and stopping your car in the middle of the street is not peaceful?

I mean, even if you kill someone, what gives the government the right to freeze your assets? Give away your dog?

The one who's at an alarming state is you. The way you let government (Administration, for the Americans) do whatever, whenever, is insane.

This kind of thing is why we have a judicial system. They are the ones who apply the law. NOT THE GOVERNMENT.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392380530.0" user="258amand34percent" delta="False">
    <text>If freezing the murderers bank account stopped the murderer from killing more people, sure. That’s an appropriate use of those powers to stop a criminal act.

And the people who were not committing any illegals acts themselves, but did financially support others who were engaging in illegal acts were punished accordingly. They also had prior warning, and chose to accept the consequences of their actions. So no, these people punished were not punished for no reason like your trying to claim.

And people arrested during all of this are getting their day in court. So the legal system is working to determine the consequences, or not, for anyone alleged to have done wrongdoing. So how exactly is our legal system working against these people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392754960.0" user="Matos3001" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If freezing the murderers bank account stopped the murderer from killing more people, sure. That’s an appropriate use of those powers to stop a criminal act

By the judicial system? Yes.

By the government (Administration, for the Americans)? Never.

Even back in 1500 they knew that the powers should be distributed to avoid power tripping, and now there are Gen Z fellows that believe the government (Administration, for the Americans) should have the power to cancel who they don't agree with it. 

We are definitely going to have a terrible few years in the future.

&amp;gt;They also had prior warning, and chose to accept the consequences of their actions.

Oh yeah, like any dictator who tells the population to shut up, so did Trudeau. Good thing you agree with that kind of power tripping.

&amp;gt;And people arrested during all of this are getting their day in court. So the legal system is working to determine the consequences, or not, for anyone alleged to have done wrongdoing. So how exactly is our legal system working against these people?

No. It didn't work as it should.

They were illegally punished by a dictator who decided to invoke an Emergency act agaisnt a group of peaceful protestors to have the power to do illegal things that are out of his scope during a normal period, as pretty much everything he did only judges/the police can do.

Like I said: You're messing with stuff who has been known for thousands of years. Government SHOULD NOT, EVER have judicial power. EVERY SINGLE dictatorship starts with the control of the judicial system by the government.

But you do you. In my country, never. Canadians? Americans? It's a you problem, not a me problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392702253.0" user="ElReyPelayo" delta="False">
    <text>All else aside, I am fairly positive that the judiciary is, in fact, a part of "the government".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392772029.0" user="Matos3001" delta="False">
    <text>No. It is not.

The judicial system is controlled by the Supreme Court, not by Joe Biden, Trudeau or any other president.

This has been like this in every democratic country for hundreds of years.

There are three powers, and none of them is supposed to be able to control the others, besides when the Martial Law is invoked, which was not the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392848912.0" user="ElReyPelayo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't, uh.. I'm not sure you know what the word "government" means. In the U.S., for example, the president is the head of the executive branch of the government, i.e. a portion of the whole government. The "three powers" you're talking about are the three "branches of government", each of which forms a part of... the "government". The judiciary is one of those parts of the government.

If you don't believe me, try sentence two of the Wikipedia article on "government": [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Government](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Government)

For a non-US source, the website of the government on the UK ([https://www.gov.uk](https://www.gov.uk)) clarifies that the UK Supreme Court is a "non-ministerial department" within the UK government: https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations#non\_ministerial\_departments</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392892332.0" user="Matos3001" delta="False">
    <text>I see. Lost in translation, I guess, as in my country (Portugal), the government (governo) is stricly the group of people that work under the Prime Minister.

However, what you are pointing out, is pretty much nitpicking something completely irrelevant.

In the exact same wikipedia article you can see that the powers are divided, and being so, any President in a democratic country does NOT have power over the judiciary system, besides electing the members (or in case of Martial Law) and aproving laws.

The President does NOT have the power to tell banks to freeze assets. The President does NOT have the power to tell the police to take pets from people.

And that's my argument, not that the judiciary system is not part of the government. That's irrelevant. Being or not part of the government (as the American English defines) is irrelevant.

You can also see in the same wikipedia page that for British English, government could also mean administration, which I see that's the word I should've used speaking to (probable) Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393323841.0" user="sygnathid" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding the president having power to tell police to take pets from people: that sounds like exactly the sort of powers the POTUS has; he's not a Prime Minister, he's not a part of the legislative (lawmaking) branch, he's the executive branch's leader; he leads the agencies that carry out the laws. 
   
The US doesn't technically have a federal police force, but we do have federal law enforcement agencies (who are structured with the President leading).
   
So I think this discussion has more than just language translation barriers, your Prime Minister is likely different than our President.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392231865.0" user="Chaostyphoon" delta="False">
    <text>Yes that's the point of a demonstration.  But when your "demonstration" results in you causing chaos in a city for over a week then it's not even remotely close to a legal demonstration.

Just because a group has a grievance doesn't mean they are allowed to do whatever they want fucking over whoever they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392322051.0" user="argylande" delta="False">
    <text>Getting some heavy Minneapolis 2020 vibes here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392432302.0" user="Muff_Divington" delta="False">
    <text>That was ok tho #ACAB #BLM &amp;lt;3

But seriously that's the point I'm trying to make, eventually the backlash you're getting is for something *you* believe in, something *you* want to *speak* out about, but, oh well, it's been deemed "hate speech" and you're a terrorist now 🤷🏼‍♀️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392239696.0" user="zizmor" delta="False">
    <text>So you mean I get to disrupt traffic, prevent people from going to their work, businesses from operating and it should be all OK because I'm voicing my opinion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392413136.0" user="Muff_Divington" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that how a protest works?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394732992.0" user="SapFireMC" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between a protest and a riot. Although people just use them interchangeably at this stage, because protests sounds more rational to them than a riot. Which is exactly what they're trying to do to justify doing so</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395293897.0" user="Swoocegoose" delta="False">
    <text>nah "rioting" is the rational choice, if you protest is easily ignored then it's not gonna change anything, if a protest is restricted to the "legal" bounds set by the people maintaining the status quo you are trying to change then its already neutered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393302785.0" user="HalfysReddit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People have a hard time seeing the slippery slope

Because it's a fallacy.  
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slippery_slope</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393562913.0" user="Muff_Divington" delta="False">
    <text>What is your point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393592449.0" user="HalfysReddit" delta="False">
    <text>That you can't make a rational argument by saying it's a slippery slope.

I'm not even commenting on the rest of your comment, just that particular detail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394337659.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394440620.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>u/Muff_Divington – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Muff_Divington&amp;amp;message=Muff_Divington%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3iddh7/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/Muff_Divington – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20Muff_Divington&amp;amp;message=Muff_Divington%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3iddh7/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394939136.0" user="2xstuffed_oreos_suck" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve never quite understood how the slippery slope is a fallacy in all cases. It makes sense it’s a fallacy when utilized on an extreme level.

But, I have trouble finding a fallacy in this hypothetical (for example):
1) A law is passed banning blatantly racist speech
2) Free speech is now limited in some capacity
3) Over time, society adapts to the new law in place. The idea that it should be illegal to say something racist becomes normalized and accepted. More generally, people now agree to a greater extent that speech can/should be restricted when doing so prevents harm to people (the justification for banning racist speech) 
4) New legislation to further restrict free speech is now somewhat more likely and palpable for citizens. This is because the step from “society that restricts free speech in special instances” to “society that majorly infringes on free speech” is smaller (even if only a little) than the step from “society that does not restrict free speech” to “society that majorly infringes on free speech.

So, to me, that type of argument isn’t a fallacy, but a necessary consequence. Now, I’m not saying that such an argument should be enough to entirely prevent any restrictions on speech, or that every restriction on speech will lead to further restrictions- only that it becomes more likely.

Can you help explain if/where I’m going wrong in my thinking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395277483.0" user="HalfysReddit" delta="False">
    <text>The slippery slope is a fallacy because it essentially argues that some action should not be taken, because it is wrongly assumed that the ramifications of it will end poorly.

For example, here is your chain of event:

&amp;gt; 1) A law is passed banning blatantly racist speech  
2) Free speech is now limited in some capacity  
3) Over time, society adapts to the new law in place. The idea that it should be illegal to say something racist becomes normalized and accepted. More generally, people now agree to a greater extent that speech can/should be restricted when doing so prevents harm to people (the justification for banning racist speech)  
4) New legislation to further restrict free speech is now somewhat more likely and palpable for citizens.

1 *may cause* 2, which *may cause* 3, which *may cause* 4. Understandably, that is concerning. However, 1 *may not* cause 2, in which case the whole concern is moot. And then even if it does, 2 *may not* cause 3, in which case again the whole concern falls apart.

Each time you say something *may cause* something else, you're describing a fractional probability of a fractional probability. After say 2-3 steps, the probability of most things is so difficult to predict accurately, that it's not valuable to rely on those predictions.

For a more concrete example:

1. A law is passed banning blatantly racist speech.  
2. Free speech is now limited in some capacity. This is effectively nothing new though, because free speech is already limited in a lot of capacities. You can't say threaten to murder someone, or encourage them to harm others. You can't incite a riot. You can't suggest that the government be violently overthrown. You can't yell "fire" in a crowded place. You cant' lie under oath. You can't lie while making a verbal contract. There are already dozens, perhaps *hundreds* of ways saying words can get you in legal trouble.  
3. Over time, ideas about free speech might change, they might not. No one can predict with any amount of accuracy how society and culture will evolve in the future. We can speculate, but that's it. Speculations are not very reliable.  
4. New legislation to further restrict free speech would need to be implemented by future people. We cannot accurately predict if this would happen or what it would look like. We cannot predict what future people will believe morally and socially, and we cannot predict what social challenges of the time they will face, so we cannot predict what the intersection of those two phenomena will look like.

In very short terms, predicting the future is hard. Our best, most educated guesses about what happens after step 1 is often times inaccurate. Our best, most educated guesses about what happens after step 2 are almost always inaccurate. Our best, most educated guesses about what happens after step 3 are about as valuable as throwing darts at a board. And because of that, it would be silly to never take step 1, because one time we threw a dart at a board and it said bad things would happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392685111.0" user="RollinDeepWithData" delta="False">
    <text>Slippery slope is a fallacy for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394847457.0" user="Ok_Ticket_6237" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not always a fallacy. See non-fallacious usage. 

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slippery_slope</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395834208.0" user="Brave-Welder" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if it's always a fallacy. It was thought to be one when people knocked down confederate statues and Trump was mocked for saying "Next up will it be Jefferson? Or Washington?". Which is exactly what happened</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392970567.0" user="SterPlatinum" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not how the legislation system works in any western democracy...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392979748.0" user="throwaway2323234442" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  or for example Trump added a republicans one, now the Liberals 

You just outed yourself homie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394830155.0" user="2xstuffed_oreos_suck" delta="False">
    <text>What does that mean? Outed as what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393234569.0" user="SaucyWiggles" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe a little late for me to reply but I was just reading the thread because I assumed you weren't American. I am, and we don't have any hate speech laws on federal books here. So it seems kind of moot to make slippery slope hypothetical arguments about whether or not the government here is going to make hate speech laws a thing. It's not on anybody's agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393952805.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>So you fear these can set dangerous prexedents that allow for actual restrictions of freedom of speech...

Well, for that I can't say anything other than "look at the defamation laws as an example". These have been around for quite a while, are much more generic and their wording and practice avoided their misuse. If hate speech laws were the first case of laws punishing discourse while in a place with free speech, I'd be afraid too

But they're not. We have a very clear precedent of very safe laws punishing discourse. Have the hate speech laws be inspired on them, and things are rather safe.

As a side note, defamation is waaaaaaay more dangerous a slippery slope than hate speech. They're more generic and with a few tweaks you can remove the intention behind the offence from the cases. If you want something to be scared of, be scared of these.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394266996.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>Defamation is one of the hardest offenses to prove in court. Which is why hardly anyone is ever punished for slander, or libel. You have to prove that the information is false, that it caused you some tangible financial harm, and that the person who said/published it, knew it was false and damaging when they said/published it. 

So, compare that with, only having to prove that someone said something that offended you, and you think defamation is the more slippery slope? Really?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394335318.0" user="GrayFoX2421" delta="False">
    <text>You're saying that the only other discourse law is notoriously hard to prove and almost never gets brought up in court much less a conviction ever happening, and you're saying that justifies being worried about hate speech rules? If anything, wouldn't that give evidence that hate speech laws would also be carefully considered like defamation laws are currently?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394377938.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>Well, no, because they aren't.

This isn't a hypothetical, there are hate speech laws on the books in England, and Canada, and they are nothing like the evidentiary requirements for defamation, at least in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395381956.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>With hate speech, 2 out of the 3 are easily proved. Adding "aimed to instigate physical or sexual violence or vandalism" (as well as other forms of violence, but i'm not knowledgeable enough to think of all of them) besides the "caused financial loss" as a way to get someone convicted be fair to you? The (apparently, politely ignored) 2016 guidelines about grossly offensive speech to the communications act 2003 in UK have specifications on these lines, and in my humble opinion, they are quite fair. Formalizing them and making hate speech on par with slander is the way to go.

I mean, if the hate speech laws are like you described, their current form is shit. But making the written law obey the spirit of the law sounds to me like a good solution. We already have discourse laws that weren't subverted for generations. Modeling other discourse laws after them is logic. I understand why some places have broad definitions of what can and cannot be considered hate speech, as the laws are adapted to the region's reality. If the UK and Canada have decent courts that won't cover for people inciting violence, greater specificity is not only doable but needed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395428327.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>Slander/Libel is about false speech which causes some tangible financial harm. 

Hate speech, is about opinions, which hurt the feelings of some claimant. 

How can the standards for these two provisions, ever be anywhere close to the same? 

One is based on an objective standard of falsehood and financial harm, and the other is based on the subjectively injured sensitives of the "victim"

So I'm not sure what you mean by "2 out of the 3 are easily proved" In the case of hate speech, the measure is entirely subjective, in the case of libel it is not. 

Now if we are talking about calls to action, then that is different. For example, speech which is calling people to commit violence against minorities, may be prohibited. However this is different that an opinion which some people find insulting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395710926.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Now if we are talking about calls to action, then that is different

We are. I specifically said so. But you seem quite keen on physical violence. Things like harassment should be taker into account too.

&amp;gt; Hate speech, is about opinions, which hurt the feelings of some claimant.

As i said before: Incitement. Of. Violence. I say that as someone from a country where this shit happens frequently. I could dig a shitload of examples, but i'll leave one quite obvious [here](https://www.terra.com.br/noticias/brasil/policia/familia-atribui-morte-de-ialorixa-a-intolerancia-religiosa-na-bahia,b4f7246b0e612bb8a8163014c331da66sx0cRCRD.html) because it's the first i can remember. The link is in portuguese, tho. A preacher in Bahia repeatedly used hate speech during his congregations, calling Candomblé a form of satanism and uttering racial slurs at it's practitioners. After a few months of doing this and going unpunished, he started harassing the local people at a nearby terreiro time and time again, with his congregation after him. In a particularly violent mob, he and his congregation spent hours and hours keeping the main priestess of the terreiro locked inside her house, screaming things like "leave, devil" (there's, like, three different ways of saying this in portuguese) and (i kid you not) "burn the witch!", until the old woman had a hear attack. Like this, there are many, MANY others. Incitement of violence and harassment, validation of violent views... Hate speech is far from just name calling, although it almost always starts as that.

&amp;gt; How can the standards for these two provisions, ever be anywhere close to the same?

Incitement to violence and harassment. If you're just calling someone names, you're just an asshole. If you say things like "go fucking kill yourself, nigga" or "go, go away or we gonna fuck you up" (to bring up very tame examples), you're inciting violence. If you say "we don't serve your kind here" or "we don't want folks like you around here", you're validating harassment. Keep that shit going long enough, and either you have a segregated community, or a violent episode. Specially if the region already has deeply ingrained hateful views. It's not rocket science.

&amp;gt; One is based on an objective standard of falsehood and financial harm, and the other is based on the subjectively injured sensitives of the "victim"

The other can be based on the incitement of harassment or violence, and/or displays of willingness to be violent.

&amp;gt; So I'm not sure what you mean by "2 out of the 3 are easily proved" In the case of hate speech, the measure is entirely subjective, in the case of libel it is not.

Hate speech that goes into descriptions is notably false, and whoever utters it does so not only knowing that it's harmful, but with the intent to cause harm. These seem pretty objective to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396219066.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>If what you are talking about is incitement, then I have no argument to make.

however for:
&amp;gt; Hate speech that goes into descriptions is notably false, and whoever utters it does so not only knowing that it's harmful, but with the intent to cause harm. These seem pretty objective to me.

This is the opposite of objective as the very basis for a crime having been committed is based upon the subjective valuations of what is "harmful"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394062689.0" user="Independent-Seat-448" delta="False">
    <text>Except that’s not really how Scottish law works you’re basing it off American law making which works very differently. In ScotLand it’s all but impossible for one party to get a majority in parliament due to the voting system used (STV) therefore this simply wouldn’t happen as even if the governing party wanted to do this the other parties would stop it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391680990.0" user="S01arflar3" delta="False">
    <text>I believe the issue is more that hate speech as defined within the law (and in more general terms) is very loose and open to interpretation. Essentially something is a hate crime if someone believes that they have been targeted. The intent or the actual facts of the matter are secondary to this, as it is mostly based upon the feelings of the alleged victim.

If you get in to a slight altercation with someone and tell them to “go fuck yourself”, then if that person is a member of a protected group they can deem that your actions were racially/sexually/etc motivated. It is their belief in it that drives falling foul of the law. It isn’t a good law</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391917869.0" user="crappy-throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is the laws are vaguely worded deliberately so the government can pick and choose who to prosecute. like how do you define what is and isn't "grossly offensive"? Is blasphemy grossly offensive? Then then section 127 is defacto a set of blasphemy laws on top of hate speech laws. Except you can say Catholics are a bunch of nonces here fine but God forbid you bring up a certain other religion and its nonces. That's hate speech and religious phobia. The government just uses it to silence uncomfortable subjects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392403905.0" user="silent_cat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The thing is the laws are vaguely worded deliberately so the government can pick and choose who to prosecute. like how do you define what is and isn't "grossly offensive"? 

That's up to the courts, not the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392814865.0" user="Rocktopod" delta="False">
    <text>Are the courts not part of the government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393337255.0" user="jamvanderloeff" delta="False">
    <text>In the context of UK-like governments no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393380825.0" user="Rocktopod" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting... so what category do they fall under?  Some kind of NGO?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393498825.0" user="jamvanderloeff" delta="False">
    <text>It's the "the government" part that's narrower, meaning the party/coalition that can hold a majority in parliament or even more narrowly the ministers that that party/coalition appoints.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393617339.0" user="Rocktopod" delta="False">
    <text>So does that mean the minority party is not considered part of "the government?"  

This seems very strange to me as an American.  Is there some other term that refers to all governing bodies or groups as a whole?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393672830.0" user="jamvanderloeff" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the largest party(/sometimes coalition) not in "the government" is "the opposition". 

"Government" can be used broadly as executive+legislative+judicial, but you wouldn't call it "the government"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393473915.0" user="owmyfreakingeyes" delta="False">
    <text>Not when it comes to making arrests that can cause massive costs and consequences for the arrested even if not convicted.  The decision to prosecute is also made by an executive branch employee or official, not the courts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394987586.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>The courts are the government mate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395088594.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>That's what precedent is for, and you're HEAVILY exaggerating the ambiguity.

Can you find any reputable legal source that says hate speech laws could extend to the government punishing any speech they don't like?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398835847.0" user="crappy-throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;HEAVILY exaggerating the ambiguity.

Define "grossly offensive"

&amp;gt;Can you find any reputable legal source that says hate speech laws could extend to the government punishing any speech they don't like?

The UK government has a history of using law to quash journalistic and press freedoms to cover up its own cockups

https://theconversation.com/official-secrets-act-uk-government-has-a-long-history-of-suppressing-journalism-to-hide-its-misdeeds-164893

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RJW_v_Guardian_News_and_Media_Ltd

There are Statutes built into the laws of the UK making it illegal to report on items of potential public interest that the government and private parties are complicit in hiding. Yes a few cases are celebrities covering up private lives from tabloids. but the concerning thing is the cases that have come to light they are the tip of the iceberg in terms of what the government and powerful entities don't want the public to see.

I do not trust my government one iota to *not* misuse laws like this to strangle free speech</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392295130.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.hrw.org/news/2012/10/14/social-media-prosecutions-threaten-free-speech-uk-and-beyond

A man in the UK was legally punished for posting unsavory things about British soldiers. Once you give a certain group special protections, everyone else will want those same protections, and the government always interprets the law in such a way that gives it more power. 

Hate speech laws are not well defined, because they cannot be well defined. What they are punishing is not defined on the action itself, but on how other people are effected by that action. There is always two other parties who are interpreting the offense. the injured party, and the person deciding if it rises to the level of a crime. Something that seems completely benign therefore, can turn in to you sitting in front of a judge, solely based on the personal interpretation of another person.  

In other words, you are leaving it to other people to decide on your behalf, what you are fit to read, write, hear and say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395137704.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Looking into this example, the justification was that he was attacking white people, because he's middle-eastern and all the soldiers were white.  Someone might well think this is an unjust application of the law (I personally do), but it is not an example of the scope of the law being expanded, the way people are trying to claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39408049654.0" user="grandoz039" delta="False">
    <text>The comment you're replying wasn't talking about scope of laws being expanded, it was talking about the unspecificity of hate laws and how they can be interpreted in a way that makes them more restrictive. Which you pretty much affirmed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392435816.0" user="captchasaysimhuman" delta="False">
    <text>And what if..... The definition of "hate speech" changes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392633731.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>As the law stands now, anything that is “gross offensive” is illegal. I see that as a pretty amorphous definition. The issue with laws that aren’t well defined is that they also act to chill and prevent speech that would otherwise have occurred.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393393560.0" user="TheStabbyBrit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Hate speech laws (for instance) can't be used against people who don't engage in hate speech as defined in the law.

But therein lies the problem, because what constitutes "stirring up hatred" is deliberately vague.

For example, leaving a piece of bacon on the door of a mosque was ruled to be an act of hatred against Muslims because Islam views pigs as unclean. However, depicting Jesus as a homosexual is NOT considered to be an act of hatred, despite homosexuality being forbidden in Christianity.

There is an obvious double standard at play there, and it is due to the blatant political and ideological bias of the people writing and enforcing these laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393896053.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, depicting Jesus as a homosexual is NOT considered to be an act of hatred, despite homosexuality being forbidden in Christianity.

What did Jesus say about homosexuality?

Oh, that's right. Nothing.

It was Paul, who never met Jesus, but somehow wrote half of the New Testament.

Not sure you have a lot to go on, there.

&amp;gt; There is an obvious double standard at play there

I mean, one's a physical act. And they're quite different in other ways. As above.

&amp;gt; and it is due to the blatant political and ideological bias of the people writing and enforcing these laws.

Yes. Christians have classically been oppressed in our Christian society. When will they ever have their day?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393949813.0" user="TheStabbyBrit" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for proving my point for me.

The biblical position on homosexuality is not up for debate - homosexuality is forbidden, and homosexuals are to be killed. This is a religious commandment just as absolute, if not more absolute than the Islamic restrictions against eating pork.

&amp;gt;Yes. Christians have classically been oppressed in our Christian society. When will they ever have their day?

What kind of an argument is that? Are you really trying to argue that it's acceptable to oppress people who haven't been historically oppressed? Because that is the argument of genocidal lunatics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394291919.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The biblical position on homosexuality is not up for debate - homosexuality is forbidden, and homosexuals are to be killed.

I mean, if you're going to claim that the Old Testament still counts, should we also be killing people for blasphemy?

Should women be forced to marry their rapist if the offender pays her father 20 pieces of silver first?

Should we spray bird blood to cure leprosy?

Hell, if we're going to claim that the OT still counts, is putting a piece of pork on the steps of a church equally offensive? Pork is also banned in the OT, remember?

&amp;gt; This is a religious commandment just as absolute, if not more absolute than the Islamic restrictions against eating pork.

I mean, all religions pick and choose which parts they are going to follow.

But although many loving^^TM Christians may well want to kill gay people, most of them don't.

Compare and contrast eating pork for Muslims. And eating pork for Christians while you're at it.

In short, your bias is blinding you to just how piss-poor your argument is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394560746.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I mean, all religions pick and choose which parts they are going to follow.

&amp;gt; But although many lovingTM Christians may well want to kill gay people, most of them don't.

&amp;gt; Compare and contrast eating pork for Muslims. And eating pork for Christians while you're at it.

Right, so what you're saying is that the homosexuals' sexuality is more sacred, by your code, than the bacon-eaters' diet. And that's your bias. 

The point is, you don't want to allow them their biases. You want to force them to think in what you consider an unbiased way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394851333.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Right, so what you're saying is that the homosexuals' sexuality is more sacred, by your code, than the bacon-eaters' diet.

You're going to need to explain this strawman better, because I have no idea what you mean.

&amp;gt; The point is, you don't want to allow them their biases. You want to force them to think in what you consider an unbiased way.

It's pretty simple: Live and let live.

And if you think your dusty old book gives you the right to treat other people like shit, then you're an asshole. 

I know, I know. A persecution complex is built right into the belief system, isn't it? And given the church's historical place in society, it's easy to imagine that the loss of privilege is actually a huge oppression.

Well, religion is crumbling as people actually have more of a choice these days. Can't just kill the heathens like we did in the good ol' days, hey?

You'll just have to adapt, I guess?...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394912139.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're going to need to explain this strawman better, because I have no idea what you mean.

If you have no idea what I mean, then how do you know it's a strawman? 

In any case, what I mean is that you're not differentiating between Christians and Muslims. You're differentiating between hatred of a sexuality and hatred of a dietary practice. You think, if I'm understanding you correctly, that a Christian putting bacon on the doorstep of a mosque is an offensive act. But depicting Jesus as a homosexual is not an offensive act. So, by implication, a Muslim putting beef on the door of a Catholic church on a Friday would be an offensive act, and depicting Mohammed as a homosexual would not be an offensive act. Am I right here?

&amp;gt; And if you think your dusty old book gives you the right to treat other people like shit, then you're an asshole.

It's not my book. But what I think is, you should have the right to be an asshole. If people don't want to associate with you, that's their right. But you have the right to say asshole things, and get together with other assholes and engage in asshole practices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395576110.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you have no idea what I mean, then how do you know it's a strawman?

Because it's nothing close to what I said.

Let's see what you meant, though, hey?

&amp;gt;  what I mean is that you're not differentiating between Christians and Muslims. You're differentiating between hatred of a sexuality and hatred of a dietary practice. You think, if I'm understanding you correctly, that a Christian putting bacon on the doorstep of a mosque is an offensive act. But depicting Jesus as a homosexual is not an offensive act. So, by implication, a Muslim putting beef on the door of a Catholic church on a Friday would be an offensive act, and depicting Mohammed as a homosexual would not be an offensive act. Am I right here?

I mean, only if you ignore the main point I'd made about people ignoring all kinds of stuff that's in their holy books, and that we need to look at what modern beliefs and practises are before deciding what is offensive to the point of hatred.

You'd rather quibble about what the OT says, ignoring how much of the OT we ignore.

&amp;gt; It's not my book.

Uh-huh.

&amp;gt; you should have the right to be an asshole. If people don't want to associate with you, that's their right. But you have the right to say asshole things, and get together with other assholes and engage in asshole practices.

Great. Now that you've stated your opinion, define where "asshole" ends and "hatred" begins. Or is hatred fine as well?

And while you're worried about the definition of hatred being hopelessly vague, perhaps you could point to an instance of a complete miscarriage of justice, where some free-thinking individual was wrongly convicted of a hate crime based on free thinking alone. Because lots of countries have very reasonable hate speech laws, despite your panic.

You know, just to show how dangerous the slippery slope you're arguing against is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395600419.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I mean, only if you ignore the main point I'd made about people ignoring all kinds of stuff that's in their holy books, and that we need to look at what modern beliefs and practises are before deciding what is offensive to the point of hatred.

I'm asking why that matters. I can write a new holy book right now, and it would be no more or less valid than the Old Testament or the New Testament or the Quran. 

&amp;gt; Great. Now that you've stated your opinion, define where "asshole" ends and "hatred" begins. Or is hatred fine as well?

Hate speech is fine. Harmful behavior isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395614565.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm asking why that matters. 

Why does what people find offensive matter?...

Is...is that your question?

&amp;gt; Hate speech is fine. 

So every kind of speech should be allowed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395632089.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Why does what people find offensive matter?...
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Is...is that your question?

Yes. If anyone could claim that anything is offensive, wouldn't that open the door to restrictions that we don't want?

&amp;gt; So every kind of speech should be allowed?

So long as it doesn't create an imminent danger, or defame character.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395664024.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If anyone could claim that anything is offensive, wouldn't that open the door to restrictions that we don't want?

Again: this isn't a lone voice in the world claiming that they're offended by blue eyes.

These are things that large groups of people from particular religious, ethnic, et cetera backgrounds say are horribly offensive.

I know, I know. You've never faced any real oppression so you have no clue what it's like and like to imagine how easy it would be for you.

&amp;gt; or defame character

Oh, you mean like what would happens when you propagate harmful racial stereotypes, for example?

Glad we agree!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395726643.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Again: this isn't a lone voice in the world claiming that they're offended by blue eyes.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; These are things that large groups of people from particular religious, ethnic, et cetera backgrounds say are horribly offensive.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

That shouldn't matter to the law.

&amp;gt; Oh, you mean like what would happens when you propagate harmful racial stereotypes, for example?

No, that's not defamatory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395746649.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That shouldn't matter to the law.

--The guy who's never the victim.

Thanks for sharing your perspective, pal.

&amp;gt; No, that's not defamatory.

Oh, so if I say one person is lazy and a liar, that's horrible and must be stopped, but if I say x people are lazy and liars, it's totally cool.

Like, do you even hear yourself? 

Just twisting your tiny mind into a fragile pretzel to try and keep from having to change it.

Sad, really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395784702.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Oh, so if I say one person is lazy and a liar, that's horrible and must be stopped, but if I say x people are lazy and liars, it's totally cool.

First, are they lazy and a liar? Because if so, that's not defamatory either.

But yes. That's the point. The law should protect people, not groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395811592.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Because if so, that's not defamatory either.

Oh, so people x ARE all lazy liars. You're "just telling it like it is."

Is that it?

&amp;gt; The law should protect people, not groups.

Groups of what, sparky? What are these "groups" made up of?

You guys probably don't realize it, but you just come across as racists and homophobes who don't want to face any consequences for your stupid hatred.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395835104.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Oh, so people x ARE all lazy liars. You're "just telling it like it is."
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

Hang on. You said you were talking about one person. If you call someone lazy, and they are lazy, that's not defamation. Truth is always a defense to a charge of defamation. 

&amp;gt; Groups of what, sparky? What are these "groups" made up of?

Groups of people. The law should protect individual people, but not groups of people. 

&amp;gt; You guys probably don't realize it, but you just come across as racists and homophobes who don't want to face any consequences for your stupid hatred.

I have a problem with the idea that, if I'm not sufficiently against racists and homophobes, that I must be one myself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396166208.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397211214.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/aabbccbb – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20aabbccbb&amp;amp;message=aabbccbb%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3jgke8/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394914931.0" user="TheStabbyBrit" delta="False">
    <text>You are missing the wood for the trees.

The law says you are not allowed to say things, or perform actions, that express hatred or a desire to enact violence against a group of people based on their religion. That is what the *law* says.

But in practice, you *can* express hatred of Christians - that is a contradiction. Why is this allowed? Because the people who demand Hate Speech laws hate Christians, so hatred of Christians doesn't count as Hate Speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395598794.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But in practice, you can express hatred of Christians

So most Christians think it would be an act of hatred to suggest that Jesus could have been gay?

Tell me you're a homophobe without telling me you're a homophobe.

&amp;gt; Why is this allowed?

As I said to the other guy:

&amp;gt; I know, I know. A persecution complex is built right into the belief system, isn't it? And given the church's historical place in society, it's easy to imagine that the loss of privilege is actually a huge oppression.

&amp;gt; Well, religion is crumbling as people actually have more of a choice these days. Can't just kill the heathens like we did in the good ol' days, hey?

&amp;gt; You'll just have to adapt, I guess?...

Moving on...

&amp;gt;  Because the people who demand Hate Speech laws hate Christians

(Citation needed.)

Oh, wait. You need no proof. You're already so sure that you're persecuted!

&amp;gt;  so hatred of Christians doesn't count as Hate Speech

Show me any hate speech law that excludes Christians.

Go ahead. 

Lot of crybabies. lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395684114.0" user="TheStabbyBrit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Tell me you're a homophobe without telling me you're a homophobe.

I'm in a same sex relationship. Unlike you, I can accurately express facts about belief systems that I do not adhere to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395732132.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>So you're presuming that most Christians would find this as offensive as most Muslims would find pork on their doorstep?

And using it as an example of the hypocrisy against poor, poor, Christians...

All while failing to provide support for your argument that these laws exclude hate crimes against Christianity?

Man, your brain must be absolutely cooking as you try to deal with all the cognitive dissonance you have going on, hey? lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39402858861.0" user="Ex_Machina_1" delta="False">
    <text>Please, please do not get into an OT vs NT debate. There's no official stance on what parts of the OT is considered "still relevant". These arguments go nowhere because there is essentially no way to prove that's ones interpretation of the OT/NT is the correct one.  Like you said, adherents of the faith are gonna offer their own interpretation, pick and choose what they believe. Its not am argument worth having.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403698162.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>I'd agree. But someone needs to point out how weak these arguments are. These people just hear one side at church and then try to force everyone else to live according to their beliefs as a result.

They need a reality check. Even if it usually falls on deaf ears at first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403713955.0" user="Ex_Machina_1" delta="False">
    <text>Ah. My bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39404188914.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, you're allowed to have an opinion. I'm just stating mine as well. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395670330.0" user="name_here___" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The biblical position on homosexuality is not up for debate

Given all the religious scholars who do, in fact, debate this, saying it's "not up for debate" is pretty dubious.  If so many people have conflicting opinions on this, I'd say it's up for debate by definition.  Here's the wiki page on various interpretations of exactly this: https://wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bible_and_homosexuality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39408065192.0" user="grandoz039" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What did Jesus say about homosexuality?

&amp;gt;Oh, that's right. Nothing.

&amp;gt;It was Paul, who never met Jesus, but somehow wrote half of the New Testament.

&amp;gt;Not sure you have a lot to go on, there.

This is pretty ridiculous argument. You, as a single person, probably not even a Christian, can't "objectively" decide on one specific and only valid interpretation of the Bible. Even if your reading of Bible was correct, if large % of christians interpret the Bible differently, then their interpretation is a one version of Christianity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39409262781.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>Great. They're free to have it.

But I was a Christian. Bible camp and the whole thing.

Then I actually read the bible for myself. Turns out that a) it's batshit crazy, and b) there's a lot in there they gloss over or leave out.

Like the "proof" that Jesus was against gay marriage. He's literally asked if a man can divorce his wife. He says that marriage is between a man and a woman, and continues on to say that divorce is always wrong except for cases of adultery.

So because we ignore all the context and the rest of what he says, Karen, who's with her third husband, can rest easy that her homophobia is supported by her lord and savior Jesus.

He didn't say shit about it, though.

So interpret the bible however suits your worldview best. Or, better yet, just let your handlers tell you what it says.

Don't mind if I point out the flaws in it, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396728318.0" user="whatsINthaB0X" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point is that you can’t and shouldn’t have one without the other. You can’t have freedom of speech while suppressing hate speech. It’s all speech so I guess that makes sense in a balanced way, tit for tat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391878519.0" user="crappy-throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>the point of those laws isn't to protect people its to use the most vaguest wording possible so the government can squish any speech it doesn't like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392457343.0" user="benjick" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What if the next government in charge of these laws kinda sque the meanings

This is such a weird reach. Why wouldn't this hypothetical next government just make it legal to put LGBT-people in jail themselves? Like they would say "darn it, if only the previous government allowed us to do X"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392775147.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Because many systems of law function on precedent. *How* you reach a particular conclusion can be more important than the conclusion itself.

You think X is genuinely offensive, and no one should ever say it because the act of saying it doesn't do any good for anyone. The government passes a law against saying X. Someone claims this law violates their rights.

The law against saying X is defended by arguing "X is grossly offensive and low-value speech." Is that form of argument accepted or not?

Later, another group of people want to make Y illegal to say. They think that Y is comparable to X. You either agree with Y, or think that Y is not such a big deal that it deserves to be treated like X.

If earlier, it was acceptable for you to argue that "X is grossly offensive and low-value speech," then the debate is now over whether or not "Y is grossly offensive and low-value speech." Maybe you can win that debate, or maybe the people in power are just going to disagree and make Y illegal too.

If the system had not accepted the earlier argument saying "X is grossly offensive and low-value speech" and rejected it, saying "Even speech that might be grossly offensive is still protected" then it is much harder for a small majority to get their law punishing Y upheld.

Of course, no system in existence can actually stop a supermajority of bad actors, but a principled system can still stop a small majority from carrying out the worst abuses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393108906.0" user="benjick" delta="False">
    <text>What a fucking fantasy. Look at Texas, fascists effectively banning abortions despite precedence saying otherwise. Liberal brain rot is thinking "the bad guys" will adhere to any rules established</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393176432.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Do you want me to point out conservative laws that have been struck down for violating the first amendment in recent years, or are you just here to rant and soapbox?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393446008.0" user="benjick" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah yeah, you believe in checks and balances, I believe in the tooth fairy. We are basically the same. Bye</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394052846.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>Not the same person, but I would like if you pointed some of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393117354.0" user="benjick" delta="False">
    <text>Also the fucking messaging, "we can't protect trans people because some bad actor might turn it against us!". Just say you don't want any protections for minorities</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394046616.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a matter of what to do, but how to do it. If the laws are explicit about incitation towards violence, for example. They're less protective, but less dangerous as well. The thing is, them being explicit about subjective things can give courts too much leeway and allows them to not enforce the law properly.

I have a great (and fucking sad) example of good laws being misused in my country, but I ended up with a fucking wall of text and wasn't even halfway trough it. But if you want me to, I can share it.

Point is: laws protecting minorities historically prosecuted are necessary, but said laws can become dangerous precedents, or become toothless in the face of enforcement by flawed people. It's a matter of balance and fine tuning, and the possibility of the laws being misused has to be taken into account when writing them. Not to avoid them coming to be, but to assure that they'll be used as intended after that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400167942.0" user="blaepic" delta="False">
    <text>Because that's dumb, obvious and could make them very unpopular. Better to keep it vague.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394851181.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I think jumping from "don't be racist" to "don't insult a party" is a bit much. By your logic, what do we do about hate groups? What does America do about the KKK, or Proud Boys?

There is no grey area when someone denies the Holocaust. There is no grey area when someone has a sign saying that being gay is an abomination. It is very easy to be on the outside looking in and say to "not let it bother you." 

Furthermore, you say that it's a slippery slope of "well if we don't allow this eventually we won't allow that," what about the opposite? If we allow this, why not that? If we allow someone to go up to, say, a gay couple, and call them slurs in public, why not allow hate groups? Why not allow KKK rallies? They're just talking, after all.

The issue is yes, it's hard to balance. I think you're too far on the casual side of the scale. Being afraid of a shitty thing someone might do is not a good reason to be against a good measure being taken. Hate groups are real, the issues you think might happen have yet to happen. In my opinion, that makes the decision easy.

In Germany, it is illegal to deny the Holocaust because to do so is to completely piss on all of the graves of those who died. The thought of "well if they ban that what if they ban criticizing the government" just.... it just can't block measures like that. You can stretch anything to sound scary. 

If you're in a situation where you have a leader that is able to enact extreme fascist policies, you have far bigger issues than a slippery slope from free speech laws. To think that these laws just open the door for that stuff is a big leap. Laws are passed and supported by people and the govt. If your country is fascist enough to stifle criticism, I highly doubt it all started from us passing laws making it illegal to be racist and homophobic. It is much deeper than that. It takes economic issues, social issues, and usually global tensions. Anyone that says otherwise is most likely pushing an agenda, or they're racist and don't want to be put in jail for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396779679.0" user="mathematics1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Furthermore, you say that it's a slippery slope of "well if we don't allow this eventually we won't allow that," what about the opposite? If we allow this, why not that? If we allow someone to go up to, say, a gay couple, and call them slurs in public, why not allow hate groups? Why not allow KKK rallies? They're just talking, after all.

I'm not the one you responded to, but I actually think all these things should be legal.  I think there's a big difference between society thinking those people are awful (which they are) and telling people to avoid them, versus making the speech actually illegal.  I think people being legally allowed to share their ideas is really, really important to a functioning society; that does mean some people will have awful ideas, and we can and should use our own ability to share ideas to denounce them.  Only when their ideas escalate to actual violence should we arrest them.

You're definitely correct that it is a scale and hard to balance, though, and I don't blame anyone for having a different opinion about where we should draw the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396857583.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>See, I think we as humans have proven we are collectively dumb as fuck. I think that, considering that, allowing those groups is just not an option.

When is the last time a nazi stopped being a nazi because you asked them nicely? People look to laws for a sense of right and wrong. Allowing that behavior and just saying "you see that over there? That's bad" is not enough.

The issue of prison turning people into nazi extremists is another topic. Obviously, as things are, throwing nazis in jail just makes more nazis. But I digress. 

On the vein of allowing those groups, I would respectfully hard disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39532843176.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Nazis aren't a threat in the US. They are being used by the left to whip people up into a frenzy for votes. If anything the attention progressives are giving to this tiny group is helping them recruit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39537231477.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>Oof</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398646568.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>The lesson everyone gets from history is that "racism is bad and caused all the atrocities we saw". The truth is the government not protecting individual people's rights did this, in almost every case. It's not like making it illegal express certain views actually diminishes those views. If everyone tomorrow was convinced that jews are evil and should be killed, the only possible thing to stop that from happening would be iron-clad laws that prevent that from becoming a reality.

The state has a monopoly on violence. It's very difficult for atrocities to happen unless the government is allowing them to happen. I think you can make a good faith argument that the state just shouldn't have the power to define what views are acceptable and which aren't at all. The state trying to do that is what actually created the environment where they could usher in laws which saw the holocaust happen to begin with.

Prior to the holocaust Germany was one of the most accepting places of jews in the europe. An insane dictatorial government took hold and is mostly responsible for this happening by not guaranteeing individual rights.

The risk of any individual rights getting eroded has a much more dire consequence than some people being offended or getting yelled at.

And before you say it, yes I understand there's a difference between harassment and "saying your views". You shouldn't have the right to threaten other people or follow them around yelling at them. That's already in our law and protected though and has nothing to do with what is being said specifically but rather a threat to an individuals safety</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398905659.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>This made me think a bit. I guess I find it hard to fathom the rights eroding in the opposite direction. I personally don't think someone should, like, be arrested for being racist. However, when there are rallies of people with Nazi flags, I just have a hard time grasping how that could be open to any form of interpretation.

When it is organized into groups and used to push agendas, I also feel that is harmful. It is pretty easy to define something that is against other humans' basic rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39406145255.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>I think organizing and advocating killing others goes way beyond what I'm advocating. That clearly should not be protected by the law. My point is that none of these actions need to be ascribed to the type of view you have, it all has to do with behavior and credible threats of violence or plots.

Germany is raiding neo-nazi's headquarters across the country today. I'm sure they are doing this based on credible threats or plots or violence - which they absolutely should be doing just like they would do that if anyone, not only Nazi's, were planning such a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39406364371.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I mean... nazis are organized hate groups so yeah they fit your criteria. That's what I mean. Nazis are legal. They shouldn't be. Instead, our senators say not all nazis are bad people. Yet antifa is a terrorist group, hmmmm</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39406812358.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>That's reverting back to beliefs though. You can BELIEVE that people should be killed or not be able to live where you do. It extends to a crime not for beliefs but for when that translates to credible action. 

When was the last time you actually heard of a nazi or kkk person killing someone? These groups are the fringe of the fringe and we pay far too much attention to them as opposed to eroding freedoms by the government.

Again, these groups have virtually no power unless you have a government where individual rights aren't guaranteed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39409838618.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>You say they have virtually no power unless you have a govt where rights aren't guaranteed. 

America is passing/proposing anti-trans and homophobic laws. We are currently going for roe v wade. We actively suppress our voters. 

In my opinion, should all be illegal. If you seek to take the rights away from someone else, very simple. Nazis and KKK members don't have to actively be murdering people to have an impact. Murder shouldn't be our line in the sand. A group of people picketing against other groups of people just shouldn't be allowed. We let nuance and, above all, religion, hold us back. Nazism is an extremely dangerous thing. You say "fringe of the fringe" and not a big deal... how? 

Trump built his entire base around scapegoating anyone that opposed him. First it was the Mexicans with their rape and drugs, then it was the disabled reporter, and now it's literally anyone that speaks up. These are all ideals of fascism and nazis. You can't diminish the influence these people have. Still tens of thousands of Americans who hardline identify with nazis or confederates. That isn't a small deal, and the reason it happens is because we allow it. Every single person at a rally where a nazi flag is allowed to fly, is a nazi. If you've got 5 guys at a table and 4 are nazis, you have 5 nazis. 

This notion of "well its just a belief" like, yeah... that's the point. Nothing just happens. Bad things don't just randomly occur. It's these hate groups perpetuating their ideas. You can't just ignore it until they fuckin murder people. But that's what America does, and half the time we ignore the murders too. Just look at how many cops get away with it.

Black children are 3x more likely to be tried as an adult. I can go on and on about institutionazed racism, but the KKK and the nazi party are not dead. We have voting suppression, racism, sexism, you name it, baked into our laws and country. Allowing these groups to continue to practice just makes it worse. It isn't hard to say "yeah, guys, nazis are bad" and go arrest every single person at the local nazi rally. It is NOT hard. It's OK when Germany raids KKK places but God forbid we take them off the streets in America. After all, they didn't kill anyone yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39414542017.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>The amount of leftist alarmism in this post must be some kind of record. You really need to read something other than whatever news sources you are consuming. You seem to think an extremely tiny problem is all-encompassing. You're also just plain wrong with about half of what you said.

You basically have the opinion I would if I never thought critically about any headline I've seen in the last ten years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39415594362.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>Huh, amazing how you just did nothing but say cool buzzwords to say how dumb I am in like 4 different ways. 

Cheers. Nice talking to you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39434405777.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>You're fully indoctrinated so no point really. Read some Thomas Sowell books</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39434425560.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I love how dismissive you are 🥰🥰🥰youre just so above me truly no need for a scholar such as yourself to waste your time with a, let me check my notes, "leftist alarmist indoctrinated" person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39434674749.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>Spend more time trying to disprove your own views. That's the only way to become an informed person. Right now you exist in a place where having "views" is fashionable. It makes you a "good person" to believe what you do and you get social credit by being morally superior to others.

If you care about issues, you should care about the truth. What you believe is simply rhetoric that seems convincing and is emotionally satisfying as a result.

I already gave you somewhere to look to disconfirm things you believe. It's not my job to do the work for you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39444021190.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I must say, checked out this Thomas Sowell guy... yikes. 

You really need to educate YOURSELF that poor people aren't just lazy. Billionaire apologist isn't a great look.

"I have never understood why it is greed to want to keep the money you earn but not greed to want to tale someone else's money." Aka: "I have absolutely no clue how the wealth gap forms, nor am I familiar with how the rich and powerful have setup systems that keep them and their family/friends rich and powerful. I have no grasp on socialist structures and I only understand rampant, unchecked capitalism."

The entirety of his platform has "pull yourself up by your bootstrap" vibes. It has "I grew up poor as fuck and I made it so anyone else should be able to make it too. I suffered, you should have to suffer too." Get a grip.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39453159838.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that's a great summary of an illustrious career including 40+ books. I'm not surprised this is what you consider "Researching something" considering your other opinions though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39457709085.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I have two friends with poli-sci degrees, one with a masters, and their summary of him was "he was a black economist during the peak of American racism that denied systemic racism had an impact. He's a token dipshit of the right."

I was a lot nicer than they were. Your source of knowledge is fundamentally flawed and incorrect, idk how else to say it. You got some learning to do</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39471296989.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you need other people to tell you what opinion you need to have? 

I have lots of liberal friends with masters degrees. They routinely have completely wrong facts about any given topic. They have these ideas in their head because they just take what they hear at face value and it already conforms with what they believe.

It's healthy to read and listen to other views that aren't the same as yours. I listen to lots of podcasts and read books of people with different opinions. Even people on the left can acknowledge many things that Sowell says - they might just come to a different conclusion. That's fine.

Spouting things that are manifestly wrong because they are morally "true" is the cancer of our time. Our ability to think critically has disintegrated where everything is now a battle of ideologies and policy controls to do the opposite of each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39471583057.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>Empathy and policy can go hand in hand. Yall so obsessed with money and power structures. I did learn a bit from this, I appreciate your time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39471625549.0" user="sandcastledx" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the right is now playing a game of identity politics just like the left was. Are you having fun yet?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394852059.0" user="get-bread-not-head" delta="False">
    <text>I think jumping from "don't be racist" to "don't insult a party" is a bit much. By your logic, what do we do about hate groups? What does America do about the KKK, or Proud Boys?

There is no grey area when someone denies the Holocaust. There is no grey area when someone has a sign saying that being gay is an abomination. It is very easy to be on the outside looking in and say to "not let it bother you." 

Furthermore, you say that it's a slippery slope of "well if we don't allow this eventually we won't allow that," what about the opposite? If we allow this, why not that? If we allow someone to go up to, say, a gay couple, and call them slurs in public, why not allow hate groups? Why not allow KKK rallies? They're just talking, after all.

The issue is yes, it's hard to balance. I think you're too far on the casual side of the scale. Being afraid of a shitty thing someone might do is not a good reason to be against a good measure being taken. Hate groups are real, the issues you think might happen have yet to happen. In my opinion, that makes the decision easy.

In Germany, it is illegal to deny the Holocaust because to do so is to completely piss on all of the graves of those who died. The thought of "well if they ban that what if they ban criticizing the government" just.... it just can't block measures like that. You can stretch anything to sound scary. 

If you're in a situation where you have a leader that is able to enact extreme fascist policies, you have far bigger issues than a slippery slope from free speech laws. To think that these laws just open the door for that stuff is a big leap. Laws are passed and supported by people and the govt. If your country is fascist enough to stifle criticism, I highly doubt it all started from us passing laws making it illegal to be racist and homophobic. It is much deeper than that. It takes economic issues, social issues, and usually global tensions. Anyone that says otherwise is most likely pushing an agenda, or they're racist and don't want to be put in jail for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392732653.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you make it a policy to arrest people over what others find offense (hate speech), then as time passes, the standard for what people deem offensive may change (ordinary offense/insensitive speech). 

There was a story out of the UK (forget where) earlier in the week about a man who has to do 150 hours of community service because he made a tweet along the lines of “the only good soldier is a dead soldier.” This is only the beginning. Shall we arrest the ACABers next?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394061330.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>Care to share the source of that story? I'd like to see the details. I understand if you don't have time to look for it now, but you got me really curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394174407.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it’s this one 
https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/31/23004339/uk-twitter-user-sentenced-grossly-offensive-tweet-tom-moore-joseph-kelly</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394263504.0" user="Awkward_Log7498" delta="False">
    <text>I did a little digging, and found [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Act_2003)) about the law that was used to convict this mean drunk man. And turns out

&amp;gt; On 19 December 2012, to strike a balance between freedom of speech and criminality, the Director of Public Prosecutions issued interim guidelines, clarifying when social messaging is eligible for criminal prosecution under UK law. Only communications that are credible threats of violence, harassment, or stalking (such as aggressive Internet trolling) which specifically targets an individual or individuals, or breaches a court order designed to protect someone (such as those protecting the identity of a victim of a sexual offence) will be prosecuted

That the guidelines put in place to avoid abuses are being ignored. The case you mentioned is indeed an absurd, and your complains and fear of a slippery slope are justified. But this is less a tug of war between free speech and hate laws and more a piece of legislation being poorly written and no enforced in it's spirit. Shit still sucks, tho. Hope the guidelines get integrated into the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395340277.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>You replied to another comment of mine asking for examples of the first amendment being used against conservatives, and for some reason I can't reply to that one.

[Georgia](https://www.jurist.org/news/2021/05/federal-judge-finds-georgias-anti-bds-law-unconstitutional/) passed a law against boycotting Israel that was struck down on 1st amendment grounds.

Both Texas and Florida have tried to pass laws to control social media, and both have been struck down.

https://www.nbcnews.com/news/amp/rcna1288

https://www.texastribune.org/2021/12/01/texas-social-media-law-blocked/amp/

It's difficult to find cases since many of the laws were passed so recently, but many laws against teaching [critical race theory](https://www.thefire.org/13-important-points-in-the-campus-k-12-critical-race-theory-debate/) in higher educational settings are almost certainly unconstitutional.

It's also really easy to find things commonly claimed, like the idea that burning a flag in protest should be illegal or that schools should be able to require students to say the pledge of allegiance, which have been settled for a long time, despite the fact that most people who would call for that kind of speech restriction being on the right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
