<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391245495.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>Who, exactly, has been arrested for saying anti-trans stuff?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391254698.0" user="CatDadMilhouse" delta="False">
    <text>Marrion Millar

https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391279473.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, did you bother to read into this case anymore than how much anti-LGBT people whined about it? The charges were dropped soon after she arrested. Which would mean you don't live in this evil Orwellian nightmare where you can't be a bigot on twitter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391292780.0" user="CatDadMilhouse" delta="False">
    <text>Dropped or not, she was literally arrested for a tweet.  And that sets a dangerous precedent.  

Imagine being an American (like me - and perhaps you are) and being arrested for tweeting against Trump.  Now I know what you're going to say: "but that's not hate speech!"  And you're right.  But a Trump-friendly prosecutor might not see it that way, and next thing you know you're in jail waiting for a bail hearing.

It sets a scary precedent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391303769.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>Except there is no precedent. If the court says they were wrong to arrest her, the precedent is literally that they shouldn't be arrested for it. Sure, that's not what the fearmongering says, but the fearmongerers think trans people exist to rape their children so you should be ignoring them.

So again, breath a deep sigh of relief that bigots are allowed to harass and abuse people on the internet without fear of punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391313964.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Except if they're going to do that they don't need 'precedent' for it. You don't need precedent for tyranny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391317132.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>people are arrested all the time for things they are ultimately found not guilty of.  people suspected of murder who did absolutely nothing wrong get arrested, and then get released once the issue has been cleared up.

What is this scary precedent you are talking about?  The precedent that these people should not be charged?  because that is the only precedent that has been set.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391830023.0" user="daddylongshlong123" delta="False">
    <text>You can literally say what you want about anyone as long as it’s not threatening or using slurs that discriminate against said person. Even then getting punished for it is extremely rare. 

You want complete free speech? So for example if I knew you personally, had beef with you, and tweeted you calling you all sorts of names and saying I would kill you. Is that punishable by law? Because it’s just words right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393148168.0" user="lem0nhe4d" delta="False">
    <text>She posted harassing posters outside of a gay man place of work while posing with a baseball bat in the middle of the night.

So no she wasent arrested for a tweet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394994862.0" user="TheBooksAndTheBees" delta="False">
    <text>That shit will get you shot in the US so fast. You can't just be menacing people with a baseball bat outside at night and think you're going home okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393246662.0" user="SaucyWiggles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine being an American (like me - and perhaps you are) and being arrested for tweeting against Trump. 

I'm an American and afaik this has literally never happened here. I thought OP wasn't American based on the post because we don't have any federal hate speech laws and nobody is planning on writing them, so I'm not sure what we're here to discuss except other countries' laws lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393924630.0" user="SeeShark" delta="False">
    <text>A tweet is speech. "Arrested for a tweet" is the equivalent of "arrested for speech" - and even in the US, there is *plenty* of speech that would get you arrested, such as incitement to violence.

Treating internet speech as wholly separate from "real" speech would be a dangerous precedent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394535947.0" user="Yangoose" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Which would mean you don't live in this evil Orwellian nightmare

Posting a comment online then being arrested and hauled off to jail unless I'm able to post bail IS an evil Orwellian nightmare even if the charges don't stick and I don't serve a long prison term.

It's terrifying to me that you don't also think so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391329100.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>[Marion Miller ](https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets) (arested, charges eventually dropped, was still arrested tho) 

For a racist tweet

[Justin Lee Price ](https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-manchester-60927111)
(Jailed for six weeks) 

[over a Celtic game, social media posts](https://www.skysports.com/football/news/11787/12392268/kyogo-furuhashi-police-scotland-arrest-two-men-over-racist-abuse-towards-celtic-forward)

Here are 3 examples, I have hear of more but finding them is difficult on my phone. There as another one in wales arested for anti-trans  posters but it seems she was charged differently so I dont know if it counts. 

It's also mostly racist tweets that seem to be causing arrests but theres all sorts. Also I cant fond the articles coz they are buried under about 700 about marion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391527565.0" user="edwardlleandre" delta="False">
    <text>So the common thread in all three of your examples isn't just that they're racist. But that they are targeted race/gender based harassment of specific individuals. Less 'people getting offended at random racy jokes' and more 'people directly harassing people based on protected characteristics'.

I mean I don't like UK hate speech laws much, but I'm not going to cry a river that someone who throws racial slurs at a football player is punished for it either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391636444.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I really dont like these people but it's like they were arrested for bullying, bullying isnt worth an arrest but is worth being called a c*** or told to leave or being fired or whatever. 

I also believe it's a very slippery slope from here though, and will be added to more often than it should be and used for things it shouldn't be</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392198000.0" user="16bitsISenough" delta="False">
    <text>People committed suicide and can have life long traumas because of bullying. Bullying is definitely worth an arrest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392616469.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I am aware, I was bullied till I dropped out of school. But I dont want people arrested for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393331599.0" user="HalfysReddit" delta="False">
    <text>Well then we disagree on that. I *do* want people arrested for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394119447.0" user="antlerchapstick" delta="False">
    <text>found the core disagreement at least</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394430406.0" user="I_kwote_TheOffice" delta="False">
    <text>You want people arrested for bullying? Are you serious?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394464413.0" user="HalfysReddit" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously it would depend on a lot of context, but yes.

Bullying is just a cutesy word for harassment. Harassment, in certain contexts, is illegal.

If you are say, encouraging someone to harm themselves, yes you should be arrested. I wouldn't say you should spend months in jail, but a few days might be reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394544558.0" user="I_kwote_TheOffice" delta="False">
    <text>Bullies are some awful, horrible people, but I don't want the government involved in anything someone says unless it is a flat-out lie with the sole intent of ruining someone's reputation (defamation) or some sort of threat.  

I would rather the private sector police themselves. I'm ok with Social Media policing themselves, but only in extreme cases like what you mentioned about promoting self-harm.   All in all, society should be responsible for their own well-being. As obnoxious and harmful as bullies and trolls can be, getting the government involved is absolutely not the right thing to do IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394289036.0" user="jtcoop02" delta="False">
    <text>Sticks and stones</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392441306.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>A slippery slope has to slip. In what ways have those laws slipped over the last three decades?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392459194.0" user="captchasaysimhuman" delta="False">
    <text>See the links she provided above</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392711286.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Those aren't slipping laws. Those are just cases that OP doesn't like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392821211.0" user="captchasaysimhuman" delta="False">
    <text>So you don't think that someone being jailed because of a tweet they wrote is an indicator of European free speech protection starting to slip? That's bad business, doesn't fly with me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393281261.0" user="Space-Ulm" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't that be jailed for harassment, then the legal system goes into the work to decide the rest. 

I suppose you should be arguing how arrests work prior to conviction, and the legal bar for a warrent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393365750.0" user="captchasaysimhuman" delta="False">
    <text>Over a TWEET? What cause of arrest could there be over a tweet, barring incitements to violence, death threats, and the like? Let alone some hypothetical conviction? Speaking for the US right now, as I'm a law student in a United States university and am much more familiar with this system of law, an utterance in a public forum cannot be cause even for arrest if the only thing it's guilty of is being mean-spirited or ignorant. This is assuming of course that the person is not a public figure, obviously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393599129.0" user="Space-Ulm" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know the details of the case, never said I did. Just could have been part of a long harassment campaign. And if not then we need to alter how arest warrants are given</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393740648.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>How? The same law has been around for some time. Believing that the law itself is dumb is different from saying that this is a slippery slope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392975211.0" user="throwaway2323234442" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but it's like they were arrested for bullying, bullying isnt worth an arrest but is worth being called a c*** or told to leave or being fired or whatever. 

Why would repeated harassment not be something you could have them arrested for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399260088.0" user="SomeNoteToMyself" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah OP chose poor examples to support their stance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393136494.0" user="lem0nhe4d" delta="False">
    <text>Miller posted harassing signs outside of a gay man's place of work while posing with a baseball bat in the middle of the night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394124265.0" user="Independent-Seat-448" delta="False">
    <text>Marion millar was arrested based on threats not just saying anti trans rhetoric. 

Justin Lee price send directed racist harassment to someone (also in England so not relevant to scottish law anyway)

And the last two again were sending directed racist harassment not making general statements that offended someone</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
