<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="77" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39394667093.0" user="Xolarix" delta="False">
    <text>I think you underestimate the power of words.

Trump only used words to instigate people into becoming convinced enough to assault the capitol.

Do you think Hitler personally has jew blood on his hands? Or did he merely use words to convince people? 

Do you think that wars are fought by the same people who hold positions of power within the religion or country or whatever and speak to the people over TV and radio only?

Anti-human sentiment based on race, creed, religion, politics, should be carefully considered. It is not about the group being offended. It is about the effect those words can have on people, resulting in more of that sentiment being created, enough to make it spin out of control and it resulting in LEGAL murder and oppression of a group of humans. It has happened plenty of times in the past. Not even that long ago. It will continue to happen. Freedom of speech is a powerful right, yes, but it is fine to have limitations on it to prevent extremism and hatred based on immutable traits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396287505.0" user="Surya1197" delta="False">
    <text>Hitler specifically ordered those people who were his subordinates to kill said Jews/homosexuals/Roma. Not going to defend Trump, but his speech doesn’t rise to the level of him being held legally liable. Governmental policy/actions and the speech of individuals are not at all the same, nice try.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
