<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="86" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39395654710.0" user="rucksackmac" delta="False">
    <text>The TLDR here is in response to **only one part of your view:**

&amp;gt;Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it.

This implies that things like nazi jokes or racist remarks are only used "harmlessly" among one or two people in front of yet another person. This would all be very well and good if it were the case, but that also happens to be the crutch hateful groups use to incite terrorism, treason, homicide, genocide, or other such group violent acts that would actively harm a community within society. Propaganda is a very real and present danger, and is not new to the year 2022.

Joking about lynching a trans person might be a distasteful, foul joke in one context. In another, it can be a downright call to action.

The point I'm making is Freedom of Speech should and does have limits, however you feel about someone's "feelings." Often those who wish to incite violence on groups of people use propaganda to do so by claiming freedom of speech, and dismissing any concerns as "having your feelings hurt."

**See my framing below:**

\-Per your comment

&amp;gt;Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

I agree in some sense, and disagree in another.

Ultimately the statement is too generalized for useful discussion, and could be broken down to better understand what is meant by freedom of speech. You live in Scotland, so I can't speak to the laws of your country, but in America the constitutional right to Freedom of Speech has already been shown to have legal restrictions--ie Freedom of Speech doesn't extend to say anything and everything under all circumstances no matter what.

Now the classic example is, of course, yelling fire in a crowded building. That said, it's a rather stale argument against your view, and the reality is it's not as simple as it sounds, so I invite you to this article of a brief history of its usage. [(link)](https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/627134/is-it-illegal-to-shout-fire-in-crowded-theater)

If you're at all like me, however, you don't really want to read through every commenter's article, so here's the most relevant snippet to what I want to highlight:

&amp;gt;“The question in every case,” he said, “is whether the words are used in such circumstances and are of such a nature as to create **a clear and present danger** that they will bring about the substantive evils that Congress has a right to prevent.”For the next 50 years, clear and present danger was the accepted—and slightly vague—metric for discerning if spoken or printed material was protected speech. Then, in 1969, the Supreme Court replaced it with something clearer. The case, Brandenburg v. Ohio, concerned a Ku Klux Klan leader named Clarence Brandenburg who had broken Ohio’s law against advocating **“crime, sabotage, or unlawful methods of terrorism”** for political purposes. (In his offending speech, he had mentioned the possibility of “revengeance” \[sic\] if the federal government didn’t stop “\[suppressing\] the white, Caucasian race.”)Brandenburg appealed his guilty verdict all the way up to the **Supreme Court, which overturned the ruling** on the grounds that his threats were too ambiguous to legally amount to more than “mere advocacy” of violence or lawbreaking. **In order for speech to cross that line to incitement, it must be “directed to inciting or producing imminent lawless action” and “likely to incite or produce such action.”**As Gewaily explains, judges interpret this standard “far more narrowly than many would presume.” **While individual institutions may condemn hate speech, for example, it's not punishable by the government as incitement unless it clears a high bar combining intent, likelihood, and immediacy of a resulting crime.** And even that high bar can be subject to interpretation.

In sum, I agree freedom of speech ought to be protected, and in a very generalized sense take precedent over people's "feelings," but the argument that you should just ignore it is a straw man. There are much bigger implications than hurt fee-fees, and it dismisses the problem entirely of marginalizing entire groups of people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
