<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="80" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39395043226.0" user="ZyairesReign" delta="False">
    <text>There are protection laws for LGBTQ+ people because there needs to be. People need to be arrested so it’s put on record and they don’t get hired places. People need to be definitely screwed if they’re saying “nigga.” You’re white so maybe you won’t get it but there is no room for racist people. Whether right next to me or across the globe. They’re the most stupid of us all. Similar shit applies to homophobes/transphobes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400379848.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>But people can also learn? It's not right for someone to never get a job because they are racist, 1 because people change a hell of a lot, and 2 because it just means they live on benefits, it's not meant to be a racists way to get out of having to work. 

But getting fired from some, even if it's as long as others remember what you did is fine to me, because who cares if billy who puts numbers into a spreadsheet also thinks that Trans people should die, Billy's job doesnt really require interaction with many others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39646381702.0" user="ZyairesReign" delta="False">
    <text>The hell? Nah. People can change, yes but a lot of people WON’T. I don’t know where you grew up or if you’re in those numbers but if you take a stroll to a small rural town with a bunch of hicks they aren’t changing. Hell they don’t even be punished for it.

And “Billy” is a danger outside of work, so why should he be able to freely stroll in and get a job?  What if his boss and trans and he doesn’t know it but he finds out. Sure he will quit but not without yelling slurs at them first, and maybe being a danger in other ways.

Bigots are dangerous. Sure it starts with language but without punishment guess where that language leads to? Suicide among minorities. The bigoted person getting excited people agree with them and continuing it, until it’s not “cool” enough or doesn’t make them feel like they’ve “punished” or “changed” someone and they go and beat them up. Go and kill them.

These are real realities that I don’t expect a potentially white straight cis women to even close to wrap her head around. Don’t say it’s over exaggerating, go do some quick research and you might get a glimpse. 

There should be punishment for speech. And yes some of it should mess up a persons life at least in some permanent way, so that they will remember to grow not get worse. Race is my biggest defended on this because it’s everywhere. You see poc since you’re little and they’re just like you, and you still choose to be racist? The fuck? People making other issues complicated and spread false info. But why is someone ever hateful? 

Anyways I could go on forever but really won’t, keep thinking what you need to I guess</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
