<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="82" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39395382921.0" user="Business-Matter9087" delta="False">
    <text>You lost me at white woman who lives in a country where you are the majority.

Free speech is a double edge sword. Racist jokes and remarks have real negative consequences that you may never experience. It emboldens racism and discrimination. In the US, Asian hate crimes have skyrocketed. Trump and his administrations sinophobic remarks “Kung Flu” “China virus” etc have fanned the flames of anti Asian attacks on full US citizens merely because of their race.

Just because you find a joke funny doesn’t mean everyone else has to. It gets really tiring as a kid having to grow up having racist jokes hurled at you everyday. It sent me the message that others do not see or respect me as a full fellow human being, only as some wacky foreign prop to tear down because “white is normal and everything else is otherness”. This was a long portion of my childhood that took years of therapy, self care, and growing to get over. No child should have to go through that. Would you want your child having to grow up experiencing this, only to be dismissed by everyone else as “they’re just jokes?”

Should we allow misogynistic comedians to continue to say offensive things about women because “free speech” and jokes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396248395.0" user="Surya1197" delta="False">
    <text>Yes we should allow people to say words, because you can ignore said people. Neither should someone being offended, or third parties choosing to do something without explicit direction, be sufficient to make it illegal. Comedians should be allowed to make literally whatever joke they want, regardless of how offensive. Don’t watch their material if you’re sensitive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396421855.0" user="Business-Matter9087" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, we can choose to not watch it if we find it offensive. The issue is when the people who do find it inoffensive become influenced by those jokes and spread it onto others, then accuse them of “being too sensitive” because they are too lazy to recognize their privilege in society. That would be like a man listening to misogynistic and racist material, then complaining why he’s getting fired at work because of sexist jokes and why isnt he immune to consequences because freedom of speech. 

Have you ever noticed when a white joke is made on social media, and then white peoples throw up all arms in offense? Whereas when white people make jokes about minorities, the go to defense is “stop being so sensitive?” It’s a power dynamic. Freedom of speech serves best to those in power. 

Why is racism so rampant in America, as opposed to Canada? I’m not saying racism doesn’t exist in Canada, but generally the US is more notorious for it. Both are democratic first world countries in the same continent. Canada does not have freedom of speech, but instead freedom of expression which prohibits obscenity. The US has freedom of speech which prohibits hate speech, although it’s poorly enforced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396472219.0" user="Surya1197" delta="False">
    <text>I’m talking about legal consequences, not private actions. Also, even if I were talking about non-legal consequences, groups of people loudly being angry at something said is not the same as people being deplatformed or censored. The US has far more diverse of a population and has a far longer history of different historical racial groups immigrating here and treating each other differently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400347781.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Social consequences are totally fine and expected, arguments ect. It's fine to do that and have those sort of things happen like losing a job. Just dont feel being able to throw someone in jail based on what they have said is at all a good idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400338574.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I am very aware that my mayonnaise complection does mean I dont experience racism but being bi I often get jokes and I've heard many, many trans ones. And jokes about my hair ect. 

I know it's probably not the same but I have felt those feelings of being viewed as lesser often, sometimes it's been my own family too. 

But I'd rather deal with it myself, like most any other nasty comment. I dont talk to people who I feel have crossed a line from jokes to asshole behaviour. And i think it should remain a more personal decision. 

I still fully believe in social consequences for rasist / homophobic jerks ect, just dont want there to be arrests made.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
