<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391925707.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Reading through your posts it appears you are against hate speech but you are concerned that if  hate speech is legislated against then less reasonable things are bound to be next, however you never explain why you think that?

We have laws that say you can't drink if you're under 18 but nobody thinks the next logical step is to ban people who are under 21 and people who are under 25 after that. We have laws that say you can't use your phone whilst driving but nobody thinks that will lead to laws that say you can't speak to passengers. Why do you believe the slippery slope fallacy when there's no reason to believe that criminalising hate speech will lead to criminalising anti-government speech or anything else you think is unreasonable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392576312.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Theres a difference between genuine safety laws and things and this in my oppinion. Being able to control peoples voices is a huge thing, it just takes it to get added to to a point topics become impossible to talk about or things are added like the army (I believe 2 people have been done for hate speach over british soldiers) or the police could be added, it could cause people to stop speaking about important things I worry</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392700594.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>What important things? Give me a clear example of what you are worried about happening so we can at least consider it's likelihood, this vague 'something bad might happen' argument gets us nowhere, what is your specific fear?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395110524.0" user="-MuffinTown-" delta="False">
    <text>He does provide two examples in the above comment. Government legislating against criticism of the police or military.

If you cannot see how this is inherently a bad thing, or imagine how a government could abuse this power, you are startlingly naive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395678527.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;He

How to say you didn't pay attention to OP without saying you didn't pay attention to OP's CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396426287.0" user="-MuffinTown-" delta="False">
    <text>"They do" vs "He does" why give a shit. We're all faceless internet people on here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396413882.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Great, there is zero practical chance of that happening so we don't need to worry right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396557981.0" user="Hazzman" delta="False">
    <text>There is zero practical chance of that happening? 

I hope you are joking, but in case you aren't. I'm not one of these people who hyperbolically claim "Lol Trump was Hitler!" but what Trump did was reveal just how easily a fascist style leader could come in and implement rules and regulation that could very quickly spiral into a scenario very much like you are describing and support for these actions could easily be achieved if this leader possessed enough conviction, charisma and intelligence to maneuver effectively - Trump had none of these attributes and instead, essentially acted as a 'Canary in the coalmine'.

For example:

Trump very much wanted to consider BLM and ANTIFA* as terrorist organizations. Which, while it wouldn't have necessarily restricted their free speech - gives a clear indication of intent and if we ever do face a leader with strong enough conviction, charisma and intelligence to carry through with a fascist dictatorship - why make that process easier for them? Yes - in the face of such a take over laws are extremely flexible... but there's absolutely no reason to make that process easier. 

*Yes I know ANTIFA isn't a coherent organization of like minded individuals with a leadership structure and yes I know there is a difference between BLM the organization, BLM the movement and BLM the concept.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396769698.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>You're talking about a different issue to the one I am, Trump tried to become an autocrat and yes, autocrats impose limits on free speech, but limiting free speech doesn't make you an autocrat. 

The main thing we want to do is limit hate speech, most democratic countries (with the obvious exception of America) have those limitations and none of them have turned into autocracies that have limited freedom of expression, the two things don't follow on from each other.

Let's go back to your examples, banning criticism of the military or police, who supports that? Liberals want to be able to criticise them and conservatives want to protect the right to criticise them so how could those laws ever come into being? Saying banning hate speech might lead to banning freedom of expression is nonsense because, in a democracy no law can be passed that hasn't got popular support.

Something could have happened under Trump but for it to happen he would have had to dismantle the American political system, removing power from Congress and the Supreme Court and that is a totally different and much worse problem. Banning hate speech doesn't lead to Trump, in fact the opposite is true, hate speech was a key component of Trump's story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396816869.0" user="Hazzman" delta="False">
    <text>An autocrat can redefine hate speech. Trump repeatedly demonstrated how policy implemented with goodwill can be flipped on its head and used against people that otherwise advocated for it.

I'm not OP btw.

As for who might be willing to support criticism against military and police... absolutely millions of (conservative) Americans would support this right now if it was on the table.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396883325.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;An autocrat can redefine hate speech

So worry about autocrats then, they're a problem, reasonable limits on speech aren't.

&amp;gt;I'm not OP btw

Yeah, I know, but I needed you to explain what they were saying, I don't know if she was drunk when she wrote it or there was something else going on,  but I genuinely didn't understand what she was trying to say.

&amp;gt;absolutely millions of (conservative) Americans would support this right now

I'll concede it would cause an existential crisis amongst Republicans, but the party could never support it, it contradicts their core beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396937130.0" user="Hazzman" delta="False">
    <text>Don't give autocrats the legal framework to operate - that is the entire point of the constitution. If you don't have a hate speech law, there isn't anything to redefine. And yes I'm aware of the obvious mental leap to any law at all - it isn't the same. My ability to call someone a racial slur already has implications. I can lose my job, I can lose friends and family. I may not face legal repercussions but the victim of my speech isn't in immediate physical danger. They may be facing stress or be mental and emotionally hurt, but that is the limit - unless you want to explain to me how that mental and emotional strain should be considered physical. In which case - I can extend that to any scenario that causes anyone emotional strain or stress.

Republicans don't give a single solitary fuck about consistency or principles. If there has been a clear and obvious lesson from everything we have seen in the last 10 years (since the dawn of the so called "Culture war" and the rise of Trump) it is that conservatives, largely speaking - do not give a fuck about using methods they claim are immoral and or unconstitutional as long as it is in support of their side.

Also - I'm not saying it was you - but do people not know how to disagree without downvoting? It's not a disagree button, it's a "This isn't a constructive conversation and or it's breaking reddits/ subreddits rules"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397029752.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Don't give autocrats the legal framework to operate

They already have that as we saw with Trump.

&amp;gt;but do people not know how to disagree without downvoting?

Wasn't me mate, I only down vote people who post in bad faith. We may disagree but I know you're not doing that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397046452.0" user="Hazzman" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly my point - we want to avoid giving them as much wiggle room as possible. Why make it worse? That's the entire point of the constitution - to restrict the potential for an autocrat to legally maneuver when they do take power - and the constitution (I believe rightly) assumes that an autocrat will take power eventually.

(Yeah I figured it wasn't you - but thanks for telling me)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39406920951.0" user="worldspiney" delta="False">
    <text>Sedition act of 1918 and alien act of 1917 both introduced limits on speech against the military</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394076274.0" user="WeeabooHunter69" delta="False">
    <text>Every example you keep turning to is way more than just "x said they don't like gay people" it's that they were harassing or defaming specific people, like doxing a police officer or standing outside a man's house with homophobic signs and a baseball bat. No one is being arrested solely for a tweet(unless it's actively calling for violence or providing a means to do so), they're being arrested for harassment of specific people where harm can be documented and proven.

&amp;gt; Your right to swing your fist ends where my nose begins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395490883.0" user="huhIguess" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; where harm can be documented and proven.

[Oh yea?](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1ojUmdF42U)

Typically such laws are used as bludgeons to allow for an escalation of allowable threats and punitive measures from the State. People have been arrested solely for a tweet. And documented harm, as linked above, can be subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395556679.0" user="WeeabooHunter69" delta="False">
    <text>So are you against different degrees of murder charges? Motivation is the biggest factor in those cases after conviction of the perpetrator, as in if it was planned, accidental, or spur of the moment. Hate crimes are the same thing where it increases the severity of a sentence because the motivation with hateful against a protected class.

Please give me examples of people who were arrested solely for their tweets and nothing else at all, because every example I've seen in these comments has been someone that was committing other crimes and their tweets were simply used to prove that those crimes qualified as hate crimes. 

Documented harm is actually pretty involved, especially with licensed psychologists and psychiatrists, among other types of doctors. If someone is traumatised, physically or emotionally, that can generally be proven with observation or exposure therapy. It's not just someone saying "my feelings are hurt" it's "I have a panic attack when I see x" or something along those lines. You can also have financial harm, though that goes more towards defamation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395619231.0" user="huhIguess" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-40842853

Wanted a to take a childish photo. Got arrested for a hate crime.

&amp;gt;  "I have a panic attack when I see x" - I was SHOOK!

We should all offer them our thoughts and prayers as they overcome this time of adversity.

So you are supportive of preventing free speech acts? Allowing the State to determine what constitutes legal and illegal speech has inevitably lead to a decline of human rights in numerous countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395708961.0" user="WeeabooHunter69" delta="False">
    <text>1) that example isn't a tweet
2) Germany has laws banning actions linked to a dictator that got their country destroyed and subsequently plunged into being split apart until the fall of the Berlin wall all because of actions taken against 11 million people he genocided, including Jews, Romani(gypsies), Africans, and homosexuals. It's entirely justified to ban the glorification of someone like that.
3) ignorance of the law does not excuse violations of it, in fact, when traveling overseas, one of the first things you should do is brush up on laws in that country, and the ones dealing with the Nazi party are very well known

States already do determine what is legal or illegal free speech, precisely on the principle I mentioned previously. You can't yell "fire!" In a movie theatre because that incites panic and gets people hurt, especially if there isn't actually a fire. You can't yell "I have a bomb" out in the middle of a street because it's a threat, whether or not you have a bomb. You can say whatever you like so long as you aren't infringing on someone else's right to do the same or otherwise harming others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396092102.0" user="huhIguess" delta="False">
    <text>1) [Quibbling.](https://www.report-it.org.uk/student_pleads_guilty_to_sending_racist_tweets) 2) Irrelevant. Human Rights, including freedom of speech, didn't cause the deaths of 11 million people. The opposite - a lack of human rights - however, did. 3) Irrelevant. An individual's lack of knowledge regarding how the State limits your freedom of speech doesn't justify those limitations.

In general, there is going to be a logical and legal push for minimization of harm. However, laws that minimize harm to the State will not always align with laws that minimize harm to the individual. 

Yelling fire in a crowded theater - claiming to have a bomb in a crowded street - verbally threatening someone in order to rob them. These are illegal actions, but a far stretch to even consider that these actions represent "free speech expressions" in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397321137.0" user="Memelord420BlazeIt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; freedom of speech, didn't cause the deaths of 11 million people.

Every work about the history of the Holocaust will tell you that the continuous propaganda from the Nazi party to incite hatred towards the Jewish population was one of most important steps that made it possible for the Holocaust to happen. This hate speech started just as regular political discussions and speeches and ended in state-sponsored propaganda. This is also why the Jewish community calls out any sign of antisemitism immediately as they remember what inciting hatred towards a specific group of people can lead to.

This is also why the restrictions on free speech in some European countries are only about public speech with the *intent to incite hatred towards a specific group of people*, not about hatred itself.  (In my country the specific group of people means groups based on race, ethnicity, religion, gender, sexual orientation, age, political affiliation).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396906882.0" user="10dollarbagel" delta="False">
    <text>What about the victims of people radicalized by hate speech? What makes the danger they're in not genuine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394076237.0" user="Mtitan1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We have laws that say you can't drink if you're under 18 but nobody thinks the next logical step is to ban people who are under 21 and people who are under 25 after that.

In the us weve banned cigarettes under 18, that was recently changed to 21, and theres discussion of banning it entirely for people born after a certain year

Most social media platforms had rules against advocating/calling for criminal activity, then became more broad to ban "hate speech" which then became "peddling misinformation " and that has become "doing/saying things we disagree with"

During covid we started with Maskrecommendations, then 2 weeks to stop the spread before becoming indefinite lockdowns and attempted forcing of vaccines into the majority of the public to continue living. While this has been pulled back due to massive public backlash it was absolutely attempted and succeeded to a certain extent

Why *wouldnt* a government abuse its authority to expand an ability to control speech is a better question. They do so in virtually every opportunity granted in every field of life. The onus is on someone suggesting they wouldnt abuse it, because history tells us they absolutely would</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396998302.0" user="no_fluffies_please" delta="False">
    <text>I think the onus is still on the person saying they'd abuse it. In the example with phone usage, you can make a generic statement like "it's about control". But as soon as you ask questions like "why would anyone care" or "who is doing the controlling", the argument breaks down.

Now, it's fair to say that it can be a slippery slope if the government is *incentivized* to do it, you just then need to actually define what those incentives are. Historically with the three letter organizations, those incentives might be related to convenience, justification of budget, laziness, or politics. But that doesn't mean that those incentives can be generalized to every situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397370866.0" user="X_VeniVidiVici_X" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; because history tells us they absolutely would

There are countries other than America, believe it or not, that have stricter freedom of speech laws and are still democracies with elections. The reason they won't abuse it is because freedom of speech is an extremely helpful tool in creating the feeling of control over government, even if this control is illusionary. Governments don't allow freedom of speech because they're nice.

The better question you should ask is "why does the government allow freedom of speech in the first place?" It is for the above mentioned reason that they allow it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394214254.0" user="antlerchapstick" delta="False">
    <text>I like how you started your post by trying to accurately summarize OP’s argument — I wish more people did that.

In response to what you said, I am not sure if the slippery slope fallacy applies here. I would guess OP feels that hate speech laws are categorically different from previous laws because they allow the government the ability to subjectively decide what speech is acceptable. 

If OP is a a huge freedom of speech lover and is also mistrustful towards government, I could see how the would be rightly worried about these types of laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394216290.0" user="antlerchapstick" delta="False">
    <text>I like how you started your post by trying to accurately summarize OP’s argument — I wish more people did that.

In response to what you said, I am not sure if the slippery slope fallacy applies here. I would guess OP feels that hate speech laws are categorically different from previous laws because they allow the government the ability to subjectively decide what speech is acceptable. 

If OP is a a huge freedom of speech lover and is also mistrustful towards government, I could see how the would be rightly worried about these types of laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394217745.0" user="antlerchapstick" delta="False">
    <text>I like how you started your post by trying to accurately summarize OP’s argument — I wish more people did that.

In response to what you said, I am not sure if the slippery slope fallacy applies here. I would guess OP feels that hate speech laws are categorically different from previous laws because they allow the government the ability to subjectively decide what speech is acceptable. 

If OP is a a huge freedom of speech lover and is also mistrustful towards government, I could see how they would be worried about these types of laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395732860.0" user="elwombat" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that "18" and "alcohol" are fixed defined terms that have no ambiguity to them. "Hate speech" is poorly defined and subject to the whims of whoever is in power.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
