<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="95" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39396162164.0" user="fatal__flaw" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree although I'll admit I'm don't have a good understanding of the legal/political system in the UK, but I think even there laws are not passed capriciously by monarchs anymore. In most democracies there are checks and balances, legal challenges, voting initiatives, etc. If there's an overstep, there is room to correct it.  
Also the argument that if the will of the people supports banning certain speech, shouldn't it be honored?  
Secondly, and perhaps more controversially, words are very powerful and we should start admitting that. Words can cause riots, incite hate crimes, propagate bigotry, lead to abuse, violence and more. Jokes can perpetuate misogyny, racial stereotypes, demean certain groups, and generally drive a wedge in society between people.  
Words hurt. Verbal abuse can be as damaging as physical abuse and causes damage the victims have to deal with for the rest of their lives. When my parents spanked me, it hurt for like 5 minutes. That was the easy punishment. The verbal abuse scarred me for life.
I think we need to stop pretending we're robots that can categorize auditory input without issue and recognize words affect us very deeply and fundamentally.  
Say someone incites violence and people get hurt and/or killed and the perpetrator simply says, "it was a joke". Should the guy who orchestrated the sinister acts go free? Anyone can claim they are joking and it becomes troublesome for the legal system to prove is someone said something as a joke.  
An easy example is yelling FIRE! in a crowded room. Say a couple of people die in an ensuing panic, and the guy who said it claims it was a joke. Now extrapolate that to other situations. Where's the line?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
