<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391695481.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>The ECHR (European Court of Human Rights) has a pretty clear criterium for this. Art. 10 of the treaty (European Convention on Human Rights) explicitly guarantees freedom of speech. Certain expressions can however be censored, limited and be subject to compulsary formalities, but only if they are provided by law and necessary for a democratic society. Journalists and Politicians are mostly exempt from this, as they are part of the public debate and they especially need to be able to voice their opinion. Their opinion may even shock, insult or disturb, as long as it's necessary for the goal they aim to achieve. 

This means that, as long as (inter)national law prohibits it, people can be convicted for things like defamation of large groups of people, inciting hatred, sedition etc. 
Racist and anti-trans remarks don't inherently fit this definition, but they can certainly go too far.
This also goes for journalists and politicians. Even these heavily protected professions can abuse a narritive and go so far that they aren't expressing their opinion, but just spewing hatred.
[Example](https://www.reuters.com/article/us-netherlands-wilders-idUSKBN25V00Z)
(Important: the title of the article is wrong. The politician was convicted, but didn't get any punishment for his crime).

You mention a prison sentence of six months after being convicted. Most breaches of freedom of speech result in fines, with some examples of short prison sentences.  Even if convicted, people can just challenge that at (inter)national courts. It that really so insane for a crime that fits everything that I just described?

Considering this, I don't think it's necessarily unfair to convict racists, anti-trans people etc. for hate speech. If their expression fits the criteria for accepted legal punishment, they should feel the consequences for the unnecessary hatred they incite. The slippery slope you mention is pretty unfounded, especially when keeping the legal context in mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391696424.0" user="AmputatorBot" delta="False">
    <text>It looks like you shared an AMP link. These should load faster, but AMP is controversial because of [concerns over privacy and the Open Web](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot). Fully cached AMP pages (like the one you shared), are [especially problematic](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot).

Maybe check out **the canonical page** instead: **[https://www.reuters.com/article/us-netherlands-wilders-idUSKBN25V00Z](https://www.reuters.com/article/us-netherlands-wilders-idUSKBN25V00Z)**

*****

 ^(I'm a bot | )[^(Why &amp;amp; About)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot)^( | )[^(Summon: u/AmputatorBot)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/cchly3/you_can_now_summon_amputatorbot/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391881456.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>Good bot, corrected my mistake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391868740.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you that does ease my worries, I'm just wondering if the ECHR actually do police there measures and stuff</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391984027.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>I promise you that the rules in the Convention and the judgements of the Court are very well thought out and motivated. The Court is a massive organisation with a huge amount of diverse great legal minds. It consists of 47 judges (one for each member of the Council of Europe), with every case being done by either 7 or 17 judges. The convention itself only does principles/global rules that countries need to keep in mind while making new laws and enforcing/interpreting them. This means that if the UK starts cracking down hard on freedom of speech and someone takes them to this court, the UK might be forced to change their laws, procedures and/or practices. It's a good system to ensure that we think about and practice human rights the same way all across Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393131911.0" user="Karasu243" delta="False">
    <text>The ECHR doesn't really believe in freedom of speech, so take no solace in that body. [They upheld the conviction of an Austrian woman who said that the prophet Muhammad was a pedophile.](https://www.wsj.com/articles/europe-court-upholds-ruling-against-women-who-insulted-islam-1540580231). Their specific ruling implied that *feeling* insulted is more than enough to pass conviction, regardless of the speaker's intentions.

&amp;gt; The ECHR said it rejected her appeal after finding that the Austrian courts “carefully balanced her right to freedom of expression with the right of others to have their religious feelings protected...”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394070549.0" user="shhhhh_h" delta="False">
    <text>Wow can't believe this really happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394494049.0" user="Karasu243" delta="False">
    <text>That is the nature of Europe. It's populace are far more hypocritical on the philosophical level. They pay lip service to freedom of speech, but their actions trample over it without a care. The vast majority of Europeans, including the British, are in practical terms vehemently against freedom of speech. Rather, much like China, they only support speech that they agree with or find tasteful. The difference is China is more overt about their authoritarian suppression of said deviants than Europe.

Of the European countries, at least Germany has the integrity and honesty to openly admit their disdain for the freedom of speech and the suppression of it, born out of fear of any growing extremist ideas growing in people's heads. I may not agree with it, but any individual or organization that is willing to *actually* stick by their principles, even by the ugly parts of those principles, are people worthy of respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394077084.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I was about to say... Europe is no bastion for free speech and not something to be modeled.

Actual quote from [the judgment](https://hudoc.echr.coe.int/eng#{%22itemid%22:[%22002-12171%22]}):

&amp;gt;  The domestic courts made a distinction between child marriages and paedophilia. In their opinion, by accusing Muhammad of paedophilia, the applicant had merely sought to defame him, without providing evidence that his primary sexual interest in Aisha had been her not yet having reached puberty or that his other wives or concubines had been similarly young.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394392437.0" user="Karasu243" delta="False">
    <text>Fun fact: the US is the *only* country in the world that has enshrined the freedom of speech as a *right*. All other countries, including the UK, merely grant their citizens the *privilege* of freedom of speech, and as such, retains the legal authority to revoke that privilege from anyone the government arbitrarily deems unworthy.

While obviously the US has its own prior history of suppressing free speech, particularly during wartime and Cold War era, the Constitution explicitly makes these transgressions illegal, and thus the transgressed citizen has at least some legal recourse. But with the proliferation of the internet, the citizens are now even more free to express themselves. Kathy Griffin can even proudly post an image of her holding the bloody, severed head of then-president Trump with no legal repercussions.

The citizens of the UK, though, are quite proud of the Communication Act of 2003, and are giddy with the convictions of comedians and memelords for their offensive humors. Count Dankula, for example, was arrested, tried, and convicted for a joke. The UK celebrated his conviction. You also have Joseph Kelly who voiced his disdain for a recently passed military veteran (and all military personnel). He was arrested, tried, and convicted to a roaring applause of brits.

I mean, at least the US *tries* to honor and celebrate freedom of speech. The UK and the majority of its citizens merely pay lip service to it, but when push comes to shove, they will drop that freedom like a sack of potatoes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394427214.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the distinction between Right and Privilege is so black-and-white here. The US does much better at protecting freedom of speech than most developing countries, true, but it's [far from the only nation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech_by_country) with free speech enshrined in its constitution, and even US's 1A has limits like incitement to violence. Better to think of it in terms of shades of gray IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394429735.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Freedom of speech by country](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech_by_country)** 
 
 &amp;gt;Freedom of speech is the concept of the inherent human right to voice one's opinion publicly without fear of censorship or punishment. "Speech" is not limited to public speaking and is generally taken to include other forms of expression. The right is preserved in the United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights and is granted formal recognition by the laws of most nations. Nonetheless, the degree to which the right is upheld in practice varies greatly from one nation to another.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394440368.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever about the merits of the ruling itself, you're mischaracterizing the court's decision, which was explicitly grounded in the claim that the government's actions were necessary to preserve religious peace (not merely to protect the feelings of the person in question), and was sensitive to the speaker's intentions (she claimed she was trying to contribute to a public debate and the court found that this was implausible, given the context of the remarks).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394869966.0" user="boyhero97" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;government's actions were necessary to preserve religious peace

And that sounds like the government should teach people to use their words, not attack others for saying stuff you don't like. If my 5 year old has more control over his anger than a grown adult, then the government should crack down on that. Not free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394870599.0" user="boyhero97" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;government's actions were necessary to preserve religious peace

And that sounds like the government should teach people to use their words, not attack others for saying stuff you don't like. If my 5 year old has more control over his anger than a grown adult, then the government should crack down on that. Not free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394884663.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>I think the idea here is that if you're going to go around trying to convince people that a religious minority in their country is totally cool with pedophilia, then the state has a legitimate interest in preventing you from doing so if it can show that your behaviour isn't predicated on any real desire to engage in public debate as opposed to trying to stir up hatred against people.

European traditions as regards freedom of speech have always been much weaker relative to a country like the US. In Europe, it's a generally accepted legal principle that the state can restrict speech for the common good, if it can make (what the ECHR considers) a compelling case for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394922777.0" user="boyhero97" delta="False">
    <text>And trust me, as a religious minority not liked by most of my neighbors, I can sympathize with that. I can see the problem with the speech, I just recognize a bigger problem with the government being the ones in charge of monitoring it. They should monitor any acts of violence that are aimed towards the people, but this wasn't even a call to violence, or even action for that matter.  And I would argue that speech like this does not so much convince people as confirm their already held biases. I do not believe there is anyone who respects Muslims that heard claims like this and goes "Welp, guess I'm getting the ol' pitchfork out of the shed." It's people who are already prejudiced against Muslims.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397630764.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And trust me, as a religious minority not liked by most of my neighbors, I can sympathize with that. I can see the problem with the speech, I just recognize a bigger problem with the government being the ones in charge of monitoring it. 





While that may be so, the historical context of Europe and hate speech is decidedly grim. It's easy to talk about absolute free speech when multiple religious and ethnic genocides aren't under your belt and if they are, your countrymen may not feel its worth the risk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39439211070.0" user="Cyanoblamin" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that the historical context of Europe and authoritarianism is far more grim than the historical concept of any kind of speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39439278015.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>Why? The holocaust alone killed over 10 million people, and it's instigators helped kill over 100 million. Not to mention genocides in Bosnia, Armenia etc. Genocide is an almost uniquely abhorrent act, that mere authoritarianism just doesn't match. 



You can, and people do and have had half decent and predictable lives under authoritarianism disturbing as that may sound. There's no such thing if your ethnic group is targeted for extermination.

At the very least laws like this can serve as a canary in the coal mine, because if someone strip that law from the books it may be indicative of another incoming atrocity. 



And for a country whose citizens suffered under such atrocities, especially if the country was the *perpetrator* of said atrocities, such a thing is more valuable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39439338571.0" user="Cyanoblamin" delta="False">
    <text>Nazi Germany, Bosnia, and the Ottoman Empire were all authoritarian systems. You are making my point for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39439516674.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and the point of anti holocaust denial laws is to ensure such a genocidal authoritarian systems do not arise again. Not *no*  authoritarian system (that is the purview of other laws), but not one so depraved as to engage in such horrors again. Hence why it is considered a valid exception to freedom if speech the same as making threats. 





Additionally free speech doesn't inherently stop atrocities or authoritarianism, the U.S. has one of the most lax interpretations of free speech there is and repeatedly committed atrocities within its borders. People even now downplay or deny some of these atrocities existence or effects. Hell the Nazis took inspiration from the U.S. in several ways. Modern authoritarianism doesn't come from mad kings in towers, it comes just as much from the people as anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397347309.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>**Hello /u/brbrWh0r3, if your view has been changed or adjusted in any way, you should award** ***the user who changed your view*** **a delta.** 

Simply reply to their comment with the delta symbol provided below, being sure to include a brief description of how your view has changed.

&amp;gt;∆

or 

&amp;gt; !delta

For more information about deltas, use [this link](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=usertext&amp;amp;utm_name=changemyview&amp;amp;utm_content=t5_2w2s8). 

If you did not change your view, please respond to this comment indicating as such! 

*As a reminder,* **failure to award a delta when it is warranted may merit a post removal and a rule violation.** *Repeated rule violations in a short period of time may merit a ban.* 

Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396461871.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Art. 10 of the treaty (European Convention on Human Rights) explicitly guarantees freedom of speech

oh good!

&amp;gt;Certain expressions can however be censored, limited and be subject to compulsary formalities

oh, that is the exact opposite of what you just said! 

&amp;gt; people can be convicted for things like defamation of large groups of people

what does this mean?

&amp;gt;inciting hatred

oh boy, what does *this* mean?

&amp;gt;but they can certainly go too far

i am sure you know my question by now.

&amp;gt;Even if convicted, people can just challenge that at (inter)national courts. It that really so insane for a crime that fits everything that I just described?

yes. yes it is. because you have a bunch of mushy "crimes" that depend entirely on subjective feelings of the most sensitive and useless people on the planet. 

&amp;gt;If their expression fits the fairly meticulous criteria
 
where is this "meticulous criteria?" did i miss it?

&amp;gt;The slippery slope you mention is pretty unfounded, especially when keeping the legal context in mind.

if the government is making the rules, imagine trump (or whoever is the opposite of your party/ideology) in power making the rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396904658.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt; oh that is the exact opposite of what you just said!

Crazy how exceptions to rules exist, right? I don't think it's insane to restrict fundamental rights when they are challenged by other fundamental rights or interests.

\- Concering the questions about "what does this mean?", these are examples of national law regarding the ways a country can criminalise certain ways of speech. They are meant to be vague examples, because explaining them cannot be done in a small Reddit comment. I'll write something up, especially for you:

Art. 10 ECHR guarantees freedom of expression. This concerns the right to hold an opinion and to receive impart information and ideas without permission from authority, regardless of frontiers. The excercise of these freedom may be subject to formalities, restrictions or penalties as they are described by law, as long as they serve a legitimate purpose that cannot be reached in another way. These purposes are summed up in the article and it's impossible for me to explain them all in one post, so I recommend you look them up.

This means that nations can limit certain ways of expression. In my post I mentioned some examples. Inciting hatred would fit under the purpose of public safety or the prevention of disorder or crime. Defining "inciting hatred" is something that Dutch National Law barely does. It says that it needs be in the open, through mouth, document or online and it needs to be because of race, sexuality or a handicap. Defamation of large groups of people would be to actively say offensive things about groups of people concerning their race, etc. etc. These definitions are vague, but are interpreted by the judge. The whole point is that the nation and the court can decide what goes too far and what not. If the convicted party disagrees with this, they can bring the case to the ECHR. If they deem the legitimate purpose of the state to be of heavier weight than the freedom of expression, the convicted party is done for. This is decided while taking everything in account, like the severity of the expression and the law itself. If the law has no regard for freedom of expression, the nation will be forced to change their laws. Otherwise the convicted person is done for.

This is what I'm trying to explain in the points about politicians and journalists. Common people can be convicted for these things quicker, since they have no business in spewing hatred, violence and offending people. Politicians and journalists are held in higher regard and have stronger freedoms, but also stronger responsibilities as I explained before.

\&amp;gt; because you have a bunch of mushy "crimes" that depend entirely on subjective feelings of the most sensitive and useless people on the planet.

I'm not going to explain to you how people can suffer from hatred, intimidation and disrespect. 

\&amp;gt; where is this "meticulous criteria"?

I'll rephrase that, but see my explaination above.

\&amp;gt; if the government is making the rules...

This is why the court is there in the first place. It's neutral in politics, as long as human rights are respected. It's what I mentioned concerning the UK in another comment. If a member state starts cracking down on free speech, common people can fight in legal cases against the state internally first. If all judges somehow turn corrupt, they can bring the case to the ECHR. The ECHR can then force the UK to change their laws. The system is not perfect and there will always be politically spicy issues, but it works generally well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397456667.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Crazy how exceptions to rules exist, right?

i guarantee i won't hit you! ...unless i feel like hitting you, based on a bunch of undefined feelings i don't feel like telling you about! just exceptions to rules!

&amp;gt;I don't think it's insane to restrict fundamental rights when they are challenged by other fundamental rights or interests.

why does your favored "fundamental right" trump mine? in america we already have a few pretty narrow and fairly well defined restrictions on free speech. it does not include "hate speech" and certainly doesn't defer to states that make laws against them anyway.

&amp;gt;Inciting hatred 

is a meaningless phrase. or rather, it could mean anything. you admit the problem in your example about the dutch law which barely defines the "crime." is saying "i don't like white men" on twitter good enough? it fits your definition. you really want to fill the jails with feminists? 

&amp;gt;Defamation of large groups of people would be to actively say offensive things about groups of people concerning their race

ok, is saying "i don't like mexicans" on twitter a crime? you see how your vague definitions do nothing to actually define what is and is not a crime, and as such chills all speech? if no one knows what will get them arrested, people stop talking. that is bad.

&amp;gt;These definitions are vague, but are interpreted by the judge.

yeah, again, that is the problem. in america we have the concept of [void for vagueness](https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/void_for_vagueness). it seems to be targeted at preventing exactly what you are describing: a law that covers almost anything a prosecutor wants, and the person needs to be arrested and brought to a judge for the one person at that particular time to decide if a law was broken or not. this is a horrible system.

&amp;gt;Common people can be convicted for these things quicker,

and you think this is a good thing?????

&amp;gt;since they have no business in spewing hatred, violence and offending people

but politicians and "important people" do? you have a truly bizarre worldview my friend.

&amp;gt;I'm not going to explain to you how people can suffer from hatred, intimidation and disrespect.

did you edit your post because you realized it might do the exact kind of damage you are so worried about? the point is that *someone* will be gravely offended by almost anything. can i get woke feminists arrested for tweeting that white men should all die, or are all abusers? what if i am a victim of abuse and seeing those words triggers trauma in me? is my single reaction out of thousands of eye-rolls enough suffering from the hate to make it illegal in your eyes?

&amp;gt;common people can fight in legal cases against the state internally first

for free? i bet the state has more money and resources in the long run.

&amp;gt;but it works generally well.

yeah as long as you don't have your dog make a hitler joke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39418834023.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;i guarantee i won't hit you! ...unless i feel like hitting you, based on a bunch of undefined feelings i don't feel like telling you about! just exceptions to rules!

Rule: Violence is not allowed.

Exception: Violence is allowed in self defence when the reaction is proportional and at the right time. If not, then it must be an emotional reaction that was caused because you had to defend yourself. If all of this is the case will be decided by a judge based on **known facts.**

&amp;gt;Why does your favoured "fundamental right" trump mine?

Because not everything is about you. Your right to freedom of speech does not include the right to threaten, harass and intimidate people. That is against public safety. Even you can go to the ECHR and claim freedom of speech when you get convicted for saying things like 'I do not like white men'. It depends on the context.

&amp;gt;Yeah, again, that is the problem.

There's jurisprudence, checks by higher courts and international law to fill the void of vagueness. Once again, if the law is too vague, this can be challenged.

&amp;gt;But politicians and "important people" do?

Yes, but you're allowed to disagree with the function that pretty much all of Europe connects to politicians and journalists. These people have the explicit job to criticize, challenge and change the public opinion. It's these people that need extra protection against convictions for saying what they need to say. That's why they may rile up, shock, disturb and more. Common people can also do this, as long as it is in the setting of the public debate. Even vloggers and the most minor of politically active people can claim this protection. If you're just a person walking home you can still say what you want, but you cannot do the same as someone that claims stuff in a public debate just for the fun of it.

&amp;gt;Did you edit your post...

No, I edited my post because I don't think you're worth offending. The whole text after the sentence I'm responding to right now is the exact reason why. Your whole argument is based on bad faith and baseless assumption about the worst case scenario.

&amp;gt;For free? 

Now this is a genuine discussion point. In Europe there are lawyers that are given out by the government to represent people with little money. As per usual, these are poorly paid and overworked, but they are there. The state has money and legal help in theh long term, but if recources are unfairly balanced and/or the state is intentionally dragging, they are committing other offenses that have consequences for them. Even with some money you can get a decent to proper lawyer to help you out. If you win, you don't have to pay anything at all. There are also mogul lawyers and companies that see interesting cases they can invest in. They can get a positive law change out of that if they bring enough recources to the table. There is a system in place, but I agree that it can be better.

&amp;gt;Yeah, as long as you don't have your dog make a hitler joke.

Once again, this is why I don't want to invest time in this conversation. This is why I refuse to lower my standards to yours. This is also why I waited with a response for a while. Your arguments are baseless, exaggerated rambles about a fear that has gotten out of hand. I don't feel like responding any further.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428619576.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>i am sure you know the multitude of ways that this is a terrible analogy? the biggest being "x things are allowed, good lucking figuring out the exceptions" vs "x thing is never allowed, the legal system will occasionally decide if it was legal." 

&amp;gt; Violence is allowed in self defence when the reaction is proportional 

what rule in free speech is similarly clear and easily understood?

&amp;gt;If not, then it must be an emotional reaction that was caused because you had to defend yourself.

what the hell does this mean?

&amp;gt;Because not everything is about you. 

and it is not about you either. so again, when does your right trump mine?

&amp;gt;your right to freedom of speech does not include the right to threaten, harass and intimidate people

actually it does. rather those things are defined by law, not defined by what you dislike. me saying you deserve a punch to the face is not a threat, even if you think it is. harassment does not mean "this person won't leave me alone." 

&amp;gt;hen you get convicted for saying things like 'I do not like white men'.

no one in america will ever get convicted for that, much less arrested. it is free speech. 

&amp;gt;There's jurisprudence, checks by higher courts and international law to fill the void of vagueness. Once again, if the law is too vague, this can be challenged.

i gave you a citation of how vague laws work. they get struck down. they go away. a judge doesn't decide if your conduct fits in, a judge decides the law is bad and in the trash it goes. you can't enforce a law as vague as "free speech is allowed unless it is bad" because that could include anything at all.

&amp;gt;Yes, but you're allowed to disagree with the function that pretty much all of Europe connects to politicians and journalists. These people have the explicit job to criticize, challenge and change the public opinion. It's these people that need extra protection against convictions for saying what they need to say. That's why they may rile up, shock, disturb and more. Common people can also do this, as long as it is in the setting of the public debate. Even vloggers and the most minor of politically active people can claim this protection. If you're just a person walking home you can still say what you want, but you cannot do the same as someone that claims stuff in a public debate just for the fun of it.

this is gibberish

&amp;gt;No, I edited my post because I don't think you're worth offending.

this offends me! i guess i should report you to the speech police! and since you are just a nobody on a website and not in a public debate you have no right to shock or annoy me! off to jail with you.

&amp;gt;Your whole argument is based on bad faith and baseless assumption about the worst case scenario.

what worst case scenario? are you not familiar with twitter, where people spend all day every day being offended by everything? calling someone's argument bad faith is just a lazy way to say you don't actually have a response.

&amp;gt;Now this is a genuine discussion point. In Europe there are lawyers that are given out by the government to represent people with little money. As per usual, these are poorly paid and overworked, but they are there. 

the problem with this approach is that some poor schmuck still has to get arrested for a tweet or whatever in the first place, and then hope a public defender is going to bring down the whole system. how is it not better to lean the other way and allow more speech? surely one person being briefly offended is less important than putting people in jail over words?

&amp;gt;nce again, this is why I don't want to invest time in this conversation. This is why I refuse to lower my standards to yours. This is also why I waited with a response for a while. Your arguments are baseless, exaggerated rambles about a fear that has gotten out of hand.

bro this [literally has happened](https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-43864133). it [is happening](https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/25/world/europe/spain-europe-protest-free-speech.html). once again you have no real argument other than "i love to kowtow to the government, i only do good speech so i don't care about these laws!" so you quit. good job, i hope you see the light before you end up in jail too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39429037364.0" user="WhatTheQueck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;...terrible anology?

I could give you plenty of examples, just look in the ECHR or any European constitution. Art. 4 ECHR forbids slavery and involuntary solitude, but mentions a whole lot of exceptions. Art. 8 guarantees the right to private family live and forbids interception, unless the democratic society demands it. This is a fundamental right but it does require interpretation from the nations. The ECHR then checks if their interpretation is acceptable.

&amp;gt;What rule in free speech...

Please define 'proportionality' and 'at the right moment' for me. This requires as much interpretation from a judge as 'inciting hatred with x and/or x as consequence'.

&amp;gt;What the hell does this mean?

That's Dutch criminal law for you.  It's an example to show the right to defend yourself, which isn't very clearly defined as well. The judge interprets these terms based on earlier cases, the motivations of the lawmakers and others things. they does so in a consistant manner. If they don't, their judgement will get destroyed by an appeal court, the supreme court or the ECHR.

&amp;gt;Actually it does.

Ok sure if you want to believe that. It very clearly isn't the case according to law and I fully agree with that. I do not believe that holding an opinion like 'I do not like white men' is hatred or harrassment, and it is very defendable in front of court that it isn't.

&amp;gt;...when does your right trump mine?

When my rights are more significant that yours. When your freedom of speech gets lawfully restricted because it's a threat to the public or other reasons. When this is depends on how the nation makes and interprets the law. If the law is restricts freedom of speech unlawfully, the ECHR will put it aside.

&amp;gt;I gave you a citation of how vague law works. A judge doesn't decide if your conduct fits, a judge decides the law is bad and in the trash it goes.

Now this is funny, because this is just straight up not true. Common law, the law system in the UK, is a system where judges decide the **precedents** and they judge based on earlier precedents. Precedents are interpretations of vague terms and norms that haven't been challenged or have been confirmed by the supreme court. In Europe, with a different system, the judge can only decide with the law as the base line. Sometimes laws are strict, which leaves no room for interpretation. Then the judge just does what the law says. Other times laws are (explicitly kept) vague so the judge can execute their part of the seperation of powers. That's the entire reason jurisprudence exists. The law provides the base line and the judge can then decide how they fill the open criteria, but need to do so in a **consistent** and **understandable** manner. They do so based on the motivation of the lawmakers, earlier decisions, European law, fundamental right etc. This is partly what the supreme court or ECHR checks. If the motivation lacks, if there is no consistency or if the interpretation is wrong, the decision is overturned. Throwing laws in the bin is something that the ECHR does, but only if the law is deemed against the ECHR. What you're describing is straight up untrue. Maybe this is the case in the United States, but not in the UK and Europe.

&amp;gt;Surely one person being offended is less important than putting people in jail over words?

I fully agree. That's why the laws aren't strict at all. 

&amp;gt;Bro this literally has happened.

Mark Meechan is also going to the ECHR to appeal. I hope he wins, since this clearly wasn't his intention. It's an insane video tho.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39430960121.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; rt. 4 ECHR forbids slavery and involuntary solitude, but mentions a whole lot of exceptions.

it mentions 4. that is not very many. similarly in america there are exceptions, but they are relatively few and pretty narrowly defined. and again your slavery example is a few positive examples relative to something that is banned. this is much easier to understand than some nebulous guidelines on what is banned based on subjective feelings. 

you originally mentioned things like "inciting hatred" and "defamation of large groups of people" but you are unable to tell me what this means. this is my problem. in self defense you have a legal right to defend yourself using the minimum necessary force to stop the threat. you can't kill a person for shoving you, you can't shoot someone in the back as they run away even if they attacked you first. there are clear tests in most cases to determine if the action was legal. but really if you kill someone, you know you are going to have to justify it. how would that work with speech? you can't give me a clear definition of what is banned, so how does anyone know what is ok to say? why doesn't [maxine waters](https://www.cnn.com/2018/06/25/politics/maxine-waters-trump-officials/index.html) get arrested for incitement of violence, or at the very least "inciting hatred?" why don't people who post [bad wishes on white men](https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/8/3/17648566/sarah-jeong-new-york-times-twitter-andrew-sullivan) get arrested? how would any of this work?

&amp;gt;Now this is funny, because this is just straight up not true.

this is true for vague laws. i gave you the link. yes, judges do interpret things sometimes, but you present the problem in your next sentence:

&amp;gt;The law provides the base line and the judge can then decide how they fill the open criteria, but need to do so in a consistent and understandable manner

self defense is pretty consistent and understandable. people get angry about cases like kyle rittenhouse, but nothing in that trial was new or inconsistent with decades of legal precedent. explain how this would work with speech? how would you be consistent with this? how could it possibly be easily understandable?

&amp;gt;Mark Meechan is also going to the ECHR to appeal. I hope he wins, since this clearly wasn't his intention.

having to appeal unjust arrests is part of the problem. millions would be in jail waiting appeals based on twitter comments alone. this is an untenable system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
