<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391256074.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>The only person I can remember being arrested for anything on your list was that dude who taught his dog to do the Heil Hitler salute, and I'm not even sure he was charged for anything. How often are you seeing people arrested and charged for 'saying things'?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391270210.0" user="CatDadMilhouse" delta="False">
    <text>Again: Marrion Millar

https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391746621.0" user="Zerasad" delta="False">
    <text>The UK seems to have a TERF problem. This article rather conveniently seems to go the whole length without mentioning the actual tweets and calls her 'gender critical' rather than a TERF.

I found this article: https://www.scotsman.com/news/crime/marion-millar-scots-woman-appears-in-court-accused-of-sending-homophobic-and-transphobic-tweets-3365741 which seems to indicate that she doxxes a police officer most likely because of her sexual orientation. I'd say doxxing should be a crime. Wouldn't you agree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392665739.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, the UK also [enables TERFs](https://www.tricitynews.com/local-news/jk-rowling-threatens-legal-action-against-coquitlam-transgender-activist-over-tweets-3123135) to silence their critics as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393341111.0" user="J2quared" delta="False">
    <text>What's the difference between an offensive tweet and libel/defamation? The tweet says:

"Rowling can no longer be trusted around children" could imply she is a pedophile or something. 

That's different than saying Rowling is a TERF, which can be a pejorative</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393622326.0" user="pointsOutWeirdStuff" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; TERF, which can be a pejorative

anything _can_ be [a word expressing contempt or disapproval.](https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/pejorative)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393634917.0" user="J2quared" delta="False">
    <text>Hence why I said “can be”. Some people might see it as a badge of pride. It’s all subjective. However the claim that she should no longer be around kids. Wouldn’t that be defamation?

I’m asking so I’m not sure why the downvotes other than this is CMV</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393740637.0" user="pointsOutWeirdStuff" delta="False">
    <text>if you're genuionely asking then you may need to rephrase as: 

&amp;gt; What's the difference between an offensive tweet and libel/defamation? The tweet says:

&amp;gt; "Rowling can no longer be trusted around children" could imply she is a pedophile or something.

is not something I can form a coherent meaning from.

unless you are being literal in which case: some offensive tweets can be libel/defamation. some are not. it depends on the criteria: https://www.hse.gov.uk/enforce/enforcementguide/court/reporting-defamation.htm

in this case: rowling cant be trusted around kids [because she is a moronic bigot too consumed by fear to employ her brain] 

meets the defence of: "the statement constituted fair comment on a matter of public interest: that is, opinion which any person could honestly hold, based on facts known at the time;"

I'm no legal scholar but **I think** _any_ implication of _why_ the author thinks she shouldn't be around kids would struggle to hold up in court due to the vagueness. you could infer that the point was that rowling is a cannibal, an alien or some sort on unredeemable tory ghoul but none of these are actually present in the phrasing 

&amp;gt; I’m asking so I’m not sure why the downvotes other than this is CMV

I'd ask what this being CMV has to do with anything but I don't want to know. I can only handle so much disappointment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394918848.0" user="TheBooksAndTheBees" delta="False">
    <text>It probably would be if they said "she should no longer be around kids BECAUSE she did x, y, and z (but didn't really)..."

By leaving it vague, they don't actually say anything factual, it's just an opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392220536.0" user="shengch" delta="False">
    <text>You can't use Twitter as an outlet for freedom of speech, Twitter is privately owned so they should be able to run it however they want, same with private property, you shouldn't be able to say whatever you want on someone else's property</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393760273.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393768482.0" user="shengch" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and as I've said that happened because we don't have freedom of speech</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393959871.0" user="mekese2000" delta="False">
    <text>Quick read of the article. She names people and threatens them.  That's what I got but they did not show her tweets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394061948.0" user="spawnofthedevil" delta="False">
    <text>What were the tweets? If she was threatening violence or an individual or calling for violence against trans people then yes. I hope she rots in hell either way, but context outside of vaguely stating that they were transphobic is needed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394328765.0" user="eliechallita" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;[https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets](https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets)

Can you provide an example of the tweets or language she was arrested for? I've been looking but so far all of the articles only discuss the case without describing what prompted it.

I'm not saying that the arrest was necessarily justified, but there is legal justification for it if she made overt threats or if what she said met the legal definition of slander or libel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396496961.0" user="funsizedaisy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Can you provide an example of the tweets or language she was arrested for? 

i can't seem to find the tweets either.

from what i've been able to find, it was a photo that she posted, along with false accusations against the person she was targeting. i can't find what those false accusations are but the photo is described [here](https://www.pinknews.co.uk/2021/10/04/marion-millar-court-transphobia-for-women-scotland/):

&amp;gt;The photo is reported to have shown a bow of green, white and purple ribbons tied around a tree, near where a named Scottish actor was working, on the basis that the ribbons represented a noose.

and [here](https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-59076966):

&amp;gt;It was claimed Miss Millar posted a photograph on social media of a sign where a named Scots actor was working at the time.

so from what i've been able to gather: she targeted someone, named them, shared personal and false info, and tied something that looked like a noose outside their work.

this seems like a normal basis for a harassment charge. but it also looks like the charges were dropped.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396498830.0" user="AmputatorBot" delta="False">
    <text>It looks like you shared an AMP link. These should load faster, but AMP is controversial because of [concerns over privacy and the Open Web](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot).

Maybe check out **the canonical page** instead: **[https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-59076966](https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-59076966)**

*****

 ^(I'm a bot | )[^(Why &amp;amp; About)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/ehrq3z/why_did_i_build_amputatorbot)^( | )[^(Summon: u/AmputatorBot)](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmputatorBot/comments/cchly3/you_can_now_summon_amputatorbot/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394505109.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395320460.0" user="SquibblesMcGoo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/immatx – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20immatx&amp;amp;message=immatx%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3igyol/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394584801.0" user="lem0nhe4d" delta="False">
    <text>She posted harassment outside a gay man place of work in the middle of the night while posing with a baseball bat.

The "just a tweet" thing was a lie of omission. The weet was of her doing the above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394704830.0" user="Tarantio" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think threatening people is an issue of free speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395531242.0" user="aguafiestas" delta="False">
    <text>Charges were dropped

https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-59076966.amp

I also can’t find what she actually posted, which seems important. But there are some hints in this article:

&amp;gt; Police received a complaint about a photo she is said to have posted on social media. The photo is reported to have shown a bow of green, white and purple ribbons tied around a tree, near where a named Scottish actor was working, on the basis that the ribbons represented a noose. The charges also allege that she wrote personal and false information relating to a female police officer on social media.

https://www.pinknews.co.uk/2021/10/04/marion-millar-court-transphobia-for-women-scotland/

So it seems it wasn’t just general political opinions, but statements about (against?) particular individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396869408.0" user="verronaut" delta="False">
    <text>The article doesn't say, do you know what the tweets said specifically? If it was a call to violence or something, then it moves beyond free speech protections in most places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398533239.0" user="Narwal_Party" delta="False">
    <text>This was for doxxing and threatening a police officer, not for “allegedly transphobic comments”. Why post something so obviously misleading?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391401252.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Jonathon Best, 52, used the social networking site to rant about black players involved in the penalty shootout against Italy which England lost on Sunday, 11 July. 

&amp;gt; On Tuesday, 2 November 2021 Best was sentenced to 10 weeks in custody at Willesden Magistrates Court. He had previously pleaded guilty to sending by public communication network a grossly offensive or indecent or obscene or menacing message or matter. 

. 

&amp;gt;A teenager was sentenced to six weeks in prison in Worcester, England on Wednesday for racially abusing England soccer player Marcus Rashford on social media last year after the European Championship final.

&amp;gt;Justin Lee Price, who is 19, targeted Rashford with abuse on Twitter after the Manchester United player missed a penalty in the shootout won by Italy at Wembley Stadium in July.

&amp;gt;Price previously admitted to one count of sending a grossly offensive message by public communication network at a hearing at Worcester Magistrates' Court on March 17.

. 

&amp;gt;Jake Henderson (30), from Retford in Nottinghamshire, recorded the video during a televised briefing by the Home Secretary, making derogatory comments about her ethnicity, before going on to make insulting remarks about people from different ethnic backgrounds. He posted the three-minute video on a private social media group.

&amp;gt;Robert Cumming (26), from Doncaster, reposted it on his own profile, from where the video went viral, with over a million views over the course of a weekend. The video and the sentiments expressed within provoked widespread condemnation and concern from members of the communities targeted by Henderson’s verbal attacks.

&amp;gt;The CPS authorised charges of sending by public communication a grossly offensive message and prosecuted Henderson and Cumming together as a hate crime. They pleaded guilty at Mansfield Magistrates’ Court on 28 June and were today (12 August) sentenced to ten and six weeks respectively. During the sentencing, the CPS presented evidence that Henderson in particular had previously expressed views of an extreme nature and had previous links to a far-right organisation.

. 

&amp;gt;A football fan who racially abused West Bromwich Albion midfielder Romaine Sawyers on social media has been jailed for eight weeks.

&amp;gt;A court heard Simon Silwood's Facebook message was intentionally racist and not the result of autocorrect as he had claimed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392115314.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>Apart from the first one, aren't these all just examples of people directly racially abusing other people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392183306.0" user="MrTrt" delta="False">
    <text>And the first one would count, too, since we're talking about specific people, those who were involved in the shootout, and not black people in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392227007.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>How is that relevant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392274167.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>Searching someone out to racially abuse them seems to be worse than people being racist in their own echo chambers i.e. their twitter feed or whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392295539.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>Still not sure how this is relevant. The OP is arguing that people shouldn't be arrested for racist remarks or insults. The commenter then asked for some examples, which were provided here. So I'm not sure how your observation that some of these are worse than others furthers the debate. Would you like to argue that people _should_ be arrested for offending/insulting people based on their race? If so, what's the argument for this (since this is CMV). If not, again, I'm not understanding the relevance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392338483.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a bit confused - do you consider the clarification that the provided examples have differences, to be irrelevant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393900109.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>If you're not arguing that people should be arrested for "racial abuse", then yes it's irrelevant to point out that the cases above are examples of racial abuse. The topic of the thread is whether people should be arrested for these things. But if you _are_ arguing this, then you should say this explicitly and then...actually make the argument for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392888210.0" user="VORSEY" delta="False">
    <text>I think most people in this thread can agree that *threats* should be illegal, right? I think a useful factor in determining whether or not an insult is a threat can be the specificity of who it targets. A severe insult toward a few individuals may read a lot like a threat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393884477.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>? The distinction between a threat and an insult has nothing to do with the _specificity_ of the target; it's based on the _content_ of the utterance, i.e. whether I'm merely expressing some derogatory/negative attitude about you (e.g. an insult) vs expressing intent to promote violence towards you m (e.g. a threat). I can insult a specific individual without threatening them. I can also threaten an entire group of people. 

Moreover, how a person "reads" a severe insult is definitely a bad standard. We're not going to arrest people _just because_ "a few individuals" _read_ their statements as threatening, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392783175.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>The first one was also him directly targeting the players involved with racial slurs.

That said, still shouldn't be a legal matter for any of these things to be resolved by the state.

People have a right to say disgusting shit and the right to face the social consequences of those actions and the government doesn't need to be involved at all unless they are directly calling for violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393529659.0" user="RussellLawliet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; unless they are directly calling for violence

Why is that the line?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394197253.0" user="darkfrost47" delta="False">
    <text>The provision reflects the judgment of Congress that "a person who makes a serious effort to induce another person to commit a crime of violence is a clearly dangerous person and that his act deserves criminal sanctions whether or not the crime of violence is actually committed."

[link](https://www.justice.gov/archives/jm/criminal-resource-manual-1081-overview-solicitation#:~:text=Section%20373%20of%20Title%2018,Crime%20Control%20Act%20of%201984.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395092300.0" user="RussellLawliet" delta="False">
    <text>Why morally, not why legally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395218791.0" user="darkfrost47" delta="False">
    <text>The moral reasoning for the law is written right there in the law though. If you have a different opinion or critique I'd love to hear it, but the law seems to explain itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393535010.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>Harassment's isn't always calling for violence. If you ask me to leave you alone for any reason, and I don't, its harassments. Its one thing for me to say "I hate Teeklin", thats free speech. Tts a completely different situation when I flood your DMs with "I hate you!!". That is harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394435385.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Part of the problem is how targeted social media is or isn't. You could make a case for flooding DMs being harassment, but if you just Tweet "I hate @So-and-So" over and over and Twitter sets it up such that, while such Tweets are public, they also alert So-and-So because they're tagged, then is that targeted?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394535649.0" user="Heisenripbauer" delta="False">
    <text>you still went out of your way to add the “@“ symbol which only exists to alert the person being referenced. I can absolutely see that falling under the umbrella of harassment. there is no need to tag them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394578577.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>OK, what if there's a social media site where everyone uses their real name and is tagged on every mention?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394788168.0" user="Heisenripbauer" delta="False">
    <text>then that social media site would be moving backwards as all current social media allows users to decide when to tag them. that’s as unlikely as Blockbuster opening a new location near you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394831162.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but I'm asking about where legal lines are drawn. If that site existed, would people be able to name-drop someone many times without it being harassment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394894151.0" user="Heisenripbauer" delta="False">
    <text>why would the law revolve around one social media site? the legal line exists and that hypothetical social media site would change to accommodate the law. if somebody used that site, posted on that site knowing that it breaks harassment laws, then that would be harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394945275.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's splitting hairs to say that I can't post "I hate u/Heisenripbauer" a hundred times a day but that I can post "I hate Heisenripbauer" a hundred times a day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394583419.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>I guess if you @ them, you are directing it at them. So if its repeated, it probably could be considered harassments. Like how I can say anything I want in a public space, but if I'm pointing and yelling at you, that is a form of harassment. 

However, if you are alleging criminal harassments, you need to provide evidence that my actions were purposeful and with the intent was to cause you distress</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394617159.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Are the social media a public space or not? If they are, then public-space speech protections should apply. If not, then the owner of the media should get to determine such things. But they shouldn't be private when it comes time to protect people from unpleasant speech and public when it comes time to curtail unpleasant speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394643586.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are the social media a public space or not?

Not. but that's not the question. You asked what could be considered targeted. Social media is free to ban you for whatever reason they can justify. But you were talking about the legal sphere and what is or isn't harassment. Twitter banning you for "hate speech" is nowhere near the same level as getting in real legal trouble for real hate speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394717068.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not. but that's not the question. 

Sure it is. A site could say, as part of its TOS, that when you join you accept that you can be @ed or DMed as much as the senders want and you cannot claim harassment. That when you join up, you accept that risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394765494.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>I.m not arguing against that. What I'm saying is, Twitters and Facebooks definition of hate speech or harassments can be different from the legal definition. And they have the legal right to ban you from their platform. That's not an infringement on free speech.  

But for hate speech and criminal harassment, there is a clear legal definition and criteria that an accuser must meet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394873698.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>And that's a problem for free speech. If the public channels have legal restrictions, and the private channels have legal restrictions *plus* terms-of-service restrictions, that's a massive curtailment on speech. 

Part of the problem is that I think that your position is something of a rationalization on where you want the discourse to wind up. If, under the current legal and private-restriction scenario, it became unfeasible for people to ignore hate speech directed at them, I think you'd be demanding change until that was no longer the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394888345.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and the private channels have legal restrictions plus terms-of-service restrictions, that's a massive curtailment on speech.

That has always been a thing. You are not entitled to an audience or platform. Any membership, to any private club can be revoked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394949088.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but now that the private clubs are such a larger part of speech, should we not consider changing policy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395012176.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>They aren't a large part of speech. They are just another form of media. If you're a program director at a television station, you can still get fired for airing your personal opinions if the higher ups don't like it. Free speech does not obligate anyone to listen to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395069383.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>That's true only in theory, not in practice. If you want to make a political argument by standing in a public place and reading it out, it will get no traction if it's not allowed on Twitter and Facebook. 

&amp;gt; Free speech does not obligate anyone to listen to you.

Maybe, but when someone doesn't want to listen to, say, white supremacist speech, all they have to do is avoid white-supremacist sites. If someone doesn't want to hear speech that advocates racial equality, they have to avoid *all* the social media, and the news sites, and popular culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395122483.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If someone doesn't want to hear speech that advocates racial equality, they have to avoid all the social media, and the news sites, and popular culture.

Life can be hard. Thats their problem. They are free to start a social media platform, and to dictate the content of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395239595.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>So when there are systemic consequences for people because of their sexuality or gender or race or work toward social justice, is the same “Life is hard” response appropriate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400502259.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is the systemic consequences are based on prejudice of their their sexuality or gender or race. In other words, things they cant change. I dont see how that is the same as having to avoid twitter because you're a racist, miserable asshole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400510343.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>If the only things about you that are protected are your immutable characteristics, then that's not freedom. People need to be free in their choices as well as their nature.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400555504.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>Being free does not mean everyone is obligated to accommodate you and entertain your bigotries. Thats childish. If you are upset that twitter is too progressive, and wont let you say the n-word, thats not discrimination. Your attitude and bigotries are not an unchangeable characteristic. Like if I act like a complete asshole at a party, the host can kick me out. 

What you seem to be advocating for her is thought protection. You're free to believe what you want, about anyone you want. Its not illegal to be racist. Its not illegal to say racist things. But there are social consequences to your words and actions. 

If you are unlikable, no one will like you. Being a Human 101. 

None of that has to do with free speech. 

&amp;gt;If the only things about you that are protected are your immutable characteristics

There are a number of legal protections outside of your speech, lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400628872.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Being free does not mean everyone is obligated to accommodate you and entertain your bigotries. Thats childish.

Then it also shouldn't mean that we have to accommodate and entertain people's inherent characteristics. That also shouldn't be discriminatory. 

&amp;gt; Like if I act like a complete asshole at a party, the host can kick me out.

I'm forced to put up with people doing things I don't like, day in and day out. Why shouldn't other people be forced to put up with me doing things they don't like?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400736432.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Then it also shouldn't mean that we have to accommodate and entertain people's inherent characteristics. 

You, as an individual, don't. However, discrimination based on inherent characteristics is not the same as discrimination based on words and actions. You seem to be struggling with that concept. 

&amp;gt;I'm forced to put up with people doing things I don't like, day in and day out.

No you're not. Your free to be as miserable and racist as you want. What you are now saying is that your feelings, no matter how unjustifiable, are more important than reducing harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400831272.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; You, as an individual, don't. However, discrimination based on inherent characteristics is not the same as discrimination based on words and actions. You seem to be struggling with that concept.

I get it, I just don't agree with it. 

&amp;gt; No you're not. Your free to be as miserable and racist as you want. What you are now saying is that your feelings, no matter how unjustifiable, are more important than reducing harassment.

I'm not talking about racism. It's like, if someone cuts me off on the highway or if I get on the slow checkout line at the store, those are other people's actions but I have to deal with the consequences. So why is it that I shouldn't get to take actions where other people have to deal with the consequences?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400878962.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So why is it that I shouldn't get to take actions where other people have to deal with the consequences?

Why do you think you don't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401016423.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think that it's acceptable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401550685.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>That's life. Your actions will affect others. We as a society should strive to make thing easier for people who struggle for various reasons. Its the most ethical approach, and we have the capabilities.  Those of us who don't struggle, don't need the help. If banning hate speech on social media makes it a more positive place for everyone except those that choose to hold on to bigotry, and it is a choice, then its a good thing. I personally don't care about people who choose to be miserable, because they are the only ones who can change their attitude. 

You can't change your race/sexuality, so society can adjust to be more inviting to those people. You can change your outlook, so its up to you to adjust to society. Don't want to? Fine, thats a you problem. But the existence of wheelchairs doesn't prevent you from walking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401752556.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>So basically I have a fundamental disagreement with your view of ethics. You think that we should comfort the afflicted and afflict the comfortable so that everyone gets to relatively the same outcome. I don't think that's ethical at all. I want to be able to improve my own life without consideration of others, and I don't think that's unethical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39401861132.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I want to be able to improve my own life without consideration of others,

Nothing about what I said says you can't do that. 

I don't ever really know what your arguing at this point. Are you saying we shouldn't strive for equality (equality in opportunity, not outcome), simply because you don't like it?  Or that we should allow hate speech to be protected for sole purpose of satisfying the status quo?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39402233115.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Are you saying we shouldn't strive for equality (equality in opportunity, not outcome), simply because you don't like it?

In a way, but really it's deeper than that. It's more important to me that people are free to do as they please than that they're protected from others. Now, obviously I don't mean that they should be free to kill or rape or steal. But I do mean that I hate how people who smoke cigarettes have had their opportunities to smoke constantly restricted. I hate how homeowners' associations have restricted the way people can use their houses, property that's supposed to be their own. I hate how parents aren't supposed to raise their children to their own values. I hate how bosses are supposed to be more concerned with the success of the team than with actually being a boss and getting to enjoy the trappings of power. I hate how you're never supposed to use a power imbalance to your advantage. And I could give you a dozen more examples.

All of these are changes made over the last few decades, and they've all been instances of the same idea, to lift up the downtrodden while taking the self-important down a few pegs. And they've been bad enough, but free speech is the hill that I die on. Because while you can make a more reasonable case for harm in all the examples I listed above, speech doesn't do harm. If I tell someone to go fuck themselves and they run home crying, it's not I who should have to be nicer. It's they who should have to get tougher.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39402524883.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's more important to me that people are free to do as they please than that they're protected from others.

So I should be free to slander you, doctor photos of you to present a false narrative, spit in your face whenever I see you, and flood your DM's with dick pics no matter how much you protest? 

&amp;gt;But I do mean that I hate how people who smoke cigarettes have had their opportunities to smoke constantly restricted.

What about my right to not get addicted to nicotine? Its the most addictive drug, and second hand smoke is a thing. 

&amp;gt;I hate how homeowners' associations have restricted the way people can use their houses, property that's supposed to be their own.

Hard agree here, but joining a HOA isnt mandatory.  

&amp;gt; I hate how you're never supposed to use a power imbalance to your advantage

So a boss threatening to fire you unless you give him head is cool? Harvey Weinstein didnt do anything wrong in your eyes? 

&amp;gt;to lift up the downtrodden while taking the self-important down a few pegs.


This is nonsense, 0 sum bullshit, that conservatives buy into. The healthier, happier, and more secure a society is, the better it is for everyone. Giving poor people a hand does not equal a kick to well-to- do people. Someone gaining something does not mean you lose something. 

know what ignoring struggling groups of people leads to? Higher violent crime rates. Poor or not, people got to eat, and will do what it takes to survive.  Awesome!!! 

So instead of allowing society to help, you are saying you would rather pay money to punish and keep people disenfranchised. Because who else is paying for prisons?  That to you is more ethical?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39402724465.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So I should be free to slander you, doctor photos of you to present a false narrative, spit in your face whenever I see you, and flood your DM's with dick pics no matter how much you protest?

Again, slander, fraud, and assault are actual crimes and should be. But you should be free to insult me, tell me how much you hate me, and spit on the ground to show me. 

&amp;gt; What about my right to not get addicted to nicotine? Its the most addictive drug, and second hand smoke is a thing.

Then you leave. Don't go to restaurants that have a smoking section. But a law that stops them from having one is more of a violation against the right of people who want to smoke. Their comfort from nicotine is not outweighed by your desire to have healthy lungs. 

&amp;gt; Hard agree here, but joining a HOA isnt mandatory.

No, but it's a societal trend in line with the others. It's putting more responsibility on homeowners and less power. 

&amp;gt; So a boss threatening to fire you unless you give him head is cool? Harvey Weinstein didnt do anything wrong in your eyes?

No, but a boss wanting you to get him coffee because he likes giving orders, or having you wash his car while you're on the clock should be cool. 

&amp;gt; This is nonsense, 0 sum bullshit, that conservatives buy into. The healthier, happier, and more secure a society is, the better it is for everyone. 

No, it makes it better for regular people. It doesn't make it better for people who are, or are trying to be, up on the hierarchy. It doesn't make it better for me. I don't get enjoyment watching other people do well. I get enjoyment when I do well. That doesn't make me atavistic. 

It also doesn't mean that I'm sadistic. I don't want people to suffer for suffering's sake. I do want people to be happy and secure; it's just that I want them to be happy by being free to do what they want, not to be happy by forcing them into what I think is a happy life. That's what you want. You want me to be happy because other people can't smoke around me instead of being happy because I can smoke where I want (if I smoked). You want me to be happy in a clean and sustainable house with solar panels on it. I want to be happy in a big house with a manicured lawn and a barbecue. And above all, you want me to be happy because no one is yelling insults at me, while I want to be happy by being free to yell insults at others if I see fit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403002179.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But you should be free to insult me, tell me how much you hate me, and spit on the ground to show me.

I am. Why should hate speech be ok, and not slander?

&amp;gt; But a law that stops them from having one is more of a violation against the right of people who want to smoke.

Smoking isn't a right, for one. Secondly, your actions have a direct negative impact on others. *"Stay off the road if you don't want to be killed by a drunk driver"*. Same thing.  Why should your addiction affect where I want to eat?

&amp;gt;No, but a boss wanting you to get him coffee because he likes giving orders, or having you wash his car while you're on the clock should be cool.

Nope. Fuck that. I was hired to do the job described. Not to be a servant. Want your car washed? Hire someone for that job, or do it yourself. Thats some straight up bootlicker shit. Lol. Your basically advocating that working people shouldn't have self respect.

&amp;gt;It doesn't make it better for people who are, or are trying to be, up on the hierarchy.

Fuck your hierarchy. Its a net negative to society. You basically just said people should suffer so you can feel better than them. No matter how much help people get, there will always be more successful people. There will always be an elite. So you can stop worrying. 

&amp;gt; I want them to be happy by being free to do what they want,

Marginalized, disenfranchised people are not free to do what they want. 

&amp;gt; not to be happy by forcing them into what I think is a happy life.

Food/financial/legal security is not really objective. And if you want to live a happy life being poor and hounded by police, go for it. You can still choose to do that. Theress a big difference in providing avenues for people to more easily escape that, and forcing them into a certain job or lifestyle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403292137.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am. Why should hate speech be ok, and not slander?

Because slander is a specific kind of fraud (the statement must be false to be slander) that causes objective damages in the legal sense to the victim. Being hated or insulted is not objective damages. 

&amp;gt; Smoking isn't a right, for one. Secondly, your actions have a direct negative impact on others. "Stay off the road if you don't want to be killed by a drunk driver". Same thing. Why should your addiction affect where I want to eat?

Smoking in particular isn't a right, but what I'm saying is that everything that isn't forbidden should be a right, rather than only enumerated rights being what you're free to do, and everything else requires permission. And the drunk-driving thing is because of the public roads, which is a separate debate. The fact that you can get arrested for DUI while sitting in your car in your own driveway with the engine off is wrong. For that matter, if I own enough land to make a private road, I should be free to drive it as drunk as I want, and if you choose to use it, you assume that risk. 

&amp;gt; Nope. Fuck that. I was hired to do the job described. Not to be a servant. Want your car washed? Hire someone for that job, or do it yourself. Thats some straight up bootlicker shit. Lol. Your basically advocating that working people shouldn't have self respect.

No, what I'm arguing is that it should be legal and acceptable to advertise jobs that way. If I own the company, I should be allowed to hire someone to both be a secretary or receptionist or mail clerk, and also to act as a personal valet. 

For that matter, I think it's part of the decline I described above that personal service is less of a thing today. Even if we don't want to make subordinates serve their bosses sexually (and if we legalize prostitution, as I think we should, then that could also be part of the job description), we should make it legal and acceptable to require a personal assistant to be an attractive woman and to make wearing revealing clothes part of the job requirements. 

It's in the same vein as the idea of hierarchy. You don't want *anyone* on Earth to be free of the common problems we all have. If there's a queue for a table at the restaurant, no one gets to jump it. If your car is dirty, no one gets to just order it washed. When people want things, no one gets to just get them.

&amp;gt; Fuck your hierarchy. Its a net negative to society. You basically just said people should suffer so you can feel better than them. No matter how much help people get, there will always be more successful people. There will always be an elite. So you can stop worrying.

But it's a net positive to some individuals. If you don't consider them, why should I consider the people you care about?

&amp;gt; Marginalized, disenfranchised people are not free to do what they want.

Let's not get caught in a semantic trap here. We're clearly talking about two different meanings of the word "free." To go back to my example above, we have two people in different situations. One who is permitted to smoke in any bar or restaurant, but can't afford cigarettes. Another who has millions of cigarettes, but is forbidden from smoking in public. 

The second person might have more *power*, but the first person has more *freedom*. Do you see the distinction? 

&amp;gt; Food/financial/legal security is not really objective. And if you want to live a happy life being poor and hounded by police, go for it. You can still choose to do that. Theress a big difference in providing avenues for people to more easily escape that, and forcing them into a certain job or lifestyle.

I'm not really sure what you're saying here or how it relates to what I was talking about above. Yes, I know that, in your ideal world, I'd be free to live a rough life. But I wouldn't be free to live the life of the idle rich. Or even just to speak about how that life is a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403961164.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because slander is a specific kind of fraud (the statement must be false to be slander) that causes objective damages in the legal sense to the victim

Not all slander result in legal troubles for the victim. Often its just a smear campaign. So you dont think hate speech results in objective damage? 

And to clarify, hate speech isnt just being insulting and feeling hatred. Hate speech, like slander, has an objective. Its basically slandering whole groups, instead of an individual, with the end goal of ridding society of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39403985896.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not all slander result in legal troubles for the victim. Often its just a smear campaign. So you dont think hate speech results in objective damage?

Not in a way that should be remedied legally. "John Q. Smith is a jerk" might not be good for Mr. Smith, but he has no legal remedy. 

&amp;gt;  Its basically slandering whole groups, instead of an individual, with the end goal of ridding society of them.

No it isn't, because again, it has to be a lie to be slander. If someone says that short people are all evil, they might have a standard of good and evil that makes that true to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39404042720.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If someone says that short people are all evil, they might have a standard of good and evil that makes that true to them.

I completely reject that premise. I believe in an objective reality. Not some flimsy, post-modern justification. 1930's European leaders claiming that Jews will steal and eat your baby is a complete fabrication. I.e slander.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39404197442.0" user="pjabrony" delta="False">
    <text>You can think that, but it demands a lot more restriction of speech than you think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396497587.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you ask me to leave you alone for any reason, and I don't, its harassments

um, what? harassment laws [vary by state in the us](https://definitions.uslegal.com/h/harassment/) but they are certainly not "this person talked to me again after i said stop."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400489235.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>You guys take simplified illustrations too literally. The point was, it doesnt have to be threats. If I am calling  you every 20 mins asking for money, that could also be considered harassments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39404420996.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>maybe you missed the link i gave to a typical example of us law.

&amp;gt;A person is guilty of harassment in the first degree when he or she intentionally and repeatedly harasses another person by following such person in or about a public place or places or by engaging in a course of conduct or by repeatedly committing acts which places such person in reasonable fear of physical injury.

"harassment" legally is not the same as "someone is bothering me."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39458158419.0" user="babypizza22" delta="False">
    <text>Harassment is only for workplace environments, or school. (I'm from America so that might be different from where you are). There is no harassment on social media, unless it's bullying a school peer, because you can just block them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40668607669.0" user="ProfaneGhost" delta="False">
    <text>Sending someone messages over social media isn't harassment. There's a block button for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40761508204.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's a block button for a reason.

People find their way around those. New/alt profiles, etc. If I ask you to stop contacting me, but you continue to contact me, that would be considered harassment in the court of law. Its no different than continuously calling someone. Sure, I can just hang up and block you, but you can just call from another number.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394288299.0" user="petarpep" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People have a right to say disgusting shit

Maybe but not necessarily *to* people. Extreme verbal abuse towards a child is something I think almost all of us would agree on being illegal. So it's not as if there isn't some room already for banning harassing speech, the discussion then becomes about the extent of harassing speech before it should become illegal. Because I also think most of us would agree that calling someone an idiot as a one off insult shouldn't be illegal. So it's somewhere between these two for most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393960385.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394241695.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394413774.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394557688.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394885879.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397309224.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Massive-Regular-6758 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Massive-Regular-6758&amp;amp;message=Massive-Regular-6758%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3ip4hj/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397319733.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/mfizzled – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20mfizzled&amp;amp;message=mfizzled%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3ii394/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397325331.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Massive-Regular-6758 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Massive-Regular-6758&amp;amp;message=Massive-Regular-6758%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3if07i/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397313770.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/mfizzled – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20mfizzled&amp;amp;message=mfizzled%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3ibbfj/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397327662.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Massive-Regular-6758 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Massive-Regular-6758&amp;amp;message=Massive-Regular-6758%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3i5add/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39750831492.0" user="Sammy9707" delta="False">
    <text>they should all be legal imo….they don’t directly incite violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39752183214.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>Are you American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753852674.0" user="Sammy9707" delta="False">
    <text>yes, but from a philosophical standpoint I don’t see why that matters</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753958035.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>Thought so, and cultural/societal background makes an absolutely huge difference to how our own personal viewpoints develop.

  


This freedom-over-everything philosophy is something that seems to be uniquely American.

  


Americans are fine with no publicly funded healthcare, with funerals being picketed repeatedly, with so many shootings that their gunshot deaths rival third world warzones, with news companies being able to say outright lies and with deregulation of industry with horrendously negative effects - all in the name of freedom.

  


Now that stuff happens in America and so let the Americans do as they see fit.

On the other hand, the rest of the developed world doesn't consider those things I mentioned to be something that should be tolerated in society, at least not to the same extreme.

  


So this case being about Britain, it should be no surprise that British values are applied to the case.

  


In the same way that certain speech is banned in America, the famous one being shouting fire in a theatre etc, some speech is banned in the UK.

  


Personally messaging someone to racially abuse them, to me, seems like something that should quite obviously be illegal.

  


It doesn't to you, because of the reasons I described initially.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754063492.0" user="Sammy9707" delta="False">
    <text>I understand what you’re saying…..but I still don’t find that the incidents that were mentioned should be illegal. I should have the right to say racist shit, and you should have the right to not listen to it if you don’t want to. I believe that in a truly free society, freedom should only be limited when it hinders the freedom of others. I think banning speech just because it hurts peoples feelings is one of the very few things i thoroughly dislike about European culture. No offense, but it seems that many europeans view free speech in a way that is sort of toxic in my opinion, Like you can only say what the government says you can. It is like this in America too, but speech isn’t censored simply because it is broadly disliked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754107890.0" user="mfizzled" delta="False">
    <text>Yep, this is why I asked if you're American. Because I'm fully aware this is how a lot of Americans think. 

But it's not just a European thing, it's literally and not figuratively the way that nearly the rest of the planet operates.

And I can see why you think it's like we only say what the government says we can but it's not really like that. These are things that society agrees with as well and in the same way the American legal freedom of speech evolved from the will of the people, so did this. 

It is not like we are all devastated about not being able to be racist to each other, it is something that is overwhelmingly supported by the society as a whole.

To refer to what you said at the beginning, I absolutely agree with and support your right to say racist shit. The same goes with anyone, say whatever you want. 

Where we differ is the "have the right to not listen to it if you don't want to". I shouldn't have to deal with you being racist or something to me. I'm trying to live my life without the negativity and shittiness that bigotry brings as I believe that a society with lots of hate quickly becomes polarised and divided.

If you want to have a party with all your racist friends and talk about how much you hate minorities then that's something I personally think people should be allowed to do. 

What you do in your own home is your own choice and as long as you don't hurt anyone, you should be allowed to do it. Going out and being racist and aggressive to strangers is going beyond the bounds of that.

It's just a your rights end where my rights begin kinda thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754199746.0" user="Sammy9707" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for replying, i sincerely appreciate it, and I think we found more common ground than I thought we would. Also, in case you misunderstood my statements, I absolutely despise the racist skinheads that I occasionally encounter more than I should. I just defend their right to say what they want, as long as it doesn’t directly harm the people they are targeting. As someone living in southern appalaicha, I have unfortunately encountered racism, homophobia, and bigotry a lot more than the average American. So I know first hand the negative effects it can have on people. I have friends who have been racially harassed by the local neighborhood racist. I dislike his behavior, however, I think he is harming himself by saying racist things more than anybody else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391441093.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>He was not only charged, he was arrested, charged, and convicted.

Because the judge said "it wasn't clear it was a joke" in the video where he literally said "this is a joke I'm doing on my girlfriend to make her cute dog do the least cute thing I can imagine", mostly because the judge was so stupid he thought that because his girlfriend was not subscribed to his YT channel, that it wasn't made with her in mind as the target demo, as if being subbed to a channel means anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393566292.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but something like [this](https://i.imgur.com/yT3sSQ7.jpeg) would be more appropriate don't you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393641178.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>Even if it wasn’t (how could it not be, though, given the context) that still essentially plays to OP’s point. An offensive statement should still be protected by free speech. You’ve essentially conceded your original counter to his point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393660423.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think judges base these things on "bah probably a shit head".

You can read the actual case,  it's hilariously shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396175487.0" user="megablast" delta="False">
    <text>So I can get away with anything as long as I say it is a joke. Sweet!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399720634.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>Is that really what you think ive said here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391484547.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure he was convicted nvm arrested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392596260.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>If it’s a moot point, doesn’t that mean your view is at least a little changed? Basically it impacts no one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392655169.0" user="MeadsyBoro" delta="False">
    <text>This is nonsense though isn't it? There's people arrested, fined, sentenced etc under the communications act regularly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392764018.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>Is your comment outside of the US? When you say the communications act, you’re not talking about the 1934 act creating the FCC are you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392898974.0" user="cultish_alibi" delta="False">
    <text>OP is from Scotland so yes, not everything is about the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393056275.0" user="CobaltHeadHunter" delta="False">
    <text>They should really specify what specific nation they are from. Otherwise it opens the floodgates for really cheap "gotcha" moments.

Edit: Personally I think CMV should add a sub rule that requires OP to be more specific in "where they are coming from" be it geographically, racially, or from a class perspective. I understand why that isn't a rule because it would be tough to enforce, but if enacted successfully would enhance the discussion and debate present.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394258281.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>It’s almost as though I asked that question for a reason….And do you know which country the person I’m responding to is from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394259243.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>It’s almost as though I asked that question for a reason….And do you know which country the person I’m responding to is from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393031223.0" user="baldur_of_rivia" delta="False">
    <text>Where is this? Any reliablale sources that arent FOX news or Infowars?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393879527.0" user="MeadsyBoro" delta="False">
    <text>I live in the UK and I'm referring to UK law in respect to objective facts. 

I don't have access to FOX News and I don't know what Infowars is but nice try.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393161556.0" user="HumanLike" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. OP's entire view is built on the [appealing to extremes](https://www.logicallyfallacious.com/logicalfallacies/Appeal-to-Extremes) logical fallacy. No point in trying to change a view built on a fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393683051.0" user="EmperorDawn" delta="False">
    <text>Proving a point is not the appealing to extremes fallacy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394113705.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>One random redditor said they don't know many cases and then incorrectly stated the details of the one case they claimed to know of. And it's OP who's fallacious for ignoring this "evidence"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394803815.0" user="boyhero97" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see much of a difference between arresting people for their speech vs. convicting. Sure, it's not on their record, but you are holding them in jail as a scare tactic for saying something you don't like with the intent of stopping them from using their speech. It's harassment at the very least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393427244.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393689715.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>If the government is able to drag you through court for 6+ years over a joke you can’t really call free speech protected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394273675.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>If something happens at a statistically irrelevant rate (not saying that is the case here) it’s hard to build a strong argument about it. If 1 person has been convicted under a law (again not saying that’s the case here) it’s hard to make a great argument about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395505858.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>That argument dosent make sense so your saying that even if a legal president is set by convicting someone over a joke that as long as it isn’t statistically relevant it isn’t a problem, that’s like saying lynching was never a problem because less then 1% of the population was ever lynched.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395800590.0" user="The_GOATest1" delta="False">
    <text>No I’m saying based on the premise above us, nothing actually ever happened. So in your analogy it would be if a legal precedent* was set and 0% of people were actually lynched.

Said differently, plenty of states have laws banning gay marriage, because federally it’s allowable, going through and changing the laws on the books at the state level is ceremonial because ultimately (at least for the time being) it’s a moot point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396342235.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>So wait you are saying 6 years worth of league fees and inconsistent court dates that would make regular employment impossible is nothing happening, shit like this is the reason you have a constitutional right to a speedy trial in the US because government can cause just as much harm to you through the trial prices as a conviction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396673848.0" user="Antares777" delta="False">
    <text>They’re saying that the case or cases of that happening are so statistically insignificant that it isn’t worth considering them damaging to free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397192348.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>Yes hence the lynching analogy, because statistically speaking an insignificant number of people were lynched there for it is not damaging to society. This is a stupid argument because reducing the societal damage caused by lynching to just the number of people directly lynched shows a narrow understanding of the problem. In much the same way if only a few people are persecuted for expressing their views and it is publicly displayed as in the case of count dancula it will stifle free expression due to fear in much the same way lynching stifled free movement and integration due to fear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397271587.0" user="Antares777" delta="False">
    <text>But you’re talking about a racially motivated crime, which means you don’t consider the entire population when discussing the numbers, you consider the entirety of that demographic only. 

And due to the nature of racial crimes, they’re a lot more personal than someone being charged for saying inflammatory shit on Twitter. Which means a much lower proportion of victims to total population is needed to make the issue a priority. 

Basically? Yeah, lynchings actually matter to people and random idiots losing money over saying threatening things is not. Want more people to care about the issue and approach it as a constitutional rights issue, you should probably encourage politicians to fund public education better, so that people can actually do the critical thinking and analysis that lends itself to looking beyond the surface of issues into the deeper societal implications. 

Not that I agree that it is a constitutional issue. I think people have seen many examples of people being punished for being purposely inflammatory, like shouting fire in a crowded theater, and know that it’s not okay to incite violence or panic. Smart people know that, anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397413128.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>The shouting fire in a crowded theater isn’t illegal that misconception is due to a decent by justice Holmes that was retracted because it is flawed, further more lynching is not necessary racial it is when a mob decides to kill someone and has been used throughout history to oppress descent weather it be motivated by politics, ideology, race, religion you name it fear is the constant. These persecutions on free speech are intended to do the same “do as you are told and do not offend us or we will ruin your life regardless if you are convicted”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397438861.0" user="Antares777" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao it was partially overturned and limited to only speech that can incite unlawful behavior, which is the issue at hand. People inciting violence against groups that are frequently discriminated against by individuals and institutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399037714.0" user="Nalock40" delta="False">
    <text>What evidence do you have that it was over turned last I checked dankula was convicted and his appeal was denied</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396356044.0" user="zbeshears" delta="False">
    <text>So because it doesn’t affect many people, yet, the post and ops point is moot? 

It will get worse if no one does anything about it, history shows that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392725542.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393011502.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>u/NovaStorm970 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20NovaStorm970&amp;amp;message=NovaStorm970%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3hetk6/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391685030.0" user="Wrekd_Ralph" delta="False">
    <text>That was hilarious. I’m pretty sure the dog wasn’t from 1940’s Germany so if it offends people then they should feel free to fuck themselves</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392146837.0" user="maxout2142" delta="False">
    <text>They charge you for the ride. He was very much publicly railroaded for a joke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392265807.0" user="Permit_Current" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.hrw.org/news/2012/10/14/social-media-prosecutions-threaten-free-speech-uk-and-beyond</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392343521.0" user="DrRockMaxwell" delta="False">
    <text>Journalists are being killed or jailed by various powerful people worldwide</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392555055.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>The Nazi pug guy went to trial and was convicted. There are hundreds of arrests each year for offensive tweets:

https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/arrests-for-offensive-facebook-and-twitter-posts-soar-in-london-a7064246.html?amp

And just recently:

https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/crime/captain-tom-moore-tweet-man-charged-b1799310.html?amp

https://www.inputmag.com/culture/uk-man-sentenced-community-service-offensive-tweet/amp</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394093123.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>But as long as Redditors can't remember them, it'd NBD...

More to the point: It's worth keeping in mind that the chilling effect that these laws have on speech is even broader than the number of actual number of arrests can measure. You'll never know how many folks self-censor out of fear of punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394517355.0" user="softawre" delta="False">
    <text>Can we not shit on people for asking questions and being willing to learn?  Not all redditors know everything and there's no shame in asking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394559070.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>Asking what? Not sure we're talking about the same person. 

Alleging that something rarely happens because you don't personally recall high profile instances of it is dubious. It's also a pretty common trope in these discussions, in which folks 'defend' suppression of speech by suggesting that it doesn't actually happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395210135.0" user="idgafaboutpopsicles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You'll never know how many folks self-censor out of fear of punishment.

I absolutely agree that punishing free speech is problematic, but I really dislike this phrasing. fear of social punishment and fear of legal punishment shouldn't be conflated under one umbrella. And I'd argue the overwhelming majority of self-censorship is from fear of social punishment, not legal punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395477617.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>In this case, I'm discussing fear of actual legal punishment.

Social sanction against free speech is also an issue in its own right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392790631.0" user="dtr1984" delta="False">
    <text>He was convicted and forced to pay a fine. The irony was that reporters said his joke just as he did but they were not fined (naturally) because context suddenly mattered when the reporters said it. Very much like Rogan and Biden using the n word where it was totally okay when Biden did it but not Rogan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392902287.0" user="TFFTN" delta="False">
    <text>IIRC he was given poor legal advice and was done for something like broadcasting his "joke" by making it available on YouTube.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393234468.0" user="wadakow" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of Americans are claiming that "words can be violence" and they're trying to outlaw hate speech. The problem is who defines hate speech and how. It's a slippery slope that we should stay away from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393589866.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>Haste speech has a very clear definition:

hate speech

noun
abusive or threatening speech or writing that expresses prejudice against a particular group, especially on the basis of race, religion, or sexual orientation.


Me saying I dont like a group of people isnt hate speech. But saying Im going to go Rambo on a bunch of them is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393665037.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>Except a good number of people will consider any dissent against them to be abusive or threatening. That’s the point here; who gets to determine what speech is and isn’t “abusive”? If it’s the person who is the object of the speech, some people are extremely thin-skinned and can feel abused or attacked by nearly anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394205456.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; who gets to determine what speech is and isn’t “abusive”?

Lawyers and judges. The same people who interpret all law. You can get offended and call me abusive for this message. People are fucked like that. But it wouldn't go anywhere because legal experts will not take your misinterpretation as law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394249763.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>How does a judge determine that when the interpretation of an insult and the resulting emotional impact on people is ENTIRELY subjective?

If someone gets incredibly offended by a phrase deemed inoffensive by a judge, do we simply say "sorry, you're wrong to be offended." If we do, then what is the point of hate speech laws to begin with if we're going to completely undermine personal perception of a statement and the emotions which such a law is trying to protect?

At this point we've done nothing but now offer an outlet for censorship and random indistinct arrests while already telling those this is supposed to help that their personally felt experience and emotions are not inherently valid.

In some instances a person will be incredibly hurt by a word or phrase deemed perfectly accepted, while others will be entirely unaffected by the deepest of cutting words that would qualify to some judges as unacceptable. Where's the line and why is it drawn when it has no bearing on harm done? It's a ridiculous concept.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394281719.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If someone gets incredibly offended by a phrase deemed inoffensive by a judge, do we simply say "sorry, you're wrong to be offended."

Offending someone is not a crime. You have a right to be offended, but they will look at the facts/evidence to determine if my actions are *criminal* or not. And if you can't provide any evidence, then sorry, no case. 

This is basic legal stuff. There's no reinventing the wheel here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394395591.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Offending someone is not a crime  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;but they will look at the facts/evidence to determine if my actions are criminal or not

But the reason this would be criminal in the first place is exclusively because of the emotional damage that the hate speech would cause. Offense is the only thing that hate speech can cause so if we're throwing that away as a point of measurement then we've completely ignored the point of banning hate speech to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394408438.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the reason this would be criminal in the first place is exclusively because of the emotional damage that the hate speech would cause

Not at all. Hate speech has led to things like lynchings and a holocaust. Its above and beyond hurting someone's feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394455934.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>And the slippery slope has been opened. Banning things because they MIGHT one day be tangentially related to something that has measurable harm is absolutely downright absurd.

If you're wanting to get rid of things because they MIGHT eventually cascade into something worse, then ban insults. That might lead to fights, vitriol, or murder. Ban rallying behind pretty much any cause, as such causes can be perverted and become negative and potentially violent. Ban religious involvement, as that can lead people to believing one's beliefs are superior to others and that can lead to inter-faith violence. Ban confrontational political speech, as that can lead to the belief that one political group is evil and needs to be controlled/eliminated. Ban any negative speech against the government, as that can lead to radicalization and potential terrorism.

There are so many things that can apply if the criteria for banning something is so incredibly loose. I'm glad we came to the point, though, just so it can be shown how unbelievably loose the ground for banning hate speech really is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394476692.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you're wanting to get rid of things because they MIGHT eventually cascade into something worse, then ban insults.

No on is talking about banning insults. I don't know what your talking about. Hate speech has a clear definition. The complainant will have to present evidence that your speech was intended to cause harm. And this is why a lot of hate speech cases get thrown out. I don't know how to make i more clear. Anyone can accuse anyone of anything. That is what courts are for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394511562.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>I’m showing that the logic you’re using to ban hate speech is grounded in nothing. No concrete causation, no specific damage done. Just "maybes" and "mights". Why should it be only applicable to one single thing? If the logic is “it could eventually result in harm” and nothing more, there is no reason to limit it to just whatever speech is deemed hateful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394619013.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If the logic is “it could eventually result in harm” and nothing more, there is no reason to limit it to just whatever speech is deemed hateful.

Do you consider enticing violent acts against specific groups of people to be on par with being rude and hurting someones feelings?

Also, you are missing a huge thing here. Hate speech isn't banned. Its not protected. Those are two different things. To get in legal trouble for hate speech, the courts will have to be provided with sufficient evidence that what you said fits the definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394865734.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>Inciting acts of violence is already an offense; it just must be direct, intentional, give specifics, and be provable. The laws that surround threats and inciting violence are very strict in what can and cannot be prosecuted. 

I see no difference in it being banned and it not being protected in your definition. Do courts NOT have to provide sufficient evidence you broke the law in instances of something that is banned? If they don’t, that is downright terrifying and I suppose it’s just my American privilege showing.

And that is also assuming the definition of hate speech actually is something concrete, doesn’t change,  and is not just nebulous nothings like some people seem to think it is. And I’m going to assume it’s not super concrete in practice given the downright embarrassing cases it has been used against so far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394908439.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it just must be direct, intentional, give specifics, and be provable. The laws that surround threats and inciting violence are very strict in what can and cannot be prosecuted.

That is the exact same criteria for hate speech. 

&amp;gt; Do courts NOT have to provide sufficient evidence you broke the law in instances of something that is banned?

If something is banned, the only evidence required is a recording of you saying it. 

&amp;gt;and is not just nebulous nothings like some people seem to think it is

Well, the legal definition isn't. So who cares what anyone else feels about it? 

Do you feel the same way about slander laws? Should slander be protected speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394959542.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>It absolutely is not the same criteria otherwise it would never be enforced  on its own. Anything that had all of those qualities would already be a direct threat which can be prosecuted on its own.

The “banned speech” thing is genuinely horrifying and makes me even more opposed to how this close slide into that classification. 

How isn’t the legal definition non-nebulous? It certainly doesn’t seem extremely concrete. Can you re-state it again to clarify?

Slander is one of the single most scrutinized accusations in the justice system. The rigor one must go through to prove it is so in-depth that most people don’t even try to pursue such charges and the majority of those who do lose. It must be qualified by exactly what I listed off earlier, and absolutely no less. You cannot just insult someone or attack his/her character. It must be direct, explicit, give something provable or disprovable as a claim and then also have intentionality of the person behind it, AKA it must be intended to defame and be slanderous in a concrete way while the person knows the accusation to be false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394971766.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt ask for the definition of slander, I asked if you believe it should be protected or not. 

&amp;gt;The “banned speech” thing is genuinely horrifying and makes me even more opposed to how this close slide into that classification.

No one is doing that, so IDK what your talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397386885.0" user="Memelord420BlazeIt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the reason this would be criminal in the first place is exclusively because of the emotional damage that the hate speech would cause.

I'm not sure what restriction on hate speech you're talking about, but this is not how hate speech laws work (at least not in my country, Belgium). Generally the idea is to ban speech that have the specific intent to incite hatred towards a specific group of people based on race, gender, sexual orientation... A judge then has to decide whether there indeed was such an intent.

Whether someone is offended has nothing to do with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394943068.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But it wouldn't go anywhere because legal experts will not take your misinterpretation as law

Why would you assume that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394996440.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>Why would any lawyer risk their job and reputation by purposefully misinterpreting a law. All that shows it that they are dumb.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395046111.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>No the question is why would you assume that the OP's judgment is a "misinterpretation"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395136878.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt say that. People in general can interpret any law in multiple ways. Thats why legal experts exist. They aren't going to care how you interpret it.  They will interpret it for themselves, based on more knowledge than the layperson.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395167768.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>You're not addressing the question. The OP mentioned that people might interpret offensive/dissenting speech to be abusive. And you said that would be be a misinterpretation of the law. The question is why you believe this would be a misinterpretation. Obviously, if we presuppose that it's a misinterpretation, then it wouldn't go anywhere, but that's sidestepping the entire debate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395194030.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The question is why you believe this would be a misinterpretation

Because the law is clear. So if your interpretation doesn't fit the clear definition, what is the obvious conclusion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395328073.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Because the law is clear.

That's the very thing in contention. You're just question-begging at this point. Do you think it was clear in the 1960s that anti-discrimination laws would be used to ban discrimination to transgender individuals, or that the 14th amendment would be used to protect same-sex marriages, or that the Due Process clause would be used to protect a woman's right to pregnancy? If so, what _makes_ the interpretation clear? And why is it so clear to you but not clear to other experts? How do you have this special epistemic access to the "obvious" interpretation of laws? And how do you know that future people in power also have this special epistemic access to the "obvious" interpretation? And how do you know that future people in power will rely on their special epistemic access to the "obvious" interpretation instead of abusing their power to further their idiosyncratic political agendas?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394348799.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>It's typically determined by the definitions given by the legislation in the relevant jurisdiction, as interpreted by judges. In that sense it isn't any different to other kinds of speech that are illegal, like defamation, or harrassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394416631.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>It is most certainly different. Defamation is incredibly strict on how it applies and one can use measurable factors to determine if the defamation claim is valid, such as negative articles written, profit lost, distinct actions taken against you spiking, and more. And harassment is also not close because it is a concerted effort to harass a specific individual over time and such an effort must be proven.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394500853.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>Defamation laws differ in some important ways depending on the jurisdiction, but since many of the examples given on this thread involve the UK, it's worth noting that in the UK the burden of proof in defamation cases rests with the defendent, so it isn't necessary to prove that you have been harmed except that the matter itself must be an imputation which is likely to lower the person in the estimation of right thinking people.

A very similar "reasonable person" standard often applies to incitement to hatred laws where the test concerns whether the material in question would be likely to incite hatred. So there's no obvious reason why one kind of law is any more difficult to interpret than the other.

As for harrassment, the point is simply that it is another example of a case where the law sets out a definition which is then interpreted by the relevant legal officials, and that can include taking account of whether a reasonable person would have felt that the behaviour in question constitutes harrassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394559503.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>Every regulation on speech needs to be grounded in provable intent and, for threats, must give concrete measures to show that it intended to be fulfilled, such as a specific place and time in addition to provable intent. 

These concrete restricts must be in place or else it all cascades into a blob of indirect potential nonsense. Such as “hate speech should be illegal because it might lead to the Holocaust.” If we’re restricting speech based on what might happen as a result, essentially everything can have that argument made for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394612851.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Every regulation on speech needs to be grounded in provable intent

I don't agree. That would mean, for example, that someone who incites violence through a reckless rather than malicious act would not be liable for it.

There are plenty of cases where the law can (and should) step in to restrict behaviour before harm occurs, if the behaviour in question tends to cause harm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394798223.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>I completely disagree. Only when there is concrete evidence that harm will be caused should the law step in. You’re giving overwhelming power to the law and government by enabling it to step in just because there is a vague possibility that harm might be caused.

That is why a threat must not only show intentionality but also plausible achievement to be capable of being prosecuted. For example, saying “I wish Trump would die” is not a threat, nor is “I wish someone would assassinate Trump.” Saying “I want to kill Trump” might draw some eyes and someone might look into it, but if you didn’t give any details nor have any means to do it, it’s still not going to be prosecuted. You need to be explicit in giving an exact time/place and also have the ability to carry it out, such as “I want to kill Trump at his upcoming rally in *X place* with my bomb/sniper.” while also having a bomb or a sniper that might be able to carry it out.

The same goes for reporting suicidal ideation of a hospital patient. A patient wishing for death is not enough to justify reporting him as a risk for suicide. The patient must confirm to you that he wishes to actively take his life and then you must still look to see if he has the means. If the dude is completely bedridden with no way of carrying it out, a suicide risk report is still not going to be filed in all likelihood. There has to be both intent and means. 

All of these requirements simply aren’t there for these propositions to limit hate speech, either with the definition of hate speech itself being nebulous or having the rationale for banning it grounded in some nebulous potential for eventual harm with nothing concrete backing it up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394844877.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>Inciting hatred is the harm in question, and it isn't particularly difficult to identify the kinds of behaviour that are likely to incite hatred (not behaviour that has a vague possibility of inciting hatred). It is as easy  to identify language that is likely to incite violence or other criminality, or language that a reasonable person would perceive as harrassment, or language that is likely to defame (or prima facie defamatory).

Intentionality shouldn't be a requirement for the reason I set out above, i.e. it excludes reckless behaviour, and we should not let people off the hook merely because they are reckless rather than malicious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394895399.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>Hatred is not harm. Hatred might eventually lead to harm depending on the person. That is highly indirect and non-concrete. Saying “this statement MIGHT cause *X emotion* which MIGHT lead to *X action*” is absolutely absurd to use as a framework for limiting speech since that logic can be used to ban essentially anything and everything. 

I disagree completely that it is “easy to identify language that is likely to lead to hatred.” Given what many groups or individual seem to think is hate speech, I don’t think practical experience supports that notion, either. And even then, how do you determine likelihood? The absolute vast majority of those who read a comment that could be considered “hate speech” are very likely not to become hateful of that group as a result of the comment. 

And once again, absolutely massively disagree about disregarding intentionality of speech. Any speech that is regulated must be intentional; that is a universal standard for all other limitations on speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394951762.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hatred is not harm. Hatred might eventually lead to harm depending on the person. That is highly indirect and non-concrete. Saying “this statement MIGHT cause X emotion which MIGHT lead to X action” is absolutely absurd to use as a framework for limiting speech since that logic can be used to ban essentially anything and everything. 

Being hated to the point that people are motivated to violate your rights because of how much they hate you is harmful. These laws didn't just appear in a vaccum. They were drawn up to apply to people with specific characteristics that have historically been (and to an extent still are) the basis of discrimination. We know that this discrimination would not have occurred in the absence of the kinds of attitudes that anti-hate speech laws are designed to deter. 

&amp;gt;I disagree completely that it is “easy to identify language that is likely to lead to hatred.” Given what many groups or individual seem to think is hate speech, I don’t think practical experience supports that notion, either. And even then, how do you determine likelihood?

The same way you determine whether one's behaviour is defamatory: if a reasonable person believed what was said, would it encourage them to hate the person/group in question?

&amp;gt;And once again, absolutely massively disagree about disregarding intentionality of speech. Any speech that is regulated must be intentional; that is a universal standard for all other limitations on speech.

Why should speech be unique among all other behaviour that we regulate such that it is the only kind of behaviour where recklessness isn't enough?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395012879.0" user="Assaltwaffle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;people are motivated to violate your rights

Prosecute this, then. Actual harm done. An actual hate crime which is concrete and provable. Simply having the potential to cause hate which might, if sufficient, eventually result in someone possibly committing a hate crime is a downright absurd non-standard of indirect potential causation which can be applied to anything. Speech against the government? That might cause hate of the government and potentially terrorism. Speech against a religion? That might one day cause you to hate the religion. Speech for a religion? Well that might convince people that you're objectively correct and, depending on the person and religion, might result in harm against someone of another religion. Ban general insults because it might lead to hate which might lead to violence. Ban rallies in generally since they might cause division and eventually violence.

You can keep going down the rabbit hole with this flimsy logic.

&amp;gt;We know that this discrimination would not have occurred in the absence of the kinds of attitudes that anti-hate speech laws are designed to deter.

You don't know this in any capacity. You assume it. But we do know how much speech is restricted by these laws and how many lives have been ruined despite the nebulous nature of such laws.

&amp;gt;would it encourage them to hate the person/group in question?

Given the hilariously broad range of nonsense which has been used against people in these laws thus far, I'm going to say that what these courts consider "a reasonable person" or "what would encourage hate" to not be held to the same level of scrutiny as defamation suits. Defamation and slander are restrictions that are highly scrutinized to the point that it is generally shocking when someone actually wins such a case.

&amp;gt;Why should speech be unique among all other behaviour that we regulate such that it is the only kind of behaviour where recklessness isn't enough?

Because speech is inherently indirect. It already goes through several levels of potential, "mights", and "maybes". Speech is also a right because the value of freedom of communication is so high and is given more protection than other actions. So it's more protected and is more indirect by a fair margin. It must be held to the highest form of scrutiny, strict scrutiny, which is a line that cannot be passed by hate speech without passing the threshold for another broken law.

Regardless, we're going basically in circles now. I think it's clear that no amount of essay content is going to change our minds, at least in the context of reddit and I don't want to spend more time arguing ad infinitum. I'm sorry we couldn't come to an agreement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395385726.0" user="MrMercurial" delta="False">
    <text>Sure - thanks for taking the time to engage. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395272895.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is not that it's possible to craft a precise interpretation of what "abusive" means. The issue is whether the interpretation crafted by legal authorities will be a good one. There are many different ways to interpret what counts as abusive, and not all interpretations are appropriate in this context. The question is, how do we know that legal authorities will use an appropriate interpretation?

Furthermore, what protection is there that this interpretation will not unacceptably broaden over time? Sure, maybe you could ban hate speech today based on some sufficiently narrow interpretation of "abuse". But nothing is stopping lawyers/judges from broadening their interpretation in the future. Interpretations of laws/policies change all the time as people with new ideas and political ideologies come into power.

For example, no one expected the Due Process cause of the 14th amendment to lead to gay marriage or Woe v Wade. Nor did anyone expect "anti-discrimination" laws to prohibit employer policies that resulted in "disparate impact" or discrimination based on "gender identity" or transgender status. Regardless of your opinion of these expansions, the point is that, whenever we make laws attempting to prohibit objectionable behavior, we put ourselves at the mercy of the discretion of future agents of power to use that law to advance their agenda. And there's no reason to expect that their agenda will be one that we want enforced by law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393674845.0" user="RebornGod" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Me saying I dont like a group of people

&amp;gt; abusive or threatening speech or writing that expresses prejudice against a particular group

Come again? It likely depends on the degree, but the continuous expression of prejudice depending on context might rise to the level of verbal abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395334130.0" user="azurensis" delta="False">
    <text>Why would that be illegal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396521905.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Me saying I dont like a group of people isnt hate speech.

how is this not you expressing prejudice against a group?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400475942.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt say it wasn't. Haste speech, and having negative thought/feelings are two different things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39404450997.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I didnt say it wasn't

yes you did. you said very specifically that you saying you don't like a group of people **isn't** hate speech, but expressing prejudice against a group of people esp for race **is**. so what is the difference? 

saying "i hate black/white/asian/whomever" is clearly a statement of prejudice,is it not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39410417327.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>A statement of prejudice isnt hate speech. Calling for harm toward the group you're are prejudice is. 

"I dont like (insert group) because of (whatever reasoning)"

Vs.

"(Insert group of people) are dangerous, and are infiltrating our society and something needs to be done." Or, "we will be happy again once we get rid of (insert group of people)." Or "(insert group of people) are not really people like you and me  and should be treated as such". 

And hate speech is not you chatting with your buddies, either. Its people using a platform to spread hate and entice action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39412491683.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>i see, you just don't know what [prejudice means](https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/prejudice#:~:text=1%20%3A%20a%20liking%20or%20dislike,damage%20to%20a%20person's%20rights).

&amp;gt;"(Insert group of people) are dangerous, and are infiltrating our society and something needs to be done." 

so in your mind this is hate speech because... why? 

&amp;gt;And hate speech is not you chatting with your buddies, either.

why not? are you not spreading the hate to your buddies? you have an aweful lot of strange qualifications for something that is supposedly so simple.

&amp;gt;Its people using a platform to spread hate and entice action.

how do you "entice" action? america has laws against inciting violence, but again it is pretty specifically [defined](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imminent_lawless_action#:~:text=The%20two%20legal%20prongs%20that,incite%20or%20produce%20such%20action.) and is definitely *not* what you are wanting.

also, you are back to "spread hate" as if that phrase has any meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39417194802.0" user="bolognahole" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; so in your mind this is hate speech because... why?

Its not about what is "in my mind" its about what fits the definition. Im not sure what your having trouble with here. There is a definition, some things will fit it, and others wont. 

&amp;gt;And hate speech is not you chatting with your buddies, either.
why not?

Same answer as my last. Doesnt fit the definition. 

&amp;gt;how do you "entice" action? 

Go watch Hitlers speeches

&amp;gt;not what you are wanting.

What do you think I *want*? Im describing current legal viewpoints. I have 0 "wants" in this conversation, so I have no idea what you're on about here. 

Anyway, I've said all there is to be said, and I'm repeating myself too much. Take care.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428713882.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>this is your exact phrase:

&amp;gt;Me saying I dont like a group of people isnt hate speech. But saying Im going to go Rambo on a bunch of them is.

this is after you gave a definition of hate speech:

&amp;gt;noun abusive or threatening **speech or writing that expresses prejudice against a particular group**, especially on the basis of race, religion, or sexual orientation.

i bolded a part so you won't miss it. then you said:

&amp;gt;Me saying I dont like a group of people isnt hate speech

so how is you expressing your prejudice against a group not hate speech when it clearly fits the definition of hate speech you just gave? if thta wasn't enough your next response starts:

&amp;gt;A statement of prejudice isnt hate speech

but again, the definiton you just gave specifically says that hate speech is a statement of prejudice. it even uses those words. those exact words. so wtf are you talking about?

&amp;gt;Same answer as my last. Doesnt fit the definition.

so hate speech can't exist when chatting with your buddies? why? nothing in your definition says anything about that.

&amp;gt;Go watch Hitlers speeches

i think the word your were meaning to use was "incite" but even still, that has a pretty specific legal meaning. 

even going along with your idea of hate speech, that is a totally different thing from illegal speech. call it hate speech if you want, but it is legal. 

&amp;gt;And hate speech is not you chatting with your buddies, either. Its people using a platform to spread hate and entice action.

you have changed your definition again. you are not describing any coherent view at all, much less a current legal viewpoint. if you were, the jails would be full of feminsts who say they hate men, progressives who say they hate men, white people, and religious people, republicans who say they hate foreigners, and politicians who hate everyone else.

&amp;gt;Anyway, I've said all there is to be said, and I'm repeating myself too much.

you've said a bunch of nonsense, and you are repeating yourself because none of it makes any sense or is based in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393874601.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's a slippery slope that we should stay away from.

So you're going to ignore all the countries that have very reasonable hate speech laws already?

And the fact that we already restrict forms of speech in the US?

Follow-up question: you know that slippery slope arguments are often fallacies, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394934622.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>No laws on speech are reasonable to anyone with decent morals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395622726.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>Tell me: are laws against death threats "immoral"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396408468.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Threats are just threats. Threats my lead to action, but the action is still the thing harming the other party, not the words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396444687.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>Well, good luck finding a "utopian" country without laws against death threats.

Some people will come up with all kinds of nonsense to defend their right to be a jerk, lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396989021.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>You indeed do have a right to be an asshole, as that isn't violating someone else's right to life, liberty, or property.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397231948.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You indeed do have a right to be an asshole

And yet, the vast majority of people clearly disagree with you.

Have fun being an asshole, though. I'm sure that'll bring you exactly what you deserve in life. lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398047809.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>People agreeing on something doesn't change the ethics or morality of it.

I don't condone racist, homophobic, sexist, etc speech, but I also know I don't have a right to use violence or have someone use violence for me to supress that speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398271883.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ethics or morality of it.

Sure. And you just saying that it's immoral is supposedly enough to convince me? 

&amp;gt; I don't have a right to use violence 

So words aren't violence but fines and jail time are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398375675.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>If you want to say you should act immorally then I don't know what to tell you mate.

And yes, words aren't violence but putting someone in a cage or holding the threat of jail or death to extort money from them is. That's pretty clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398647238.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you want to say you should act immorally then I don't know what to tell you mate.

You're begging the question, aka presenting your personal opinion as a fact, when it's the very thing that we're supposed to be debating.

I know *you* find it very convincing, but don't expect anyone else to.

&amp;gt; or death to extort money from them is

You have quite the flare for the dramatic, don't you? lol

Anyway, what I find immoral is defending people's right to be bigots and homophobes because it won't affect you all based on some slippery-slope pretense that isn't supported by any logic or reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398432885.0" user="ocjr" delta="False">
    <text>But ethics and morality and laws are a reflection of society and they have changed over time so yes to a certain extent if a majority of people say that it should be illegal to say the word “red” then in that society it would be ethical and moral to stop it. 

The whole reason we have these debates is because we don’t agree on the ethics or morality of every action. Heck we don’t all agree on whether killing a human is ethical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398469790.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Our disagreement doesn't change an actions morality. An action is either objectively moral, ammoral, or immoral. Us having two different opinions on it only makes one of us right and one wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398584169.0" user="ocjr" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but who decided what is moral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398593687.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>To me, God, but if you're not religious then take your pick as a constant law of the universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398606911.0" user="ocjr" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly though if someone doesn’t believe in god then you idea of morality and theirs are already different.

My point is that we live in a society and that means that laws and collective morality are determined by society, not necessarily a majority of society but a majority of society is certainly a good start.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395814434.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>neither is racism or homophobia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396397885.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>No one is saying they aren't. What we are saying is that you don't have a right to do an objectively more immoral thing (supress speech using violence.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397581309.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>racism is worse than not letting people be racist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398039258.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Someone saying racist shit is not worse than someone using violence on someone saying racist shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398398643.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>one is hatred for a valid reason (someone being racist) one isnt (skin color). youre falling for the tolerance of intolerance paradox</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398403558.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to be tolerant in that you accept their opinions as valid, but you do have to tolerate them by not using violence to suppress their rights to say stupid shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398411628.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>people shouldnt be allowed to say stupid shit and the cons of not being allowed are nowhere near the pros of people not having to hear it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398435610.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>You saying peoples rights should be stripped qualifies as stupid shit to me. Human rights violations would be a reasonable metric to use force on someone to most people.

You don't get to infringe on rights just because you feel it's beneficial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398498773.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>if the stupid shit you say hurts others rights than yes you should lose your right to say it. i dont "feel" its beneficial, it doesnt take a scientist to know saying racist shit isnt beneficial</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398556585.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Spoken words can't hurt someone. They can offend that person, but no actual harm is done. You want to cause tangible harm to someone for spoken words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398669885.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>you think racism isnt harmful?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399181126.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>In a way that violates your rights? No. Not any more so than any other form of mean language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39399267388.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>being racist shouldnt be a right. seems we just have different values</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395760817.0" user="wadakow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm aware of the slippery slope fallacy. But the argument applies logically here because my argument is that I don't trust anyone on either side of the political spectrum to have the power to decide what speech is legal and what speech is illegal. The gift of free speech, though it may be used in offensive ways by some, is one of the main things keeping new ideas flowing and tearing bad ideas down. Sure, bad people may be able to speak their bad ideas, but at least the law will protect the voices of those with good ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395787910.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>K, so you addressed one of my three points...the least important...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396499374.0" user="wadakow" delta="False">
    <text>I saw your third point as the most important since it most closely addresses my argument. You'll have to be more specific with your first point if you want to hear my opinion on a specific country. Same with your second point. I don't want to falsely assume the laws you're referring to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398665930.0" user="aabbccbb" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You'll have to be more specific with your first point 

I mean, given that you love the slippery slope argument, I would have thought you'd have had many, many examples from, well, [take your pick.](https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Hate_speech_laws_by_country)

You know, seeing as this is a horrible idea that can only lead to abuse, you must have many good examples of such abuse, given that so many countries have these laws, right?

If it's not just an empty argument meant to defend people's right to be bigots...

&amp;gt; Same with your second point.

You cannot threaten someone's life in the US. We already don't have free speech. Therefore, we're ripe for authoritarian overreach according to your stated beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394865895.0" user="Soleos" delta="False">
    <text>The slippery slope argument is fallacious here. There are many countries with well established hate-speech laws (and legal processes for defamation no less) that have not led to authoritarianism.
I'd compare the "slippery slope" you're pointing to with [Freedom to Roam](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_to_roam). You can argue it's importance as a freedom sure, but clearly minor laws that make things like jaywalking illegal would be a step on a slippery slope towards authoritarian restriction of people's movement. Clearly the state has power to define what are public and private spaces, where people should be able to roam etc, you even have more contentious control of which spaces in which people are allowed to protest in these countries. Yet, it's not something that has seriously led to authoritarianism any more than laws that criminalize public urination. And arguably, verbal harrassment and hate-speech cause a lot more harm than public urination.

I'd be much more worried about laws that limit women's freedom to access medical care, laws banning language that describe LGBTQ+ folks' very identities, and laws that restrict the movement of transfolk within freaking bathrooms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394938676.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Any laws on speech are authoritarian. You having a higher tolerance for the state's authoritarianism doesn't change what it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395397362.0" user="Soleos" delta="False">
    <text>Possibly. I think there's a really fruitful debate about whether it's true that any laws on freedom of opinion and expression are authoritarian, but I've got no energy at this moment. The debate may be similarly applied to any laws that violate the right to education or freedom from discrimination, right to life liberty and security of person, etc.

For me, my priority for curbing authoritarianism would be about laws on speech related to banning language related to LGBTQ+ identity over banning hate-speech. These laws have more justification as slippery slope as there's clear historical precedent re: discrimination and unequal protection under the law of minorities. Moreover, [laws related to the education system](https://www.cbsnews.com/news/ohio-lgbtq-legislation-dont-say-gay-education/) also violates the right to education. With these considerations, they seem much more of an authoritarian threat than banning language that perpetuates discrimination against and incitement of violence against LGBTQ+ (for example), which leads to [physical violence and death](https://www.hrc.org/resources/fatal-violence-against-the-transgender-and-gender-non-conforming-community-in-2021).

Certainly, it's not a zero-sum game and we can have an argument about hate-speech laws without detracting from the importance of other laws on speech, but for me, it seems a bit less pressing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39397658288.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>But there should be material effects should they not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398036527.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not following?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398054120.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>Authoritarianism, and other similar political philosophies should have some tangible negative effects. If they do not have any, one should wonder as to just how negative the particular implementation of authoritarianism is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398382904.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>The infringement of rights is the negative effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398577459.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but what are *material* effects? Its very nice and philosophical to say, but unless there are tangible benefits it doesnt seem to hold much weight.


If you have an authoritarian government that says "you cant talk bad about other peoples religion, and in return you get affordable healthcare, housing and consumer protections for all citizens" then a lot of people will take that deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398600009.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>The material effect of infringing someone's rights is that person losing either life, liberty, or property.

Utilitarianism is a flawed moral philosophy as any bad action can be justified provided it benefits enough other people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39398614152.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The material effect of infringing someone's rights is that person losing either life, liberty, or property.





Okay so in this case it would be liberty. How much liberty are they really giving up?



&amp;gt;Utilitarianism is a flawed moral philosophy as any bad action can be justified provided it benefits enough other people.


Sure, which is why ultilitarianism practically is limited by other political ideologies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396563790.0" user="wadakow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm aware of the slippery slope fallacy. But my argument applies logically here because my argument is that I don't trust anyone on either side of the political spectrum to have the power to decide what speech is legal and what speech is illegal. The gift of free speech, though it may be used in offensive ways by some, is one of the main things keeping new ideas flowing and tearing bad ideas down. Sure, bad people may be able to speak their bad ideas, but at least the law will protect the voices of those with good ideas. Your analogy is invalid. Someone jaywalking does not prevent the initiation or progression of a nation-altering idea. But put the power to ban speech in the wrong hands, and it can have a detrimental effect. Especially among minorities. For example, the 1st amendment is enabling the LGBTQ+ community to gain awareness. If the wrong group, even if it's the public, has the ability to ban the talk of ideas they didn't like, then the LGBTQ community probably would never have gotten a voice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393356645.0" user="NerozumimZivot" delta="False">
    <text>BBC this week: man avoids prison time for offensive tweet
https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-60930670</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393416277.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39409893411.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/EmperorDawn – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20EmperorDawn&amp;amp;message=EmperorDawn%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3htmj9/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393901562.0" user="Suffer_Like_G_Did_" delta="False">
    <text>Count Dankula, and yes, he was convicted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393921216.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394671355.0" user="Fatherknowstoomuch" delta="False">
    <text>https://youtu.be/iI2NpnjHIrE[here's a video](https://youtu.be/iI2NpnjHIrE) of a woman who was literally arrested for what she wrote in Facebook going against the mandated lockdowns of not being allowed to leave her home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39409887791.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394685701.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39409889852.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Fatherknowstoomuch – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Fatherknowstoomuch&amp;amp;message=Fatherknowstoomuch%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/twocko/-/i3iku11/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394968469.0" user="EatAssIsGross" delta="False">
    <text>That is evidence enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395116045.0" user="Plastic_Committee770" delta="False">
    <text>Nope he definitely got charged.

[article](https://www-newsweek-com.cdn.ampproject.org/v/s/www.newsweek.com/youtuber-count-dankula-avoids-jail-following-hate-crime-conviction-teaching-896831?amp=1&amp;amp;amp_gsa=1&amp;amp;amp_js_v=a9&amp;amp;usqp=mq331AQKKAFQArABIIACAw%3D%3D#amp_tf=From%20%251%24s&amp;amp;aoh=16491836131486&amp;amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com&amp;amp;ampshare=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsweek.com%2Fyoutuber-count-dankula-avoids-jail-following-hate-crime-conviction-teaching-896831)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395586040.0" user="Jk_rowling_fanboy" delta="False">
    <text>Why does the likelihood of imprisonment matter? The point is that there are laws that hinder speech in favour of a few people who might be offended</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395635492.0" user="pyr0phelia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Everything you just said I’ve never heard of so it doesn’t exist

You are the reason our society is fractured beyond repair right now. OP is 100% correct. Last arrest was a week ago and 2 weeks ago the largest fine for a tweet was levied for “insulting a dead politician”. When the band aide is finally ripped off there will be dire consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396418280.0" user="Gleapglop" delta="False">
    <text>https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/C-46/section-319.html

Additional info for you. This is the Canadian law against  public incitement of hatred, which they are arresting people for. If you take five minutes to read it in its entirety it should be very concerning to those living in a free and open society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396953519.0" user="Jesse0016" delta="False">
    <text>He was charged and did jail time if I recall</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396982307.0" user="Guilty_Assignment_25" delta="False">
    <text>Dankula actually went to jail for it. Iirc it was like a week, but still.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39460636281.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
