<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="116" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39398750709.0" user="keklwords" delta="False">
    <text>So here’s the issue with your argument. It doesn’t allow for exceptions. 

The ability to consider individual circumstances is the key to equal and earned results, especially when you bring legal systems into it. Legal systems almost universally claim to be based on examining intent and accountability. 

If we assume they are intended to be based on examining intent and accountability, then in order to achieve your objective we have to be able to consider the circumstances. If we can’t, then someone with ill intent might not be punished, while someone with good intent might end up being punished. And your stated objective is avoid unjust punishment based on speech. 

If we only avoid punishing good intent, and allow ill intent to go unpunished, it is necessarily unaccountable as a system. Because it doesn’t fairly distribute consequences. If we set up the system to be unaccountable, it encourages us to be unaccountable. 

Accountability is the reason to encourage your perspective. If you believe everyone, at the end of the day, is ultimately responsible for resolving unwanted speech on their own, that’s asking for accountability. From both sides. If you want people to be accountable, the systems that evaluate them need to be accountable. In order for the systems to be accountable, they have to be able to judge individual circumstance. And that means no absolute rules. 

If I can offer an alternative, we might be able to set a reasonable general rule that very few people would disagree with and allows for accountable assessment of individual cases. And this rule should include protections, as well as punishments.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
