<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391951945.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying something the govt doesn't like

We're already there, Edward Snowden and Chelsea Manning are good examples in the US, but Assange was arrested by UK police, and here in the uk specifically look at the scottish guy arrested for joking about soldiers, or in Australia look at David McBride, charged for exposing Australian war crimes, while the people who actually committed the war crimes face no punishment, you won't find a country where free speech genuinely exists

Also in terms of the UK I'd say the official secrets act is a bigger barrier to free speech than any of the laws against social media posts (between people being allowed to tweet racist jokes, and journalists being allowed to report on what the govt does, I'd say the second is more important) 


https://theconversation.com/official-secrets-act-uk-government-has-a-long-history-of-suppressing-journalism-to-hide-its-misdeeds-164893</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392559746.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I'd deffinately say that's more important but I'd not heard of it tbh. I know it's all fucked basically, I just wish people cared about it enough to be upset and angry rather than supportive when something like hate speach laws exist. I'm paranoid but ik it's not just me worried by the hate speach laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392654756.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>Edward Snowden leaked confidential information. There isn’t a government in the world that won’t arrest you for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392821740.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>You're right but that's kind of my point, op is arguing its a slippery slope to not being able to say something the govt doesn't like, but you already can't</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393027449.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>You can actually publish confidential information as long as you had no hand in actually leaking said information. You’ll note that the papers that printed Snowdens info weren’t prosecuted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393276498.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not aware with US law in fairness, but in a UK context I think it would still apply

&amp;gt;Members of the public are bound by the Official Secrets Act; it is not 
necessary for them to have signed it. Under Section 5, if a member of 
the public (or any person who is not a Crown Servant or government 
contractor) has in their possession official information in any of the six 
categories, and this information has:
• been disclosed to them by a Crown Servant without lawful 
authority; or
• was entrusted to them by a Crown Servant in confidence
then it is an offence to disclose this information without lawful 
authority.14
It is also an offence to make a “damaging” disclosure of information 
relating to security or intelligence, defence or international relations if 
this has been:
• communicated in confidence to another State or international 
organisation; and
• the information has come into the person’s possession without 
the authority of that State or organisation.

A journalist presumably is still a member of the public

Edit, the BBC is state media so I doubt they'd get the law wrong, and they say

&amp;gt;Anyone - including journalists - can be prosecuted for publishing leaked information covered by the legislation

www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-57998950</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393717207.0" user="Scienter17" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a significant difference between the US and UK then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393750975.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, I added some US examples because they're more publicised (perhaps even *because* journalists have protections there)

But I still think UK law fits here because op is from the UK</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393471237.0" user="OmNomDeBonBon" delta="False">
    <text>Assange was arrested because of a credible accusation of a rape in Sweden, then skipped bail and hid in the Ecuadorian embassy to avoid being extradited to Sweden. His excuse? "Sweden would extradite me to the US!"

Note #1: Sweden does not extradite anybody to the US for political crimes.

Note #2: the UK does extradite people to the US for political crimes.

Assange was swanning about in the UK without a care in the world. He was never afraid of being extradited to the US. He was just desperate to avoid justice for the alleged rape.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393533396.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>Still leaves Chelsea Manning, and I'm sure there are other less publicised cases

And Assange is still considered a criminal by the US govt for wikileaks regardless of the rape</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396109004.0" user="ieilael" delta="False">
    <text>We've already passed the place where the president can order a drone strike to assassinate you, along with separate attacks for your children, because they don't like what you're saying.  Look up Anwar al-Awlaki.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39396124459.0" user="dahuoshan" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't surprise me in fairness but thanks for the info

The 1985 MOVE bombing is another example I suppose</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
