<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39392811131.0" user="BillyTheHenFucker" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of speech can be used to limit other people's freedom of speech, both sides understand this. 

If there are a bunch of racists in front of town hall expressing their opinions, they are exercising their freedom of speech, but this will have the effect of basically preventing non-white people from going to the town hall and expressing *their* opinions. 

The idea of restricting some free speech in order to have more overall is not really controversial, I see plenty of people on the right talking about social media companies being regulated so they can't just ban anyone. This is a violation of the platforms free speech in order to give more people access to freedom of speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393115933.0" user="SwiftAngel" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;preventing non-white people from going to the town hall and expressing their opinions

How?

And why do you automatically assume "racists" are white?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393595547.0" user="BillyTheHenFucker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And why do you automatically assume "racists" are white?

I live in a majority white western country, and when people say "racism" they generally default to thinking of anti-POC racism, most of who would be white. The same example works the other way around though. 

&amp;gt; How?

Because black people generally don't want to be around a bunch of people shouting "kick out all the *n-words*" or ranting about them raping white women. People feel (understandably) unsafe around people who appear to hate and want rid of them based on some innate characteristic. Not only can it be physically dangerous, but it also sends a message that "your kind are not welcome here", which has the end result of decent bits of society not feeling like they are allowed to exercise their freedom of speech, even if there are no laws against it. 

The reasons don't really matter, obviously this would limit the extent to which black people wanted to participate in that community, the point I'm making is that free speech doesn't exist in some vacuum, and a society with "absolute free speech" would actually contain less exercising of free speech than a society with some restrictions on it. (which everyone accepts to some extent as we have anti-harassment laws and slander laws)

Also none of this is to say I want laws preventing racists from protesting. I think "free speech restricting laws" should probably be kept to really obvious stuff (slander, harassment, yelling fire, doxing, threats/calls to action etc). And then other measures can be put in place to prevent situations like the one we are discussing here (some kindof right for multiple groups to occupy the same area when protesting or just increased police).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
