<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391851027.0" user="jake_burger" delta="False">
    <text>I used to think along the same lines as you: that saying hurtful things should not be taken that seriously and people should be allowed to say anything they want.

Then I gained some more life experience and saw that people listen to what others say and are deeply affected by it. Some can be bullied to suicide, out of jobs or just to despair. Some people can use jokes and rhetoric to gradually convince others that a particular group are sub human and this leads to persecution, civil war and genocide. 

Hurtful, racist/sexist etc comments, jokes, terms and opinions are often founded in ignorance or just plain lies, not fact, so are just propaganda - essentially the same as defamation against a group. While the individual person telling a racist joke might be unaware, the person who wrote that joke may well intend to subtly influence and encourage more racism in the world, and use the joke teller as a tool to spread more hate. We should also be suspicious of the use of jokes, as the fact that they can be walked back or dismissed as just a joke seems to me to be a rhetorical weaponisation to hide behind to avoid criticism. 

I feel now that while most freedom of speech is very important, hateful, hurtful pejorative language serves no good in the world and I support it’s suppression. We can still have “free speech” (not that I’m aware of anywhere where there is 100% free speech) while limiting the most harmful aspects.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
