<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39393167121.0" user="justahominid" delta="False">
    <text>Disclaimer, I'm American and thus don't have much knowledge about the state of Scottish freedom of speech laws. Nevertheless, my comments here are applicable.

The question is not whether or not we should have freedom of speech. That's undeniable, we should. Rather, the question is one of line drawing and determining what speech is or is not protected and what speech can or should be criminalized. Because it's just as true that we should have freedom of speech as it is that that freedom has limits and certain types of speech are going to exceed that scope and justify criminal charges.

Words have power. They have the potential to be incredibly destructive. One should not be free from punishment simply because they did not act if their words incite others into violent or harmful behaviors. As an easy example, the mob boss should not be off the hook for someone's death if he told his number two to go kill that person.

But there are also harder lines to define. Should someone not be punished if they, solely through words, hone in on someone's vulnerabilities and constantly attack them in order to cause that person to harm or kill themself? As we learn more about and become more sensitive towards mental health, shouldn't there be some recognition of the fact that the harm one can cause by words can be even greater than the harm one might cause with their fists? And if so, why should there be criminal liability for punching someone in the face but not viciously attacking them through words?

Of course there is going to be a point that is too far. Certain types of speech should absolutely be protected as a fundamental liberty, but that doesn't mean that there shouldn't be a line of speech that is subject to criminal penalties.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
