<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="118" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39399118153.0" user="Calm_Worldliness8442" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think jumping from “don’t be a racist” to don’t insult a party” is a bit much.

In less than 25 years, the American government (and several other NATO govt’s) went from having to actually wage war on foreign powers and having to get a warrant to spy on a free citizen, to doing those things illegally, and then getting *a codified law* in a moment of National weakness that says they can kidnap indefinitely, assassinate, and torture anyone they want as long as they’ve decided they have some spurious link to “terrorism”, which is basically a fucking fictional concept.  They did this when we were scared of “terrorists”.  Joe Biden announced early in year one that he intends to “use the full force of the measures of the PATRIOT act” to fight “terrorism” at home (specifically about the Jan 6th clowns).  

The idea that the government (mine at least) wouldn’t make a jump from hate speech being defined as person to person, to person to party, is staggeringly naive.

&amp;gt; By your Logic, what do we do about hate groups?

Absolutely nothing.  You know how many people ‘hate groups’ kill a year stateside?  About none statistically.  You know how many people the American military has killed, tortured, kidnapped, drone strikes without due process and how many civilians they’ve killed in bullshit wars because we ceded all power to them like infants?  

People constantly underestimate the consequences of ceding power by laws, and it’s tiring seeing people talk about the slippery slope like it’s impossible.  Homie, we’re at the bottom of the slippery slope.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
