<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="109" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39397968384.0" user="JordanLeDoux" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be very much against violence, but also seem to hold the opinion that speech, no matter what the content of the speech is, cannot be "violence".

So I suppose what I would say is, have you ever had to deal with or know anyone who has had to deal with severe mental issues? PTSD, severe depression, manic depression, suicidal ideation, etc.?

We know from decades of study that it is entirely possible to cause or exacerbate these issues in people with the right speech in the right conditions. Do the people who suffer these issues that affect every moment of their lives, sometimes for the *rest* of their lives, not experience that speech as violence?

I'm not saying that all "hurt feelings" and "mean things" should be regulated. I'm not even saying that *any* of them should. But if you are basing your position on the idea that speech *isn't* violence, I can only assume that you have lived a very sheltered and/or privileged life. If that's the case, it will be difficult to convey to you why I think you are wrong, because I cannot say things which will give you that learned experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400211304.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>I have severe depression, severe anxiety and ptsd, I've not lived a sheltered life and had an attempt to end my life. I do know they can hurt but I guess I'm more scared of the outcomes of the government controlling speech. A lot of how I cope with what happened to me is I make jokes about it or others jokes about similar things can sort of help me with it weirdly. And they arent exactly the lightest joke topics. 

I also feel there are loads of ways to keep these people out of your life. Like you can block certain words on Twitter I'm sure and you can block people aswell, in person is a bit more confusing I guess but they would still have to hear people dindt like trans people or didnt like x people often as it doesnt stop protests or news rn. Idk how much it really protects people ig.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39400332816.0" user="JordanLeDoux" delta="False">
    <text>There are loads of ways to help people that have been punched in the face too.

There's bandaids, topical analgesics, neosporin, ice, stitches... it doesn't make it less violent. Like I said, this isn't a slam dunk argument *for* regulation of speech, but it *is* a complete rejection of the idea that speech isn't violence. It is. It is a reasonable position for someone to take that some violence is more acceptable/necessary/palatable than others, but your position is just as arbitrary as anyone else's. It's not based on universal principal. Good news though, basically everyone else is in the same boat as you, so that's not really an argument that you're wrong.

But, it's important that you don't come from the position of "I have principles for what I believe and other people don't", because that's simply not true *and* it makes it basically impossible to have productive discussion.

But, since you *do* have the lived experience to understand the point I'm making, it's basically this: something isn't less violent because it is less visible. Violence is related to the amount of suffering caused to someone through actions, not to the visible or physical remnants of the act. For instance, someone who is into BDSM may enjoy getting slapped in the face with a partner they trust. That would not mean that a stranger walking up to them and slapping them in the face in public would be non-violent though. The same act can be violent or not depending on the amount of suffering it causes in the person who receives the action.

The reality is that violence is not something that can *only* be defined by the person committing the act. It also includes the person who experiences the act and this necessarily means that what is violent is fluid and contextual.

Something being fluid and contextual is usually a *good* argument for avoiding general rules, like the kinds that governments make. But that means that violent speech will have a spectrum just like violent acts.

Clapping someone on the back is often not perceived as violent but it could be if it was hard enough, while slashing with a knife is virtually always seen as violent. Similarly, speech that is framed as comedy is not often perceived as violent but it could be if it was particularly vicious and personal, while speech that advocates for genocide is virtually always seen as violent.

Some speech should be regulated for the same reason that some assault is regulated.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
