<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="74" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39394511109.0" user="Liamtheshades" delta="False">
    <text>I am also from Scotland and I wouldn’t worry to much, most of the stories you would read are normally exaggerated just said in a way to make all the gammons outraged 

They will make it out as if “ person A was arrested for calling a person B a racial/religious/gender slur” 

Then when you really look at it the person A was terrorising person B for ages and was harassing them and threatening them continually 

I don’t trust the  government with making certain laws about freedom of speech as it can be hard to really nail down what the law counts for (most of the examples people have gave don’t really make sense).
I was effected by the offensive behaviour at football act before it was repealed and have friends who were terrorised by the police back then for nothing mostly just being suspected of signing a song but today I f you were to call me a one of “ slur” there’s no much chance of you getting convicted of anything 

For example I think I should be able to say “ fuck up you Tory cunt” but would hate to think I would get flung in with the rascist / homophobic arseholes 

But if I said “ I’m going to stab you ya Tory cunt” that’s a different story as it becomes a threat</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
