<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="69" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39394437172.0" user="eliechallita" delta="False">
    <text>In general I would agree with you, but you're reducing all harmful speech to "a few people being offended" when there are much worse situations than that.

For example, someone shouldn't be arrested for lobbing insults or even slurs at another person. There should certainly be social consequences, but not legal ones.

However speech doesn't consist solely of insults. There are a few categories where I think a legal response is justified, such as:

* Overt threats against someone: Those should be taken seriously, since the person was apparently committed enough to make them in public.
* Calls for violence by a third party: Such as directing said party to harm someone, like saying "The KKK needs to lynch X". This is especially harmful if they include information that can make said harm easier to inflict, like the person's home address or workplace.
* Doxxing a non-public figure, since most private citizens have an expectation of privacy. Especially when combined with the previous one.
* Slander or libel: And I would extend this one beyond the usual "person X has done Y" to more generalized calls against vulnerable groups. One example is the propensity of anti-LGBT activists to call all LGBT people groomers or sexual predators. That is not a lightly made statement: It builds on decades of institutional violence against these categories, which often does result in real harm. That kind of misinformation feeds directly into calls for violence and shouldn't be treated separately from them.

So while I agree with you that most speech should not carry legal consequences, **some** speech really should. However most countries are very lax with addressing even that kind of speech, so I'm not sure what problem you're objecting to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
