<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1808402856.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/twocko/cmv_fredom_of_speech_is_far_more_important_than_a/">
    <title>CMV: Fredom of speech is far more important than a few people being offended</title>
    <original_poster>brbrWh0r3</original_poster>
    <original_post>Freedom of speech should be protected and kept, there shouldn't be people arrested for anti trans comments or insulting a soldier/soldiers, or for nazi jokes, or racist remarks or jokes.

Those should all be handled between people, if someone says stuff you dont like you handle it, simply block them or avoid them, theres a whole world you can be in and that persons in a very tiny part of it. 

It makes me nervous seeing people arrested and charged for saying things. It's only leading us to a place where we can be arrested for saying whatever the government doesnt like. And they shouldn't be in that much power to effect our communication with eachother. 

I live in scotland and dont feel I have freedom of speech anymore. 

(For the record I'm a white woman who's bi and have trans thoughts ig for those folks who say it never has been about me, it has sometimes, and in more ways than just those)

Edit: No it's not just anti trans people, Yes I believe crimes other than hate crimes involving speech should be illegal (threatening violence, doxing, defamation) but I also believe insults, jokes and bad takes or thoughts should not be.

Edit 2: Consequences for what is said like losing a job, getting insulted, losing friends ect is totally fine I just dont think the Government should be in charge of what can get you arrested in this sence.

Edit 3: I live in SCOTLAND in the UNITED KINGDOM or in BRITAIN depending what you say, I'm not american, im also not here advocating for my right to be a dick, im just saying the government arent the ones I want saying what I cant say, I mean twitter can destroy lives without them anyway.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39391354074.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>If you are such an advocate for Freedom of Speech, then surely you won't mind if somebody doxxes you, including your bank information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391385681.0" user="brbrWh0r3" delta="False">
    <text>That again isnt the same thing. This is insults, dislike of groups, racism ect. 

Puting people in danger or threatening to should be illegal, but insults, jokes and just bad takes shouldn't be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391838850.0" user="daddylongshlong123" delta="False">
    <text>Where do you draw the line between threats and insults/jokes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39393045587.0" user="eloel-" delta="False">
    <text>Wherever they want</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392203932.0" user="EnzoYug" delta="False">
    <text>There's a concept called non-physical violence.
It's possible to injury, or disadvantage someone, or to create distress and emotional damage through words alone.

Now let's say that someone calls a white woman "a Karen" that's a negative term that could affect her ability to make friends, to land a job, to be accepted in social situations.

Wouldn't you say this harms her?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392469231.0" user="captchasaysimhuman" delta="False">
    <text>Not as much as society would be harmed by the precedent set by police arresting someone for calling someone a Karen. Tiktok would be devoid of users within a week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391404856.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>If you are such an advocate against freedom of speech, surely you won't mind being arrested for what looks to me like a credible 'threat' to dox a person?  Will you be turning yourself in for this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391936714.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>How would I doxx you from a single Reddit post, you dumb cluck?

To be fair, I suppose I should have added a "/s" for the idiots of the site.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39392346294.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>So you think you have access only to 1 post?   Are you sure you should be even taking about doxing in any capacity if that's what you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39394864561.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>Relax, brother.

I was pointing out to the OP a truly major flaw in his reasoning.

Freedom of Speech has its flaws as a theory. I could point out many other issues, such as slander, or mental cruelty to a spouse, or even treason. (Theoretically, one could get around treason laws by using the spoken word to give information to an enemy.)

And no, I have no special desire to hand over nuclear secrets to the Commies. Jeez.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395422115.0" user="Soundch4ser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I was pointing out to the OP a truly major flaw in his reasoning.

I wonder if you even read and understand OP's reasoning at all, considering you missed the bit where she's a woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395444365.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>Most people--we Americans are the worst--have an absolutist view of Freedom of Speech. I submit to you that it was never meant to be absolute, and in fact an absolutist view of that right is a bad idea to an extreme, for all of the reasons I have laid out to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395440809.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>Lol... you come in calling people names... and I respond, and I need to relax?  

I appreciate the irony.

Btw, we're grown ups, we can say "dumb fuck" instead of some silly childish fake 'cluck' work around.  Which also is ironic considering the topic at hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395449766.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you do.

You accused me of plotting a crime.

That's hysteria.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395497622.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>Were you plotting a crime?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395580144.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, of *course* not, you silly goose. I didn't even know she was a woman.

Good God man, you're not stupid. Use your head. I was pointing out to her a *very real scenario* where Freedom of Speech could ruin her life.

Goodness Gracious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395596917.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>It's almost as if *that was my entire point from the very start*.  Maybe you missed that when you were responding with just random name calling?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39395745310.0" user="jeremyxt" delta="False">
    <text>You implied that I was planning a crime with your first post.

Maybe that post was meant as sarcasm. It's hard to tell over the Internet.

For my own part, the simple truth is that I was supplying to the OP a real-world example, in terms of a threat that she could relate to, why unbridled Freedom of Speech is an exceedingly bad idea.

I do think we have begun to beat a dead horse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39391777403.0" user="MilitantTeenGoth" delta="False">
    <text>That's a whole different crime. You can say whatever you want, but you also cannot put other people in danger.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
