<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1813912970.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tzyg7e/cmv_homosexuality_is_not_natural_and_neither_is/">
    <title>CMV: Homosexuality is not natural and neither is heterosexuality</title>
    <original_poster>Much_Society_6170</original_poster>
    <original_post>Homosexuality is not natural, and neither is heterosexuality

There is no such thing as attraction in other mammal species, just the male raping the female and reproducing. 

Attraction in humans is a social construct. It's a way to soothe people or to bond similar to how bonobos do it.

Because us humans have “the instinctive need to produce offspring,” the sheer fact that men want to have PiV sex with women just for fun or without wanting kids, proves it's not a natural attraction.

Plus, most women don't care about being penetrated. It doesn't feel good for us, clitoral stimulation is a need for most. PiV sex has no purpose outside of getting pregnant. Sexual relationships are not necessary at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39427677145.0" user="lt_Matthew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; juts the male raping the female and reproducing

That's heterosexual, number one. Two, only some animals do that. Most animals have family dynamics and even lifetime partners. They most definitely are capable of attraction, they literally have ways to do it too. Like dances, colors, special calls, etc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427713814.0" user="Much_Society_6170" delta="False">
    <text>I mean heterosexual *Attraction* isnt natural. Those animals arent attracted, just want to reproduce.


Obviously family dynamics are natural. And those calls are more like luring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427721759.0" user="College_advice12" delta="False">
    <text>What part of hetrosexual attraction is unnatural?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427742358.0" user="Much_Society_6170" delta="False">
    <text>I said it in my reply before this and post .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427753732.0" user="College_advice12" delta="False">
    <text>It still isn't clear to me.

What exactly are you using to differentiate the two here?

Do you hold one to be unnatural because it is done for no reason other than the fun of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427768846.0" user="Much_Society_6170" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Attraction is fake and sex for fun isnt natural. Im not saying its a bad thing. It just isnt natural either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427898176.0" user="lt_Matthew" delta="False">
    <text>You're combining sex and attraction. If we were juts supposed to all be mindlessly reproducing, emotions wouldn't be a thing at all. Whether or not your view is evolution or creation based, in either case, we wouldn't have emotions if we didn't need them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428115448.0" user="AlwaysTheNoob" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes. Attraction is fake and sex for fun isnt natural.

This is 100% objectively false.  Please watch any number of documentaries on the animal kingdom.  Look at mating rituals.  Look at what males will do to attract mates.  Look at what females will engage with instead of ignoring.  Attraction is absolutely, positively real in the animal kingdom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427758597.0" user="lt_Matthew" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you know how attraction works.... There's a specific chemical ik the brain that is only for romantic attraction</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427774562.0" user="Much_Society_6170" delta="False">
    <text>Isnt that just dopamine? Just being happy when you’re near someone you enjoy being with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39427802092.0" user="lt_Matthew" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there that, there also serotonin, the stronger versions, and oxytocin, a pleasure chemical.

Emotions are natural, and biologically controlled, because saying attraction isn't, means you also have to say depression isn't either. Heartbreak is a physiological thing that actually kills some animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428266239.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Those animals arent attracted, just want to reproduce.

Wait, how do you know? Like, how can that even be a knowable thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39430911319.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>How do you suppose reproduction even works if there is no attraction? How does the male become aroused enough to perform the sexual act, if he isn't attracted to the female?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39431224503.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>If an animal is choosy about their mates (turning down/avoiding mates in favor of someone else), would you consider that "attraction" to the the animals they do choose to reproduce with?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
