<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1813912970.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tzyg7e/cmv_homosexuality_is_not_natural_and_neither_is/">
    <title>CMV: Homosexuality is not natural and neither is heterosexuality</title>
    <original_poster>Much_Society_6170</original_poster>
    <original_post>Homosexuality is not natural, and neither is heterosexuality

There is no such thing as attraction in other mammal species, just the male raping the female and reproducing. 

Attraction in humans is a social construct. It's a way to soothe people or to bond similar to how bonobos do it.

Because us humans have “the instinctive need to produce offspring,” the sheer fact that men want to have PiV sex with women just for fun or without wanting kids, proves it's not a natural attraction.

Plus, most women don't care about being penetrated. It doesn't feel good for us, clitoral stimulation is a need for most. PiV sex has no purpose outside of getting pregnant. Sexual relationships are not necessary at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39434642675.0" user="LetMeNotHear" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There is no such thing as attraction in other mammal species, just the male raping the female and reproducing.

Incorrect on many ways.

If it were all male on female rape (which it isn't, but still) why would that happen? Male attraction to the female. Heterosexual attraction.

Moving back a step, it's not all male on female rape in amongst Mammalia. There are many instances of female on male rape, as well as mutual courtship. The motivations for both, being... attraction.

&amp;gt;Attraction in humans is a social construct. It's a way to soothe people or to bond similar to how bonobos do it.

It most certainly is not. It may fill other roles but attraction exits originally to propagate genes. If an animal that is only physiologically capable of reproducing through the act of sex, then desire for the act of sex (or sexual attraction for shorthand) is selected for.

&amp;gt;Because us humans have “the instinctive need to produce offspring,” the sheer fact that men want to have PiV sex with women just for fun or without wanting kids, proves it's not a natural attraction.

This is a misunderstanding of how evolution works. Evolution is not a conscious process. It is not a thinking feeling being atop Mount Olympus. For example, humans feel fear and the reason is evolution. Those that felt a desire to flee when presented with a threatening entity (fear, for short) survived longer and passed that on. However, humans today often expose themselves to things that illicit fear (skydiving, abseiling, bungee jumping, haunted houses, horror movies, etc) without fleeing. That does not prove that fear is not natural or that its purpose isn't to make us flee danger. It just proves that we have gamed the system.

&amp;gt;Plus, most women don't care about being penetrated. It doesn't feel good for us, clitoral stimulation is a need for most.

Citation please? I know that clitoral stimulation is a major plus, but "women don't care about being penetrated"? Your use of the word "us" makes me feel like you've extrapolated your own personal feelings to half of your species.

&amp;gt;Sexual relationships are not necessary at all.

True, but we aren't discussing what's necessary, we were discussing what's natural.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
