<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1813912970.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tzyg7e/cmv_homosexuality_is_not_natural_and_neither_is/">
    <title>CMV: Homosexuality is not natural and neither is heterosexuality</title>
    <original_poster>Much_Society_6170</original_poster>
    <original_post>Homosexuality is not natural, and neither is heterosexuality

There is no such thing as attraction in other mammal species, just the male raping the female and reproducing. 

Attraction in humans is a social construct. It's a way to soothe people or to bond similar to how bonobos do it.

Because us humans have “the instinctive need to produce offspring,” the sheer fact that men want to have PiV sex with women just for fun or without wanting kids, proves it's not a natural attraction.

Plus, most women don't care about being penetrated. It doesn't feel good for us, clitoral stimulation is a need for most. PiV sex has no purpose outside of getting pregnant. Sexual relationships are not necessary at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39428365655.0" user="Sagasujin" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a lesbian. How exactly does that work in your worldview? Society spent years trying to convince me that I was straight and should be interested in men. There's a lot of social pressure for me to go along with men who want to date me. I still want to date women. I'm still uninterested in dating men. I still want to have sex with women. My desire to fuck women has absolutely nothing to do with reproduction because that's an impossibility. I just want to feel pleasure and make another woman feel pleasure. How do I know exist when all social forces are pushing me not to be who I am? How can I experience attraction when I was raised to be attracted to an entirely different group?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428466046.0" user="Much_Society_6170" delta="False">
    <text>I am a woman attracted to women too. Though asexual. I believe no attraction is natural whether its m/f attraction or gay ones. We evolved into this fake attraction because we are complex peoples. But it was not natural.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39428701355.0" user="Sagasujin" delta="False">
    <text>If I experience attraction, then how is it fake? It's not something cultural because our society was definitely not pushing me to want a girlfriend.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
