<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1813912970.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/tzyg7e/cmv_homosexuality_is_not_natural_and_neither_is/">
    <title>CMV: Homosexuality is not natural and neither is heterosexuality</title>
    <original_poster>Much_Society_6170</original_poster>
    <original_post>Homosexuality is not natural, and neither is heterosexuality

There is no such thing as attraction in other mammal species, just the male raping the female and reproducing. 

Attraction in humans is a social construct. It's a way to soothe people or to bond similar to how bonobos do it.

Because us humans have “the instinctive need to produce offspring,” the sheer fact that men want to have PiV sex with women just for fun or without wanting kids, proves it's not a natural attraction.

Plus, most women don't care about being penetrated. It doesn't feel good for us, clitoral stimulation is a need for most. PiV sex has no purpose outside of getting pregnant. Sexual relationships are not necessary at all.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39430092276.0" user="Alejandre-the-Great" delta="False">
    <text>Sexualities and *varieties* of sexual relationships can be social constructs without the *need* for a sexual relationship being a construct. That not everyone has sex, or wants to have it, does not mean sex is not a need; rather, for some folks it is either an *unfulfilled* or an *unexpressed* need. The basis for sexual *attraction* to other individuals is the *need* for sex, not the availability of either sexualities or varieties of relationship available in a given society: the latter, on the contrary, have to do with how and towards whom attraction is *expressed,* not with its basis. 

So, heterosexuality and homosexuality are not "natural," but for different reasons than the one's you've given. Namely, who we decide is an appropriate object of our sexual attraction (same or different sex, etc.) and how we express that attraction is a social construct, but attraction *itself* is not. 

FWIW: mammals *do* experience attraction, except we don't usually call it that. Rather, males and females of the same species will aim to find a mate that maximizes the ability of their potential offspring to survive, and they do so by assessing whether or not their potential partner has the right characteristics (e.g., shiny coat, tasty pee, etc.) We do something similar, except, for us, what we regard as "attractive," is also influenced by social norms and attitudes in a given time and place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39430693035.0" user="chimp246" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with what you're saying but this reads as jiberish</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
