<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="181959121.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/30c0k1/cmv_celebrity_amas_are_ruined_by_victoria_from/">
    <title>CMV: Celebrity AMAs are ruined by Victoria from Reddit</title>
    <original_poster>ithinkimtim</original_poster>
    <original_post>**EDIT: [Please read this from the /r/IAmA  mods](http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/30ea3g/mod_post_riama_misconceptions/)**

----

I have no problem with Victoria herself, just the concept of "Victoria from reddit is here helping me out".

To me the entire point of an AMA is having someone of note interact
with this unpredictable medium.  Ask Me **Anything**.  It's fun and interesting to see them negotiate the comments, with the potential for them to be reading the most bizarre and funny points of view, with strange interactions on lower voted comments as well as random replies to far reaching child-comments.

Victoria from Reddit turns the medium into yet another "send in your questions and we'll pick the best to ask this person who is so much better than you".  Instead of interacting directly with someone, there's a filter.  A filter who types the same way in every AMA, using *italics* and -laughs- and -umms- which completely takes away from it for me.

Here Victoria says that the Woody Harelson AMA would have turned out differently:  https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2fgsv2/i_am_victoria_from_reddit_amaa/ck91rpw  Which shows that comments are being filtered.  That is what made AMAs so great, it's a celeb being talked to directly, and this is more often POSITIVE rather than that negative example.

In essence I think Victoria turns it into a basic interview with fan questions that has been done a million times before.  If a brand wants to promote via AMA, jump in and get dirty.   I don't even read AMAs anymore if it's got Victoria doing the typing.

If there's a better way of looking at this , please CMV, I want to enjoy AMAs again without the frustration.

-----
Reason for view change:

I still dislike AMAs with Victoria, and am clearly not the only one.  This comes from Victoria creating a difference between the celebs and us average Joes.  Of course this isn't always the case.  As it turns out, Victoria will help anyone that fits in her schedule.  So in reality it is just some AMAs (Ludacris as a recent example) that may turn out far more interesting if they had to navigate the website themselves in exchange for publicity.

With a few people commenting with first hand experience, I've decided that because the benefits of Victoria are more heavily weighted by the majority, my post title view has been changed.  Even if I'm stuck hating the AMAs, Victoria doesn't "ruin" them.

Thanks for all the replies!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your overlords. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes always change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please [don't](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)**. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27678437789.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>I believe Victoria mentioned in her own AMA that some celebrities want to answer questions themselves and the ones who do generally get tired after a short period of time because of how many questions are asked at once and how many responses each comment from the celebrity gets, so when she types it allows for more questions to be answered as she is used to typing quickly and answering questions as fast as possible. I also believe she said that she filters both by best/top and by new while your average celebrity who may never have used reddit before may not know how to do this, so they may only answer questions with the most upvotes instead of those and new questions. I think these things enhance celebrity AMAs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678502267.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>I think this would change my view if I knew how often the celebrities were actually present.  I'm pretty sure a lot are over the phone, which is a big part of my problem. If they're over Victoria's shoulder and Victoria is showing them things like sorting by new then you're right it's an enhancement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678540583.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>What difference would it make if they're on the phone or there in person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678553884.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>Engaging more directly with the platform vs. hearing an editorialised selection of questions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678560681.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>The celebrity still picks and chooses what questions to answer and what questions to ignore if they are in complete control over the AMA, so while they may be "engaging more directly with the platform", the entire AMA is still editorialized based on which questions the celebrity chooses to answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678567347.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>Of course but the potential for them to answer something more off beat or engage a troll in a funny way is there. 

The old "duck sized horse" as much as people hated it was a good gauge of how an AMA was going to play out.

Now it's just generic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678570196.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>If celebrities encountered more trolls during AMAs then there would ultimately be fewer celebrities who would do AMAs because of potential trolls.

Aside from that, what makes you think that a celebrity is actually answering questions if they aren't getting help from Victoria as opposed to their publicist, social media coordinator, agent, or someone else on their staff?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678623308.0" user="Nycamm" delta="False">
    <text>I think this may be the best answer. Whether or not Victoria's presence results in bias towards certain questions and away from others (and whether or not that bias is good for Ama's, like selecting from new AND top comments; or bad, like avoiding risque questions), having someone who understands the community means more celebrities have better experiences, which in turn means other celebrities are more likely to participate AT ALL. How many Rampart's would there have to have been before every major publicist decided the risk was greater than the reward and just stopped arranging these for their clients period?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678671846.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>I like this point a lot. But I think since POTUS doing one it's probably seen just as risky and doubly as useful as any platform now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678677706.0" user="Nycamm" delta="False">
    <text>Funny enough I almost mentioned Obama's Ama as well. To my mind there's no way the president would EVER do an entirely informal online interview without some assurance that A.) there was a history of these going well for a wide range of celebrities and VIPs and B.) there was a process in place to ensure the interviewee both understood the community, and was understood by the community. Without Victoria I don't think that interview would have happened at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678956095.0" user="qwortec" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that that AMA didn't need to happen as there was nothing of value in it. I think the OP is concerned about AMAs like that where it's just a publicity stunt. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679757350.0" user="ghoti_styx" delta="False">
    <text>What's the point in there being an Obama ama if it's going to be just as filtered and sanitized as any other interview? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680000354.0" user="Nycamm" delta="False">
    <text>The point isn't whether or not having an Ama with Obama is good, or even if that Ama returned a good result.  
  
Think about it this way:  
there is a range of people who are willing to do Ama's. Somewhere within that range are the people who would do one no matter what. They've heard of Reddit independently, are familiar with the community, and either are interesting enough that the community requests they participate, or are confident enough that we'll be interested to host one themselves. These people are never going to use Victoria, but they also will be able to "filter" almost as well as she does because they are already familiar with what is and is not expected of them. In fact, I would say these are the least interesting people to have Ama's around because it's going to be very rare that they will answer in truly interesting, unexpected, and potentially divisive ways.  
  
Outside of that core group who *absolutely* will do an Ama a few different things are happening. Some potential participants have heard of Reddit, and either have make a decision NOT to do one or have not decided one way or the other yet, and some just have no idea what Reddit or Ama's are. Also, some may be interested but, due to the nature of celebrity, are being advised to not participate in something potentially damaging to their reputation.  
  
With Victoria's presence we see an increased trust in Ama's. There's a snowball effect as people further and further away from that core group of definite participants start to take part. Celebrities who have very little or no experience with our community feel more comfortable interacting with us (which I think makes their responses less filtered not more, but that's a whole other point), and all those people who schedule celebrities publicity and interviews start recommending us, not warning against us.  
  
So Ama's become better known in more diverse communities, the people who were on the fence before feel more trusting of the system, and maybe even one or two of the people who had decided not to do one think twice. You'll also find that, while Victoria does participate in big name Ama's, she isn't there for every one of them. That's where the President comes in.  
  
At the point where the President (or his handlers) has A.) heard of Ama's and B.) put enough trust in them to participate our initial range of potential participants has grown exponentially. Within that growth, there are a huge amount of new participants who may never have even heard of Ama's who are now taking part (many of them without Victoria to help). Who is going to be more cautious about participating in one of these than the POTUS?  
  
So, whether or not you like Victoria's presence in the Ama's she does mediate, and whether or not you care if we ask the president anything or if his responses are filtered, the fact that it can happen means there is a glut of other personalities who are able and willing to participate, unmediated, who we would never have had a chance to ask anything to otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678670860.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that questions are going to be screened etc no matter what, but on non-Victoria AMAs there seems to be more wildcard answers and funny conversations that comes from someone being hurled into the wilderness. 

Having someone who knows the platform and does it over and over ultimately creates a routine and the same thing happens in every AMA.  

I should probably put the routine thing in the main box, I think that's one of the big downsides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678860169.0" user="Ivysub" delta="False">
    <text>I think the type of celebrity that gives those in depth funny answers when they're typing them selves is probably the type that is comfortable with computers and the internet in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678880240.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely agree.  I just get frustrated when I see celebrities who are active on other social media and would be perfectly capable at using reddit go down the Victoria path because that's the way it's done now. 

So by having Victoria available, PR will take that option even if they understand the site perfectly, rather than take the risk of it going anywhere, which is what an AMA should be about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678891566.0" user="Ivysub" delta="False">
    <text>I think there's a fair selection of celebrities that pay people to maintain their social media presence. There was a kerfuffle a while ago about Hugh Jackman Tweeting about seeing the Opera house, but the picture accompanying it was of a different building or something. Now, as an Aussie, he would definitely have known the tweet was wrong. You cant mistake that building for literally any other in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678896893.0" user="ithinkimtim" delta="False">
    <text>That's pretty funny.

And it is probably true of a lot but doesn't change that there are plenty who DO use their own social media and go the Victoria route.

If they go the publicist route at worst it's a mediocre AMA that maybe Victoria could have done better.  But at best it's the celeb themselves interacting with funnier and more interesting comments... But then that can also be terrible... ah the more I write these replies the more I go back to being on the fence about whether the downsides are worth the upsides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679093291.0" user="Seakawn" delta="False">
    <text>I think your beef comes down to your opinion of what makes a good AMA.

While Victoria's absence might make the quality of the majority of AMA's better, I think most people consider an AMA good on the criteria of if an AMA is made at all--assuming that Victoria reinforces more potential AMA's because of her role, as opposed to otherwise.

I really just think it comes down to favoring Victoria because without her, it's presumed that we just wouldn't have as many AMA's.

But even if it came down to Quantity vs. Quality, I suppose a progressive argument would be how much quality exactly is Victoria allegedly removing from the potential of an unfiltered AMA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678815029.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>There would still be AMAs because like it or not Celebrity AMAs are nothing but advertisements, they would still do the AMAs because of the free advertising to millions of people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679733222.0" user="ibopm" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree. If troll questions get pushed to the top due to upvotes, then clearly the reddit population WANTS to troll them. And if that's what the hive wants, then that's what should be asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678739700.0" user="FARTBOX_DESTROYER" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think anyone is going to argue that it's not better for the celebrities to interact directly, but most of them just don't have time for that. Victoria makes these interactions more efficient, allowing the  maximum amount of questions answered.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678952019.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>If they are only seeing the questions that vVictoria picks for them over the phone then it isn't he same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679133456.0" user="mjkelly462" delta="False">
    <text>No filter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679734242.0" user="joatmon-snoo" delta="False">
    <text>[But they *are* in the office for their AMA](https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2fgsv2/i_am_victoria_from_reddit_amaa/ck91o24) a lot of the time!:

&amp;gt;Chances are they are with me in person - if it says I'm assisting them, that probably means I'm helping out with their AMA via phone.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678628232.0" user="akiws" delta="False">
    <text>But both of those things - normalized speed of replies, and normalized selection of questions to answer - take away from the rawness that used to make AMAs different from any other interview that celebrities could sign up for when they have something to promote.

Today, by allowing celebrities to all go through such an effective filter before we see them, you remove what used to make the reddit AMAs special: it was people of whom we normally only see a very specific &amp;amp; tailored image, letting their guard down by engaging in direct conversation with the reddit user base. There was no guarantee that things would go well - it was a lot more...real...for lack of a better word than it is now. 

I would go as far to say that there is no longer any fundamental difference between asking a question on a Victoria-run celebrity AMA than there is tweeting that same question to Ryan Seacrest before he interviews that same celebrity. In both cases, you are submitting your question in the hopes that someone (other than the person answering the question) will choose to ask it on your behalf.

A lot of us aren't especially interested in celebrity interviews. We would however be interested in engaging a celebrity directly...even if it's just 1 question &amp;amp; 1 answer. Yes, it's likely that agents and/or handlers were screening the questions or answering on the celebrities behalf for some of these, even before going through Victoria became the norm. But with the Victoria-managed AMAs, it is essentially guaranteed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678692194.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Victoria is an *option* for celebrities who want those filters. She attracts celebrities who would otherwise not be willing to take part in an AMA. A celebrity's greatest asset is their reputation, and the majority will not risk their reputation by doing an unfiltered interview on reddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678721312.0" user="Snookerman" delta="False">
    <text>But that used to be the whole point of AMAs and it differentiated them from regular interviews. I don't see the point of having one more regular interview with celebrities that don't want to do an old school AMA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678725009.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It provides celebrities with a unique audience in a format that that audience is very familiar with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678734488.0" user="Snookerman" delta="False">
    <text>That's the point of the argument made by OP, that the format is no longer the familiar one that was interesting and different. It's now just a regular interview filtered by a sort of journalist.

Sure, some people will find that interesting, but it's no longer an AMA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680336468.0" user="Xer0day" delta="False">
    <text>But that's the point. We don't want what's essentially a transcript of a Hollywood interview. We want 1 on 1 person to person type answers, in a more unguarded fashion. AMA's a few years ago were a lot different before reddit allowed every celeb to plug their shit in the AMA title or description.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678951960.0" user="Derpatologist_7" delta="False">
    <text>How do you think the process would work? Would the celebrity be, say sitting on a couch, and Victoria would scroll through the questions saying to he celebrity "how about this?" Or "what about this one? Or would the celebrity have their own laptop and they'd read through the questions and tell her which ones to answer?

I've always been curious to know how they do it. If it was simply just Victoria scanning the questions and choosing the contact then I think I'd take umbrage to that.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679182150.0" user="DasHuhn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Or would the celebrity have their own laptop and they'd read through the questions and tell her which ones to answer?

IIRC it depends on the celebrity, if they're with Victoria or not.  Some of them are AMAs done entirely on the phone - some are done at the Reddit Offices, and they sit down and have questions read to them, and some of the celebrities read through and answer some, and have victoria answer others.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679267979.0" user="wellmaybe" delta="False">
    <text>If they get so tired so easily, maybe they're not really here to answer our questions but to promote whatever they promote.

Now, if Victoria were to proxy an AMA with the Glorious Leader, that'd be a different matter... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679715751.0" user="matholio" delta="False">
    <text>If they get tired and have to quit, let them.  Let people know their capacity for engagement.   I'm with OP, be genuine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
