<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="181959121.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/30c0k1/cmv_celebrity_amas_are_ruined_by_victoria_from/">
    <title>CMV: Celebrity AMAs are ruined by Victoria from Reddit</title>
    <original_poster>ithinkimtim</original_poster>
    <original_post>**EDIT: [Please read this from the /r/IAmA  mods](http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/30ea3g/mod_post_riama_misconceptions/)**

----

I have no problem with Victoria herself, just the concept of "Victoria from reddit is here helping me out".

To me the entire point of an AMA is having someone of note interact
with this unpredictable medium.  Ask Me **Anything**.  It's fun and interesting to see them negotiate the comments, with the potential for them to be reading the most bizarre and funny points of view, with strange interactions on lower voted comments as well as random replies to far reaching child-comments.

Victoria from Reddit turns the medium into yet another "send in your questions and we'll pick the best to ask this person who is so much better than you".  Instead of interacting directly with someone, there's a filter.  A filter who types the same way in every AMA, using *italics* and -laughs- and -umms- which completely takes away from it for me.

Here Victoria says that the Woody Harelson AMA would have turned out differently:  https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2fgsv2/i_am_victoria_from_reddit_amaa/ck91rpw  Which shows that comments are being filtered.  That is what made AMAs so great, it's a celeb being talked to directly, and this is more often POSITIVE rather than that negative example.

In essence I think Victoria turns it into a basic interview with fan questions that has been done a million times before.  If a brand wants to promote via AMA, jump in and get dirty.   I don't even read AMAs anymore if it's got Victoria doing the typing.

If there's a better way of looking at this , please CMV, I want to enjoy AMAs again without the frustration.

-----
Reason for view change:

I still dislike AMAs with Victoria, and am clearly not the only one.  This comes from Victoria creating a difference between the celebs and us average Joes.  Of course this isn't always the case.  As it turns out, Victoria will help anyone that fits in her schedule.  So in reality it is just some AMAs (Ludacris as a recent example) that may turn out far more interesting if they had to navigate the website themselves in exchange for publicity.

With a few people commenting with first hand experience, I've decided that because the benefits of Victoria are more heavily weighted by the majority, my post title view has been changed.  Even if I'm stuck hating the AMAs, Victoria doesn't "ruin" them.

Thanks for all the replies!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your overlords. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes always change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please [don't](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)**. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27679079610.0" user="BrutallyHonestDude" delta="False">
    <text>Let's ask her.

/u/chooter.  Care to respond?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679411596.0" user="chooter" delta="False">
    <text>Sure! (sorry, I'm out on the West Coast for 1.5 days and my schedule's all messed up)

So when OP says:

*Here Victoria says that the Woody Harelson AMA would have turned out differently: https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2fgsv2/i_am_victoria_from_reddit_amaa/ck91rpw Which shows that comments are being filtered. That is what made AMAs so great, it's a celeb being talked to directly, and this is more often POSITIVE rather than that negative example.*

How I would have "made things different" would have been:

* setting clear expectations from the outset with Woody and / or his team as to what an AMA is, and what it's not. An AMA does not belong to you. It belongs to the community that's asking the questions, and if that's not something you're comfortable with, then an AMA probably doesn't make sense.

* ensuring that enough time was set aside for the AMA - while the Woody Harrelson AMA was before my time and thus I don't have a lot of information on it, something that seems pretty consistent is that there was not a lot of time spent on it. I have extensive dialogues with many, many people to ensure that when someone confirms to do an AMA, they've set aside enough time.

* Make sure that whomever is doing the AMA knows EXACTLY what it is they're about to do, and that they have to be relevant to the question at hand - not promotional throughout. Surprisingly, a lot of people sign up to do things without knowing what they are - so I make sure they know what AMAs are, their history, and why they should care.

* Get to as MANY questions as we can - whether random, rude, ridiculous or sincere - and as thoroughly as possible.

Just following these principles would have really changed the trajectory of the infamous RAMPART AMA.

I really care about both redditors and whomever is doing an AMA. So it's not always easy, but I practice what I preach.

Happy to answer your additional questions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679559939.0" user="walkingtheriver" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying that you don't at all filter questions? Because once in a while I've seen controversial questions about the celebrity in question being voted to the very top on an AMA, and it's gone unanswered...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679614460.0" user="lula2488" delta="False">
    <text>It means that the person either didn't want to answer (which happens, and they're free to make that choice. But you all are free to vote on their post accordingly; it is an Ask Me Anything, not I'll Answer Everything), or the question was upvoted to the top after the person had already left (like most of the questions in the Obama AMA, for example).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679630466.0" user="chooter" delta="False">
    <text>I'm an equal opportunity asker. If the highly upvoted question seen when the AMA is live, we do ask it, and we do tackle it. Here's [one example](https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2ikmuz/robert_downey_jr_avengers_member_emerson_lake/cl2znwz?context=1). If it's upvoted after the AMA's concluded, there are times when talent will come back to answer them (like Jean Schulz, who [sent in some later answers for questions for her AMA](https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/1snoy1/im_jean_schulz_my_husband_drew_the_peanuts_comic/) ).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679639000.0" user="Ravenman2423" delta="False">
    <text>I'm assuming it's not so much a filter, but more the celebrity not wanting to answer that question.

 Victoria: "yo, here's this question."

 celebrity: "Yeah.. I'm not answering that."

 Victoria: "k." 

Or maybe Victoria reads the question and, since she kinda knows her job and probably has a decent idea of how X celebrity will react, just skips it.  Which im totally fine with. It's understandable.  

Does that make sense, /u/chooter? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680884966.0" user="cahaseler" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Or maybe Victoria reads the question and, since she kinda knows her job and probably has a decent idea of how X celebrity will react, just skips it. Which im totally fine with. It's understandable.

I don't think she ever does this, even if its something that's likely to offend or annoy the person. But yes, if they do find it offensive or annoying they probably won't leave an answer. We put Victoria in an awkward position sometimes I'm sure. But she's very good at dealing with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680895866.0" user="Ravenman2423" delta="False">
    <text>I meant that she kinda gets a feel for how each celebrity will react to each question. If the guy is more serious and the conversation is about serious topics and then someone says "*celebrity*, when was the last time you laughed at your own fart?" she'll skip it. but if its Louis CK, she obviously wont skip it.  see what I'm saying? idk, thats just how i picture the scenario going. Someone like Louis CK would totally answer that question and Victoria knows that. but someone asks Hillary Clinton when she laughs at her own farts, victoria will skip it. I feel like a question like that would probably also give reddit a bad image, if the celebrity doesn't know the place, and they most likely do not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680975058.0" user="cahaseler" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, that's exactly what I mean. She *does* ask the ridiculous questions to everyone. Sometimes she doesn't get an answer. And a lot of the time the really crazy questions don't get upvoted in the first place, so she's less likely to see them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679779554.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Victoria, do I have this right?

(i) You brief participants about AMA and Reddit in general

(ii) You commit participants to at least one-hour for each AMAs

(iii) You select the questions and read them out to participants (either in person or by phone)

(iv) You type their answers 


Follow up questions:

(i) Do you have access to their Reddit accounts, or do you create brand new ones?

(ii) I get that Reddit takes some getting used to, specifically in terms of format and community mentality. And without your guiding hand, some celebrity might not be inclined to participate. However, in your opinion, does your role prevent participants from familiarizing themselves with Reddit, and thus, permanently handicapping them to the site? Is it a fair trade-off, or is the cost too high in the long run?

(iii) Would you agree that your role is similar to that of a typical PR/talent manager. Don't participants have their own army of those? 

(iv) Shouldn't the onus be on the participants (or at least their staff) to familiarize themselves with Reddit?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680892061.0" user="cahaseler" delta="False">
    <text>IANV, but I do mod IAMA and interact with her a lot. You're correct on your statements.

(i) Sometimes they log in, sometimes she creates a new account for them with their assistance. She doesn't retain access to the accounts, they keep them in case they want to come back and keep redditing (Chevy Chase just showed up a couple weeks back for the first time since his AMA).

(iii) It is, but she's working for the interest of good AMAs and reddit, and the ones working for the talent are just in it to promote their latest movie or whatever. And they don't know how to use reddit. (Speaking as a mod, it can be incredibly frustrating to deal with the armies of PR reps. Victoria speaks their language and can help us mods interface with them).

(iv) Yes, but they don't bother. If they have to take the time to teach themselves how to reddit they are that much less likely to do an AMA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27681582732.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for responding on Victoria's behalf, man. My post wasn't meant as a criticism (I just reread it, and realized it could have been interpreted as such).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680330389.0" user="toiracse" delta="False">
    <text>I'll preface this by saying I think you do a good job, I've just got a couple of questions that would be clearer from your perspective.

Do you believe if you were always involved in the AMA process from its inception... do you believe that the "Would you rather fight one hundred duck sized horses or one horse sized duck?" question would have ever been answered, or would have ever become as well recognized in reddit's culture?

And is the presence of a mediator between Reddit and the person answering (but no longer conducting) the AMA preventing more such obscure, unique and genuine questions being asked, seen and by extension genuinely answered? Even if the genuine answer is "What the fuck is wrong with you people?"

Some people get the impression that your role manufactures, rather than mediates the situation and if there's something reddit hates it's astroturfing and manufactured content presenting itself as something else. In the case of AMAs this is represented by the idea that people don't like when the person hosting it isn't being themselves because it's supposed to be about their personality.

At least I think its those (i dont want to say complaints or concerns) ideas that are pervasive across reddit that bring forth these types of discussions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680502337.0" user="chooter" delta="False">
    <text>If there are questions (or thematic questions) that the reddit community wants to ask, from varied individuals, cross-AMA, I absolutely think they would be answered and become iconic.

In terms of your second point, I would say that's absolutely not the case. In fact, that actual answer (or an answer very much like it in response to a confused reddit questioner) was [just posed last week.](https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2zldsp/i_am_josh_mcdermitt_actor_and_comedian_you_might/cpjzvar)

And in regards to your final point, I am not here to filter, or buffer, in any way. If anything, I am here to present an AMA as it stands, and not misrepresent it, and ensure its veracity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27680520489.0" user="toiracse" delta="False">
    <text>TY!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
