<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="181959121.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/30c0k1/cmv_celebrity_amas_are_ruined_by_victoria_from/">
    <title>CMV: Celebrity AMAs are ruined by Victoria from Reddit</title>
    <original_poster>ithinkimtim</original_poster>
    <original_post>**EDIT: [Please read this from the /r/IAmA  mods](http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/30ea3g/mod_post_riama_misconceptions/)**

----

I have no problem with Victoria herself, just the concept of "Victoria from reddit is here helping me out".

To me the entire point of an AMA is having someone of note interact
with this unpredictable medium.  Ask Me **Anything**.  It's fun and interesting to see them negotiate the comments, with the potential for them to be reading the most bizarre and funny points of view, with strange interactions on lower voted comments as well as random replies to far reaching child-comments.

Victoria from Reddit turns the medium into yet another "send in your questions and we'll pick the best to ask this person who is so much better than you".  Instead of interacting directly with someone, there's a filter.  A filter who types the same way in every AMA, using *italics* and -laughs- and -umms- which completely takes away from it for me.

Here Victoria says that the Woody Harelson AMA would have turned out differently:  https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2fgsv2/i_am_victoria_from_reddit_amaa/ck91rpw  Which shows that comments are being filtered.  That is what made AMAs so great, it's a celeb being talked to directly, and this is more often POSITIVE rather than that negative example.

In essence I think Victoria turns it into a basic interview with fan questions that has been done a million times before.  If a brand wants to promote via AMA, jump in and get dirty.   I don't even read AMAs anymore if it's got Victoria doing the typing.

If there's a better way of looking at this , please CMV, I want to enjoy AMAs again without the frustration.

-----
Reason for view change:

I still dislike AMAs with Victoria, and am clearly not the only one.  This comes from Victoria creating a difference between the celebs and us average Joes.  Of course this isn't always the case.  As it turns out, Victoria will help anyone that fits in her schedule.  So in reality it is just some AMAs (Ludacris as a recent example) that may turn out far more interesting if they had to navigate the website themselves in exchange for publicity.

With a few people commenting with first hand experience, I've decided that because the benefits of Victoria are more heavily weighted by the majority, my post title view has been changed.  Even if I'm stuck hating the AMAs, Victoria doesn't "ruin" them.

Thanks for all the replies!

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your overlords. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes always change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please [don't](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)**. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27678649444.0" user="aphoenix" delta="False">
    <text>I'd urge you to look at one of the AMAs that you indirectly reference; the Woody AMA. It was a *train wreck*. It was complete garbage, and it ended up being intensely negative for both the askers and the askee.

I don't know how /u/chooter does what she does, but I know that when I read an AMA that she works on, I'm going to see:

* a lot of answers
* a pretty accurate depiction of how that person answers the question

Compare that to some other AMAs, like the one from today about the army girl who became a poacher hunter. Interesting topic, but generally short and pointless answers.

I think that unless someone is a redditor already (like /u/GovSchwarzenegger for example, who is possibly the best celebrity redditor) then having someone facilitate the conversation just makes the conversation better. Heck, sometimes it's just what makes it *possible* at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27678665649.0" user="Krazen" delta="False">
    <text>Um, the Woody AMA spawned a dank meme. The whole "Let's talk about Rampart", redditors and the internet actually gained something from that.

Victoria version of Woody Harrelson AMA? Bunch of vanilla whitewashed nonsense. 

*"Oh Woody, I'm a huge fan of your work, what's the funniest street encounter you've ever had?"*

*"Well pancakefucker9969, this one time this girl giggled a lot and asked for my autograph and I signed my name Hoody Warrelson"* 

***cue 1799 upvotes.***

Twenty seven hours later, NOBODY fucking cares about that AMA.  Nobody talks about it, nobody remembers it, it doesnt leave any impressionable mark except for that one schlub who got to ask some canned question about Woody's XYZ Charity that he's involved in and totally loves because it helps the children, and Woody tells him that he remembers meeting him at XYZ Charity's annual ball or some shit.

I mean they're boring. AMA's are boring. Ludacris has an AMA yesterday, he's a cool guy but fuck if that AMA wasn't a fucking waste of time. Seriously what the fuck was gained from that? I walk away from Ludacris' AMA, and what do I remember? Nothing.

Celebrities get a takeaway - because it's all about promotion. Probably free promotion, I don't know if reddit charges per interview, but Ludacris' AMA title was pretty much "I'm Ludacris, buy my new album". And what do we get from that?

http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/306p0a/ludacris_is_ludaversal_amaa/cpplpfe

&amp;gt;Yes.
It's on the cover of my album. Make sure everyone on here pre-orders my album RIGHT NOW on iTunes: https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/ludaversal/id974115539[1]
It's a 1993 Acura Legend.


How is this better than "Let's talk about Rampart"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679039470.0" user="George_E_Hale" delta="False">
    <text>That's Ludacris. Do you expect that's Victoria's fault?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679075338.0" user="fallingwalls" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "Oh Woody, I'm a huge fan of your work, what's the funniest street encounter you've ever had?"


&amp;gt; "Well pancakefucker9969, this one time this girl giggled a lot and asked for my autograph and I signed my name Hoody Warrelson"

I used to give interviews - these are standard questions you're expected to ask by handlers.

&amp;gt;"What was it like working with [person]?"


&amp;gt;"How did you feel when you [recent accomplishment]?"


&amp;gt;"What made you want to get the band back together for this tour?"


Questions of no substance that everyone already knows the answer to, but every celebrity has already been prepped to answer. Personally I don't know why anyone would want to sit through this type of interview, but apparently a lot of people do, and these are the type of questions you get in these regulated AMAs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679530151.0" user="MrTastix" delta="False">
    <text>It's cheap publicity for the masses who are easily amused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679633318.0" user="Ravenman2423" delta="False">
    <text>This comment is perfect.  I could not have summed up my opinion on the subject better. I even laughed a few times.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679823379.0" user="aphoenix" delta="False">
    <text>You'd rather watch a train wreck because a train wreck is memorable? And the train wreck gives some (I literally shudder as I type this) "dank memes"?

I think we're just on different sides of the reddit fence. Personally, I would rather get actual information from a celebrity, even if it's forgettable at a later date than observe a train wreck and get nothing but a "dank meme".

I think that Victoria from reddit has very little to do with how much a celebrity tries to pimp their projects; in the case of Ludacris, I think it's pretty obvious that he came on /r/iama after being told that it would boost record sales, and he's clearly trying to do that; that would happen if Victoria was there or not. But then there are other AMAs that have been great - Sean Bean springs to mind - where Victoria managed to capture the endearing things that were said, and there was very little in the way of overt marketing.

I'd rather have a Sean Bean AMA than a Woody Harrelson one, even though I don't remember specifics of the Sean Bean one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679045026.0" user="Lereas" delta="False">
    <text>There are quite a few pretty well known celeb redditors. /u/wil is a big one, as well as /u/zachinoz. There have been a few other people who have mentioned using reddit or have referenced it clearly enough that we know they use it, but they haven't revealed their username. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27679584174.0" user="aphoenix" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there are several celebrities out in the open on reddit. Personally, /u/GovSchwartzenegger is my favorite because he is open, supportive, and just generally kind and good. He is fairly active, seems to really get technology, and make all interactions seem personal.

I like him for all the same reasons I like /u/wil; they're just being themselves on the internet.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
