<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39482027343.0" user="ShaunLevi1995" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

Perez Hilton is still a thing? Wow.

Hilton spreads nasty gossip and rumors. But Grande was in a bad position, because if she doesn't comply with his request, then he'll reframe the narrative as "Ariana Grande supports with fans attacking openly queer celebrity journalist!" She'll be made to look like a homophobe. 

Shouldn't Hilton be the one condemned for bullying people like Ariana Grande. If it's even true that she did a line of cocaine, what business is it of his to announce that to the world?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
