<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39474969281.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Celebrities have a larger outreach and a bigger voice. If their fans are threatening violence they have a moral imperative to tell their fans to chill out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475198177.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I would beg to differ. If some putz buys an album and is a self-professed fan of me and blows up a public building, I don’t think I have the duty to make a public statement of any sort.

It’s like when a kid killed themself over An Ozzy album, and people were demanding he tell kids to not kill themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475296490.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>If they are doing acts of violence *for* you, then yeah, you kind of have a moral imperative to tell them to stop, even if you never asked them to do it in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476005201.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39477457538.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/theguyoverthere50 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20theguyoverthere50&amp;amp;message=theguyoverthere50%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/-/i4uzsk1/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475579392.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re fine with it if they blow up that building in your name? For example imagine your a musician you go to jail for whatever reason, so you’re fan blows up a government building because “free theguyoverthere50”. You cool with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476041506.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Of course that wouldn’t sit well with me, but any act of disavowing the violent act is more of a charity case as opposed to something I MUST do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476070411.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>If it’s a one time thing then sure, but if there’s multiple people doing it in your name then I feel like it’s on you to say that you disagree with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476143186.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>If I spray paint none nonsense on a synagogue and spray “I’m a big Oprah fan, too”, I would say Oprah has no duty to weigh in on the matter, but if she does, she cannot give a verbal order or incentivize acts against people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476384360.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>What if every Oprah fan was tagging synagogues with I love Oprah?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476390508.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>That would be pretty funny</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476519149.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>So religious building being vandalized is funny?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476542241.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>If some neonazis spray-painted “check out Oprah at 8:30 Easter standard time on OWN, oh and uh…..get out of our town or something” on the side of a synagogue, I’d get a chuckle, yes.

It’s because of the absurdity and the knowledge that there’s pretty much no connection between Oprah and this anti-Semitic act of vandalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476571531.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty much no connection and no connection are different things. Even if it’s just the fact that they put her name on it means she’s connected to it. And if she doesn’t denounce it publicly then some people are going to look at like she supports it. Legally she’s safe but if she doesn’t come out against her brand is going to take a hit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476581112.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Her brand might take a hit, but it shouldn’t</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476614975.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>You’re right it probably shouldn’t, but it’s going to because until she comes out against people are going to assume she’s for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475723480.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>You do though. That's what denouncing is - Separating something that could be tried back to you, from you. 

Failing to denounce something, means that it can get tied back to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476052084.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>In the court of public opinion, sure. But in the court of fact and reason, not so much.

You’re only connected if you’re connected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476222299.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>But you are connected. Them invoking your name connects you to them. Unless the tie is explicitly severed, It's their word against nothing. They win by default. By denouncing them, at least it's your word against theirs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476259534.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>If I spray paint a swastika on a synagogue and spray “I’m a big fan of Oprah” right next to it, what does she have to do with this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476332222.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Her name is next to a swastika.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476341918.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>And her connection to this stops there if you can’t find words that she said overtly promoting this act, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476442241.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Her connection goes only that far. 

But that's still a connection. 

The only way to completely severe the connection in this case would be to get the graffiti removed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39482068985.0" user="ShaunLevi1995" delta="False">
    <text>How many fans are legit threatening violence? In this case, were Grande fans literally threatening violence against Perez Hilton?

And not only that, but threats and harassment in general is pretty much commonplace on Twitter and Instagram. Drake was straight up getting bullied on IG when Pusha T made his diss towards him, and I don't recall anyone saying "Tell Pusha T to call off his fans." Drake had to turn off his comments because it was so bad.

Beyonce's fan went after Rachel Roy when they thought it was her Beyonce was singing about having an affair with Jay-Z. They even went after Rachel Roy's daughter's social media saying things like "How does it feel to know your mothers a whore and home wrecker?" It was insane. I don't recall anyone pressuring Beyonce to tell the Beyhive to stand down.

[https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/davidmack/she-just-wants-to-cook-brunch](https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/davidmack/she-just-wants-to-cook-brunch)

[https://metro.co.uk/2016/04/24/rachel-roy-learned-the-hard-way-not-to-mess-with-beyonces-beyhive-5838251/](https://metro.co.uk/2016/04/24/rachel-roy-learned-the-hard-way-not-to-mess-with-beyonces-beyhive-5838251/)

\^They pretty much treat it like laughs.

Doja Cat was being bullied by Cardi B fans on social media. No one said shit to Cardi B.

Nicki Minaj's Barbies regularly go after people on Twitter. No one's telling Nicki to say anything to them.

Often times, blue checks demanding that another blue check to tell condemn the actions of their "fans" are sometimes doing it to just make them look bad. To slander them in the process by saying, "See, look at how bad they are based on their fans!" How many legit fans are actually engaging in actual threats of violence, and how many are just posting criticism?

Getting "dragged on Twitter"=okay

Online bullying/harassment=not okay

But aren't they...the same?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
