<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475167072.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>clearly there is nuance depending on the situation, but like it or not, there are crazy people in this world who think they need to to act like a militia for people like celebrities.  And while these celebrities never asked for this or wanted it, its simply a sad result of fame and a big enough population of people that some who have mental health problems will be in the mix.  

Now clearly the celebrity isn't responsible in most cases as they aren't telling their fans to do this, but if a misguided fan who thinks they were told to do this can be corrected with a simple tweet from their celebrity saying they don't condone these threats and other horrible behaviors, it can go a long way to stopping these troubled people, and it reflects highly on a celebrity who would take just those few seconds to use their influence to send a message to clear the air.  No rational person would assume that telling people to stop doing something means they were the one who told them to start.  

If a tells a bank robber to put down the money, does that mean he previously told him to rob the bank?

If an overzealous drunk boyfriend wants to punch a guy for looking at his girlfriend and she tells him to stop it and pulls him away, does that imply she previously told her boyfriend to fight on her behalf?  thats crazy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475847709.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Take the Trump-White Supremacist situation for example. Since Trump didn’t personally wave a banner saying “racism bad”, people assumed that the two are in cahoots without evidence, even though the default assumption is preferable. 

I see it nice to calm the fans, but I don’t see the moral imperative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39480604617.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>And when trump doesn’t just say nothing when asked to tell them to stand down, but instead says things like “stand back and stand by”, people will justifiably wonder what the meaning behind that choice of words are.  

He isn’t being legally forced to call off something his fans did, but people have the right to judge him if he won’t use his influence to clear up confusion where his fans think he wants them to do something terrible. 

Heck, I am not anywhere near a celebrity, but if tomorrow I found out thousands of people were making death threats against the Irish, or whoever, for whatever reason they think it’s what I wanted them to do, I would not hesitate to post something on social media saying I never condoned this, I denounce this, and anyone doing this in a misguided attempt to gain my favor is wrong and should stop.  But if I knew they were doing it because they thought I wanted them to, I would be a pretty shitty person to just stay quiet.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
