<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475078647.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>So your specific case is a bit different in the sense that Perez Hilton acted in a really crappy way like that. 

But here's the thing about fans. A subset of them for any given person, book or group is toxic. And some of them are fanatically so. There's nothing at all you can do to alter that fanaticism and they take a critique (legitimate or not) as an attack against the object of their fandom. That can cause them to lash out in ways that are just not ok. For a good example take those manic Marvel fans who made threats to harm/sexually assault/kill Elizabeth Olsen for not putting a black mark on her social media when Chadwick Boseman died. That's a level of mad people don't abide. 

Now a manic fan for the most part can be stopped with one thing. Proof their idol wants nothing to do with their behaviour. If Marvel or Boseman's family comes out saying "All those people saying these despicable and horrible things; we don't consider you fans, we don't condone your behaviour and we actively condemn it." That's incontrevertible proof to these starstruck fans that their idol rejects their behavior. 

We could argue this all day but I think it's fair to say someone who threatens a woman over this and then doxxes people who defend her are too far up their own ass to see their behavior as wrong; and as long as they maintain the illusion that this is ok they keep doing it. But a statement from the person they 'support' saying what they are doing is not ok is an easy way to stop the behavior dead in it's track.

I don't think people think Perez Hilton was right for what he did. But letting people send death threats and constantly harass him isn't beneficial.  
And when fans start going after people who did nothing wrong it's even worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475813530.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I like your response.

It’s polite, yes, but I don’t see the imperative. I’m not one to villainize a complicit party even though others are the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475907143.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>I mean yes and no. The initial hounding is the fault of the fans, they are the ones who choose to commit acts of violence. But as I said. The person is in a unique position to staunch the bleeding immediately and more effectively than anyone else could at that time.

Let's do a scenario.

I (the idol) see a group of rabid bulls (the fans) stampeding towards another person on the street. Next to me is a button (my statement denouncing my fans) that will cause at least a majority of the bulls to stop stampeding. If I don't press it, Am I an ass?

I don't judge Ari for her fans behavior, and I'm not particularly sympathetic to Perez Hilton for digging himself a lovely hole to drown in. What I judge Ari for is how she chooses to respond. Does she want to be the head of a rabid fanbase that makes online attacks their mode of communication? Does she alllow herself to be a complicit party? Or is she a good enough person to stop the hate?

Also as I said most people who catch the mobs are more Elizabeth Olsen and less Perez Hilton. They didn't wake up looking for problems, problems woke up and found them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476095564.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>If you don’t press the button, sure, you’re an ass, but not an ass I’d throw in prison for it.

You mentioned the three alternatives: enable the fans, don’t weigh in, and denounce the fans. I would say the latter choices are morally acceptable, and the last one is nearly heroic.

There’s nothing wrong with complacency, and I don’t understand where people are coming from when they use the word as a pejorative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476162115.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think anyone is advocating jail time if fans act crazy.

Most are like you in this response. Like me being an ass for not pressing the button, she's an ass for not stopping her fans.

I consider stopping her fans the correct moral action. I consider not weighing in to be in the territory of being an ass; I wouldn't advocate jail time for it or even a fine but I would definitely acknowledge it made her more of an ass. 

Where we really disagree is the enabling. If Ariana Grande actively came out supporting her fans harassing people I would call her morally wrong. She's no longer just complicit she is actively participating in the bullying and doxxing of others. I would shame any star, politician or person who did that and if their fans turned to physical violence (were it my choice) I would have them tried under [US Code 373](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/373) \- Solicitation to commit a crime of violence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476215189.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>No, I think I’m in agreement with you on that last point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476249913.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>Ah I just reread and you are. Glad we agree.

I'm not sure which part of your view to change then. I've made the only case that I can, that while being neutral might not make you evil it certainly doesn't fall into the moral good camp either.

What would it require to really change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476281051.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>To prove that there are positive moral obligations. A requirement to act.

Where I stand, currently, is that good-Samaritan compulsion by the state or whoever, is nonsense. 

If you watch a baby drown in a puddle, you’re a dick, but not a killer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476461811.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>Are we talking morality or legality?

Because your post suggested morality and now it seems we've shifted to legality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476480753.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>In an ideal society, the two mesh.

If you were a judge by agreement of 100 people on an island you crashed on, would you recognize that there are positive obligations or none?

I am of the conviction that there are none, and inaction is an acceptable thing in cases like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476544408.0" user="Tanaka917" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and no I'd say.

Look I think that societal shame is actually a very useful part of the morality system. It's that halfway house where we acknowledge that while no wrongdoing worthy of legal penalty has been commited, the act is distasteful or otherwise not what we might consider right. The reason I say this is that we as people do things that are morally unjustifiable and yet not illegal. 

Carpooling is objectively better for society with less cars and the environmment, eating vegetarian is good for you as a person and promotes less animal harm, rather than taking weekends to drink and play our hobbies our spare time is best used at a soup kitchen. Morally the correct thing to do is the latter. Legally we make no distinction

Your original CMV said nothing of legal penalty. If your actual view is that doing nothing is a bad thing but one not worthy of legal punishment I am agreeing with you. But I think your CMV doesn't reflects that very well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
