<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475197892.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>If a celebrity witnesses their fans misbehaving _in their name_ and do nothing about it, that is implied approval.

So it is a matter of their publicity. If they want publicity showing them as a bully or villain then they can just sit by and do nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475855637.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, it’s all about perception and is socially beneficial.

But what I’m saying is that there is no inherent imperative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39478845546.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, well you said it is extremely stupid. I argue that managing your public persona and perception isn’t stupid at all.

So anyone from a PR manager to a concerned friend could make the request without it being stupid.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
