<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475214037.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>If you were just talking about insults or whatever then I'd agree however when it comes to actual threats I think celebrates should actively discourage them and condemn those who do. 

Threats are not expression they are a mob intimidation tactic they are designed to create distress and force people to comply under that distress and sure an online threat isn't that big of a deal compared to say a mob boss but it's still you know a threat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475923597.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I know for a fact that Hilton sat cozily in his house but said he “feared for his life” as he digested the whole cow he ate. I’m convinced he didn’t receive that intimidation factor you mentioned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476501497.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>Some people have a thicker skin. Doesn't make it okay to send violent threats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476509980.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn’t a perceived legitimate threat have to be present? Don’t there need to be victims for there to be a crime?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476540768.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>Now you're getting into if a tree falls in a forest and nobody is around to hear it does it make a sound territory. 

Sometimes someone is around to hear it and the person making violent threats can't be sure if it effects the person they are sending it to or not and likewise the person receiving it can't be sure of how serious or credible it is. 

If you're talking strictly about legality it's still illegal even if the person received it doesn't care and the threat wasn't particularly credible just rarely enforced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476548992.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>That last thing you mentioned is messed up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476589171.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>Usually the sentence is pretty tame but the US being the US sometimes it's insanely disproportionate. Personally I don't see the issue with it being illegal just the heavy handed sentences should basically just be community service imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476606001.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I hate the way the legal system goes about this kind of thing.

I recall a story where teens laughed at a homeless man drowning in a river and they filmed it. It was rude, tops, but the court system preached that “they were obligated to help”. They had no duty to that man, in my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476613134.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>I think the issue in that case was they didn't contact the authorities, they weren't duty bound to "help" persay just call 911, which I don't think is an unfair standard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476619457.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I say they didn’t have a duty to do that either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476628732.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it's already borne out in the courts...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
