<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39474997231.0" user="foreverloveall" delta="False">
    <text>What is evasive pussy conduct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475220821.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Hilton talking crap then hiding behind the threats of violence and act like Ariana has an obligation to make it stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475329978.0" user="foreverloveall" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it’s also extremely stupid to make threats of violence on behalf of a celebrity for any reason. I don know who Perez Hilton is but he sounds like a ridiculous person who is just starting drama for no reason.
That being said Ariana Grande’s fans seem incredibly immature. I may not be able to change your view on that but sounds like those people need to grow up. No celebrity in the world is worth getting that riled up for to the point of making threats to another celebrity. Sounds incredibly petty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476024016.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I would highly recommend looking Perez Hilton up, he’s a celebrity blogger who makes a living trying to “out” celebrities who he thinks are gay (he is gay, himself). He’s a big douche. He’s like if all the tabloid magazines in the world paper machaed into a pudgy human Shrek.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
