<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506944220.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”.

Countries acting in the best interest of the country isn't really the concern of "forms of government".  If breaking their own constitution is acting in the best interest of the country and the people of the country, I don't actually see any problem with breaking the constitution since following it in therefore not in their best interests.

The point of a form of government is to ensure that individual leader acts in a way that is best for the country and the people of its country instead of best for the leaders themselves.  Are there corrupt politicians in democratic countries? Absolutely.  Is it harder to get away with blatant self-serving corruption in a democracy? Absolutely.  Politicians in democratic countries still put their self interests first, but the system in place helps force them to act more in the interest of the people of their country or else they'll get voted out or arrested for taking bribes, etc, which isn't in their interest.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
