<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39507654965.0" user="Mafinde" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by “forms of government”? A simple functional definition might be - how decisions get made. I think that’s a fair definition that most other definitions will align with. 

There is very obviously a great diversity in how decisions get made at any governmental level. And just as obviously, “opportunism” isn’t one of those. 

I see the point you’re trying to make but you need to define your terms or tighten up your language a little.

Edit: I think you’re trying to say human nature is opportunistic and those in power extract what they can. But then one might argue that political systems a function to counterbalance and they do so to varying degrees. The history of political development (for example on a large scale: monarchy to constitutional monarchy to republic) has led to more oversight, ethics, accountability, among others things - these are the counterbalances to opportunism and different political systems do them differently. In such an analysis, the exact opposite of your point is demonstrated.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
