<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506842245.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying you see no difference between an absolute monarchy, a theocracy and a democratic Republic? All of those forms of government look exactly the same to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506854420.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>no im saying if you really study political history governments are not nearly as different as modern popular culture makes them out to be and the one unifying trait is they are all damn opportunistic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506861346.0" user="Claytonius21" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so how are those 3 types of government the same, who is being opportunistic in each of them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507643272.0" user="nonsensetheydbefine" delta="False">
    <text>The question:

&amp;gt; Are you saying you see no difference between an absolute monarchy, a theocracy and a democratic Republic? All of those forms of government look exactly the same to you?

Your answer:

&amp;gt; no

You Changed Your View.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39510735431.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>But that's not the actual governing system, this is like (if you'll excuse my weird metaphor, I'm a screenwriter) saying "animation" is the only genre of cartoon because whether a given cartoon is realistic-fiction like Arthur, sci-fi like Jimmy Neutron, high fantasy like Avatar: The Last Airbender or urban fantasy like W.I.T.C.H., animation is the one unifying trait</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39514567291.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>im saying if we need to find a commonality at all (we probably don’t).  It’s more like if all governments were a bunch of paperback romance novels and you wanted to do a dissertation on the nuances behind them but realize they are all basically smut filled money grabs, but then theres a group of people that insist they are some high level literature and insist that their brand of romance novel are the best books in the world and all books should be written like them because their brand is the only one that has a scantily clad women on the front and that is what makes a book good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40219310580.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Now you've gone so deep into your metaphor you've almost got my autistic brain thinking that if I can find one paperback romance novel (those are the only requirements you gave, you're just implicitly assuming that means bodice-rippers when you didn't say that, it just has to be romance-centered and fiction in paperback) that's actually well-written there's an allegory somehow Da-Vinci-Coded into its plot for what the perfect government system is</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
