<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506867875.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history.

Then why do we see more rights and accountability in systems like liberal democracies as opposed to military dictatorships?

If your view was consistent with reality, wouldn't we see relatively identical results from opposing systems?

Generally, when a government is formed by the people, it's priorities reflect the desires of the population rather than an individual  like in a dictatorship? You seem to be assuming an individual controlling everything creates the same outcomes as elections controlling everything and that self-interest is indistinct from outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506913844.0" user="Zoetje_Zuurtje" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then why do we see more rights and accountability in systems like liberal democracies as opposed to military dictatorships?

Because if you'd try to coup a stable democracy, the odds are stacked against you. It'd be hard as heck, maybe lead to a civil war, and any widespread destruction is guaranteed to destroy the very wealth it intended to capture - the wealth made by productive, educated, free citizens.

That leaves getting elected. If that's your goal, then granting more freedom absolutely can help.

Democracies are better to live in than democracy not because the leaders are saints, but because their incentives are, if not the same, at least _close_ to yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506945567.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, the incentives structures for leaders in different systems lead them to wildly different policy outcomes. In cases of military dictatorship, those outcomes are often in the best interests of the individual leader, not the country. Form of government is integral to whether or not the interests of a nation are pursued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506962610.0" user="Zoetje_Zuurtje" delta="False">
    <text>Then I might've misunderstood your OP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506977564.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>OP's argument is that nations always act in self-interest. This isn't true especially in cases where an individual controls policy outcomes rather than a collective. Otherwise, we are just assuming everything a government does is in the interest of the nation rather than whoever controls the government. Just because an action is taken doesn't mean it was in the best interests of a country or government. It may even be a perceived best interest while not being a best interest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506994547.0" user="Zoetje_Zuurtje" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, you're right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
