<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506954688.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. 

A country isn't a homogenous entity. It doesn't think or do anything. The people running the country will do what they think is best but the form of government is what determines who is running the country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507047182.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>until it doesn’t fully determine it …see myriad ways to fuck with democratic process: gerrymandering, electoral college and other things too nuanced for public discussion. and this is just in the “freeist country in the world”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507136894.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The electoral college and gerrymandering are part of the form of government in the US. I agree that they are problems but the point is that those methods of selecting government officials are not the same as in other countries and those differences matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507658702.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>they are not the same because there are literally infinite ways to do things. what im doing is making an effort (albeit probably quite useless effort) to find one unifying thing i can say about how all governments operate. really every government should be viewed as a unique “personality” and these boxes we try to fit them into are quite crude.

Just like labeling a person as “quiet” or “loud” or “bubbly” or “serious” they are quite useless labels at the end of the day and don’t help us understand the true workings within if we are truly trying to understand how people act on a deeper level</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507706548.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So is your view that opportunism is the only form of government that exists or is it that opportunism exists in all forms of government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507760153.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>it exists and is the over-arching predictor of most government action and policy if we need a descriptor for that

that the terms we use for “forms of government” are quite limited and really hold back a lot of productive discussion bc they are all trigger words at this point. same thing with terms like “socialism” and “communism”</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
