<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506985881.0" user="gandalf_el_brown" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”

Can be said the same for community leaders, tribe leaders, family elders, parental figures, elder siblings, the individual, etc.  People are opportunistic.  Great observation, what's your point and what's there to change your view on that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507023287.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>very true. i think its too nuanced of a point for mass adoption, but if anyone can spread this point maybe some change will happen?

no real point besides sharing something i realized lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507100714.0" user="gandalf_el_brown" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;spread this point maybe some change will happen

Change human behavior?  And if we can do that, change to what?  Perhaps communism could finally be achieved if humans weren't so opportunistic. The Soviet political experiment found out it's not possible to change human behavior by force. China has been attempting to do so through cultural change, but also having issues. 

The US is still struggling with effects from slavery and Jim crow laws. About 1/3 the population is against acknowledging this history.  We are slowly changing our culture, though it's always a constant battle with conservatives.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
