<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506848271.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>So you, clearly, would have no problem living in a dictatorship instead of a republic, right? Because there's no difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506876512.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>no, there are differences on paper. But the way real governments operate blur the lines much more than modern popular culture thinks. 

“Democracies, republics, dictatorships” throughout history have all done MANY things you can define as democratic or unilaterally dictative etc. the commonality at the end of the day is that they are out for themselves and will likely continue to perform actions that are in correspondence with this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506895135.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Are there actual differences or there only differences 'on paper'?

Like if your argument is that democracies occasionally do undemocratic things, yeah, sure, that happens occasionally. Do you think that dictators do more or less undemocratic things that democracies or republics?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506948697.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>i think these labels while currently necessary for discussion are crude at best and prohibit deeper analysis of how uniquely acting every government throughout history was/is

the best blanket statement you can make is well every government is self serving before they abide by what they say are their “national ideals”

Opportunism is a far truer label in practice than any other label.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507086414.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Are we talking about forms of government or 'national ideals'? Republics and democracies are forms of government, they're how the people in power get in power. There is nothing in there to indicate how those people will act when they get power, except perhaps to say they shouldn't try to change the form of government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507330566.0" user="Biptoslipdi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; no, there are differences on paper.

So you think an individual dictator would reach the same conclusions about policy action regarding the interests of a nation than a slate of elected officials and the judiciary that checks them?

Isn't that just assuming that any action a government takes, whether individual dictator or elected body, is in the national interest? Somehow government is always acting in the best interest of the nation, even if it collapses the nation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507636599.0" user="nonsensetheydbefine" delta="False">
    <text>Question:

&amp;gt; So you, clearly, would have no problem living in a dictatorship instead of a republic, right?

Your answer:

&amp;gt; no

You Changed Your View.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
