<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1826249911.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u7avg7/cmv_the_only_form_of_government_that_exists_is/">
    <title>CMV: The only form of government that exists is Opportunism</title>
    <original_poster>jerkularcirc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Everything else is just propaganda. History has proven time and time again that countries will always do/find a way to do what they think is in their best interest, quite irrespective of morality, laws, or even their own “constitution”. These labels of government and/or thinking one type of governing is always better than another is purely a result of propaganda and has been a great blinder throughout history. 

In group vs out group aka “us vs. them” thinking has been shown by research to be one of the best predictors of human thought and behavior and it has been utilized by those in power for much of human history to control the masses.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39506884601.0" user="absolutemagician" delta="False">
    <text>All governments prioritize their own national interest, and will sometimes do bad things in the name of national interest, so all government types are the same? In some ways, sure, but there are important differences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39506898943.0" user="jerkularcirc" delta="False">
    <text>they are not all the same, in fact they are all so uniquely different that these simple labels everyone uses dont fit, but the common denominator and the thing people should use to predict their behavior is looking at self interest.

it is much more an important factor than being a “democracy or dictatorship” on paper</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507097633.0" user="absolutemagician" delta="False">
    <text>Self interest is always a factor, but I don’t think it’s more or less important than the government system. They’re both essential to analyze if we want to understand why things are the way they are.  


To me, it’s like you’re saying that the most important factor in a strawberry banana smoothie is the banana lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39507649178.0" user="nonsensetheydbefine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; they are not all the same

Then you've Changed Your View.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
