<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564846753.0" user="thatmitchkid" delta="False">
    <text>The courts have decided that the KKK can march down the street spewing hate filled shit as long as it doesn't threaten violence.  How is it fundamentally different if they can do it on an internet platform?  Sure Twitter has the right to stop them from doing it but why is the world going to burn down when, practically speaking, they can just spread hate on a new website?  Do you have *that little* faith in your fellow citizens?

Maybe you do have that little faith, but KKK members still get to vote so you're stripping away one thing but leaving them with a far more powerful tool.  At that point, just leave &amp;amp; go somewhere you can trust the electorate.  Or throw democracy out the window &amp;amp; only let people vote who don't offend you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565185451.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between them sharing their repugnant views on fringe sites that everyday people have no clue about or in sad basements in rural America vs. platforming them on one of the biggest social media sites that gets millions of vists per day. Their influence is magnetized by allowing them on popular platforms. I have little faith because this already is happening in all the "Twitter alternatives" that don't moderate for hate speech or misinformation. Each and every time, the far-right overruns those sites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565942910.0" user="thatmitchkid" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Their influence is magnetized by allowing them on popular platforms.

This is not settled &amp;amp; is currently just an opinion.  Sociologists have not come to a consensus on deplatforming &amp;amp; they study this kind of thing for a living.  Some will tell you it's better to force some level of engagement with alternative views, others take your side.  

&amp;gt;this already is happening in all the "Twitter alternatives"

Because the kind of person who left for the alternatives is a different kind of person than the ones who stayed.  Maybe the temporary ban is the best of all worlds.  It shunted the super crazies somewhere else but the reachable ones will come back because the alternatives haven't reached critical mass.  Or maybe the temporary ban was the worst of all worlds because it pushed people who previously only had unconscious bias into full-on KKK nuts.  We just don't know because we haven't been doing it long enough.

What we have been doing a while is let people say what they want on public property &amp;amp; it's worked well enough that no one wants to change it.  The obvious answer is that it would work similarly with Twitter but maybe not, the obvious answer isn't always the correct one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39566018890.0" user="doge_gobrrt" delta="False">
    <text>it's actually amusing

elon is playing the far right like a deck of cards</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39566568506.0" user="AbolishDisney" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The courts have decided that the KKK can march down the street spewing hate filled shit as long as it doesn't threaten violence.

Just because it's the law doesn't mean I have to agree with it. The KKK's entire goal is to incite violence. As long as we continue to believe the myth of "peaceful Nazis", we'll continue to have incidents like [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlottesville_car_attack) on a regular basis.

&amp;gt; How is it fundamentally different if they can do it on an internet platform?

Social media sites aren't public spaces. The law says the KKK can march down the street, not that they can hold a rally in Walmart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39567201535.0" user="thatmitchkid" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t agree with freedom of speech?  I’m almost too afraid to ask, what should be the limits in your opinion?  Hurting someone’s feelings?  I’m guessing you don’t have a problem hurting the feelings of Disney executives.  Maybe just “hate speech?”  What if it’s only against serial killers?  What if they only killed 1 person but it was my mom?  What if they just said something very rude?  Which also begs the question, can I be rude?  What about crude?  Is it ok if it’s a joke?  Or is misinformation the line?  Who’s defining misinformation?  “Lab Leak” was racist &amp;amp; misinformation 2 years ago, now it’s mainstream; when did it become ok to say it?

For the second part, I never said twitter should be *forced* to allow freedom of speech.  I just think it’s a good idea for twitter, in the same way I think it’s a good idea for the country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39567784633.0" user="AbolishDisney" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You don’t agree with freedom of speech?

Unrestricted free speech already doesn't exist in the US. We have laws against threats, workplace harassment, intellectual property violations, false 911 calls, fraud, unauthorized legal advice, perjury, defamation, inciting suicide, conspiracy to commit a crime, and false advertising. Should these laws be changed?

&amp;gt; I’m almost too afraid to ask, what should be the limits in your opinion?

At the very least, the US should start treating domestic terrorist organizations the same way it treats foreign ones. Right now, what we have is a system of ridiculous double standards.

&amp;gt; Hurting someone’s feelings?

Would you describe the [Atomwaffen Division](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atomwaffen_Division)'s actions as merely "hurting someone's feelings"?

&amp;gt; I’m guessing you don’t have a problem hurting the feelings of Disney executives.

I'm threatening their copyrights, not their lives.

&amp;gt; Maybe just “hate speech?”

Refer to what I said above.

&amp;gt; What if it’s only against serial killers? What if they only killed 1 person but it was my mom? What if they just said something very rude? Which also begs the question, can I be rude? What about crude? Is it ok if it’s a joke?

These are all terrible analogies. Similar non sequiturs could be used to argue against almost *any* law. There are options besides "allow everything" and "allow nothing".

&amp;gt; Or is misinformation the line? Who’s defining misinformation? “Lab Leak” was racist &amp;amp; misinformation 2 years ago, now it’s mainstream; when did it become ok to say it?

Where did I mention misinformation?

&amp;gt; For the second part, I never said twitter should be *forced* to allow freedom of speech. I just think it’s a good idea for twitter, in the same way I think it’s a good idea for the country.

Then do you think it would be a good idea for Walmart to host KKK rallies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39567786111.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Atomwaffen Division](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atomwaffen_Division)** 
 
 &amp;gt;The Atomwaffen Division (Atomwaffen meaning "nuclear weapons" in German), also known as the National Socialist Order, is an international right-wing extremist and Neo-Nazi terrorist network. Formed in 2013 and based in the Southern United States, it has since expanded across the United States and into the United Kingdom, Canada, Germany, the Baltic states, and other European countries. The group is described as a part of the alt-right by some journalists, but it rejects the label and it is considered extreme even within that movement.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39569309225.0" user="thatmitchkid" delta="False">
    <text>In my head the questions after I asked for your limits were rhetorical, sorry for making it more confusing by including them.  I support the status quo on freedom of speech in the US, at this point, I haven't heard of a limit I disagree with.  The Atomwaffen Division sounds bad &amp;amp; should probably get increased surveillance but I don't want any additional limits on their speech.

Since I confused things, I'll ask the all important question again, **what are** ***your*** **limits**?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39580938899.0" user="AbolishDisney" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Since I confused things, I'll ask the all important question again, **what are *your* limits**?

You already asked this question. Was my last comment unclear?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
