<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564704882.0" user="MinuteReady" delta="False">
    <text>This is a bit of a catastrophization. At most, twitter will revert to how it was before politically controversial right-wingers were removed. It is unlikely that Musk is going to remove every rule from twitter, and twitter culture itself can only be influenced so much.

If anything, twitter will revert to 2015 rules. We've seen the 'hands-off' approach before. Though there is likely some valid concern in this changing of ownership, to say that twitter will become some ruleless wasteland of alt-righters is only a fear, and not a realistic outcome of what happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565252267.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>What made 2015 different was that it had an established socially-progressive user base to counteract some of the far-right elements. But with a right-wing figurehead buying up Twitter, the dynamics are way different and I don't think socially-progressive or non-fringe people are going to stick around for long.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
