<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564681819.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise.

Good.  Makes 'em easy to spot.  And it'll often force Republican officeholders to reluctantly condemn their own base.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564715835.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>What good is spotting them when platforming them will grow their membership? When you see a tumor growing, you don't just let it fester, you do something about it to contain and manage it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564812714.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What good is spotting them when platforming them will grow their membership?

It will just as likely shrink their membership, as people who would have previously been on the fence or casually supportive of those views suddenly find themselves having to firmly distance themselves from those views upon seeing the social backlash they earn when they're brought out into the light for everybody to see.

&amp;gt; When you see a tumor growing

Stay on topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564920570.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>I was on topic, I was using tumors as an analogy because that's what hate movements are... they're like social manifestations of cancer that only grow bigger without something to counteract it.

What makes you think "it will just as likely" shrink their membership? Twitter is a platform where you can block people and only follow people you want to follow. The far-right extremists will likely lock themselves in an information silo where they are only hearing from people who think like them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564986645.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What makes you think "it will just as likely" shrink their membership?

People who would have previously been on the fence or casually supportive of those views suddenly find themselves having to firmly distance themselves from those views upon seeing the social backlash they earn when they're brought out into the light for everybody to see.

&amp;gt; The far-right extremists will likely lock themselves in an information silo where they are only hearing from people who think like them.

No, that's what they're doing right now.  On Twitter they'll hear from everybody, whether they want to or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564955943.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty sure that was an analogy, not an unprompted detour into oncology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564974604.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape

Stay on topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564982549.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>They were very clearly talking about Twitter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564989645.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>You weren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565011819.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>If comments about whether something is off topic are off topic, what exactly are your last three comments?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565021052.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>An increasingly irritating waste of my time, same as this one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564834876.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt it. Leftist calls to violence are frequent on Twitter and it hasn't forced Democrat officeholders to condemn their base - they're able to still say that it doesn't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564970803.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't sound right at all. The Democratic party has had a huge problem as of late distancing itself from the crazies yelling Defund the Police on places like Twitter. Pretending it doesn't exist has not worked out all too well for them in the polls.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565093634.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Pretending it doesn't exist has not worked out all too well for them in the polls.

What was it that both Biden and Stalin said? It doesn't matter who votes, it's who counts the votes that matters. Guess what the Democrats have been trying to do for the past two years?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565162211.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>I'm kinda worried we're about to venture into conspiracy land, but I'll bite. What have the Democrats been doing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564999632.0" user="itsnotsemantics" delta="False">
    <text>That's because aside for a handful of exceptions (literally enough to count on one hand), Leftists don't vote for Democrat officeholders. 
 Thus, even if Democrat officeholders did condemn Leftist calls to violence, they wouldn't be condeming their base.  

Nobody spray-painting "ACAB" and calling for violence against SFPD also waited in line at the polls to vote for Nancy Pelosi.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
