<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564666080.0" user="DankLeader" delta="False">
    <text>While you’re right Musk doesn’t care about protecting marginalized groups, he does like money and power, which makes this outcome unlikely. Why?

Well Twitter didn’t just ban calls to violence out of the goodness of their heart. Especially now that there will be a before and after with clear contrast, if this starts to hapoen there will be many lawsuits against twitter for hate speech and calls for violence. Musk likes money, it seems doubtful he’ll part with more of it just so well known supremacists can be on his platform. He’s going to get them hype to pump the value of whatever he wants, and then probably forget about it and move on like he does with all his other toys. They’ll eat it up because it let’s them keep playing the victims, and because they know he’s more aligned with them in the long run anyway.

Hopefully this helps alleviate your fears!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564704342.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>Musk claimed he wasn't doing this for money and doesn't care about the economics of it. He has reiterated that he wants it to be "free speech" absolutist platform, just by his tweets today. So that means hate speech would be accepted under this and it doesn't seem like he cares all that much. He is basically creating a cult base that will become the fodder he needs to make even more money in ways beyond Twitter ad revenue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564806392.0" user="DankLeader" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you take him at face value when he says he doesn’t care about money, but you don’t take him at face value when he says all he wants is free-speech?

Like the other commenter worked out he needs to make money, if Twitter becomes that toxic people will leave, and he will be on the hook for a big load of money if that happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564834671.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>I'm taking him at face value both times: he claims he wants to allow all free speech under the law, which includes hate speech, and he says he doesn't care about the economics of this and wants this principle to remain intact. I am more than pleased to not take him at face value here, but I haven't seen any indications otherwise. Unless you can provide them to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564872535.0" user="DankLeader" delta="False">
    <text>You aren’t though, if he really means free-speech then nothing will change, you only worry because you understand its a dog whistle. That he can’t be talking about actual free-speech because that’s never been on the line. However, doesn’t that mean he could just make some meaningless performative change and say he’s done it? His sycophants will eat it up regardless. Why is it unlikely this is just Musk telling some lie to bring attention and value to his brands? It’s disgusting to pander to supremacists, sure, but why are you so sure he’s genuine about any of this when he so seldom is about anything?

Is there any sign he is ideologically driven from his actions and behavior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564964154.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>No. He said he is a free speech absolutist. He said he wants all free speech under the law to be tolerated on Twitter. That is a departure of pre-Musk Twitter, where hate speech is banned. So if he's intent on a "free speech absolutist" approach, it would mean no longer enforcing hate speech, which constitutes a change to how things have been done previously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565221770.0" user="DankLeader" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, well if you want to insist on trusting what Musk says I don’t really have anything to help assuage your fears</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
