<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39565216203.0" user="bobsagetsmaid" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The toxicity will get so bad that the most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. 

And go where?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565327142.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>Most Twitter users have other social media accounts as well. Reddit? Instagram? Who knows. Point is that Twitter will lose a sensible base of non-extremists if they plan on letting the far-right run rampant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565428262.0" user="bobsagetsmaid" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people will stop using Twitter. People are resistant to moving social media platforms - it's just a part of the human tendency to be a creature of habit. Twitter is the digital town square, and people won't leave.

People won't even go to a different platform to follow a content creator they supposedly enjoy watching. There's one particular former youtube personality who had just shy of a million followers - then he was banned. You go to his new page on Dlive and he has 86,000 followers. That means fully 90% of his former audience couldn't even be bothered to bookmark a different page to keep watching his content.

So with that in mind, it seems extremely unlikely that people will stop using twitter. They can't get the "twitter experience" anywhere else. No matter how much they scream and cry, they won't go anywhere. Elon knows it. He was so sure about it that he spent 44 billion dollars to buy it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565504083.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>That's because pre-Musk Twitter had moderation and prioritized the user experience by moderating against misinformation and hate speech. Under this new Twitter, if Musk stays on course with his "free speech absolutist" attitude, the entire culture of Twitter will change and it won't feel the same anymore. It would be equivalent to moving to another platform entirely. And don't be so sure that just because Twitter has big price tag that it will always remain that way. Many people hung their hopes on MySpace and Yahoo and MSN Messenger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565575867.0" user="bobsagetsmaid" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think people typically follow people who agree with them, or people who don't agree with them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565611971.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>The former. And that's exactly the issue. Without moderation, hate groups will congregate unchecked, leading to the radicalization of even more people. While pre-Musk Twitter was far from perfect, they at least made a more concerted effort to tamp down on hate groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565642702.0" user="bobsagetsmaid" delta="False">
    <text>Well hold on, now you're changing the argument. You said that people would leave if twitter let the far-right "run rampant". But we agree that people overwhelmingly create their own ideological echo chambers on twitter. So why would people care what experience other people have? Are you saying that people will leave twitter because they might allow what you call "far right" content, even though they will see no such content on their own feed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565680657.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people primarily only follow people they agree with. "Hate-following" is a big thing on Twitter, and there are people arguing there all the time. If we allow far-right to run rampant on Twitter, their views will only deepen because they will likely surround themselves with like-minded people. When they do engage with the larger public it won't be for purposes of a "free exchange of ideas". They will do what they always do, troll the demographics they despise, fill their inboxes with hate and sling around slurs and derogatory remarks. Twitter provides them the opportunity for them to sour the experience for everyone else and the ability to retreat to their own information silos. Nothing productive can be gained from this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39566230497.0" user="bobsagetsmaid" delta="False">
    <text>If you enforce draconian censorship rules on twitter to drive out what you perceive to be harmful opinions, they'll just congregate elsewhere. You accomplished little except to create yet another echo chamber. There are places far-right people go already. One major site is 4chan, and it doesn't seem to be going anywhere.

I would say that the issue is that as I mentioned, you're just creating yet another ideological echo chamber on the internet. That's the last thing we need. The best disinfectant is sunlight. If people post opinions you don't like on twitter, quote tweet them and provide a detailed debunking of why their argument is wrong. Maybe some people on that side will see it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
