<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564815818.0" user="LongLiveSmoove" delta="False">
    <text>You mean like how Reddit is a left wing hellscape? How Reddit mods and users brigade against anyone who commits thought crimes.

Will these people appear? Sure. The internet is full trolls but I don’t think that’s what people are afraid of. What I think you and others are afraid of is someone being able to present a view point that you don’t agree with. 

You’re afraid that you’ll potentially have to engage with someone you disagree with without an entire platform to back you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564977058.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>I'm literally on a sub called "Change My View", evidently I am not scared of encountering other viewpoints.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565000038.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565627215.0" user="SeattlePoliceOfficer" delta="False">
    <text>There is no worse censorship than you will find right here on Reddit. It all goes in one direction. Same as all major media. Those in power fear losing this power and control, that's all this talk is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39568474198.0" user="platinumrelictime" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You mean like how Reddit is a left wing hellscape? 

Lol this classic right wing victim complex. You're not being oppressed because people are allowed to hold opposing views to you. 

Shall we look at a few of the subreddits that have been banned and why:

* r/beatingwomen, *'The community, which featured graphic depictions of violence against women, was banned after its moderators were found to be sharing users' personal information online, and collaborating to protect one another from sitewide bans.'*
* r/niggers, r/coontown, r/shitniggerssay, AKA the "Chimpire" (refers to a collection of subreddits and affiliated websites that promoted anti-black racism), *'In June 2013, the subreddit* r/niggers *was banned from Reddit for engaging in vote manipulation, incitements of violence and using racist content to disrupt other communities. Reddit general manager Erik Martin noted that the subforum was given multiple chances to comply with site rules'*
* r/fatpeoplehate *'hosted photos of overweight people (mostly women) for the purpose of mockery\[...\] A Reddit admin said, "We will ban subreddits that allow their communities to use the subreddit as a platform to harass individuals'*
* r/jailbait *'featured provocative shots of underage teenagers, became the chosen "subreddit of the year" in the "Best of reddit" user poll in 2008 and at one point making "jailbait" the second most common search term for the site. Erik Martin, general manager of Reddit, defended the jailbait subreddit by saying that such controversial pages were a consequence of allowing free speech on the site.'*

The interesting thing to note is that most of these subs weren't even banned due their hatefulness or 'thought crimes' as you put it. Subs like r/niggers were actually given multiple warnings and allowed to continue, but only FINALLY shut down after they continued breaking policy over targeted harassment and active incitement of violence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
