<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564786318.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>The problem isn’t the lack of censorship. The problem is algorithms designed to to fuel addiction through 1. tunneling people into silos of information that provide a narrow rather than broad view and 2. Driving clicks through thinks that fire our sense of outrage. 

Without the algorithms that all the socials use to cause addiction, free speech is a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564818054.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>Algorithms or not, Twitter is a platform that allows you to see the posts of everyone you follow. You don't need to explore what's Trending, you can just see the feed of your chosen accounts. The natural result of this is there will be inevitable silos of information anyways. Allowing more disinformation and more hateful content onto the platform provides nothing of value, and certainly nothing that can be described as a "good thing", considering this dynamic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
