<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1835287404.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ucokto/cmv_twitter_will_be_transformed_into_a_rightwing/">
    <title>CMV: Twitter will be transformed into a right-wing hellscape</title>
    <original_poster>newleafsauce</original_poster>
    <original_post>I fear Twitter will become yet another fringe, conspiracy-fuelled and bigoted platform like all the sites that don't moderate for misinformation or hate speech. User enjoyability will plummet and the loudest and most active sect will be those who ordinarily would be banned under the pre-Musk terms &amp;amp; conditions. 

Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. What does this mean? This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world. They will be allowed to brigade and hate on any Twitter user who belongs to the identities they despise. And their victims can't do anything meaningful about it except to spend hours blocking harrasing accounts / DMs or to leave the platform entirely.  

The toxicity will get so bad that the  most socially-progressive people and people with non-fringe views will likely leave. Twitter will skew heavily right-wing and far-right fast under Musk. 

If you can say anything to alleviate my fears and predictions, I would be open to hearing it so I can have my mind changed on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39564691255.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Musk has expressed his intentions today to transform Twitter into a site that allows all free speech under the law. 

Maybe you should take a second and ask yourself why you're afraid of free speech and what that says about you. 

&amp;gt;This means white supremacists, incels, misogynists, conspiracy theorists, science denialists, and anti-LGBT zealots, among other far-right groups will be able to promote the most repugnant content and disinformation, and grow their respective movements, which will inevitably spill over into the real world.

They were already doing that. They were already doing that on Twitter. You're kidding yourself if you think that Twitter wasn't already a cesspool or was very good at moderating its content. But the cool thing about Twitter is that you can control what content you come into contact with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564764772.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying pre-Musk Twitter was perfect, but they at least made an attempt to ban hateful content and inciting content, which they did with some notable high-profile bans and thousands of other bans that don't reach the news. This undoubtedly made Twitter less toxic than your average right-wing "Twitter alternative". 

What does it say about me that I don't tolerate white supremacist viewpoints? It says to me that I don't tolerate movements who would have me killed if they had their way. I have no problem with tolerating most viewpoints, so long it is not hate speech. That is my red line, because I don't see how you can tolerate the intolerant (Popper's paradox).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564791322.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not saying pre-Musk Twitter was perfect, but they at least made an attempt to ban hateful content and inciting content, which they did with some notable high-profile bans and thousands of other bans that don't reach the news. 

Dude the Taliban have multiple accounts on Twitter. They're really not trying that hard. 

&amp;gt;What does it say about me that I don't tolerate white supremacist viewpoints?

What does it say about you that you equate free speech to white supremacist viewpoints? 

&amp;gt;It says to me that I don't tolerate movements who would have me killed if they had their way.

Again, the Taliban are still on Twitter. Were you quaking in your boots before Musk announced he'd purchased the company? 

&amp;gt;I have no problem with tolerating most viewpoints, so long it is not hate speech.

What is hate speech? 

&amp;gt;That is my red line, because I don't see how you can tolerate the intolerant. 

It's pretty easy, you just ignore people saying things you don't like. It's like how I don't follow the Taliban on Twitter and the fact that the Taliban is on Twitter has very little effect on my life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564896808.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>If you're looking for consistency, I have no problem having the Taliban kicked off from Twitter. But you're arguing for free speech absolutism, which means evidently you don't want them kicked off. What does that say about me and what does that say about you?

Hate speech is the advocacy of hatred and promotion of discrimination, and vilification of protected classes of people, such as based on race, sexual orientation, gender, etc.

I can't just "ignore" the platforming of far-right extremists on one of the most influential social media sites. I know that their platforming on this site will lead to them recruiting more people into their twisted ideologies. As their movements grow, it will have real-world consequences. That's why I can't ignore it, and that's why I don't consider them to have "little effect" on my life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39564942477.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>I always have to suspect that people like this are privately really racist. "We can't let people hear racist screeds because they're just too persuasive!" Uh, not to the average person they're not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565009677.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>This requires the assumption we're all using the same facts and decorum, like in a proper academic debate setting. In reality, people make stuff up, craft disinformation, promote false stories and people get hoodwinked into believing them. The average person doesn't even read past the headline. It is very easy for people to become radicalized into fringe movements without moderation. To suggest otherwise flies in the face of human history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565028933.0" user="ToucanPlayAtThatGame" delta="False">
    <text>People also get radicalized *by* moderation. To the conspiracy-minded, it sure looks a lot like an orchestrated cover-up of the truth.

I think the track record of free speech is historically a lot more defensible than that of censorship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565150686.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>But there has to be balance. No guidelines or moderation is anarchy and unproductive. It pushes out the sensible voices and leaves the fringe in its wake. We can strike a balance that actually bolsters public discourse, and that's in the form of sensible terms &amp;amp; conditions we all agree to abide by.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565430475.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you're looking for consistency, I have no problem having the Taliban kicked off from Twitter.

But you're not bemoaning the descent of Twitter into Islamism and violence, despite the fact that the Taliban continue to remain on Twitter. 

&amp;gt;Hate speech is the advocacy of hatred and promotion of discrimination, and vilification of protected classes of people, such as based on race, sexual orientation, gender, etc.

Which classes of people are protected from speech? Who determines what a protected class on Twitter is? Elon Musk? 

&amp;gt;I can't just "ignore" the platforming of far-right extremists on one of the most influential social media sites. 

I mean you can. In the same way, you've ignored the platforming of the Taliban. 

&amp;gt;I know that their platforming on this site will lead to them recruiting more people into their twisted ideologies. 

Oh so just like the Taliban? Who again have yet to be kicked off Twitter and have sparked no fear or anger from you. 

&amp;gt; As their movements grow, it will have real-world consequences.

Like the abuse of millions of women and LGBTQ people in Afghanistan. 

&amp;gt;That's why I can't ignore it, and that's why I don't consider them to have "little effect" on my life.

Seems like you've been doing a pretty good job so far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39565466875.0" user="newleafsauce" delta="False">
    <text>The Taliban are far-right extremists so my critique of far-right extremism would encompass that group as well. Religious zealots who are misogynists and anti-LGBT pretty much describes far-right extremism to a tee.

Nothing about what I said implied I ignored far-right extremism before Musk acquired Twitter. I am merely saying that far-right extremism will be even more difficult to tackle if this "free speech absolutist" attitutde continues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39594265162.0" user="Odd_Profession_2902" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s clear OP is against the taliban being on twitter and wants them removed.

OP is saying that he doesn’t want *more* cases like the taliban being on twitter which will happen when twitter loosens its grip on moderation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39568389869.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39568304664.0" user="Boomerwell" delta="False">
    <text>I do fear free speech because people in power like Trump was can spur morons to commit violence.

Idk why there is this idea that freedom always equals correct.  Twitter has always had the right to free speech there were just consequences if you did some bad shit with it.

The idea that people in power can say whatever they want without these consequences is just dangerous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39568391419.0" user="platinumrelictime" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Maybe you should take a second and ask yourself why you're afraid of free speech and what that says about you.

What a disingenuous take. The only forms of censorship that have ever been discussed are against dangerous misinformation campaigns and nasty bigoted hate speech inciting violence etc. 

Free speech in the absolute would also require that people aren't even banned for advocating things like pedophilia or sharing illegal child porn on Twitter *(have you ever been to 4chan /b? Because that is what ultimate free speech looks like)*. So I find it exceptionally hard to believe that you actually support total free speech as much as you claim to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
