<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1844554756.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ui77k4/cmv_weve_all_been_trained_to_believe_were/">
    <title>CMV: We've all been trained to believe we're supposed to look a certain way, that is the lie that enslaves us</title>
    <original_poster>umikumi</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just realized this, just now.  I was typing to this girl on relationship advice about her bf criticizing her weight, but its something I've been searching for, for a very long time.  There's this book, Ishmael by Daniel Quinn.  He wrote about how we are all in a cage.  A cage of our own making built, more or less, on false narratives.... these are the bars of the cage.

Ok, so, do you ever feel like something is wrong all the time, but you can't put your finger on what it is?  This is the thing.  Bo Burnham's inside has this song.... how the world works, in it he has some lyrics "false narrative" and "entrenched" for example...(I'm referencing the song so people can look it up and I don't have to go into great detail here).  

What this boils down to is that we are entrenched in a war of narratives, many false; and those narratives are controlling a lot of people's actions, and those people are going out and physically controlling other people.  These two source materials alone give a general explanation of these points with individual perspectives.  But nobody explained how to escape.  It is so hard to see the ever shifting bars, the ever changing narrative - will we go to heaven or hell.  But there is truth beyond the narratives - in nature there is truth.  Trees produce oxygen, that is undeniable.  Yet someone can convince people to cut down all the trees.  Women are the arbiters of life, yet someone can convince people to control women's bodies.

It's because, when we are children, we are taught that everything is supposed to look a certain way; and children will believe whatever you tell them.  So people figured out that you can just lie to children and they will believe you, you can say, "everyone needs to look this way" and they will believe you and kill everyone who looks different.

I've been studying this for a long time, this is certainly what is happening.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39623262958.0" user="Sexpistolz" delta="False">
    <text>Your post is confusing but I’ll respond to the first part.

What attributes we are attracted to depend on the cultural/biological meaning behind them. Early on biological healthy features were favored for reproduction. While still true, as societies formed, economic and other cultural influences made impact. In many cultures light skin was favored because it meant you weren’t a poor person working in the fields. In Ancient Greece small penis were favored on statues as bruteness to woo a woman was viewed inferior to intellect and charisma. In some being fat meant you could afford an abundance of food. Today, well-groomed, suits etc are associated with well paying jobs and higher status. 

Is it bulletproof assessment? No. But if you care about status and responsibility chances are you’d favor someone well-groomed over someone that looks like they just climbed out of a dumpster. Healthier people in general are always going to be viewed more attractively, all things equal would you prefer someone in good health or bad health.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39623314941.0" user="umikumi" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so I'm talking about people who are trying to convince us to ignore our biological realities in favor of the narrative they would feed us.  Here's an example:

it's 1200 AD, you live in a castle, you have a great wife, and kids and a mistress, and a bunch of servants and spend most of your time hunting and telling people what to do.  Then, one day, someone arrives on your doorstep and says, "give all this up and trekk 10,000 miles across the desert with me to kill people you have never met before".  Do you go?

What if the man says, "God's only son was murdered by these infidels and if you want to go to heave you have to go reclaim the holy land with me?"  because that was called the Crusades.  

A guy just made up a really great sounding story over a long time and convinced thousands of people to cross a desert to do his bidding.

And we're all still crossing deserts for no reason today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39646599534.0" user="Sexpistolz" delta="False">
    <text>The fuck you just write?

Probably not. Most crusaders went looking for fortune and prosperity thus the Crusader States and lords. As you described I seem to be doing pretty well. But maybe I want a bigger castle. Maybe I don't Like my liege. Am I at war with another  another lord? There's advantages fighting an enemy 10k away rather than my neighbor. Think you picked a poor example and are naive about many of the details of the conflicts. If anything I think you would want to use the First Crusade, more specifically the people's crusade which was 11th century.

Being attracted to fit healthy people is not world-wide ploy of a secret society. That IS our biological reality. It has been consistent throughout history. Now if you have an example of people NOT being attracted to fit, healthy, prosperity. I'd be open to hear about it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
