<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1844554756.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ui77k4/cmv_weve_all_been_trained_to_believe_were/">
    <title>CMV: We've all been trained to believe we're supposed to look a certain way, that is the lie that enslaves us</title>
    <original_poster>umikumi</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just realized this, just now.  I was typing to this girl on relationship advice about her bf criticizing her weight, but its something I've been searching for, for a very long time.  There's this book, Ishmael by Daniel Quinn.  He wrote about how we are all in a cage.  A cage of our own making built, more or less, on false narratives.... these are the bars of the cage.

Ok, so, do you ever feel like something is wrong all the time, but you can't put your finger on what it is?  This is the thing.  Bo Burnham's inside has this song.... how the world works, in it he has some lyrics "false narrative" and "entrenched" for example...(I'm referencing the song so people can look it up and I don't have to go into great detail here).  

What this boils down to is that we are entrenched in a war of narratives, many false; and those narratives are controlling a lot of people's actions, and those people are going out and physically controlling other people.  These two source materials alone give a general explanation of these points with individual perspectives.  But nobody explained how to escape.  It is so hard to see the ever shifting bars, the ever changing narrative - will we go to heaven or hell.  But there is truth beyond the narratives - in nature there is truth.  Trees produce oxygen, that is undeniable.  Yet someone can convince people to cut down all the trees.  Women are the arbiters of life, yet someone can convince people to control women's bodies.

It's because, when we are children, we are taught that everything is supposed to look a certain way; and children will believe whatever you tell them.  So people figured out that you can just lie to children and they will believe you, you can say, "everyone needs to look this way" and they will believe you and kill everyone who looks different.

I've been studying this for a long time, this is certainly what is happening.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39623081406.0" user="hashtagboosted" delta="False">
    <text>Very vague post, I would go into more detail about what the specific look is, and what the alternatives are. I have no clue what you mean</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39623210787.0" user="umikumi" delta="False">
    <text>idelta 

I don't know if I'm doing this right, trying to be more specific, I was going to edit but I'm not sure if it starts to make not sense.. it's kind of a complex topic:

There is an argument by Daniel Quinn who wrote Ishmael that we are all living in a cage, but not a physical cage, an invisible one made up of people who force you to do what they want and use physical means to do so.  
Ok, we have all been taught that we are supposed to look a certain way both in our physical bodies and our actions, however those narratives about how we are supposed to look are not universal, so it becomes complex in the breakdown.    
We are taught too love things that look one way and hate things that look another and we tend to this automatically and without question.  People tend to automatically believe what they are told unless they are given reason not to.  People who go through trauma, who hear one thing and see another, who see people living in different circumstances with their own eyes and maybe those who read about it... start to question, but it is an actual event that causes the questioning.  
For example, nazis believed everyone had to be white christians; and the KKK believe white people are supposed to be in positions of power over black people; and almost all americans believe people should be clean.   There is not one narrative.  The point is not what the narrative is, but that many narratives are false.  
Very smart people have been trying for a long time, to make one narrative, and have not succeeded yet, but some have come closer than others.  The narrative is - things that look this way are good and things that look that way are bad, how you feel about it doesn't matter, don't listen to your feelings/thoughts/experiences listen to me.  
How to tell a false narrative from a real narrative becomes a question.  How many people care, another question.  How much force can those who convince others to believe their narrative a third question.    
Why do people believe they are allowed to force others who are not harming them, to do things?  I have heard various arguments, might makes right, god's will, they are bad... people sort of trying on excuses and points of view as they would a set of cloths.  Like the emperors new cloths.  I don't know how to explain it in a specific way that doesn't take an essay or book.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39623839288.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I don't know how to explain it in a specific way that doesn't take an essay or book.

That is often a problem of not understanding a topic well enough. I've read what you've said in this post so far, and I'm struggling to see what you're getting.

My guess would be that you're talking about how we should follow reality, and not artificial concepts or something? Many artifical concepts are important, but most concepts have some connection to reality.

Take your crusades examples: The zealous belief in god might have been what landed the person their castle, wife, mistress and kids. A belief that muslims would destroy Christianity (and christians) is a very rational reason to go on the crusades for example. Many went for desire of loot/land, that's rational too.

&amp;gt; people sort of trying on excuses and points of view as they would a set of cloths.

We're not omipotent, changing your views is an important part of growing, not just in knowledge, but as a foundation for views later in life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39638027966.0" user="babycam" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Daniel Quinn who wrote Ishmael

Great book.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
