<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1844554756.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ui77k4/cmv_weve_all_been_trained_to_believe_were/">
    <title>CMV: We've all been trained to believe we're supposed to look a certain way, that is the lie that enslaves us</title>
    <original_poster>umikumi</original_poster>
    <original_post>I just realized this, just now.  I was typing to this girl on relationship advice about her bf criticizing her weight, but its something I've been searching for, for a very long time.  There's this book, Ishmael by Daniel Quinn.  He wrote about how we are all in a cage.  A cage of our own making built, more or less, on false narratives.... these are the bars of the cage.

Ok, so, do you ever feel like something is wrong all the time, but you can't put your finger on what it is?  This is the thing.  Bo Burnham's inside has this song.... how the world works, in it he has some lyrics "false narrative" and "entrenched" for example...(I'm referencing the song so people can look it up and I don't have to go into great detail here).  

What this boils down to is that we are entrenched in a war of narratives, many false; and those narratives are controlling a lot of people's actions, and those people are going out and physically controlling other people.  These two source materials alone give a general explanation of these points with individual perspectives.  But nobody explained how to escape.  It is so hard to see the ever shifting bars, the ever changing narrative - will we go to heaven or hell.  But there is truth beyond the narratives - in nature there is truth.  Trees produce oxygen, that is undeniable.  Yet someone can convince people to cut down all the trees.  Women are the arbiters of life, yet someone can convince people to control women's bodies.

It's because, when we are children, we are taught that everything is supposed to look a certain way; and children will believe whatever you tell them.  So people figured out that you can just lie to children and they will believe you, you can say, "everyone needs to look this way" and they will believe you and kill everyone who looks different.

I've been studying this for a long time, this is certainly what is happening.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39624442791.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39624591805.0" user="umikumi" delta="False">
    <text>Um....Not everyone acts out of fear of retribution.  Some people face actual retribution.  Powerful people generally know how to avoid retribution.  Also, I'm not sure how you're trying to change my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39624602212.0" user="studiostudioo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry - I was agreeing not trying to change your mind!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39624628885.0" user="umikumi" delta="False">
    <text>very cool, it sounded like you agree.  I'm not a docile body though, I'm having a fun debate about how much harm I can sustain and how much change is worth it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39657604004.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/studiostudioo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20studiostudioo&amp;amp;message=studiostudioo%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ui77k4/-/i7bdbqf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
