<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="185873319.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/32nwrr/cmv_google_chrome_is_better_than_mozilla_firefox/">
    <title>CMV: Google Chrome is better than Mozilla Firefox</title>
    <original_poster>zer0t3ch</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, this is an all-encompassing opinion, not a statement of fact. I am in no way saying that Chrome is technologically superior or anything of that nature, it's just.... well..... *better*.

# My reasons

* **Chrome is more secure**
 * as far as I can tell, this is basically undeniable fact. Tab sandboxing being the most obvious feature, but there also hasn't been an vital exploit (that I'm aware of) in years
* **Better technology support**
 * I haven't checked in a while, but Chrome always seems the fastest to adopt new technologies, which is great as both a consumer and a developer
* **Ease-of-use**
 * As an end-user, this one is key. I install Chrome, I'm good to go. Get an Android phone with Chrome; Log in on both, now everything is synced. Want to see currently opened tabs? Great. It's just so simple and streamlined. (Coincidentally I'm a Linux user who hates Apple for the exact reason of making things "just work")
* **Chrome Apps/Extensions**
 * From what I can tell, Chrome has a lot more people developing for it's web store, while Firefox's add-ons site is dated and minimally supported. Also, from what I understand, Firefox completely lacks any "Apps" and while I understand why not everyone can agree that this is an inherent con, I regularly use apps such as SSH, VNC, Google Play Music (for the mini player), and Hangouts.
* **Development**
 * I know FF has a lot of developer tools, as does Chrome. I honestly haven't used FF for development in years, so I have no basis as to which is better.

---

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27715771026.0" user="Rikvidr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Better technology support

&amp;gt;Chrome is faster to adopt new technologies

Yeah, Google technologies...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27715793780.0" user="zer0t3ch" delta="False">
    <text>Google made HTML5 and CSS3? News to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27717112322.0" user="justregisteredtosay" delta="False">
    <text>In a way, yes. As did Mozilla, Microsoft, Apple, and many other companies. They, and many others, are all [W3C members](http://www.w3.org/Consortium/Member/List). They all have input on the features that make it into technologies such as HTML and CSS.

[EME](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Encrypted_Media_Extensions) for example is something that Google needed for serving copy protected video on YouTube with HTML5. It's a form of DRM though, which goes against Mozilla's beliefs, so it's taken some time for Mozilla to come up with some compromise on how to add it to Firefox. In the end they went with using a plugin from Adobe([Primetime Decryption Module](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-drm)) to enable EME, and OpenH264 Video Codec from Cisco to enable the playback in Firefox in recent versions.

Google pushes many features that it needs for it's own web services. So naturally they are going to be ahead of the pack in supporting those specific features.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
