<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1860088617.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/urg5k9/cmv_we_dont_possess_a_rational_mind_only_to/">
    <title>CMV: We don't possess a rational mind only to sometimes think irrationally, and we don't evolve to get here only for some of us to feel complacent not to go any further at anything.</title>
    <original_poster>rtanada</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't know, it just doesn't come to me that these faults of irrationality and not wanting to improve still exist within us all. The cause of basically all the world's issues, why we never get stuff done, the one thing holding us all back. What's more perplexing is the very attempt at fixing these "faults" is seen as something very detrimental. 

A case of tall poppy syndrome? Is this the limit of our improvement? Is there some sort of a kill switch preventing us from becoming uncontrolled? Is rationality in fact the undesirable byproduct of evolution? We're given opportunity to be awesome and the right ways to get there, and we just reject them? I just need to understand what I've been missing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39721377691.0" user="JiEToy" delta="False">
    <text>Where do you see that we have stopped improving? Because I don't see a huge stagnation in improvement at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721397722.0" user="rtanada" delta="False">
    <text>Not stagnation in science, biology, nothing. It's just some people are just okay with not doing anything helpful, maybe as a way to give something back. As well as not doing anything beneficial, in fact, they are more than willing to do evil just for kicks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721580833.0" user="JiEToy" delta="False">
    <text>Well, yeah. People are different, and our traits go all across the spectrum. I can't convince you there aren't any lazy people, any bad people.

However, if you think this is a large part of our population, then I think you are wrong, and you're seeing acts of bad people as defining of the person's wants and needs, while they might not be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
