<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1860088617.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/urg5k9/cmv_we_dont_possess_a_rational_mind_only_to/">
    <title>CMV: We don't possess a rational mind only to sometimes think irrationally, and we don't evolve to get here only for some of us to feel complacent not to go any further at anything.</title>
    <original_poster>rtanada</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't know, it just doesn't come to me that these faults of irrationality and not wanting to improve still exist within us all. The cause of basically all the world's issues, why we never get stuff done, the one thing holding us all back. What's more perplexing is the very attempt at fixing these "faults" is seen as something very detrimental. 

A case of tall poppy syndrome? Is this the limit of our improvement? Is there some sort of a kill switch preventing us from becoming uncontrolled? Is rationality in fact the undesirable byproduct of evolution? We're given opportunity to be awesome and the right ways to get there, and we just reject them? I just need to understand what I've been missing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39721330913.0" user="HerbertWigglesworth" delta="False">
    <text>Depends whether you want more or not, and whether you sometimes want to be irrational or not - how this manifests itself is somewhat subjective, you would need to understand what the subject was knowledgeable about and what they desired.

What are we defining as irrational, what are we defining as complacency? 

If someone is happy and does not seek more than they have, why get all bothered about it. We are not robots programmed to optimise existence 24/7 via an instruction manual, there isn’t one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721366851.0" user="rtanada" delta="False">
    <text>I just believe what people make or do for the society around them is the test on whether whatever they do is sane and enough. 

And then there's such thing as too much. Then there's subjectivity.

And then a part of me just thinks more is more and that there has to be a objective good in some way.

I might be wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721448439.0" user="HerbertWigglesworth" delta="False">
    <text>You could argue people have an obligation to ensure that their benefits to society outweigh their negatives, that positive impacts and promoted, and that negatives avoided where possible.

Beyond that applying any scale on expectations is somewhat difficult outside of a specific role such as your job, where expectations and responsibilities are clearly defined. More generally, obviously the socio-economics and political framework of a given community impacts agency here, but again, to apply levels such as ‘you contribute X to GDP’ kind of gets complicated.

Anecdotally I am almost equally grateful for the neighbour who speaks to me and is helpful, as is the one who leaves me alone undisturbed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
