<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1860088617.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/urg5k9/cmv_we_dont_possess_a_rational_mind_only_to/">
    <title>CMV: We don't possess a rational mind only to sometimes think irrationally, and we don't evolve to get here only for some of us to feel complacent not to go any further at anything.</title>
    <original_poster>rtanada</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't know, it just doesn't come to me that these faults of irrationality and not wanting to improve still exist within us all. The cause of basically all the world's issues, why we never get stuff done, the one thing holding us all back. What's more perplexing is the very attempt at fixing these "faults" is seen as something very detrimental. 

A case of tall poppy syndrome? Is this the limit of our improvement? Is there some sort of a kill switch preventing us from becoming uncontrolled? Is rationality in fact the undesirable byproduct of evolution? We're given opportunity to be awesome and the right ways to get there, and we just reject them? I just need to understand what I've been missing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39721348598.0" user="alfihar" delta="False">
    <text>Ok.. so im not 100% sure what view it is you want changed... but it seems to be something along the lines of we arent rational because we cant seem to get it together as a species.

First an easy one.  Evolution does NOT have a goal and has no desires. It cares nothing for our ideas of "progress" and any increase in complexity is more of a side effect than some end product. 

So as far as evolution by natural selection is concerned.. that we are here at all indicates we have desirable traits for passing on genes. 

I think the problem with why cant we get it together has a short simple answer, that is however also unfortunately extremely unsatisfying.

As a veteran of leftist infighting, I feel comfortable in saying that the reason those who want to make the world a better place cant organise to solve the worlds issues is because almost everyone has a slightly different idea of what the problems are, which ones we should be focusing on, what a solution would look like, and how to get to that solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721387792.0" user="rtanada" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First an easy one. Evolution does NOT have a goal and has no desires. It cares nothing for our ideas of "progress" and any increase in complexity is more of a side effect than some end product. 

Fair point.

&amp;gt;the reason those who want to make the world a better place cant organise to solve the worlds issues

Just can't argue with that, except right now I'm struggling with the thought of trying to help these "lost" individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39721472699.0" user="alfihar" delta="False">
    <text>So I feel your pain... Ive been thinking about these problems for a really long time... enought to go study political science and ethics at uni and still have no solution.

Ive spent a lot of time just trying to even get an grip on what the problems are let alone come up with a good way of resolving them. 

Some problems are specific, like some event etc, and they are usually somewhat straight forward.  Other more complex issues are to do with systems we have set up which result in negative consequences for parts of our society like our economic systems or gender roles or political structure.  Too many people act as if some of these things are natural or forget that any system we made we can change. 

Then there are the really difficult ones which are more to do with us as individuals and how we treat each other.  

I came across a quote a while ago which summed up an issue I have encountered over and over regardless of which issue was being discussed. 

"I dont know how to explain to you that you're supposed to care about other people."

And that really is the issue a lot of the time... I keep coming across people that just dont seem to give a shit about others, which feels totally insane to me, but also makes most of my arguments useless because they rely on actually caring about other people.  

So this is kinda where im at now. Trying to understand why some people feel that way and what if any ways of framing issue or appeals to ethical positions can make a person actually care about the welfare of someone else if it doesnt help then in any way but indirectly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
