<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753800514.0" user="MooliCoulis" delta="False">
    <text>Given our limited perspective and your fuzzy memory, let's assume the statement you responded to could have amounted to any of:

- every white person should feel personal responsibility for this person's actions
- white people should acknowledge that many of their everyday actions/inactions sustain the culture that cultivated this tragedy
- to the extent that they identify with their race, white people should feel shame that a white person committed these actions under the influence of a mindset that's common among white people

You've heard the former. I think that's the weakest position of the three, which makes me think that:

- it's the least likely to be the intended one
- you might have heard it _because_ it's the weakest; you were primed to find fault in what the commenter was saying

So, I think you should change your view by adopting the principle of charity: When you interpret a statement, consider all the possible intents the speaker could plausibly have had, and choose the strongest one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753826697.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I was able to resurrect the comment using Unddit. I posted it in the edit. My memory was actually on point for once.

The statement was specifically your first bullet, pretty unambiguously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753848247.0" user="MooliCoulis" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think it's implausible that they could have intended either of the other two meanings I suggested?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753868298.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, for sure, even the structure of the statements are nearly the same:

&amp;gt;every white person should feel personal responsibility for this person's actions

Part of comment for comparison:

&amp;gt;they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754058252.0" user="MooliCoulis" delta="False">
    <text>It's kind of telling that you went straight to sentence structure. It speaks to an attitude of: "I can make a grammatical case so strong, it'll override whatever thoughts might exist in that person's head".

Friend, English is full of shorthand and metaphor and irony and malapropisms. If you want to understand what someone was **intending to communicate**, take your lawyer hat off and put your empathy hat on, because I think it's obvious to anyone who's interested in authentically communicating - not just being right on the internet - that any of the three interpretations in my original comment are plausible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754232550.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what I'm doing though, that "sentence structure" argument was just adding to my point. My primary point is they are explicitly saying that white people should feel guilt because a white person did something bad. 

I believe guilt doesn't *do* anything and we should instead focus on solutions to the problems which the OP was not saying at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755507553.0" user="prepend" delta="False">
    <text>The original comment was deleted and the poster isn’t around to ask for clarity. It’s only reasonable to judge the statement based on what was written as that’s the best way to know intent. Guess about intent that contradicts what is written is impossible to reconcile as the person could be thinking anything and we only know what they wrote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758453936.0" user="6___-4--___0" delta="False">
    <text>That's why they said to make a choice to infer in the most charitable way possible</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755563174.0" user="Vuelhering" delta="False">
    <text>Is it telling that the comment matched nearly exactly what you called the weakest of the arguments?

I see nothing "telling", that is, betraying a lack of understanding or a hidden agenda, in noting it clearly was a similar sentence with a similar intent using similar loading of words. If the person meant one of the other things, they didn't communicate it and instead assigned blame just like the first statement.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
