<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755168616.0" user="RaisinBranKing" delta="False">
    <text>OP would you feel comfortable if I shared this in r/WhitePeopleTwitter ?  Would be interesting to see what members think about it.

To make sure I follow CMV rules in this post I have to criticize your view so I will argue that what you were saying is not exactly the "opposite" of white fragility because generally people who subscribe to the Robin Diangelo view think that white people today are still complicit in systems that are deeply racist.  In other words, no white person is "innocent".  That's not something I agree with at all, but yeah I think what you're saying isn't quite the "opposite" in a technical sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755187609.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Yea for sure but as it contains previously banned content you might get banned yourself. I would be careful with that. 

By the way I agree that white people are complicit in systemic racism simply by continuing to exist in society so I guess I'm more extreme than you in this regard. I'm not claiming innocence on that. I'm claiming that white (or any immutable characteristic) as a group are not responsible for the actions of an individual white person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755257920.0" user="RaisinBranKing" delta="False">
    <text>Oh true they would probably ban me as well.  Nevermind.  

Oh interesting.  Let me try to understand your thinking if you don’t mind this side bar.  Why stop at one person?  If we aren’t responsible for one person’s actions, what about two?  What about 100?  What about a thousand?  What about 100 million?  What is the number of people where we become complicit in their actions?  

I could understand the argument for being complicit in climate change by driving a gas car for example.  Yes my impact is extremely small, but it’s still nonzero and I’m part of the problem.  But that’s a problem that is clearly defined and has actionable measures to fight.  I struggle to see systemic racism in the same light.  What is an example of a specific system which you participate like the gas car example and what is the solution that you’re failing to implement?  With climate change it’s that you aren’t carbon neutral.  What is it for being a white person in America?  Genuinely interested in your perspective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755324190.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>It's just one of scale to me for climate change. I do have nonzero yet infinitesimal impact on climate change. The best way for me to have zero impact on climate change is to kill myself and that's a pretty silly conclusion. I'm also not responsible for anyone else who decides not to kill themselves to help solve climate change. I have only done minor things like reduced the amount I drive and meat consumption. It's one of those problems where I think system-wide change needs to occur for it to make a noticeable impact.

Similarly for systemic racism I am complicit in the system because I am a cog. However, as with climate change I'm not responsible for the other cogs, just the system. I hold some nonzero albeit infinitesimal responsibility for propagating the system and I can feel guilty (however unproductive that is) that we still have a criminal justice system that disproportionately impacts black Americans but I wouldn't feel guilty that a particular person within that system who happens to share an implicit quality with myself does something awful.

As to solutions to systemic racism I truly believe it begins at education. There are a lot of revisionist history narratives that paint the civil war as some glorious resistance against tyranny along with many, many other points between then and now which should be rectified. I would reinstate the equal-time rule for all media which claims to be news. I would provide universal basic health insurance and income to all Americans controlling for the cost of living in a given area. I think there's tons of simple solutions that would make a measurable difference they're just not easy to implement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755517567.0" user="RaisinBranKing" delta="False">
    <text>I support a lot of the solutions you just mentioned.  The one thing I’m struggling to understand in your response is how specifically you contribute to systemic racism.  Maybe I’m just missing the point but in the climate change example it’s clear when we consume we emit CO2.  But in living your life as an American, what is the synonymous action you are taking which contributes?  Is it that by merely living in America we are responsible for the war on drugs for example?  It sounds like you’re already supporting good causes to stop this.  Is there some level of effort that would absolve you of your contribution to the problem?  For example in the climate change case, instead of killing yourself you could work on technology or initiatives that reduce CO2.  For instance Elon Musk is probably one of the most carbon negative people to ever live.  In other words, Elon Musk is part of the l solution to CC, not part of the problem.  Is there something analogous that could be done with regards to systemic racism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755574629.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>My tax money directly pays for the cops, lawyers, judges, and legislators who are responsible for the policies so that's me, yea.

I'm not looking for absolution. If there were a way to attain absolution it would be to create and/or live in a place where no such systemic inequities exist which, to my knowledge, is nowhere on planet earth besides perhaps Antarctica.

As to your prophets vs wizards example, the only way to have a net negative carbon footprint is to literally be the wizard who discovers the solution. Just working towards it isn't enough IMO. So props to all the folks working on cultivating plastic digesting microbes, renewable energy, long term power storage, and other ways of reducing carbon emissions but that's only a few thousand people tops actually making the leaping scientific contributions. 

For systemic racism it would need to be an MLK level person or group of people who inspires some sort of amendment to the constitution which helps move the country forward on racial issues. Although the BLM movement is great they aren't it. I am actually less hopeful of comprehensive action on this than climate change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755609863.0" user="RaisinBranKing" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for sharing your thoughts.  I guess what I get hung up on is something you mentioned which is that there’s not really anywhere on the planet we could live that doesn’t have inequities and injustice.  So there’s not really another option we can take.  But that’s just me, thanks for engaging</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
