<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753960999.0" user="chinmakes5" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem is that people are mixing up guilt and trying to correct a wrong.   Do I feel guilty that black people were discriminated by laws made by white people?   Not particularly.   I am a progressive, we progressed, You can't look back using today's lens and feel guilty for that. 

THAT SAID, to the guy who told me all I have to do is not be racist today, and if we have any type of affirmative action that is actually racism against whites, you're an f'ing moron.  Tell me the kid who grew up in the projects has the same opportunities as your kid.  Whether it is opportunity, the caliber of schools, role models showing them how to be successful, the fact that their parents never saw the benefits of a good education,. What about generational wealth,  that a kid whose parent worked two jobs who never saw them are more likely to get in trouble. 

I'll be able to retire comfortably because my parents bought a house in 1969.  It appreciated 10x and I will inherit a few hundred thousand dollars.    Had my parents bought a house in a red lined area, I doubt the house would have appreciated 2x.  I will benefit, my kids will benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754224079.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really disagree with anything that you're saying except that people who believe racism will go away naturally if we eliminate interpersonal racism are morons. I just think they're ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
