<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753320046.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>So, for white fragility, people of color (inclusive of myself) consider that to be a result of racism as an institution. 

The reason being is that only by actively discussing and changing our viewpoints can we come to at least a starting ground of understanding where the other side is coming from.

As an example, as an Asian, I regularly discuss various topics inclusive of race between friends. It's not a heavy topic, but sometimes just comes up. I would find it extremely weird if another friend felt uncomfortable discussing the negative results that came as a result of their culture-group's actions.

White fragility is seen as racism because the lack of willingness to discuss is almost akin to willful ignorance while enjoying all the benefits that society provides to being white. Because you don't wish to come to terms with the idea that your society's history is very checkered, you run the risk of willfully brushing away the bad things history has inflicted upon other people. 

As a result, you misalign people who either directly or indirectly are affected by the actions of your group when the goal really should be a unified approach.

On another note, the reason why the Buffalo shooter comes up a lot, in particular, is specifically because he was extremely racist against people of color. Embedded racism is a result of a culture unwilling to resolve their past mistakes in an honest and open way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753411178.0" user="AleristheSeeker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would find it extremely weird if another friend felt uncomfortable discussing the negative results that came as a result of their culture-group's actions.

I have a problem with this sentence. How do you define "white people" in that context? How do you define any "race" here? How do you define a "culture group" here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753477549.0" user="sillydilly4lyfe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would find it extremely weird if another friend felt uncomfortable discussing the negative results that came as a result of their culture-group's actions.

I mean it is famously said that white people don't have culture.

But that is just a sticking point about how white people's cultural identity that is not tied to race. Most people identify with an ethnicity, or a religion, or even a state before they specifically identify as white.

You are asking a wide group of people with drastically different backgrounds and cultures to exhibit responsibility for people that acted and behaved nothing like them?

Like if you are a white first Gen immigrant from an extremely poor family, is it an issue if you don't want to talk about America's issues 100 years before anyone in tour family arrived here?

Or since you are Asian, is it fair for me to talk about the personal responsibility you hold because of the racist past and present of Japan because your ancestry comes from that continent?

And worst of all, pointing out 'white fragility' does absolutely nothing. If you have cognitive solutions to present day problems, that is not an issue and will be discussed. But jf the goal os to simply talk about past racist issues, I understand not engaging in that topic. We learned about them in school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753671188.0" user="gtrocks555" delta="False">
    <text>Do I feel bad about what happened? Obviously. Do I personally feel guilty? Not really. Am I open to talk about racial issues? Of course and that’s because I don’t necessarily identify my “in-group” as just being white so it’s never been an “us vs them” mentality.

I think I agree with OP on this. However, from reading, it seems like the people who do have white fragility are those that know what we’re talking about are them, it’s pretty much white people telling on themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753718668.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Is it really a good idea to foster the idea of white people as needing a strong group identity? You’re using it to assign guilt and shame here, but couldn’t it just as easily go the other way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754614839.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>I think white people should have a strong group identity. You should be proud of whatever country you come from. If your grandparents are from Italy, of course, you should be proud of it. 

People who emigrate from China, from South Africa, from Brazil- they should all be proud of their homeland. 

That said, I don't see how coming to terms with white fragility causes a strong group identity. What coming to terms with it means is that you don't try to compartmentalize racism into "is this racist or not racist" and rather try to understand the nuances that are a result of race. Black people aren't a monolithic group by any means, neither are Asians, and neither are Whites. What the people of color in this nation have are a tacit understanding of differences between the race and know that people a person of color comes with some challenges. 

It stuns me when some of the white people I know are surprised to hear about that when its so ubiquitous in our society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755902598.0" user="sillydilly4lyfe" delta="False">
    <text>Being white does not mean being Italian? You get that right?

When you say white people should have a strong identity group, what traits do you think they should prefer and exhibit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756544067.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>What traits? I'm not white so I shouldn't define it. What shouldn't define it is the unwillingness to understand other cultures past the surface level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758031988.0" user="sillydilly4lyfe" delta="False">
    <text>Okay yeah that isn't a defining traits in anyway and i think there are plenty of white people that are willing to understand culture past the surface level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756739491.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Italian, slav, ashkenasi, Irish, mostly can be seen under the umbrella "white" but that's sort of useless if you want to actually include their experience in discourse in a meaningful way. Everyone can be grouped as human but if we want to be specific then we have to go further than melanin content in the skin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756727464.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>A strong identity within a group whether that's a family or a society, or even a sports team is a powerful way to keep an eye on each other, nurture empathy. Without that identity within the group loneliness takes over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753722172.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the thoughts. Does something being a result of racism automatically make it racism? I see emancipation as a result of systemic racism and yet I would say that's quite the opposite. Same for the Civil Rights movement. 

Also do you believe I was being a fragile white person in my response?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754568447.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>No, I think the white fragility note is when people dislike talking about race issues in general or take knee jerk reactions

In terms of something being a result of racism, there are obvious measures that are made to alleviate racism right? The world isn't a bipolar world as there are a million greys in between. 

For example, consider redlining and multi-unit housing. Only a generation ago did we stop allowing neighborhoods to deny based on race and forced African Americans to stick to low-value zones that continue to be much lower in value today due to the cyclical nature of low-income areas. 

On a similar note, California, a place that espouses the most liberal ideas, regularly fights to allow multi-family housing in single-family zones because it would lower their property value by bringing in people who are less affluent. As affluence generally skews on the poorer side for people of color, this is a situation where there is a clear refusal to see the bigger picture.

On the side of the people who live there already, their thought process is: value down bad. What they don't see is that the reason why these people are poor is precisely because of historic redlining, racism, and the modern-day aftermath of keeping the socioeconomically poorer away. 

It's the idea that you try to boil an issue to \[Race\] \[Not-Race\] when there are a million factors affecting the reason why we do things. Race has a direct impact on poverty today- and trying to say something like "don't give handouts to the poor" isn't necessarily a vacuum.

For example, on another point, I see the Buffalo shooter as a case of racism sure, but more mentally ill people abusing lax gun laws that really should come with at least a mental aptitude test. There's been a number of cases where a black man attacked a bunch of Asians. White people did some weird mental gymnastics on that one in the news and social media. Liberally-leaning people tried to not say it was a black man which doesn't make sense. Conservative-leaning people wanted to wave this as proof that black people can commit hate crimes too. The people that I talk to see it as, yet again, a failure of mental health and access to weapons for people that really shouldn't have it. For the one in NYC, was the gunman black? Yes. Is that ALL he was? No.

In my experience of white America, the need to boil things down into a singular surface-level race-related talking point is, in my eyes, a result of white fragility. Almost like a hands-off approach to racism by only hitting the surface rather than understanding it to the core.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754693744.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, red-lining was BS and NIMBYism is the worst. 

Are you saying that the shutting down of general discourse on race into an oversimplified talking point is an example of white fragility? If so I think I agree but what makes it racist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755298462.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would find it extremely weird if another friend felt uncomfortable discussing the negative results that came as a result of their culture-group's actions.

I've had some version of this conversation before, I'd like to skip a few steps and get to what I think to be the underlying divide--I think viewing people as members of their "culture-groups" as though that somehow defines them or is a large part of their identity is inherently wrong.  I'd go a step further and say that it's a facet of post-modern thought that racial identity and/or things like nationalism are...not inherently bad, but inherently *incorrect*.  It's the Ecological Fallacy.  It's essentially demographic essentialism or demographic prescriptivism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755741512.0" user="jaam01" delta="False">
    <text>The concept of "white fragility" "argument" should be dismissed right away, because is just a fallacy by itself. It's a Kafkatrap, a sophistical rhetorical device, in which any denial by the accused person, is used as if was evidence of guilt.  
  
Examples "You deny been a witch? Then you're a witch, because that's what a witch would say"  
  
It's circular thinking and a specious way of shifting the burden of proof (because you don't have any evidence to prove your acussation on the first place). Its a gotcha, like "damn you if you do (admiting you are a racist), and also damn you if you don't (deny that you are a racist)"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756825578.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>When you say culture group actions it implies a consensus and agenda that is shared within different groups which are actively acted on. If we accept that society was and continues to be built by the elite class then wouldn't they be who we hold accountable, and not just people who look like them, or benefit from their systems?

Are we not all the result of those systems and should work together to tear them down, but the responsibility is in those who built them, the church, the monarchy, the elites.

Individuals today who never participated in past cultures cannot bear responsibility for those sins. Resolution for past mistakes must see a benefit and progress for society as a whole, advancement rather than continued in fighting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757503238.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>While I totally understand the concept of "the sins of the fathers are not the sins of the sons", that rarely comes into fruition in multi-generational issues. 

Here's an example- are a random sampling of white people in America responsible for the redlining and gov't-enforced segregation laws? Definitely not. They took no party to that. That said, they do generally receive the benefits of the aftermath of those same laws down the line. While the sins of those who created the laws aren't your own, because you are the beneficiary of those laws, it's important to create systems to level back the playing field.

You can't separate a black family who, generationally, were forced to exist in only certain areas that evolved into project/low-income zoning- are somehow able to completely move past generations of educational deficit, and most importantly, lack of strong, motivational role models within their own community.

It's circular. Just as a white family who is stuck in a small town and exists only in trailers will generally engender a new generation of similar whites of similar socioeconomic status, you can't tell a single generation to reject the past.

While you're correct that technically that the main beneficiaries are the elites, there has and will never be a unified approach towards taxation in America mostly due to the mentality that many Americans have. While there are many reasons why someone wouldn't support the taxation of the rich, the most peculiar of them all is the "tomorrow millionaire" Americans. Many people genuinely believe that they, at some point in the future, will become a millionaire. By not taxing the rich today, you're protecting your assets whenever you become a millionaire. As that's ludicrously absurd unless you're on particular career paths, I think that mentality is particularly unique to America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757527528.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Your examples are colourblind, and support my point. As an outsider to the American system it does seem silly that those same white people living in a trailer would be grouped in with all other white people because that's what the words white fragility does even if that's not the way they are being used in context. That's what I think people take issue to. Its why better language can shape a better shared understanding. That it isn't calling white people fragile, that it's a critique on conversations around race. Language does matter to shape these conversations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757664087.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>You say it seems silly, but for many, conversations around race are most problematic at the socio-economically poor areas. 

I'm not sure if you're not from the US, but this is a common issue particularly in the US around race as it's political in nature. 

By even 1960s, LBJ's quote is "If you can convince the lowest white man he’s better than the best colored man, he won’t notice you’re picking his pocket. Hell, give him somebody to look down on, and he’ll empty his pockets for you."

That mentality has persisted throughout as an institution and only very recently (relative to history) has been tackled. While race shouldn't normally be a political one, as Americans generally find politics extremely important, it became one. 

The term white fragility is a shock tactic more than anything else. It's to rile up people into defending themselves and force conversations about it rather than taking a passive approach to language. Once conversations are more open and honest about race, the language will evolve as a result. The language is purposefully confrontational rather than inclusive because the onus is on a particular race in specifically America rather than all white people in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758067838.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I am not from the US.

In your last paragraph you still point to the idea of a particular race specifically in America, as if there really is a white race that isn't a huge diverse system of interlocking cultures and communities and backgrounds. It sees you can't escape that idea even when discussing it in the broadest sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758193462.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. There are a huge range of interlocking cultures in America. Definitely. But unlike other countries, we're far more willing to judge someone not from where they come from, but their race.

For example, you can be a fair-skinned Mexican or Spanish-American and we will consider you white for all intents and purposes when it comes to basic things like judging at face value. We'll inherently trust an immigrant from France than an immigrant from Gabon. 

America is a nation of many cultures, but because there are so many, we tend to tribalize the bigger issues into broad categories. That said, America has people living here for many generations- any kinship to their original motherland is more of a passing glance.

The reason why it's Black v White in this case is because blacks who were brought here through slavery lost connection with their original motherland due to various factors. As a result, their identity as Black Americans is one of only America. Black Americans aren't targetting, let's say, Anglo-Saxons- because anyone from Anglo-Saxon heritage historically had as much to gain through segregation as did a French, Scottish, German, Italian. 

Rather than being a clash of cultures, it's an ideological clash between races. I think what non-Americans don't understand is we generally accept you regardless of what country you come from- or if anything, we think our country is better than yours no matter what. I think you'll understand that most American will dislike you if you try to say how your country is better than ours- regardless of race. This is an inter-country issue rather than an international one. We can talk about how Puerto Ricans are different from Mexicans who are different from Brazilians in America- but here- we class them as Hispanic. Hispanics have their own united grievances with the culture in America despite being from very different locations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758233961.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like a terrible way to operate within complex social dynamics. America does have many citizens who have been there for generations, but surely any descendant of a white person who came to America as a black person has just as much identity as simply American, with the same lack of detailed nuance as an African American?

Segregation isn't really a part of things like Anglo Saxon invasions of Britain because the term simply doesn't fit the dynamic. Pagans and Christian culture didn't mesh but instead of segregating the different groups they would simply be killed, or converted. The framework is entirely different down to the nuances. This means in Europe there is no one who isn't a descendant of rapist murdering oppressors, that history is shared by most "whites" as close to a common heritage as its possible to have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757093139.0" user="Plusisposminusisneg" delta="False">
    <text>So its an academic term and would apply the same way to a black guy being uncomfortable if people around him were making generalizations about black people?

Someone makes a sweeping generalization about black people, and the black individual in that discussion feels uncomfortable that means he is suffering from black fragility? 

You would find it very strange if a black friend became uncomfortable when some white dude started spouting crime statistics and talking about rap and gangster culture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757434716.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's a little disingenuous. The most applicable way of applying it (since I personally don't know much about race in African history) would be talking about how China treats white people as gofers and "white monkies" which they use to leverage only for the sole purpose of interfacing with other white people and to show off as a status symbol for the company.

It's hardly China's #1 problem, but that would make more sense. Ex-pats in China have a strong feeling of exclusion, but that's somewhat understandable given China's always pushed for a singular, exclusionary identity since the communists rose.

We're addressing entirely American problems here. The established power and precedence is white. While it wouldn't be as much of a discussion point if America was a singular ethno-state, it really isn't. It is one of the rare multi-ethnic nations in the world. As a result, we will always need to have a conversation about race as it plays a direct impact in our day-to-day interactions.

 So to shun discussion about race as it plays into average life and regular gov't policy is what white fragility. The kneejerk reaction to a minority community coming out against a certain proposal or bill is often called race-bating. While that's true to some extent, it's not a polar one or the other. It's always somewhere in the middle, but there is a clear refusal to talk about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757665067.0" user="Plusisposminusisneg" delta="False">
    <text>No, white fragility is a made up term to guilt trip spineless white people into agreeing with the advocates position, asserting the acceptable ways to address race relations, and dismissing criticism.

Everything that denies the advocates assertions is retreating into white fragility, everything that describes race relations outside of the advocates predetermined terms is white fragility. 

White fragility as a concept is a thought terminating activist tool designed from the ground up to insult, guilt trip, and terminate all discussion on race relations and instead creating a one sided lecture on race relations from the person who starts throwing that worthless term around.

That is probably why you didn't answer the question and instead went on some lecture about broader race relations without specifics. So I'll ask again. Is it black fragility to oppose a white guy sputing off crime statistics and criticizing hip-hop and/or gangster culture? I remind you that 

&amp;gt; I would find it extremely weird if another friend felt uncomfortable discussing the negative results that came as a result of their culture-group's actions.

Or is it only weird when white people feel uncomfortable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757799964.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>Is it black fragility for a white guy to sputter off crime statistics and criticize gangster culture when a black guy is uncomfortable with it?

This is such a boiling down moment that it tries to ignore the nuances that race has into binary answers- we don't live in compartments.

But for your answer, it really depends and your question has three parts.

Is it black fragility for a white guy to criticize gangster culture? I think any black person that I know who doesn't live in the projects ALSO criticizes gangster culture. That's a real problem with the low-income communities and there are open discussions about it. I don't see how that applies here unless you're directly criticizing someone who is a part of the gangster culture.

Is it black fragility to criticize a particular genre of music? I honestly find this is a weird place to go since it's just a odd hill to die on. I don't think anyone will hate you for saying hip-hop sucks. I hate country, but some people love country. I hate polka, but some people enjoy it. That's not really race-specific. 

The main point that is the issue here is the note about crime statistics. What is the end goal with this one? I could say it's not offensive to bring it up if you're willing to accept that this crime statistic comes with a LOT of nuances around racial profiling, poverty, past systemic racism, and general us v them mentality.

Critically, what I want to know from you is: do crime statistics, hip-hop, and gangster culture have an outsized impact on whites in America? Has it done something to marginalize them or negatively impact the cultural zeitgeist of white America to require a discussion on race? If the answer is no- then that's the problem. Bringing up general issues that you perceive as a "yes, but" is trying to create false equivalence. Black people bringing up these issues is specifically because of the impact white culture has on people of color in negative ways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
