<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753776206.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

I want to take a minute to respond to this part. "Fragility" is not an example of racism (the belief that one's value as a person is in any way influenced by their race), as a defensive "not all people of [X race] are like this/represented by this action" is a very racism-disavowing statement.

Rather, it's a *response* to racism. As a white man, any time a "discussion about race" (heavy air quotes there) opens up around me, the odds favor that I'm about to be insulted, guilt-tripped, accused, and/or generally disparaged on the basis of my race. Not only is that *wrong* (obviously; it's the actual textbook definition of racism), it's not very productive, either, and most "discussions about race" begin and end with blaming white people for everything. Understandably, I leave those discussions behind quickly (and get called "fragile" for it, thanks guys).

Of course, there's still reasons why that might not be the best thing for society, if scaled up. Some "discussions about race" *really are* discussions about race, that need to happen and result in progress, but it can be difficult to tell them apart from "discussions about race" that are actually just racist circle-jerks. Treating all of the former like the latter is going to make it very difficult to move on as a society, so we kind of need to *not* do that, regardless of how unpalatable it may be for the individual.

Does that all make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753816614.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>To summarize your response are you saying that when one is accused of "white fragility" that white person is actually the recipient of racism in that instance?

Would you say the phenomenon of "white fragility" doesn't exist at all or are you saying that it's justified?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753846372.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>That depends on what you mean by "justified". Is it understandable that people respond that way? Yes, very. Is it the best possible response to that situation? Not necessarily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753881007.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so I don't think it's justified to respond negatively to being confronted with evidence of racism even when one feels like they are being accused of racism. 

What about that first bit, do you think that when a white person is accused of "white fragility" that white person is actually the recipient of racism in that instance?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753931747.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know about that instance, in that being accused of fragility is necessarily racist, but the phenomenon exists specifically because racism against the accused is percieved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754598572.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Alright help me out here, then. I can certainly see why any person would be offended at a direct accusation of racism because that's essentially ad hominem even if it's true. 

Isn't the heart of the issue the perception of an accusation of racism by a white person when no such accusation was levied?

To me (and I'm sure many if not most people who believe white fragility exists), although DiAngelo probably includes the former situation as part of "white fragility" I believe it's come to mean the far more truncated set of experiences described by the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754852703.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. That's the problem exactly. Fragility is a learned response to adverse situations. It's like having a particularly sensitive area of skin after being injured; you can't really fault someone for wincing if it's touched, but pulling away when you go to treat it doesn't help anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755071080.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty much with you here. If you can tie it into my comment I'll give you a delta. How was I pulling away from OP touching my wound by saying that guilt isn't productive and we should focus on actual solutions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755605500.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>That depends entirely on what was already said. If the other guy didn't actually indulge in any racism, responding as though they did presents an overreaction and is needlessly aggressive. However, looking at the OP, they very clearly did and the response that no, you can't just bundle people up like that, is an entirely justified and measured response. In this scenario, you did absolutely nothing wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755828247.0" user="CN_Minus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Isn't the heart of the issue the perception of an accusation of racism by a white person when no such accusation was levied?

If a situation discussing race gets to the point where the accused is called fragile for protesting an accusation as serious as racism, it isn't a useful conversation. It's a reverse card, usually, for the racist language often utilized by the accusers. The term itself, even if you can convince yourself the meaning isn't derogatory, has a strongly negative connotation. To even have a discussion accepting it you have to rationalize why a good-faith actor would even choose to utilize this language rather than nuanced, mutually respectful terminology.

Choosing, intentionally, not to use respectful terms proves immediately that the party using these terms doesn't care about the other party and isn't having a discussion. People using these terms, by the nature of them, aren't having a good-faith discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755350709.0" user="Laxwarrior1120" delta="False">
    <text>The argument being "you are ____ because of your race" is a racist statement outright, bust especially when it's something negative in that blank space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755490529.0" user="prepend" delta="False">
    <text>Things can be both racist and a response to racism. If I as a vulnerable minority respond to a hate crime perpetrated by another minority by being racist then there you go. 

Just because something is a response to racism doesn’t mean it is automatically good or justified or valuable. If someone calls me a racist term and I kill them and their family and their dogs, that’s not right even though it is in direct response to racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755624864.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>Great, except those were two independent statements.

1) This is not racism because it very explicitly takes antiracism (the belief that a person's value is NOT correlated to their race) as a premise.

2) This is a response to racism.

You aren't wrong, but you've missed the fact that these are different points in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763616371.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "not all people of [X race] are like this/represented by this action" is a very racism-disavowing statement.

So if someone said, “I was mugged by a black person, so I no longer like black people”, and I replied "not all people of that race are like this/represented by this action"... I would be the racist one?

I think... no, wait, I am sure, I am sure it is the first statement that is racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764981338.0" user="Maximum-Country-149" delta="False">
    <text>...That is literally what I said. Racism-disavowing. As in, denying any support for racism.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
