<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755123703.0" user="catniagara" delta="False">
    <text>“A situation over which you have no control” does not describe racism in the USA. It does not describe wealth generated by and stolen from black peoples. It does not describe the continued abuses against black peoples. 

Restitution needs to be paid in any war crime or loss of freedom. The USA and Canada paid reparations to indigenous peoples. Germany paid reparations to Jewish people who were effected by the holocaust. 

We are aware of which families benefited (and continue to benefit) from monies generated by slavery. Those families need to pay reparations to the families they murdered, raped, exploited and used to create wealth with zero restitution whatsoever. 

It’s pretty simple. If your family’s wealth was generated by murder you carry the guilt of that wealth unless and until you make reparations or pay restitution for what you have done. 

“It’s not my fault” has never been an apology. 

Furthermore, the idea that you personally are being accused and expected to feel guilty is another matter of “othering” people who are asking for equality and to be treated like human beings. 

“It’s not my fault so I don’t have to…” what? Advocate against systemic abuse of people because of the color of their skin? Question racially biased police violence? 

You don’t have to what? Advocate for black citizens of your country the way you would advocate for white ones? 

Because you’re “not racist”. Because it’s “not your fault”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755166475.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know enough about reparations to comment on that but I do know it's incredibly unpopular as a policy so won't be passed at any time in the near future which makes it moot regardless of whether it's justified or not. 

I agree "racism in the USA" is a situation over which I have some control but that's not what I was responding to. I was responding to the comment that I am responsible for the shooter murdering a bunch of black people.

&amp;gt;the idea that you personally are being accused and expected to feel guilty

Would you explain how being told to feel guilty isn't being expected to feel guilty? I'm not sure I follow you there.

I have to assure you I do advocate against systemic racism and police violence. I just don't think feeling guilt is productive. I think working towards solutions is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755828088.0" user="catniagara" delta="False">
    <text>That is called deliberate ignorance. You are telling yourself that reparations have never been discussed, [which is completely false](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/19/us/reparations-slavery.html) because you want it to be true. 

Refusing guilt is a way to absolve yourself of real human interaction with and compassion for “others” who don’t have the luxury of saying “this isn’t a me problem”. 

Have you read [the Whipping Boy?](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Whipping_Boy)
Fleischman explains, at a level even children can grasp, what it is to absolve yourself of guilt by expecting someone else to take it on for you. What it is to act against compassion because you’ve never been punished. 

You’re upset because you were, for the first time, disciplined for something. You weren’t shot, raped, attacked, threatened, told you deserved to die, [arrested for](https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/15/us/starbucks-philadelphia-black-men-arrest.html) having a cup of coffee, or forced to suffer any of the thousand micro-aggressions that women, people of color, and many children suffer every single day. You were banned from a sub. And you had to say something. You had to stand up. You thought “wow, white people are really being oppressed! I refuse to feel guilty for what someone else did!” 

Since you don’t want to talk about slavery or reparations or all the myriad reasons someone might use the words “you should feel guilty” let’s limit ourselves to this single situation. 

You broke a rule set by a Reddit sub. You paid the price. Why isn’t that fair? 

Because you’re white? Is that what you’re saying? That the rules shouldn’t apply to you and you should not be subjected to them because you’re white? 

Only…where would you learn something like that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756410629.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm having difficulty understanding your point because I'm not as emotionally invested in the arguments as you seem to believe. 

I totally understand reparations have been discussed for example it's the actual execution I'm not educated enough on to have a meaningful opinion. 

I'm also not looking for absolution. I'm mostly wondering why my specific comment was interpreted as counterproductive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756862134.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758079748.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/catniagara – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20catniagara&amp;amp;message=catniagara%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9i7j5i/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760162998.0" user="Wooba12" delta="False">
    <text>Hey now let's not bring race into it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755261357.0" user="Acerbatus14" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;“It’s not my fault” has never been an apology.

what are they supposed to apologize for exactly? "i'm sorry people i had no control over screwed you"? because that's quite the hollow apology</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755741715.0" user="catniagara" delta="False">
    <text>Just to recap, you believe that when you marry someone and move into a home with them, regardless of their income and especially if it’s lower, you are liable. You believe in a court system that reverts your debts to your children after you die. You believe that the Jewish people deserved reparations for the wealth stolen by the Germans through gross disregard for property and liberty rights, let alone security of the person. You believe that indigenous peoples deserved to be paid reparations for “stolen land” despite the fact that their ancestors entered into a series of signed contracts, many during meetings conducted in their own language, because the very nature of the long-past contracts is wrong. But you don’t believe that dark skinned people CHAINED, BEATEN, and forced to create wealth without access to human rights or healthcare AFTER the Declaration of Independence deserve to be paid reparations why? 

The Second World War lasted 6 years. Slavery started in the year 1526 and Jim Crow laws which unfairly demonized black people and which were VOTED for in your “democratic” country lasted until the 1970s. 

Racism against people based solely on their skin tone (since their ethnicity is 100% American and they’ve been in the country for more generations than most people who are allowed to call themselves American without specifying a skin tone of American) is happening right now. 

So I repeat, what is it you think you don’t have to apologize for? And if you don’t apologize, what are you saying you don’t have to do? 

What work on racism are you so afraid of doing that you cannot even ADMIT that racism is a problem?

Because you know what’s crazy? You can admit that Americans with melanin [experience horrible inequality](https://www.vox.com/platform/amp/2020/6/17/21284527/systemic-racism-black-americans-9-charts-explained) in the moment but you “white” peoples are terrified to talk about what caused and, more importantly, WHY it is ongoing. Why people feel safer attacking certain bodies than others. 

Is it because you’re terrified to be [seen as someone like us?](https://youtu.be/g2O8wJVu5o0) Is it because you’re horrified of the way minorities are treated and terrified to be lumped in with us? Is it because mommy and daddy won’t invite you over for Colonial Christmas in November if you talk about the fact that grandpappy was a rapist and maw-maw was a murderer? 

Or is it because you can’t feel superior if there’s no-one you can easily abuse and get away with it? 

Denying history doesn’t make it disappear. Look into your family’s history, find out if they were slave owners or land-grabbers or if they raped anyone who ended up with a mullato baby, or if they contributed to the residential school system or helped take any children away from racialized parents, and do something. 

TL;DR Nobody has ever in your life asked you to apologize for anything related to racism. But on the inside most of us are good people who want retribution for evils that occur. Your assertion that you “shouldn’t have to apologize” is the knowledge that you DO (and should) feel guilty for being given a voice but refusing to take action, butting up against generations of racist brainwashing. Time to break the cycle, look into our family histories, and start [calling out with histories, names, and photos](https://youtu.be/BGjSday7f_8) the exact war criminals responsible for these ongoing problems. Then AND now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756142560.0" user="Acerbatus14" delta="False">
    <text>you are barking the wrong tree here. im not white and i don't think there's anything inherently wrong with reparations. stolen goods should be returned where possible. (although i think a standard tax that simply distributes wealth to poor people regardless of race is best). all i said is a apology is hollow when you are not the perpetrator of a crime. its like telling a black person a black guy stole your bike and then the black person apologizes, its stupid and it wouldn't' and shouldn't make you happy, because the person who did the damages is different from the one that's apologizing.  


all i get is from your comment regarding what to apologize for is the inaction white people have taken in not ending inequality, but at that point might as well forget apologizing and just do the action itself, since the latter speaks louder and is more useful</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756857073.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758161279.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/catniagara – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20catniagara&amp;amp;message=catniagara%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9i7f8x/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/catniagara – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20catniagara&amp;amp;message=catniagara%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9i7f8x/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
