<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39754225962.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>White fragility is racist, because it judges people differently for the same behaviours depending on their race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754251552.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>What is your definition of white fragility? 

To me it's the phenomenon whereby a white person reacts negatively to any discussion of race. If a person of color reacts negatively to a discussion of race I don't think they would be judged differently it would just not be "white" fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754321358.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What is your definition of white fragility?

It's the set of behaviours/phrases that makes people think it's a good time to use "white fragility" to get the upper hand in a discussion. Essentially it's an ad hominem fallacy, failing to address the point at hand and instead redirecting the discussion to personal characteristics of the other person.

&amp;gt;To me it's the phenomenon whereby a white person reacts negatively to any discussion of race. If a person of color reacts negatively to a discussion of race I don't think they would be judged differently it would just not be "white" fragility.

To me it's entirely irrelevant how that person looks. If they don't want to discuss it, it's up to them to justify it. If they have good reasons they have good reasons, and those don't suddenly become bad reasons if their color would be different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754363140.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I see how the concept is applicable to discussion but how does an accusation of white fragility cause one to gain the upper hand?

If white fragility is in play the discussion is already usually over as the "fragile" person has reacted negatively and/or walked away because as you say it's usually interpreted as ad hominem if brought up at all. It would therefore serve as a self-fulfilling prophecy against anyone who doesn't have thicker skin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756150544.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I see how the concept is applicable to discussion but how does an accusation of white fragility cause one to gain the upper hand?

Because it undermines the credibility of everything the other person said and says. It also refocuses the discusion on that credibility, distracting from what is actually being discussed and putting that person on the defensive.

&amp;gt;If white fragility is in play the discussion is already usually over as the "fragile" person has reacted negatively and/or walked away because as you say it's usually interpreted as ad hominem if brought up at all. It would therefore serve as a self-fulfilling prophecy against anyone who doesn't have thicker skin.

That assumes it's only ever used justly. But in reality it can be used against anyone that is white. Or anyone who is assumed to be white, for example on digital media. So effectively it's used as a blanket argument to shut down criticism against a certain range of positions, even if that criticism is justified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756600099.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Would you clarify whose credibility is undermined?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759061783.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>It's an attempt to undermine the credibility of the person accused with white fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
