<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="50" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39757481254.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>"White fragility" doesn't exist.  It's a conspiracy theory invented by racists to denigrate white people.  

&amp;gt; I don't think the ban was justified

This is correct.  Best way to deal with crazy people banning you from a cesspool like that for idiotic reasons is to shake the dust off your feet, say "good riddance to bad rubbish", and move on.  

&amp;gt; many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race.

And why does this happen?  Because there is a lot of racism against white people these days, and we get blamed for things we didn't do, and we get called "racist" for no reason, and so on.  

When people do this they are not being "fragile" or "white".  When people do this, they are having a normal reaction to being put in a stressful situation in which other people are being or are likely to become hostile towards them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757542164.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>No I have certainly seen instances of "white fragility" where someone takes a benign comment about race incredibly personally and gets super confrontational when it has nothing to do with them personally. Believe you me it is a thing that happens I just hope it's not as common as my friends of color say it is.

As a white person I do not believe racism against white people is pervasive. Most people in America are white and we own the vast majority of wealth. Even if I, as a white person, am accused of racism getting hostile is not the proper response as a grown human being. That is something children do.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
