<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39756535809.0" user="BranAllBrans" delta="False">
    <text>Do white ppl generally not feel some greater responsibility for the actions of some white individuals? I’d wager all non white americans do for their ethnic groups</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756654305.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I don't feel responsible for other white people, no, and the fact that you feel responsible for people who share a random implicit characteristic with you sounds rather strange to me. Why do you feel responsible for someone else's actions halfway round the world who shares your skin color?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756906349.0" user="BranAllBrans" delta="False">
    <text>Becaus there are consequences on ppls perception of you based on those characteristics in our current society when bad behavior hapepns</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757045566.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>To me that sounds like a problem with the other people who imply those things not you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759283238.0" user="BananaLee" delta="False">
    <text>I would cheekily answer that this is actually a perfect example of white privilege, in the sense that it's much easier for a white person to choose their identity as opposed to people of colour.

As a general rule, POC get lumped into their identities by society whether we like it or not. For example, a bad white driver is just a "bad driver" but a bad Asian driver is a "bad Asian driver". One also hears the common refrain "you're one of the good ones" when white folks are comfortable enough with a POC who's been culturally raised in the same environment.

So to answer your question, no one *should* feel responsible for the actions of others of the same implicit characteristic, but in our society's Zeitgeist at least, we definitely act and speak as though POC should. 

So I think you can understand that some get more annoyed because white folks complain about the novel unfairness of being lumped into a group (which let's be clear, it is) when that's the standard life of and certainly not novel for most POC.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
