<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="45" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39757036571.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them.

So when they are called racist they get pissed off and stressed and that makes them fragile? This is fucking moronic anyone would act that way to an accusation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757059319.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I don't act that way when an accusation of racism is levied against me.

IMO white fragility is when an accusation of racism is *not* levied but the recipient perceived it as such which is even milder. 

In no way is anger an appropriate respone. People have such thin skins these days.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757160852.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't act that way when an accusation of racism is levied against me.

That's because you accept the accusation as true. You don't view it as a false accusation/smear. But if someone were to call you a pedophile in public or some kind of smear that you didn't accept you'd react that way.

&amp;gt;IMO white fragility is when an accusation of racism is not levied but the recipient perceived it as such which is even milder. In no way is anger an appropriate respone. People have such thin skins these days.

Implying the accusation isn't less likely to get a anger response it's more likely because you are pissed off that they are playing words games on top of accusing you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757209664.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>No, I wouldn't get angry if someone called me a pedo either. That's just silly and I know it's not true. 

I'm not understanding your second point. I don't believe I'm arguing semantics here. Do you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757282539.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757381594.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>If you knew me you would know that I would instead start laughing at how ridiculous the accusation of pedophilia was. I guarantee I would not get upset and in fact I argue that anyone who would get upset is being silly. 

I have no idea what you're talking about in your second paragraph. An argument is either semantics i.e. definitions of words or it's not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757405413.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you knew me you would know that I would instead start laughing at how ridiculous the accusation of pedophilia was. I guarantee I would not get upset and in fact I argue that anyone who would get upset is being silly.

Okay while your laughing your boss fires you. Are you still laughing? 

&amp;gt;I have no idea what you're talking about in your second paragraph. An argument is either semantics i.e. definitions of words or it's not.

We aren't arguing about definitions, we are arguing about how phrasing that pisses someone off more subtlety doesn't make them less pissed off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757471801.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>My boss would also know that it's a BS accusation immediately. She's laughing with me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757580618.0" user="DemonInTheDark666" delta="False">
    <text>Nope you're fired.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757492247.0" user="budlejari" delta="False">
    <text>u/DemonInTheDark666 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20DemonInTheDark666&amp;amp;message=DemonInTheDark666%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9igjjf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757492843.0" user="budlejari" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/DemonInTheDark666 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20DemonInTheDark666&amp;amp;message=DemonInTheDark666%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9igjjf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760125513.0" user="Wooba12" delta="False">
    <text>I think most people wouldn't be "angry", but it would be perfectly natural to feel mildly irritated and to get defensive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760226040.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Now what if the accusation isn't levied against you but rather a random celebrity you happen to like? Would you still get defensive? I feel like this is more analogous to the situation OP and I were actually talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760556872.0" user="Wooba12" delta="False">
    <text>You could get defensive of the celebrity, certainly. It would be unreasonable to see it as a reflection on yourself, though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
