<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753410496.0" user="Spectrum2081" delta="False">
    <text>It can be white fragility. It can also be an intellectual discussion.

Whether pointing out that a white person shouldn’t feel guilty for the actions of other white people is an example of white fragility depends heavily on context. 

We don’t know the context of your ban, and having been banned and shadow-banned myself, I am not one to judge.

But think of it this way. 

All men are not alike. Men should not feel guilty for the actions of a criminal who also happens to be a man. It is not wrong to note that or acknowledge it or point it out.

But if we were discussing a crime perpetrated by a man against a woman, and some guy feels the need to shift the discussion from the victim to “not all men…” it’s not really about whether it’s all men. It’s fragility.

Edit to add: or Black Lives Matter. Of course all lives matter, but if you feel compelled to point that out, perhaps that all lives have value is not what’s really going on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753761897.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I certainly agree with your examples except I feel like I was proposing a solution to solve the issues of systemic racism superior to "feeling guilty" which doesn't accomplish anything.

EDIT: If you can point out something in my response where I'm shifting the discussion or deflecting from the issue of systemic racism more broadly I would much more readily agree that my comment could be an example of white fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756049489.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756197929.0" user="Megaxatron" delta="False">
    <text>I understand your point, but if we're going to dismiss ideas about solving big problems because it seems arrogant to believe you might be able to help solve such a big problem, then we end up in a place where people are discouraged from trying to solve such problems. And that doesn't seem like a good plan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756210252.0" user="HKBFG" delta="False">
    <text>Consider that your idea (which we don't get to know because you won't tell us) went over as well as it did. Try to ask yourself why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756228093.0" user="Megaxatron" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not the OP, I just feel like your comment dismissed them on the basis of criteria that would shutdown the whole discussion if broadly applied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757010291.0" user="BigTuna3000" delta="False">
    <text>r/whitepeopletwitter didn’t like something so now the whole world knows it’s a trash idea? Come on dawg</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756475933.0" user="Xperimentx90" delta="False">
    <text>They didn't say they solved it. They said

&amp;gt;figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation

which is obviously \*part\* of the solution.

Shitty reductivist takes like yours are offering even less to the discussion than OP's comment you criticized.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756726224.0" user="taybay462" delta="False">
    <text>this is really unnecessary, the world would be a better place if more people shared earnest ideas to do better. OP isnt asking for a medal lmao just giving the context</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763422643.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/HKBFG – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20HKBFG&amp;amp;message=HKBFG%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9hq441/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757993400.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>No one - and I mean no one - wants you to “feel guilty” about anything you have not personally done. If you think they do want you to feel guilty, then you’ve misunderstood them. 

What they want is for people who share traits with perpetrators to take *responsibility* for helping right those wrongs. That isn’t the same thing as saying you’re *at fault*. It’s saying that as a part of the same group, you have an opportunity to speak out against malevolent members of your group. If you instead choose to point out that you’re not as bad as those bad people, it shows that you’re insecurely defending yourself, rather than confidently helping condemn the bad actors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758071276.0" user="speaker_for_the_dead" delta="False">
    <text>Now that is just a flat out lie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758267879.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Then please elaborate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758495005.0" user="Daystar1124" delta="False">
    <text>Many do want guilt. Many do want reprimands. I've had this discussion a lot and it hurts. I'm afraid I've seen the term "fragility" used in ways that can only be described as gaslighting and I hate both terms equally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759012606.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Gaslighting isn’t remotely relevant here. Not sure how you’ve heard it used, but it has a specific meaning and people sometimes misuse it. 

People don’t want guilt. They want responsibility. Even those who may say they want guilt, actually want responsibility. 

It’s hard to explain, but I promise that people of color will support you if you say “I don’t feel personally guilty for things I wasn’t involved with, but I’m willing to make sacrifices to right the wrongs committed by my cultural ancestors”. 

The thing that matters is willingness to take responsibility and action in the present. No one actually cares if you feel personally guilty or not, because it doesn’t have any impact on anything except your feelings. What people want is actual action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759259416.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you’re just saying people should be guilty without using the word. I’m not responsible for my “cultural ancestors” (which must be some new term made up to reconcile the fact that the vast vast majority of white Americans don’t have any slave owning ancestry). what is “take responsibility”  supposed to mean other than feel guilty? If I’m not supposed to be guilty why am I responsible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759695314.0" user="YennefersChin" delta="False">
    <text>Uh, put laws in place and pay reparations? Like y’all literally just made lynching a hate crime. In 2022.

Seriously, no one cares about your personal feelings. That’s the delusional importance of Whiteness™️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759784044.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Uh gee wiz let me just push my make a law button and fix that up, why didn’t I think of that /s. What part of I’m not going to feel guilty for things I have no control or potential to impact don’t you guys not get. 

Murder and being an accessory to murder have been illegal for quite a while. If someone murders someone because of race, it’s a hate crime. The law is little more than a virtue signal to make people like you think they did something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759792301.0" user="YennefersChin" delta="False">
    <text>So you also think I meant you personally should pass laws?? I genuinely don’t think you have the range for this conversation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761770686.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>This conversation has never been about what should or shouldn’t  be passed, but whether or not I am responsible for the actions of others. Read the OP, whole threads about whether or not it makes sense to feel guilty about stuff Weve contributed absolutely nothing to. 

Listen, you seem like a pretty insufferable person. Just cool it with the racism, reading through your comments it’s obvious you’ve got some pent up spite agains the “melanin deficient”. Just realize, for whatever reason you hate them, it’s got nothing to do with me, which has always been my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761378716.0" user="Mauricethett" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, nobody cares about our feelings, we get real fucking confused when other people ask us to care about their’s.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761513502.0" user="YennefersChin" delta="False">
    <text>I think most people would just like to avoid the oppression. Your actual “care” isn’t particularly important or necessary. They think they can appeal to the humanity in people who have historically been the most oppressive and cruel creatures the planet has ever seen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761645140.0" user="Mauricethett" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it was an off comment, but here, I’ll give you my actual thoughts.

White’s haven’t been the ‘most oppressive and cruel’ people in history just because of the fact that they were white. Humans, as a whole, have been a pretty immoral bunch across the board.

No, the main issues with white people began in the colonial era, in which Europe expanded *first.* Spain didn’t send visionaries, or people interested in human rights, they sent conquerers, which started a cycle or repression. Triangular trade started as Colonies, by the wide margin, were not profitable, at all. At the same time, there was hope that they could be profitable to the elite with time, and they were extremely strategic for trade and military reasons. Slaves were then brought in. This could have been avoided if all European powers simultaneously decided to leave America alone, but that was never going to happen.

After all this, we jump forward a bit, and the rise of nationalism begins, and to your credit, whites are incredibly racist, as are the Japanese, as are the Indians, as are the Pakistani, as are the Turkish, etc.

America, has a lot of of those various cultures intermixed and it *doesn’t go well* people with economic ties to slavery get resentful, this is an issue, this is an instance of whites being racist en masse and I *get it*, that is a legacy we have to work through and have been.

But to my point, everyone has been racist, which isn’t good, but as of the age of globalization, disproportionately more attention is placed on the actions of white people as ‘The enemy’. I’m not your enemy, though. I will go to marches, I will donate to BLM, I will demand that my representatives do what they can for the minorities in my community, I’m not going to tolerate being the enemy because of a dead age we’ve accepted as terrible.

I will do those things because I will give as much respect as I wish for in turn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761397422.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761479845.0" user="YennefersChin" delta="False">
    <text>Realistically reparations would be paid by the government to the descendants of enslaved Africans. They promised 40 acres and a mule and instead paid reparations to former enslavers. The government should pay its debt.

That means the citizens of this country, including most Black people, would ultimately be contributing via taxes. The desire to be oppressed is so strong with the melanin deficient smh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761529386.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39775617972.0" user="gasoman3" delta="False">
    <text>The 40 acres and a mule was from the after the civil war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759998759.0" user="Daystar1124" delta="False">
    <text>Google says: "Psychologists use the term “gaslighting” to refer to a specific type of manipulation where the manipulator is trying to get someone else (or a group of people) to question their own reality, memory or perceptions."

I think it fits. And I'm not lumping all POC into this, as is the general point I'm making with gaslighting. Id actually also include white SJW seeking guilt and attaining it with gaslighting. Most of my black friends feel the same way you comment, but it isn't all. There is a spectrum in this as well and it is rather broad, unfortunately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760672256.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Of course there’s a spectrum. No one said otherwise. 

And no one is gaslighting you. I know the definition of the term and still have no idea how you think it applies here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39776109412.0" user="Daystar1124" delta="False">
    <text>It applies. The point of gaslighting is to be subtle and try to change the person's view of themselves and their world. That's what happens when something doesn't fit a narrative and gets lumped in as "white fragility" when it should be something else. Saying anything that could even be construed as "white fragility" is also racist is gaslighting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39779177045.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>A) You still don’t understand what gaslighting is. 

B) No one wants you to feel “guilty”. That’s a red herring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39779239536.0" user="Daystar1124" delta="False">
    <text>Disagree, both counts. Thanks for your input! Check the upvotes and downvotes on this thread to see where the rest of the folks that followed this convo have felt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39779600172.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Only angry fragile white personalities read this far down. Good try though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40083384270.0" user="cyprocoque" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't apply here. What you are basically saying is that any perspective that attempts to change your worldview is gaslighting. You need to check your definition of gaslighting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40085155045.0" user="Daystar1124" delta="False">
    <text>I have. Please check yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758183559.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>No one is under any obligation to help anyone because of a wrongdoing, real or perceived, done in the past by someone of a similar skin tone.  Relative moral standing to one another is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758270397.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>No one here said anything about helping anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758445651.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>You did.  In the comment I replied to. lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758990253.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Try again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759252999.0" user="nyx-of-spades" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What they want is for people who share traits with perpetrators to take *responsibility* for helping right those wrongs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759282044.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand the confusion. Let me clarify: Taking responsibility is not about helping people. It’s about accepting things as being what they are. 

I don’t expect you to actually do much. I might hope you will, but I don’t expect it. But I do expect you to accept reality for what it is. In doing so, you will hopefully adjust how you think and vote, nothing more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758497537.0" user="arz1" delta="False">
    <text>Just a question - I am white, but I don’t feel like a member of any ‘white’ group, or at least a group that is small enough to be culturally ‘white’ with enough commonalities to have me speak to them as a unified group. What are the expectations for someone like me in the context of white fragility? 

And also, if I were part of a unified ‘white’ group, wouldn’t addressing them by their race be inherently backwards? I mean, we’ve already established that race has no bearing on ideas, intelligence, morals, etc - how is it at all progressive to believe *that* while also morally addressing a group on the basis of their race?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759061283.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>This is a great question, and I commend you for asking it openly and articulately. I’ll try to give it the same respect. 

Let me start by challenging the premise in the second sentence of your second paragraph. No one said race has “no bearing” on those things. It doesn’t *have* to have bearing on those things, but everyone knows that it does sometimes. 

What we’re broadly talking about here is “identity”. Race is merely one component, but for a lot of people it’s a big part. One of the most dramatic shifts in political science and social science research in the last generation is treating “white identity” as a distinct form of self-identification. Previously people only considered minority groups as having “black identity” or “Latino identity”, but we’ve come to realize that even people who don’t self-identify as part of a specific white-group-subset, still often posses a broad sense of “white identity”. This can be measured scientifically, and is well established in the social science literature if you’re curious about it. 

As to your critical question of “what is expected of me?”, the answer is of course largely contextual. But I’ll suggest a few broad strokes…

1. Listen and learn. Be actively curious about the experiences of people who don’t look like you, and believe them when they explain that their experiences are far more different from yours than you might expect. 

2. Be willing to help right the wrongs against them. This isn’t *because* you or your ancestors perpetrated those crimes. It is simply because those crimes were not perpetrated against you. 

The phrase “white privilege” is easily misunderstood because we tend to think of the word “privilege” as meaning “advantage”. What it actually means in this context is not “White privilege”, it’s  “White, (lack-of-the-specific-harms-perpetrated-against-black-people)”. 

The “privilege” isn’t an advantage, it’s the lack of specific historic and current harms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759349228.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The phrase “white privilege” is easily misunderstood because we tend to think of the word “privilege” as meaning “advantage”.

This is literally why that term is so divisive. We ought to be talking about black disadvantages, surely?

The implication is that it's a race to the bottom, not that our fellow people are being denied basic rights and decency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759372475.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. This is what the term has always been meant to imply. It can be confusing, but it’s easy to understand once it’s clarified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758869311.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>What traits do they share other than skin color? Less than half a percent of Americans owned slaves. Should all Asians “take responsibility” (whatever the heck that means) for china’s treatment of the Uighur? 

You in one paragraph say they shouldn’t feel guilty, then spend the next paragraph describing how they should feel guilty without using the word. You basically detailed a secular version of the Original Sin targeted at one race.

Swap out feel guilty/take responsibility with repent and you’ve got yourself genesis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759075677.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>To your second question about the Uighurs, yes. Emphatically YES. 

AND… So should anyone who has not been subjected to those kinds of harms. The point is not “feel guilty”, the point is “if you and yours haven’t been harmed, please help defend and uplift the people who have”. 

This includes me and probably you. We should all stand up for people who have been subjugated, *especially but NOT ONLY* if our cultural ancestors were involved. 

I realize it’s a subtle yet critical distinction. Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759179398.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Idk why we should have varying levels of common curtesy and human empathy based off of how much we perceive “our people” were wronged in the past. Every “and yours” has been harmed at one point, and  has been the harmer at another. 

Just be a good human being and step in to help when you can regardless of your race. I’m Latino, Mexican ancestry. I have nothing to do with the cartels, and no matter how many or how few people they behead, Thats a non factor in the way I treat others because **I’m not responsible for the actions of any random bloke who shares a similar ethnic background as me**.

Edit: my response was more tailored towards the pre edit comment before you deleted you for a second time saying we should take responsibility for the actions of others of our race and before it was generalized to everyone speaking out instead of the just the bad races. I agree more with the edited comment but I don’t agree with the “especially but not only”, don’t let your race be a factor for your virtues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759261151.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>That edits is critical. The whole point is to have empathy for - and actively try to help rectify - any harms which are currently still relevant to modern life. 

Yes, basically anyone besides the royal families of the world have some degree of oppression and persecution in their backgrounds. But not all of us are *still feeling those effects*. 

My people are Irish. Once upon a time we were heavily persecuted both in our home country and in the US. But we are no longer treated unfairly in almost any way whatsoever, and the effects of those past harms have mostly dissipated. Today, Ireland is a prosperous nation and Irish-Americans are among the most prosperous and socially advantaged populations. 

Thus, we don’t need much help. We don’t need much sympathy, and we don’t need much material restitution, even from Americans whose cultural ancestors may have persecuted us. If you feel like feeling bad about what your ancestors did to us, I don’t really care, because we’re doing ok. 

None of these statements apply broadly to Black Americans. As a group they are not among the most prosperous Americans, and they are not generally socially advantaged in today’s society. Many of them still experience many of the same prejudices that their recent ancestors experienced. And by and large they are still experiencing the material effects of the disadvantages their ancestors were handed. 

How can we not sympathize with this? How can we not want to help rectify this? How can you look at these people who helped build our country and *not* want their whole race to be uplifted by its prosperity in the same way other groups have?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759274768.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I can sympathize, I could help rectify. I am not responsible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759375067.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>This humanist description of how you think about this is similar to mine. Except it doesn't chime with your previous comments.

Also words like responsibility and guilt are not the right ones in my view. The fact I want to help my fellow man to prosper is nothing to do with my heritage. The Uighurs need help _because they need help_.

But this is totally universal. There's no reason that I, a British man of Indian ethnicity, should feel more empathy for the Uighurs than my mate Dave.

So I'm with you, right up until "especially if our cultural ancestors were involved".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759378531.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Well then that’s where we differ.

Personally, if my dad does something shitty to you, I’ll feel more shitty about it than if it had been someone else’s dad.

If that isn’t how you feel about things, that’s entirely up to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761579170.0" user="jiambles" delta="False">
    <text>The big issue is that generally, it's not your dad. It's your great great great grand uncle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761771134.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>So? I realize the effect dissipates, but when does it stop mattering at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761861381.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Once We get to an ancestor who I’ve never known because they died before I was born. So Somewhere between great and great great grandpa. 

Also again, most people have no slave owning ancestry. .35% of Americans owned at least 1 slave at the time. You’re looking at the jeff bezos’ of the 19th century and extrapolating it to everyone sharing the most superficial trait with them. May as well push for all bald people to to own up to his actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761933881.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Again, what matters most is the experience of black people today, not the culpability of specific white people. 

Black people have remained oppressed for generations past slavery. And if you don’t think you personally know any white people who helped contribute to that, then you’re not paying attention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761966784.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Even if I did know white people who helped contribute to oppression (I don’t, no one in my life has enough power to be an oppressor) it’s not my responsibility and it’s not my fault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39762111686.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>That’s up to you, but it’s a shitty attitude. Again, if someone I know does something shitty to you, I will care about it and gladly do my best to correct it. 

If you don’t give a shit, that’s your right, but it’s a sad way to live.

And everyone has the ability to contribute to racism. Everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763698494.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Except Nobody in America knows a slave owner. I’m not buddy buddy with whoever passed Jim Crow or redlining. 

I wasn’t alive when any of this happened and my ancestors had zero to do with any of this.  Again, its the concept of original sin rebranded towards one race, the only relation your average white guy in America has to any of the people who are actually responsible is that they share a similar skin color.

If that’s all it takes then modern day African Americans should “take responsibility” for selling black people into slavery. You can pretend they are personally familiar with the tribe leaders of 400 years ago.

A sad way to live would be feeling guilty over things that you couldn’t possibly effect because it happened **hundreds of years before you were born**. I’ve never been a fan of catholic guilt and I’m not a fan of its cheap racist rebranding as white guilt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763764010.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>We absolutely should take responsibility for crimes that were committed in the name of groups we’re attached to. 

If I bought a restaurant and discovered that the prior owner had been using unsafe practices which made many customers sick, I would absolutely issue a statement apologizing to the victims on behalf of the restaurant, and promising to make things right. I wouldn’t have a legal obligation, but I would feel a moral obligation. Likewise if someone in my family - no matter how distant - hurt someone else, I’d feel a sense of moral obligation. 

Our country hurt people. Badly. And many people in our country continue to hurt them. That bothers me and I feel personally committed to acknowledging and righting those wrongs. 

You don’t have to feel the same way, but that’s how many of our moral compasses work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763870785.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I never said I wouldn’t right those wrongs, or stop racism when I see it. In fact I distinctly remember a comment where I said the opposite. 

I’m not attached to the slave owners of hundreds of years ago. 99.65% of white Americans didn’t have slaves, nor were they the only race who had slaves even in America. Your wealth was a much much more accurate determining factor than skin color whether someone of those times were a slave owner or not.

&amp;gt;If I bought a restaurant and discovered yada yada yada.

I never bought a slave, you took responsibility of the restaurant when you purchased it and the bad reputation it may have had at the time. 

&amp;gt;Likewise if someone in my family yada yada yada. 

No one in my family distant or not ever owned slaves nor have I personally bought one. You keep bringing up actual threads of relation and my point has always been 99% of people have none of these. The only actual commonality is a superficial trait.

Where do we stop with feeling guilty over those “in the name of groups we’re attached to”. Do all people with black hair have to apologize for the actions of Hitler? Should those under 5’10 be racked with guilt cuz Mao killed millions? Are all women responsible for Casey Anthony murdering her child?

I can acknowledge the actions are bad. I could do what I can to remedy them. But I had zero to do with it and I don’t feel any more bad about some atrocity if I found out the guy doing it also wore glasses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764072917.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>“…you took responsibility of the restaurant when you purchased it and the bad reputation it may have had at the time.”

YES! Finally, you get it. That’s it exactly. When we choose to be citizens of this country we assume responsibility for the harms it has caused *just like we would with a restaurant*! 

That doesn’t mean you should feel “guilty”, that doesn’t mean you did anything wrong, and it doesn’t mean you have to personally apologize. But we do - to use YOUR words - “take responsibility” for the institutions and what they’ve done in the past. 

Glad we got there, you said it perfectly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764134064.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>What did your average white person do to earn the responsibility of slave owners actions from hundreds of years ago. In the hypothetical You purchased the restaurant. I’ve never purchased any plantation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764311695.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You joined the United States of America and happen to be part of the white majority. This is the restaurant.

You have benefitted indirectly while other people have been harmed. The least we can do is acknowledge those harms and - again using YOUR words - take responsibility (NOT culpability) for making those wrongs right if we can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764559352.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t not benefit from the actions of slave owners. My family history traces relatively recently to both Mexico and Ireland, my grandpa was put in the retard class because he didn’t speak English, he had to drop out of middle school to work the fields with his dad to help pay rent.  Whatever place of privilege you believe I started from, I guarantee it’s little more than every other person who was lucky enough to be born in America.

Even then you still seem to be not understanding that being born somewhere is a draw of the cards, purchasing a restaurant doesn’t happen by chance the moment you were born. You are responsible for the restaurant, you bought it, you own it. 

I’ll say it for the fourth time: im not against acknowledging bad things historically, im not against righting those wrongs. But im not responsible, by any stretch of the word, for the actions of those who I had no control over. And Im also not going to treat any one atrocity worse because by happenstance we share a similar superficial trait. If the Holocaust is 95 out of 100 bad I’m not going to say it’s a 75 because the perps weren’t Hispanic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764708487.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I already addressed the “I didn’t earn anything from slavery!” stuff on the other thread. But I’ll just repeat again that privilege isn’t bout what you earned, it’s about how many ways you *weren’t harmed*. 

Also again, you don’t HAVE to do anything. But just like you said you would take responsibility for a restaurant if you bought it, I believe you have a moral obligation to take responsibility for the restaurant if it was given to you for free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764764854.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>No one alive was harmed by slavery. So I guess we all have white privilege.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765423223.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>It’s batshit crazy to claim that no one alive was harmed by slavery. If your grandfather was murdered, you’ve still been harmed. If your great great great grandfather was brutally oppressed and you’ve lived in a society prejudiced against you your entire life, you have absolutely been harmed. 

Have some damn compassion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763040305.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>I'd feel bad if my Dad did shitty things to people, because he's my Dad. He's directly in my sphere of influence and whilst I'm not responsible for his actions, I can help change them. 

I'm not sure what point you're trying to make, because that's obviously not true of people centuries ago, in places thousands of miles away, that I've never met and couldn't possibly ever meet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763324429.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>What if your dad did these things and died before you were born? If I met someone who was wronged by him I’d still feel worse than if it was some random guy I have no connection to whatsoever. And if I even slightly benefitted from those crimes, even indirectly, I’d feel extra badly and seek to set things right if I could. 

It’s natural for humans to feel responsibility for the actions of others. We do it all the time. You don’t have to if you don’t want to, but it’s a natural human compassionate response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763961991.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It’s natural for humans to feel responsibility for the actions of others.

Yeah, maybe if they don’t know what the word responsibility means. If I break something on the job I’m responsible. If my coworker does independent of me he is responsible. I may feel bad, pity, sympathetic, etc. I could go out of my way to help him fix whatever’s fucked up. But at the end of the day I’ll be pissed if the employer is mad at me for something I have no control over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764047666.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>That’s…a weird way of taking this. No one is mad at you. That’s not what this is about at all. 

If I bought a restaurant and discovered that the prior owner had been using unsafe practices which made many customers sick, I would absolutely issue a statement apologizing to the victims *on behalf of the restaurant*, and promising to make things right. I wouldn’t have a legal obligation, but I would feel a moral obligation. Likewise if someone in my family - no matter how distant - hurt someone else, I’d feel a sense of moral obligation to that victim.

Our country hurt people. Badly. And many people in our country continue to hurt them today. That bothers me and I feel personally committed to acknowledging and righting those wrongs. I call that a sense of “responsibility” but you can call it whatever you want.

You don’t have to feel the same way, but that’s how my moral compass works, and I’m not alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764105815.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve already [responded](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/i9mdr29/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;amp;utm_name=iossmf&amp;amp;context=3) to an almost word for word copy of this comment and the hypothetical situation you seem to think reinforces your point. Whether or not you want to call it mad, resentment, disappointment, or whatever. You’ve said people are less moral for not feeling guilty (or personally remorseful, or whatever long winded synonyms you want to give) about someone else’s actions they had no possibility to effect. 

You obviously think less of them for not having white guilt specifically, even if they’re already doing what they can to remedy the wrongs of the past. I’m just saying using that logic everyone in the world should have this exact same guilt for everything because there’s always going to be 1 trait they share with with someone who did bad things too. Still waiting to know if a dog owner is more responsible for the Holocaust because hitler owned a dog.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764121528.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Well your last response said it perfectly when you acknowledged that the restaurant owner is taking responsibility for the past actions of the restaurant, even though he has no reason to feel “guilty”! 

I’m so glad we can ditch the whole “why should I feel guilty?” argument. It was never about guilt and I’m glad you can see that now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764140961.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you did a good job of ignoring what I said and pretending like I agreed with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764308461.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You explicitly agreed with me. You even used the word “responsibility” in a place I hadn’t. You said it even better than I had.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764429497.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, I used the word responsibility? Now show me where I said we should be responsible for the actions of slave owners.

I didn’t agree with you, I pointed out how your hypothetical is a completely different scenario than the white guilt this whole post is about. You do an awfully good job at misrepresenting what I said but anyone who earnestly reads my comment could tell I was differentiating the active role you would have in purchasing a restaurant with a bad reputation vs the complete lack of choice the same skin color as someone who did something bad hundreds of years ago. 

One of them directly assumed responsibility with the purchase the other is complete random chance, luck of the draw. That is why I used the word responsibility when specifically talking about the restaurant. You can pretend like me pointing out that distinction is me somehow agreeing with you that modern whites are responsible for the acts of white people 200 years ago, but at this point you’re just showing off how dishonest you are about this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764495783.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You’re right, you didn’t purchase the restaurant. It’s more like you inherited the restaurant for free and lived your whole life benefiting from the fact that some of the restaurant was stolen from other people. 

In my mind that makes it even MORE morally imperative that you “take responsibility” than if you had actively bought it. 

Again, this is an entirely moral debate. If you don’t feel a moral obligation to take responsibility for the harms done by members of groups you’re a part of, that’s entirely up to you. 

But I’d guess that you do have this same instinct when the events are closer to you in time and place. The only difference between us is that I extend that compassion back farther.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764567295.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Well if you know where my inherited slavery money is I could really use it right now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764633786.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You inherited the ability to not be harassed and judged and discriminated against. You also inherited something called “network wealth” which is hugely valuable and worth googling. 

Again, most of what is meant by “privilege” is a lifetime free from the harms done to oppressed groups. You and most of your ancestors had those advantages, even if they never earned a dime directly from slavery.

Every time you say “my ancestors didn’t have slaves!” or “I didn’t earn anything from slavery!” all you’re really saying is “I don’t actually understand what people mean by “privilege” and I’m too stubborn to learn because it’s easier to win an argument if I don’t!”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764747220.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I googled network wealth, only things that popped up was investing firms and financial planners. If this is something you coined right now to try say that minorities have a harder time with getting into institutions such as jobs or schools, The opposite is true due to the prevalence of affirmative action.

Sorry, but I don’t believe oppression is a large factor in the day to day lives of your average American regardless of skin color. It’s illegal for employers to discriminate based off race age or gender (unless you’re white or Asian), sure every once in a while you deal with some dickhead who maybe says something mean or some crazed gunman, but for all the other 23 hours and 58 minutes of the day they’re just any other American who goes about their day. The existence of individual racists is not tantamount to oppression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765441577.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Network wealth is the measure of the combined wealth of everyone in your personal network. The average white American’s network is massively more wealthy than the average black American’s. This is a direct result of slavery and generations of subsequent oppression and prejudice. 

It contributes to the people you know who can help your parents raise you, how much free time people around you had when you were a kid, how many role models you’ve had, contacts that helped you do your homework or get into college or connect you with jobs. The list goes on and on and on. 

If you don’t see how these factors compound exponentially over generations, then you’re simply not doing the math.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759358191.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Should all Asians “take responsibility” (whatever the heck that means) for china’s treatment of the Uighur? 

As someone who is ethnically Indian, born in Africa and grew up in Britain, this made me laugh.

Thing is though, because I identify as British primarily, I feel colonial guilt. It's not rational, but the emotion is often there.

Totally agree with your assessment of Original Sin. I read White Fragility and it's a rephrasing of Catholicism as far as my novice theology can discern.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759703120.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>I feel a similar way about the US’ imperialism and overall foreign fuckery, but I would not attribute it to guilt. 

Nothing I could do about it. The worlds a shit place, I could spend my whole life trying to inform as much people about ongoing ~~forever wars~~ ‘conflicts’ and the pattern of being lied into them, and nothing will change. There’s hundreds of incels (internet celebrities) already doing that.

The world isn’t my sphere of influence. I’ll do what I can where I can, but taking on the military industrial complex or making sure no one is racist ever seems like an unnecessary stressor for how little of an impact I could have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763013806.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>Agree with you, but I'm not sure if you misused "incel" on purpose. If not, that usually means something extraordinarily different to "internet celebrity".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763627179.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>It’s a [bg kumbi reference](https://youtu.be/edf49-_Czs4).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759166338.0" user="frivolous_squid" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about who shares traits with the perpetrators, it's about who is currently benefitting / suffering from the system they set up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759220119.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>It’s both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759277948.0" user="BlueSkySummers" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is really how much responsibility should be taken for the actions of their ancestors. For instance, I'm from a country that wasn't involved in imperialist conquests, the slave trade, or many of the things that many would argue "benefit white people" in the us. My country was also attacked and brutally conquered by the Swedes. Now, do I have any animosity to them? No. Do I think modern day swedes should come to terms with what they did hundreds of years ago? Also no.

The bigger issue is these types of identity politics generally are framed within an America centric model, because that's quite easy to see the treatment of native Americans, or slaves. Which obviously, was horrific, and beneficial to white colonists. But to call it out as something embodied within "whiteness" is actually very short sighted to the history of the world.

And on top of that, it generally doesn't extend beyond criticism of white Americans. For instance, India still has a very real caste system, and theres tons of  Brahmin who have immigrated to the us. They're privilege is absolutely tied to privilege and racism. It's likely why they have the opportunity to leave India. So how should we address them and teach them to come to terms with their privilege, how do we single them out as a race and call them out not for injustices of the past, but those still occurring today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759296954.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the term “white” is American-centric in most of these discussions. I generally agree that it should be considered in whatever context it was originally meant. 

To your point about other privileged classes, the general rule is simple: if you see a group who has been oppressed historically and/or currently, and is still feeling the effects of that oppression, try to help them. If you happen to have a personal history which has benefitted from that oppression, try to help even more. But help them either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759315048.0" user="BlueSkySummers" delta="False">
    <text>Right. But this is also generally about someone telling someone else how to feel. So with Indian immigrants to the us for instance, how to educate them about their own racist history that benefits them? If we're honest it's generally not about just making things better, it's focused on guilt, which is what turns people off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759338397.0" user="nesh34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No one - and I mean no one - wants you to “feel guilty” about anything you have not personally done.

This isn't true. Many want people to feel guilty and feel guilt themselves.

An example of such a person is the person that banned OP, and the person who they replied to.

&amp;gt; News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened last week.

What am I misunderstanding about this person's intentions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759362011.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>There are definitely people who believe others should feel guilty about things they have not done.

To be highly specific: They may or may not want to elicit desirable behaviours, but the definitely want their target to *feel guilt*. They write as much, we don't have to speculate.

More generally, writing an absolutely definitive statement on behalf of all of mankind is obvious nonsense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759368113.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Who is the most powerful one you can name? Because anyone of import is concerned with what I’m talking about, not random guilt from random people. Guilt accomplishes nothing, and anyone with any real power knows it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759393200.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>I don't need it to be an important person, or sourced, for my point to stand. You made a very bold statement about absolutely no-one. I'm telling you the absolute statement is patently untrue. Overall, it detracts from the valid points you are trying to say which are preceded by such an obviously falsifiable opening statement. I'm not making any statement about the utility of guilt (although I don't agree with you) only that your absolute statement about the intentions of every person on earth is obviously untrue. If you mean "no-one I consider important wants you to feel guilty" then write that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759505722.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, well then I’ll be happy to walk it back to “virtually no one” if that makes you willing to accept the rest of it.

But that’s a weird point to take umbrage with if you otherwise agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759571571.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree "virtually no-one" wants people to feel guilt for things they haven't done. It's a totally baseless assertion, just like the first version, and moreover is not in line with my experience. You can tone down the language but that doesn't change the wildly speculative heart of the point.

You do not know the motives of that many people. 

You opened with a point, then strongly reinforced the same point in the same sentence. Then when challenged, you iterated a slightly toned down version of that point a *third time*... At which point you switch to the implication that this point wasn't that important after all... and then start with oblique slights at me for picking up on it. I'll get whiplash of you keep changing course like this.

If you mean "no-one I consider important wants you to feel guilty" then write that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760647337.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I mean what I said and I reserve the right to clarify anything that isn’t perfectly worded the first time. Now that you understand, feel free to respond rather than continuously attacking the original wording.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760950511.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not attacking you or your wording. I'm saying I don't agree with your statement. If you want to say something else, please go ahead. I already told you I did not agree with your second version, for the same reasons as first time. That issue is logical, not phrasing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761781568.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You very clearly attacked the wording multiple times. 

If we disagree then we disagree, but that’s not all you’ve been saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763194530.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>Disagreeing with you is not attacking you. I have no intention to offend you, but I utterly disagree with your **point** and I told you as much. You know it was the **point** not the wording because when you rephrased it I *still disagreed*. 

At this stage, if you're taking that personally, maybe consider a breather and re-read the exchange in a few hours/tomorrow.

All I have been saying, many times, is that you cannot possibly know the motives of all (or virtually all) people. I stand by that, and I do not think it is an attack to tell you so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763309535.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You’re welcome to disagree with me. But I honestly can’t believe you’re pretending like you didn’t repeatedly attack my wording. Scroll up dude. 

Now that you DO understand my meaning, it sounds like you’re merely quibbling with the fact that I don’t believe there are almost any people who actually want guilt alone, rather than action. I would argue that in order to disprove my assertion you’d have to prove the opposite. If you can find hoards of people who want people to feel personally guilty about sins from our ancestors, let me know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763534958.0" user="FantasticMrPox" delta="False">
    <text>I scrolled up as requested. I saw me repeatedly reject your point. I even saw me very clearly tell you that toning down the language wouldn't make the point valid: https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9jtlrn

I then told you again that the issue was logical, not phrasing:
https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/-/i9kn5rj 

Please show me where I "attacked" your wording. I cannot find it.

Your second paragraph is not an accurate characterisation of my point which I've now made several times. You also tell me I'm "quibbling". OK buddy, I'm not going to bother engaging if you want to put words in my mouth and insult me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759560621.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It’s saying that as a part of the same group, you have an opportunity to speak out against malevolent members of your group. If you instead choose to point out that you’re not as bad as those bad people, it shows that you’re insecurely defending yourself, rather than confidently helping condemn the bad actors.

But what if they’re not “part of the same group”?  It’s not like all white people are in the same country club (…bad example) and get together on the weekends to discuss the merits of deciding whether we, as white people, should be racist or not. 

Just because we share the same skin color doesn’t mean I should be associated with someone else, and certainly not take responsibility for their actions. That’s insane.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760662827.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Again, it isn’t mostly about being white. It’s mostly about not being black. 


But being white is a piece of it, and you do benefit from the color of your skin every single day. Again, not by gaining some huge advantage, but by not experiencing the countless *disadvantages* that having other colors of skin can cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39762896137.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>I have no problem recognizing that I don’t face the same kind of discrimination as other folks face. That’s a fact. 

But no way in hell am I going to take responsibility for other peoples actions just because we are both white. 

Which is exactly what you’ve suggested I do. No way. I don’t know what color your skin is - but what if someone asked you to take responsibility for every terrible thing everyone else who shares your skin color did. That’s a terrible way to group people - it’s actually racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763338494.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Again, no one is asking you to take FULL responsibility for anything. We’re merely asking you to acknowledge that you have benefitted (however mildly and indirectly) while others were harmed. Even if the only benefit you received was to *not be harmed* that’s still an advantage over those who were. 

Given that these harms were perpetrated en masse for generations, the compassionate thing to do is acknowledge them and try to help those who were hurt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763373329.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>That’s very different from what you’ve laid out. As I said. No problem recognizing that I don’t face similar discrimination. But I won’t take any responsibility for actions that aren’t mine. And you asking me to do so is pretty over the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763403948.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Again, “full responsibility” is different than acknowledging something happened that hurt someone else and relative to them benefitted you. If you understand the difference then please respond to that and not just specific words that are apparently very triggering for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763714065.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>I’m just responding to the words you wrote. If you don’t mean them - go ahead and retract. 

Any responsibility whatsoever is different than “acknowledging.”

I won’t take *any* responsibility for thing I didn’t do. You asking me to do that is over the line. The fact that it’s not full responsibility is irrelevant. Any responsibility at all for thing I had no control over is too much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763798724.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>We absolutely should take responsibility for crimes that were committed in the name of groups we’re attached to. 

Millions of Muslims and Muslim leaders spoke out denouncing the 9/11 attacks on behalf of their faith and community. Every time there’s a school shooting, the leaders and members of that community speak out denouncing the attacks as not representative of the institution they care about. 

If I bought a restaurant and discovered that the prior owner had been using unsafe practices which made many customers sick, I would absolutely issue a statement apologizing to the victims *on behalf of the restaurant*, and promising to make things right. I wouldn’t have a legal obligation, but I would feel a moral obligation. Likewise if someone in my family - no matter how distant - hurt someone else, I’d feel a sense of moral obligation to that victim. 

Our country hurt people. Badly. And many people in our country continue to hurt them today. That bothers me and I feel personally committed to acknowledging and righting those wrongs. I call that a sense of “responsibility” but you can call it whatever you want. 

You don’t have to feel the same way, but that’s how my moral compass works, and I’m not alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765066065.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the leaders and members of that community speak out denouncing the attacks as not representative of the institution they care about.

Ok - maybe if I was a white supremacist I would care about that. But I’m not a representative of “the white people”. I don’t look at another white person and wink clandestinely and think “we’re part of the same crew because of our skin tone”. And I won’t take any responsibility for other peoples actions because we share the same color skin. 

Un like me, you seem to believe that people ought to be lumped together and affiliate with one another based on their race. There is a word for that…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765413450.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You’re a member of the white people club whether you wanna be or not. The most conceited thing in the world is benefitting from something you didn’t earn for generations and then claiming you don’t owe anyone anything because you didn’t ask for it. Have some damn humility and compassion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765502592.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>Ok - so now, in addition to having to take responsibility for something I didn’t do because of my skin, I also *owe* someone something because of my skin? What do I owe? Money? 

As I said earlier: I have no problem recognizing that I don’t face the same kind of discrimination as other folks face. That’s a fact.

But saying that someone must do/be anything because of their race is straight up racist. It’s literally deciding how someone should act or behave or be treated based on the color of their skin. I should not be held responsible for the actions of people who weren’t even my ancestors just because we share the same skin color/race. And neither should anyone else. 

And you ought to seriously reconsider your world view that organizes and groups people based solely on the color of their skin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765522019.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>The only thing you owe is the one thing you’re refusing the give: humility and respect. You won’t acknowledge the disadvantages others have because you’re unwilling to acknowledge that you and your ancestors benefitted from NOT having those disadvantages.

You can’t say “I respect and acknowledge the suffering of others” and simultaneously say “I never benefitted from anything”. Those statements negate each other. 

If for hundreds of years your basketball team has played in a league where many other players had one hand tied behind their backs, you can’t look at your record and say “We did it all on our own, no one ever helped us and I don’t feel any responsibility to make those generations of unfairness right.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765656021.0" user="Montallas" delta="False">
    <text>When did I say “I never benefitted from anything”? 

And when did I say I don’t respect or empathize with people who are discriminated against? You don’t need to take responsibility for something in order to respect the folks going through an ordeal. 

And the notion that white people should be viewed as a homogeneous or monolithic entity through space and time where each individual is responsible for the sins of the others - even from generations prior - is total bullshit. It’s not like I get to have some of Bill Gate’s money - even though we are both white. Do you think the same way about other skin colors too? 

Entire kingdoms in West Africa made vast fortunes by selling other Africans into the transatlantic slave trade for hundreds of years.  Hell - one of my friends grew up in Mauritania and he’d regularly see slaves being walked through the streets in chains with bags over their heads driven by slavers. The slavers were black. So should *all* black people today take responsibility for what those slavers did? Both hundreds of years ago and also just 25 years ago? By your logic, the answer is yes. Seems like by your logic black people are just as culpable and should take just as much responsibility as white people. 

The funny thing is, you’re making all kinds of assumptions about me just because I told you my skin color. Which is racist of you. Sure I’ve benefitted by not facing the same kind of discrimination as other. And that has an effect of compounding over generations. But my ancestors were discriminated against too for being indentured, Irish, and poor. My kids are only half white and will likely face some discrimination. Same for my wife. But I don’t feel guilty for that. Nor should I. Nor should anyone other than the folks doing the discriminating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39765955118.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus. You’re just having a conversation with yourself. I never said any of the crap you’re putting up as strawmen so you can knock them down and make yourself feel smart. 

No one said you should feel guilty. Least of all me. That’s the point I keep making, and you keep coming back and defending against the opposite for no reason. 

It’s incredibly boring to say to someone “I don’t believe ‘Thing A’ but I do believe ‘Thing B’” and have the other person say “Thing A is insane and here are ten reasons why it’s wrong.” 

Good grief it’s exhausting. Enjoy talking to yourself, this is boring. 

For what it’s worth, I’m glad you can recognize at least some of your privilege. I will continue choosing to take responsibility for the groups and institutions I’m lucky to be a part of by recognizing their flaws - past and present - and honoring those who’ve been hurt while also recognizing how I have tacitly benefitted from those injustices. I hope you will too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760055153.0" user="Anklebender91" delta="False">
    <text>Why do I need to right other people’s wrongs? They aren’t my problem.  All I need to do is just live a decent life.

Everyone is so hung up on righting the wrongs of others when the real positive change in the world is just being decent to each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760634572.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t want you to right those wrongs. I want you to acknowledge that those wrongs existed, still exist, and are still having massive effects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39760789700.0" user="Anklebender91" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that they happened. There will always be affects with shit that happened in the past. But personally I think unless you become forward thinking harping on the past is the equivalent of someone that keeps talking about how their ex fucked them up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761786928.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>That’s an unbelievably insulting and ignorant comparison. Holy shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763606098.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No one - and I mean no one - wants you to “feel guilty” about anything you have not personally done. If you think they do want you to feel guilty, then you’ve misunderstood them.

I gotta say, that is a very, very sweeping statement — and it’s wrong.

&amp;gt;What they want is for people who share traits with perpetrators to take responsibility for helping right those wrongs.

Really?  I am curious what you think Muslims should be doing to right the wrongs of 9/11 and the thousands of other terrorist attacks committed by Islamicists.   And what do you think black people generally should do to right the wrongs committed by Darrell Brooks, the black man who drive an SUV into the Waukesha Christmas Parade — heck while you are at it, black males, who are 8% of the population, commit 55% of murders — should every black male be righting those wrongs?

Or maybe, just maybe, each person is responsible for righting the wrongs that he personally is “at fault” for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763731875.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>You might remember countless Muslim leaders and regular citizens condemning 9/11 on behalf of their faith and community. So too do members of other groups when crimes are committed in their name. It’s incredibly common. You should try it sometime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763860452.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You might remember countless Muslim leaders and regular citizens condemning 9/11 on behalf of their faith and community.

Do you think white people would hesitate to condemn attacks made supposedly on behalf of white people?

My question is, do you think Muslim leaders and regular citizens have a positive obligation to try to right the wrongs caused by Islamic terrorism?  

&amp;gt; You should try it sometime.  

Try harder to not be a jackass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764099777.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;Do you think white people would hesitate to condemn attacks made supposedly on behalf of white people?

Yes. It happens all the time including this week with the Buffalo attacks. Also, you’re doing it right now. 


&amp;gt;My question is, do you think Muslim leaders and regular citizens have a positive obligation to try to right the wrongs caused by Islamic terrorism?

Legally, of course not, but morally, yes. We should all strive to right the wrongs caused by other members of our community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764128799.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It happens all the time including this week with the Buffalo attacks.

What?  Have you heard a single person *defend*, or even fail to criticize, the Buffalo shooter?

To the contrary, people seem to be engaging in aggressively claiming that the shooter somehow caucused with their own opponents.

&amp;gt;Also, you’re doing it right now.  

Uh, what?  If you are trying to construct a kafka-trap, (a) you are doing a terrible job and (b) stop.

&amp;gt;Legally, of course not, but morally, yes.

Have you tried this theory out on your Muslim friends?  I have known a lot of Muslims, and as a group they are very peaceable and considerate, but I think you are going to get punched in the mouth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764344561.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt; What? Have you heard a single person defend, or even fail to criticize, the Buffalo shooter?

No one said anything about defending slavery or being pro-slavery. The point is about acknowledging the harms done by the thing you belong to (the USA and white majority) as well as the ways those harms continue to hurt other people and not you. Then doing what you can to help set things right if you are able and willing. 

Again, this is just how my moral compass works, you don’t have to share it. But if a group I belong to does something wrong to others for prejudiced reasons - past or present - I’m going to acknowledge it and want the victims to know that I’m sorry *on behalf of the group*. Not personally sorry or guilty; sorry *on behalf of the group*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764372099.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The point is about acknowledging the harms done by the thing you belong to (the USA and white majority) 

Let’s *start* with all the bad things that black people have ever done.  And Muslims.

Would that be OK?

No, I don‘t think it would be.  

&amp;gt;this is just how my moral compass works

What do you call a “moral compass” that singles out disfavored groups, exaggerates their shortcomings and minimizes their contributions, and insisting they apologize?

&amp;gt; I’m going to acknowledge it and want the victims to know that I’m sorry on behalf of the group.

What gives you the right to apologize on behalf of other people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764461742.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re a part of a group, you have a right to apologize on behalf of that group if the group does something you believe is wrong. You aren’t “in charge” of that group, but you’re allowed to speak as a part of that group. Like a kid apologizing on behalf of his family if his dad does something wrong. He’s saying that he condemns the harm and wants the victims to know that at least one member of the family is sorry for the harm that was done. 

&amp;gt;Would that be OK?

Yeah sure, why wouldn’t it be? I wouldn’t do it as a retort to talking about harms by other groups because it would smack of “whataboutism”. But in another context it would be fine for any victims of any crimes to talk about the harms perpetrated against them, even if the perpetrators are minority groups. 

&amp;gt;What do you call a “moral compass” that singles out disfavored groups, exaggerates their shortcomings and minimizes their contributions, and insisting they apologize?

I’m very confused. Are you calling white people a “disfavored group”? Or are you saying I want oppressed groups to apologize? I have no idea what you’re saying because neither seems to make any sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764491010.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yeah sure, why wouldn’t it be?

OK, let’s do that first.  I want to start a nationwide conversation among black people about all the things black people have done wrong.  After that happens, Muslims.  Then gays.

&amp;gt;Are you calling white people a “disfavored group”? 

Are you not disfavoring them?  I can pull up a half-dozen examples if you like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764526773.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>I have no idea why you think white people are disfavored or why you think that I think that. But I can make this easy and say that no, white people are obviously not “disfavored” in today’s society, nor should they - or anyone else - be. But plenty of other groups still are. 

Saying that you think it’s only fair to have these discussions if we talk about other groups first, feels a little disingenuous to me. But if you’re serious then I’m happy to have those conversations in any order. I’d suggest going chronologically, which in the US means that we’ll have a few hundred years to cover before we talk about much other than white harms against people of color. 

But yes, I don’t have a problem talking about the harms other groups have perpetrated as well. (I’m extremely curious what “harms” you think that gay people have perpetrated as a group.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766094579.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have no idea why you think white people are disfavored 

Then I am not making my point clearly.

We are supposed to talk about all the things white people have done wrong.  I don’t know if you believe that white people have done more things wrong, or that we should only talk about them, but since they are the ones getting talked about, *that* is the disfavoring.

&amp;gt;Saying that you think it’s only fair to have these discussions if we talk about other groups first, feels a little disingenuous to me.

Well, I meant it sarcastically.  I don’t think it is healthy, productive, or factually correct to talk about the things “white people” do — but I thought the reasoning would be more obvious if we started with other groups.

&amp;gt;I’d suggest going chronologically, which in the US means that we’ll have a few hundred years to cover before we talk about much other than white harms against people of color.

What?  Why on Earth would we need to do that? 

That is a rhetorical question. In fact, people of all colors were doing terrible things to each other for millennia before the US ever existed.  The US by and large did fewer terrible things than other nations.

The fact that you don’t know that already is part of the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766125985.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt; I don’t know if you believe that white people have done more things wrong, or that we should only talk about them, but since they are the ones getting talked about, that is the disfavoring.

&amp;gt;The fact that you don’t know that already is part of the problem. 

Here, you are twice in one response responding to things I haven’t said at all. You even admit I haven’t said the first thing, but you argue about it anyway. 

You’re not having a conversation with ME, you’re having a conversation with hypothetical people you’ve seen on Twitter or Reddit or in memes - or even just your own imagination - and preemptively arguing with them instead. 

&amp;gt; That is a rhetorical question.

It’s exhausting and boring to have someone tell you what they think you think, or even admit that they don’t know what you think, and then argue with you anyway. It’s also exhausting to have someone pose questions and answer them for you. If you want to know what someone thinks, ask an honest question. Then wait and address their actual answer, not the one you think you’ll get. 

Have fun talking to yourself, I’m bored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766132991.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Have fun talking to yourself, I’m bored.

I win! 

(Why do people who lose and say “I have better things to do than this” not realize that they are conceding defeat in a far more embarrassing way than just admitting it?  They are losing *and* looking petulant about it.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766151313.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not what’s happening. There’s zero point in talking to someone who makes up your half of the conversation and argues against shit you haven’t said. I could post baking recipes in response and you’d still be going on about whatever nonsense you think I meant instead.

The irony is that you’re doing it again right now. I cited exactly which things you said were guilty of this and instead of addressing those or even defending yourself, you once against mischaracterized my response to make yourself feel better. 

I don’t actually exist in this conversation to you, I’m just a place for you to practice talking points you’ve already made up your mind about.

I should’ve bailed when you randomly went off about white people being “disfavored”. Your capacity for bringing non sequiturs in whenever it suits you is staggering. You’re arguing against your own imaginary idea of a person, not the real one in front of you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766169319.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That’s not what’s happening. 

’Tis.

&amp;gt;There’s zero point in talking to someone who makes up your half of the conversation

Not what was happening.  If it *were*, why would you bother to say so?  If you were done talking, you would *stop talking.*

&amp;gt;I cited exactly which things you said were guilty of this and instead of addressing those or even defending yourself

Why would I “address issues” to, or defend myself from, someone *who has left the field*?

I don’t know how sincere you are in not feeling heard, but once you say you are done talking to me, I have to be done talking to you.

So, are you done talking or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766192724.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>If you cared about the mistakes and failures of decorum and logic that I described, the natural impulse would be to at least defend yourself. A thoughtful person might even apologize whether they thought the other person would hear it or not. 

The fact that your impulse is instead to gloat about annoying someone enough to make them leave, shows exactly what a one-sided playground taunt this was from the beginning.

I would’ve felt bad if I’d misjudged you, but I guess it’s nice to know I didn’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766230538.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the natural impulse would be to at least defend yourself

To whom?  You’re gone. 

Or are you?  Do you want to discuss this or not?

&amp;gt;The fact that your impulse is instead to gloat about annoying someone enough to make them leave

It made you reconsider your choices, didn’t it?

If you want to walk away, walk away — with my blessing, if that means anything to you.

If you want to continue discussing this, fine, I will talk.

If you want me to explain myself better or to pay closer attention to what you have say, ask for that and I will consider it.

But act like a child, threaten to take your ball and go home, and you’ll be treated like a child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766237465.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Are you politely *asking* for a chance to respond? 

Ok sure! I’ll give you a shot at actually responding without making anything up. Go for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766244241.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t work for you.  If you have a question, ask it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766265805.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus. You said you would respond but only to someone who’s sticking around. So I said I’d stick around and now you’re sticking out your tongue like a kid. 

It’s just pathetic man. You’re doing exactly what I said you were doing. Thanks yet again for proving me right I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766281214.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You said you would respond but only to someone who’s sticking around.

I would respond — are you sticking around?  Do you have anything to respond *to*?

&amp;gt;It’s just pathetic man. 

Remarks like that do not bolster your claims of good faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766344109.0" user="CitizenCue" delta="False">
    <text>Good grief. Yes, I already said I would stick around. IF you can show that you’re willing to respond only to what I say and not make up things you think I might think instead. 

Go back to where I quoted you multiple times and start there. Respond to what I said you were doing and show me that you either didn’t mean to do those things or disagree that you were doing them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39782171457.0" user="Ambitious_Vanilla105" delta="False">
    <text>But I really don't identify with my ethnic group, nor do I identify with another ethnic group. I just am against racism as a principle. I prefer this over dividing people in to separate groups. I acknowledge though that racism happens manly towards minorities. So if I am part of the majority i will tell other member of the majority to cut it out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754236521.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem is broader than the OP has presented, but, is oddly different from what you're going after.

I'm Jewish.

I was remarkably offended and, frankly, felt incredibly marginalized while watching MSNBC this week while the screen crawl talked about how white nationalism is a threat to "Jews and Minorities."

\*blink blink\*" What?? Jews aren't a minority now??

I'm not white. I'm Jewish. Yet, according to the American concept of "race" which is incredibly lacking in both historical and global context, I'm white, for all discussions where my being white is convenient and Jewish when it's useful for that to be the case.  No wonder Dara Horn felt the need to title her book "People Love Dead Jews." Is it any wonder that Whoopi stepped in it on the View?

So, try this on for size -- how would you like be in a class and be forced to listen to some clueless grad student lecture you about how you're the beneficiary of all the evils done by the whites under white privilege  during the same semester you buried the last Shoah survivor in your family? And that if I get angry about that -- it's because I'm too insecure about my privilege??!?!  


White fragility is a cheap concept that fails to recognize that there are a lot of marginalized people in the US out there who got lumped in as "white" today, but whose ancestors were never "white" in the past.  The Irish, for example, who came to America and absolutely did not benefit from the color of their skin for generations. Or the Scotch who were marginalized to the poorest parts of Appalachia and basically abandoned by modernity. Eastern Europeans about whom texts like "The Jungle" were written. And so on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754584014.0" user="QueenMackeral" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah seriously as a member of a group that went through a genocide and is dealing with the generational trauma and effects of it, who is lucky to be alive because my ancestors were among the ones to survive. It feels so insulting to hear people tell me that I'm white so that doesn't count as racism.

The current discussion about race is so disorienting because we are both outside and inside of whiteness at the same time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754599178.0" user="JackC747" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but if you bring that up 9 times out of 10 those people will blast you for focusing on the exceptions to the rule. Like no, what my family and my ancestors had to go through can't just be discounted just because most people didn't have to go through it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756051070.0" user="QueenMackeral" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah if I fight back then I'm a fragile white person. I had a friend say "why can't you accept your white privilege and accept that you don't face racism, all my white friends accept it", yeah probably because none of their other white friends had their family literally displaced from their ancestral home because one group of people decided that they don't have the right to exist anymore, and then told that what they experienced wasn't racism.

I do understand the concept of systematic racism in the US and how pocs are disadvantaged, but I do have a problem with people changing the definition of racism in a way that makes it so it can only legitimately apply to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756424891.0" user="JackC747" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, or my ancestor's didn't *really* face racism because it was perpetrated by white people towards other white people. They don't see how me and my siblings being encouraged to learn a functionally dead language to hold onto what little culture wasn't stolen from us is a direct result of racism.

And you're right. The US has a very shortsighted view on what constitutes racism. Their experience with racism is very narrow, and for whatever reason they think that their experience encompasses all possible types of racism. So you get the redefinitions that make it so only POC can experience racism, when the current definitions are already fit for purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755508938.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>I sympathize with what you're saying but I'm also failing to actually understand what your issue is...

&amp;gt;I was remarkably offended and, frankly, felt incredibly marginalized while watching MSNBC this week while the screen crawl talked about how white nationalism is a threat to "Jews and Minorities."

&amp;gt;*blink blink*" What?? Jews aren't a minority now??

Okay, so you're upset that you felt separated from your minority status by not including you under the umbrella of being a "minority"? Okay, I'm reading you here. That being said, they are still acknowledging your marginalized status. Maybe they were using "minorities" as a stand-in for PoC (which I'm aware Jewish people can also be). I'm not sure why this upset you so much but I'll rock with it. At the end of the day, you were still acknowledged as being under the threat of white supremacy. No one erased that from you and the reason you're under the threat of white supremacy is the historical context in which white supremacy has traditionally manifested. You're just mad that they didn't call you a minority? 

&amp;gt;So, try this on for size -- how would you like be in a class and be forced to listen to some clueless grad student lecture you about how you're the beneficiary of all the evils done by the whites under white privilege during the same semester you buried the last Shoah survivor in your family? And that if I get angry about that -- it's because I'm too insecure about my privilege??!?! 

Okay, now you're upset that someone thought you were white. Did you tell them you were Jewish? Did they double down when they told you that? 

I can't speak to the Jewish experience at all. I guess I'm just a little confused as to what the problem is...

&amp;gt;White fragility is a cheap concept that fails to recognize that there are a lot of marginalized people in the US out there who got lumped in as "white" today, but whose ancestors were never "white" in the past.

No, that's not what "white fragility" means at all though. I think you're talking about the concept of "privilege". If someone is attacking you for being white and you say, "I'm not white, I'm Jewish" I'd be hard pressed to find even the most left leaning person say that's "white fragility". You're talking about privilege which is unrelated to the topic. 

&amp;gt;The Irish, for example, who came to America and absolutely did not benefit from the color of their skin for generations. Or the Scotch who were marginalized to the poorest parts of Appalachia and basically abandoned by modernity. Eastern Europeans about whom texts like "The Jungle" were written. And so on.

This is all true which is why the idea of "whiteness" in and of itself is dubious and exclusionary in nature. So I agree with this part. But that isn't an issue with the concept of "white fragility" and "white privilege". That's an issue with the concept of "whiteness" to begin with. You're lashing out at the reaction to a bad framework as opposed to the bad framework.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755770340.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not white. I'm Jewish. 




The thing is that white (and race in general) is a sliding scale, so you are arguably both. If you are Ashkenazim you are arguably white.


&amp;gt; The Irish, for example, who came to America and absolutely did not benefit from the color of their skin for generations. 

But now they do. 

&amp;gt;Or the Scotch who were marginalized to the poorest parts of Appalachia and basically abandoned by modernity. Eastern Europeans about whom texts like "The Jungle" were written. 
 


But now they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756476759.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say that black people now also benefit from the colour of their skin in many parts of the world? 

The "but now they do" argument erases the history of oppression and focuses on the injustices of today which is admirable but makes the conversation a very different one, and mostly one that focuses on the global South?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756523037.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The "but now they do" argument erases the history of oppression and focuses on the injustices of today which is admirable but makes the conversation a very different one, and mostly one that focuses on the global South?




How does it erase history to state that some formerly and currently ethnic groups are now considered part of a racial majority? And as such would gain some- though not all benefits of being in that majority?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756559580.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>The claim wasn't that former ethnic groups are now considered part of the ethnic majority, and if it was then I would argue against that, just because there is a broad catch all colour term it doesn't make other visible genetic, cultural and linguistic differences go away. Just because you can't tell the difference between a brahmin and a dalit and may refer to them both as simply Indian it doesn't mean someone more attuned to the culture would not be able to distinguish and apply different prejudices to both. 

The claim was that these groups once did not benefit from privilege due to their skin colour, and now they do, which is an idea that can be applied to anyone living in a western country under a modern day democracy. 

Discrimination in Western Europe or America is looked down on as one of the worst forms of injustice a person could commit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756580481.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The claim wasn't that former ethnic groups are now considered part of the ethnic majority, 




Racial majority not ethnic.


&amp;gt;The claim was that these groups once did not benefit from privilege due to their skin colour, and now they do, which is an idea that can be applied to anyone living in a western country under a modern day democracy. 



Not neccessarily, Europe still has significant amounts of ethnic discrimination. The United States on the other hand has absorbed formerly marginalized and even currently marginalized groups into being white to the point where the average white american used to be part of a marginalized ethnic group.



Even some Americans who are technically black sociologically benefit from it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756624380.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>What is your differentiator between racial and ethnic? I would use the terms interchangeably in these discussions, as in someone who is ethnically Ukrainian would also be racially Ukrainian. Is there a nuance to the words that I've missed?

It seems like you're mostly arguing on semantics, and I think that just because labels change and borders move it doesn't actually change the essence of the thing being redefined.

Your last sentence is especially telling to me that we aren't arguing the same point, the idea that someone can be "technically black", either someone is or isn't black, or is or isn't of black African descent, or any other form of black. If we reduce things down to the point where someone can be considered black by technicality (without some other factor like being albino born to black parents) then there won't really be a way to find common ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756698605.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What is your differentiator between racial and ethnic? I would use the terms interchangeably in these discussions, as in someone who is ethnically Ukrainian would also be racially Ukrainian. Is there a nuance to the words that I've missed?





Ethnicity is an ancestral group, race is an arbitrary concept based on appearance. An ethnic Ukrainian is racially white for example. 


&amp;gt;Your last sentence is especially telling to me that we aren't arguing the same point, the idea that someone can be "technically black", either someone is or isn't black, or is or isn't of black African descent, or any other form of black. 



Race and its conception differs from region to region and era to era. "Technically" means within the more formal confines of the society. For example in the U.S. Obama is black. in my region he is mixed. Similar practical outcome but different officially. 


What I am talking about is that there are light skinned black people (as in two black parents) who at first glance could pass for white and/or or considered more respectable or treated better because of their lighter pigmentation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756797456.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough if that's the lens you see the world through. I think globalisation is shifting the number of people who can accurately identify a real ethnic origin, in my own case I have a white Scottish parent and a black Jamaican parent and I present as basically a white person, no real distinguishing features that would indicate anything other than white. I don't know anyone who is purely one ethnic ancestral group, and by genetic modelling alone we are all part mongol, and further back we are all black. I am not sure this is the most useful way to see people, sure it's interesting to know where we came from but it doesn't affect my relationship or treatment with those around me.

Melanin doesn't mix well with social constructs of the world that much is fairly obvious from history and present day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756850082.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think globalisation is shifting the number of people who can accurately identify a real ethnic origin,



That is very true.


&amp;gt; in my own case I have a white Scottish parent and a black Jamaican parent and I present as basically a white person, no real distinguishing features that would indicate anything other than white.


Yes, and that is basically my point in a nutshell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756370708.0" user="thewirereal" delta="False">
    <text>The concept of white fragility is not contradictory to the fact that some people with white skin can be marginalized..? I don't really get your point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758939096.0" user="PapiBIanco" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone becomes a minority when you stratify them into smaller and smaller subgroups. You’re white, you’re also Jewish. You’re white, doesn’t mean your ancestors weren’t oppressed. A square is a rectangle, but not all rectangles are squares. 

&amp;gt;How would you like to be in a class and be forced to listen to some clueless grad student lecture you about how you’re the beneficiary of all the evils done by whites under white privilege. 

That’s part of the consequences of teaching that all white people benefit from white privilege. Even white people who obviously did not benefit are “privileged” now, ask the irish. Besides, Jews as an average score higher than other whites in most economic measurements such as household or median income; when a cop sees you driving you’re just another white guy in a car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39774714913.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You’re white, you’re also Jewish.

No, I'm Jewish.

Hitler didn't commit genocide against the white people who happened to be Jewish. He committed genocide against the Jewish race. Germans have a different word for ethnicity.

America's concept of race being limited to and defined by skin color is a modern, ahistorical, post-WWII concept that is fairly unique to America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754271004.0" user="Telkk2" delta="False">
    <text>I honestly don't think white fragility actually exists.  I think it's just people in general who get huffy when they fundamentally disagree with an analysis that, at least on the surface, seems to clump all races and genders together.  

And that messaging, whether they mean it literally or are just bad at explaining themselves is what's ultimately ruining the Democratic Party.  Corporate politics pushes it, which energizes a radical few and everyone else who is just normal and watching the news is getting angry because its deflecting us from acknowledging real problems.  

If we just made everyone better off, we'd see far less of what everyone is rightfully freaking out about on both sides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755266822.0" user="QuickAnything" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, there’s schools that are banning BLM clothing and CRT, which doesn’t even really exist outside of academia. I’d say those folks are prime examples of white fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755318091.0" user="oberyncartel" delta="False">
    <text>Because CRT is divisive race essentialist drivel that has no place in schools (and yes, is everywhere outside of academia).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755526305.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>What is CRT?

And who are you to decide what doesn't belong in schools? Divisive subjects get taught all the time. Modern economics is divisive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755545506.0" user="oberyncartel" delta="False">
    <text>You’re equating modern economics with race essentialism? A strange flex, but OK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755563911.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>Learn how to use that expression, please. In no universe is what I did a "flex". 

No, I'm saying they teach divisive topics in schools. So that shouldn't be a reason they shouldn't teach CRT as an elective. Again, what is CRT and what makes it race essentialist ? Can you elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755791810.0" user="oberyncartel" delta="False">
    <text>Divisive topics are not all based in race essentialism. You can Google CRT if you don’t know what it is, but somehow I don’t think that’s the issue…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755826764.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>It's not an issue. You're absolutely right. I'm asking *you* what it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756064008.0" user="HKBFG" delta="False">
    <text>Critical race theory is the body of work in critical theory regarding racial justice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756096871.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>Cool! Now explain why that's bad and shouldn't be taught in schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756122305.0" user="HKBFG" delta="False">
    <text>It should. It's very important for people to learn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756873190.0" user="Jojajones" delta="False">
    <text>Psst that’s not the moron you were arguing with who clearly has zero understanding of what CRT actually is</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758385102.0" user="Agnes-Varda1992" delta="False">
    <text>I see that now. 

The speed with which he ran away. 🤷🏿</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756060409.0" user="HKBFG" delta="False">
    <text>Race essentialism is not the same thing as critical theory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755928018.0" user="QuickAnything" delta="False">
    <text>CRT is not in schools. It’s a bullshit GOP boogeyman talking point intended to inflame their base and get them to the polls. It’s absolute nonsense, yet Karens are foaming at the mouth with outrage over a nonissue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757874880.0" user="ab7af" delta="False">
    <text>[The National Education Association,](https://web.archive.org/web/20210705234008/https://ra.nea.org/business-item/2021-nbi-039/) the largest K-12 teachers' union, has stated that "it is reasonable and appropriate for curriculum to be informed by ... critical race theory", indicating they consider some kind of K-12 use of CRT to be a real thing that would be under their purview.

[The Virginia Department of Education](https://archive.today/bI76d) listed "Foundations of Critical Race Theory in Education" among "resources the Office of Equity and Community Engagement references in the development of our work, as well as texts we recommend" in public K-12 schooling.

The New York Times reports ['Grace Church School "incorporated the language of critical race theory"'.](https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/27/us/new-york-private-schools-racism.html)

Here's the website of the [Critical Race Studies in Education Association.](https://www.crsea.org/)  Videos like [this one](https://youtu.be/J-KFNhT0_nY) make clear they are talking about using CRT in high schools at the latest, perhaps earlier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757722159.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>If you believe that you do not understand what CRT is or what is taught in schools</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754288471.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But if we were discussing a crime perpetrated by a man against a woman, and some guy feels the need to shift the discussion from the victim to “not all men…” it’s not really about whether it’s all men. It’s fragility.

If the discussion is talking about men in general however, then someone would be correct in pointing that out and reframing it to the subgroup of people that are both men and perpetrators of such crimes.

&amp;gt;Edit to add: or Black Lives Matter. Of course all lives matter, but if you feel compelled to point that out, perhaps that all lives have value is not what’s really going on.

Frankly, "all lives matter" should have been adopted as main slogan of the protests against racially biased and other police violence as soon as their opponents came up with it, instead of falling for that rhetorical trap. By making a problem of "all lives matter", they confirmed the dogwhistle implication that "black lives matter" protests "don't care about whites, which is obviously incorrect. But as it is that was a rhetorical victory for the people opposing BLM.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755095245.0" user="ouishi" delta="False">
    <text>I recall a brief period of time where I saw a lot of variations paired with blacklivesmatter hashtags, including brownlivesmatter, arablivesmatter, and yes, alllivesmatter. The problem is that the latter was hijacked by the opposition as if it wasn't being said, which it was. It very quickly became used as a shorthand for "I don't support the Black Lives Matter movement," so those who did use it stopped as to not be mistaken for the opposition. I attend a local BLM vigil for a black man killed by an officer in 2020. His mom ended her statements with "black lives matter, all lives matter," so the phrase is still used by BLM supporters, they are just more careful how they use it.

This is exactly what happened with "fake news." Originally, this was used by Democrats and left media in the 2016 election to call out Trump's misinformation.  As Samantha Bee said, "fake news is like a loaded gun that Kellyanne deftly plucked out of reporters' hands and pointed at their heads."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756124876.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I recall a brief period of time where I saw a lot of variations paired with blacklivesmatter hashtags, including brownlivesmatter, arablivesmatter, and yes, alllivesmatter. The problem is that the latter was hijacked by the opposition as if it wasn't being said, which it was. It very quickly became used as a shorthand for "I don't support the Black Lives Matter movement," so those who did use it stopped as to not be mistaken for the opposition. I attend a local BLM vigil for a black man killed by an officer in 2020. His mom ended her statements with "black lives matter, all lives matter," so the phrase is still used by BLM supporters, they are just more careful how they use it.

From a PR perspective, there should have been active efforts to reclaim the slogan, instead of efforts to distance themselves from it.

&amp;gt;This is exactly what happened with "fake news." Originally, this was used by Democrats and left media in the 2016 election to call out Trump's misinformation. As Samantha Bee said, "fake news is like a loaded gun that Kellyanne deftly plucked out of reporters' hands and pointed at their heads."

Yes, and that's why we should call back to the meaning of the word fake: not supported by evidence, intentionally so. Words have meanings that matter. That is one thing that distinguishes fascist mobs from democracies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757402308.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Frankly, "all lives matter" should have been adopted as main slogan of the protests against racially biased and other police violence as soon as their opponents came up with it, instead of falling for that rhetorical trap. By making a problem of "all lives matter", they confirmed the dogwhistle implication that "black lives matter" protests "don't care about whites, which is obviously incorrect. But as it is that was a rhetorical victory for the people opposing BLM.

But the implicit meaning behind “Black Lives Matter” wasn’t that black lives were the only lives that mattered, but that “Black Lives Matter Too,” and that they should be valued as all lives are valued. The messaging deliberately left off “Too” since it shouldn’t be required for black lives to be humanized and granted the same essential worth that “All Lives” have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757737720.0" user="ParanoidAgnostic" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. The implicit meaning behind "black lives matter" was "you need to be told that black lives matter."

It works something like a loaded question. If I ask you whether you have stopped besting your wife then your answer isn't really the point. The point is the implication of asking the question at all. If I am asking this then you must have beaten your wife. It's hard to pivot into challenging the implication because it isn't stated explicitly. 

This is a pattern in a lot of woke messaging. The difference is that it's not a question, it's a demand. The point is not having the demand met. It is the narrative formed by the implications. The world-view is not argued, just treated as a necessary precondition for the demands to need to be made.

It is exactly what 4-chan pulled off with "it's okay to be white." It's a totally inoffensive statement on the surface but the implication is that if people need to be told that it is okay to be white then there is a lot of anti-white bigotry. 

This made a lot of people angry but they were never able to explain why. Just vague accusations that it was a white supremacist dog whistle.that's because what made them angry was never actually stated. Only implied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758007970.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not really. The implicit meaning behind "black lives matter" was "you need to be told that black lives matter."

Ummmm… what? If that’s what you took away from that pretty straightforward slogan then there may be different issues at play here. That would be like claiming that implicit meaning behind the slogan of the Boy Scouts, “Do a Good Turn Daily,” was “You Need To Be Told To Do a Good Turn Daily.” It just doesn’t make sense in any good faith reading of the phrase. 

&amp;gt; It works something like a loaded question. If I ask you whether you have stopped besting your wife then your answer isn't really the point. 

I assume you meant “beating” my wife. That’s what is called “a good faith reading” of your argument. Regardless, you actually hit upon the central issue that originated the slogan, albeit accidentally. As the systemic racism and violence has for generations treated the lives of Black Americans as if their lives didn’t matter, the natural response to that messaging (backed up by the data clearly illustrating the problem) is that Black Lives Matter too. Black lives also matter. 

&amp;gt; The point is the implication of asking the question at all. If I am asking this then you must have beaten your wife. It's hard to pivot into challenging the implication because it isn't stated explicitly.

It isn’t. I’m not married. The implication doesn’t work because the preconditions of your statement don’t match the facts. I have no wife, so I could not be beating my wife. However, in the case of Black Lives Matter, there is data going back generations showing racial disparities across the board in our criminal justice system. Thousands of examples of police committing murder and getting nothing more than a paid vacation out of it. The preconditions of the statement that Black Lives Matter was a response to have been met. 

&amp;gt; This is a pattern in a lot of woke messaging. 

“Woke messaging?” Can you clarify? Who is the arbiter of messaging for wokeness? What organization does the CEO of wokeness work at so that we can go talk to that person? Is it Fox? Because I see that Sean Hannity guy tell people all the time what the “woke” message is. Then there’s also Ted Cruz and Jim Jordan. Those asshats rail against woke messaging that they come up with, which seems like an incredibly disingenuous way to conduct oneself. Who do we go to to correct this issue?

&amp;gt; The difference is that it's not a question, it's a demand. 

Do you think it’s unfair to demand that black lives be given the same inherent value that other lives are granted? 

&amp;gt; The point is not having the demand met. It is the narrative formed by the implications. The world-view is not argued, just treated as a necessary precondition for the demands to need to be made.

Sure, if the data didn’t back it up. But it does. 

&amp;gt; It is exactly what 4-chan pulled off with "it's okay to be white." It's a totally inoffensive statement on the surface but the implication is that if people need to be told that it is okay to be white then there is a lot of anti-white bigotry.

Never heard of this “movement”. There’s probably a reason that, of the two efforts, one was actually relevant. I would recommend treating anything that 4chan spawns with a skeptical eye. They are the murky cesspool that gave us “Q” and gamergate after all.

&amp;gt; This made a lot of people angry but they were never able to explain why. Just vague accusations that it was a white supremacist dog whistle.that's because what made them angry was never actually stated. Only implied.

I hadn’t even heard of it so I don’t know where your information is coming from, but I don’t think it got a ton of notice, much less making any significant portion of the population angry. It’s pretty lowbrow and cringey.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759060016.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The messaging deliberately left off “Too” since it shouldn’t be required for black lives to be humanized and granted the same essential worth that “All Lives” have.

And that was a mistake, because it allowed it to be framed as "*only* black lives matter". It turned a message about equality into a message about competing group interests, thereby reinforcing the idea that there is a competition between races going on, and allowing the opposing forces to claim the slogan "all lives matter" and thereby the rhetorical high ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759136874.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>But… they haven’t claimed the rhetorical high ground… as it’s rightly still considered distasteful to respond to “black lives matter” with “all lives matter.” To view “all lives matter” as rhetorical high ground is simply another facet of the central problem underpinning this whole issue: just because black Americans have become fed up with the decades and generations of disparities large and small and the consequences of merely being born black in our country… up to and including the loss of their lives - and then speaking up about it… *is not and never has been a position that targets you or I.* In fact, as they are our fellow citizens, our American brothers and sisters, if you’re not doing what you can to support that movement then you are failing the promise America is supposed to represent. The fact that there are still people who actually believe that there is a competition between *races* going on is the whole root of the problem. And if you find yourself suddenly on a side that is in opposition to a movement for equality in the justice system or anywhere else… you took a wrong turn somewhere. Especially if you look around at your “side” and all you see is a sea of angry white faces.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759215360.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But… they haven’t claimed the rhetorical high ground… as it’s rightly still considered distasteful to respond to “black lives matter” with “all lives matter.” 

To those who already were committed to the side of BLM.

More fundamentally, they have succeeded in diluting the conceptual coherence of the movement, as the ones brandishing the slogan "all lives matter" are against equality and those with the slogan "lives of a particular group matter" are the ones in favour of it. Anti-equality movements generally despise the power of words to constrain their actions, and as such it's a victory for them when they can muddle the waters and pervert the conceptual framework of the ideology of their opponents.

&amp;gt;The fact that there are still people who actually believe that there is a competition between races going on is the whole root of the problem.

Exactly. So don't play into the hands of their leadership.

&amp;gt;And if you find yourself suddenly on a side that is in opposition to a movement for equality in the justice system or anywhere else… you took a wrong turn somewhere. Especially if you look around at your “side” and all you see is a sea of angry white faces.

See, but that's rhetorics: those people most certainly *feel* they are rightfully angry, and a quantity of them *feel* they are fighting for "all lives". You must prevent them winning rhetorical battles so there are less people in the middle drawn into their camp.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761067610.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To those who already were committed to the side of ~~BLM~~ equal protection under the law, the freedoms promised to every American in the foundational documents for our nation, and basic human dignity, decency, and value.

I mean… if you’re not in the side of those things, what are you doing here? 

&amp;gt; More fundamentally, they have succeeded in diluting the conceptual coherence of the movement, as the ones brandishing the slogan "all lives matter" are against equality and those with the slogan "lives of a particular group matter" are the ones in favour of it. 

Once again, you are making a conscious choice to dishonestly interpret the slogan so that you can argue against the meaning you have misattributed. Please try to engage without resorting to these type of tactics. BLM has never been about *only* black lives mattering. They’ve never conducted themselves that way, they’ve never claimed that Black Lives Matter more, and they’ve targeted specific institutions that have long documented histories of treating black lives differently than others. 

&amp;gt; Anti-equality movements generally despise the power of words to constrain their actions, and as such it's a victory for them when they can muddle the waters and pervert the conceptual framework of the ideology of their opponents.

They can certainly try. Most equality movements throughout history have spawned any number of reactionary groups wanting to lash out against the perceived harm they experience by being made to share the power and access that they had previously enjoyed while excluding others. And well, you can see how successful/unsuccessful those have ultimately been. This is more of the same, except thankfully on a smaller scale and not dressed up in white robes.

&amp;gt; Exactly. So don't play into the hands of their leadership.

I’m not. Remember: I am firmly in the side of equality (see above) as I was adopted into a multiracial family and growing up saw first hand the disparity of treatment my little brother and sister experienced merely because the color of their skin.

Don’t play into the hands of the reactionary embers that want to convince you to fear equality. Those embers always get stomped out eventually. Be on the side of empathy and humanism, it’s sunny here and we have mojitos.

&amp;gt; See, but that's rhetorics: those people most certainly feel they are rightfully angry, and a quantity of them feel they are fighting for "all lives". 

See, that’s what’s nice about dealing with a group that is inherently disingenuous. You know that their claims are bullshit. Absolute bullshit. Why? Well,  because they weren’t fighting for “all lives” before BLM or else BLM never would have been necessary. 

&amp;gt; You must prevent them winning rhetorical battles so there are less people in the middle drawn into their camp.

People in the middle drawn to their camp is such a marginal subset of a subset of people who in all likelihood already felt that way anyways and were just waiting for permission to say it. True people in the middle (and decent human beings) landed at ‘equality’ a long time ago. People who still can’t get there aren’t ever going to get there because they fear and revile the “other.” They will most likely always fear the “other” because that’s how they were wired as kids. So I find it heartening to see how young and energized the BLM movement is, and how effective the younger generations have been at converting their peers. Especially as the opposition is aging into irrelevance while also opposing common sense pandemic protocol. It’s really well past the tipping point now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39762931017.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Once again, you are making a conscious choice to dishonestly interpret the slogan 

No. I'm simply taking it at face value: "all lives matter" is far, far better slogan to represent the goal of *equal protection under the law* than "specific lives matter". It is *you* who needs to invoke a specific historic context and knowledge of the rhetorical history of the issue. You have to admit that makes it harder to reach the less informed parts of the population.

&amp;gt;Please try to engage without resorting to these type of tactics.

Again, you're entering a street brawl and then complain they're fighting dirty. We all know that's what they do, just don't let yourself be conned next time.

&amp;gt;BLM has never been about only black lives mattering.

Of course. Which means their slogan badly represents their goals.

&amp;gt;They can certainly try. Most equality movements throughout history have spawned any number of reactionary groups wanting to lash out against the perceived harm they experience by being made to share the power and access that they had previously enjoyed while excluding others. And well, you can see how successful/unsuccessful those have ultimately been. This is more of the same, except thankfully on a smaller scale and not dressed up in white robes.

Acting smug won't help you actually realize progress.

&amp;gt;I’m not. Remember: I am firmly in the side of equality (

Your tactical effectivity and your personal commitment to the cause are two entirely different elements.

&amp;gt;Don’t play into the hands of the reactionary embers that want to convince you to fear equality. 

How am I "playing into the hands of the reactionary" by giving tactical advice to counter their rhetorical strategy?

&amp;gt;See, that’s what’s nice about dealing with a group that is inherently disingenuous. You know that their claims are bullshit. Absolute bullshit. Why? Well, because they weren’t fighting for “all lives” before BLM or else BLM never would have been necessary.

Of course, we all know. But you needn't preach to the choir. You need to get the less informed people in the middle on your side.

&amp;gt;People in the middle drawn to their camp is such a marginal subset of a subset of people who in all likelihood already felt that way anyways and were just waiting for permission to say it.

No. The silent middle is where it's all about to obtain political power. You're not going to convince the hard core of either ideological extreme. It's the people who might change opinion, or might change between active and passive opinion, that swing the power balance.

&amp;gt;True people in the middle (and decent human beings) landed at ‘equality’ a long time ago. People who still can’t get there aren’t ever going to get there because they fear and revile the “other

Do you realize how ironic that is? You yourself divide people into good and bad here.

With that attitude, there really is no other way for you to gain influence than a civil war to kill off some of the others.

&amp;gt;Especially as the opposition is aging into irrelevance while also opposing common sense pandemic protocol. It’s really well past the tipping point now.

You can't even properly defend the right to abortion. I don't call that "well past the tipping point".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39764845842.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No. I'm simply taking it at face value: "all lives matter" is far, far better slogan to represent the goal of equal protection under the law than "specific lives matter". It is you who needs to invoke a specific historic context and knowledge of the rhetorical history of the issue. You have to admit that makes it harder to reach the less informed parts of the population.

I don’t need to invoke anything. It arrives with all the context it will ever get. Ignorance of racial disparities is a choice, as is the demonization of anything non-white. I am not responsible for the choices of someone else, what a weird responsibility that would be. 

&amp;gt; Again, you're entering a street brawl and then complain they're fighting dirty. We all know that's what they do, just don't let yourself be conned next time.

Conned by whom, exactly? 

&amp;gt; Of course. Which means their slogan badly represents their goals.

How so? “All lives” don’t face the same institutional targeting or indeed the same threats to their existence that black lives do. So, to use the slogan “all lives matter” instead creates an immediate false equivalency which is even less suited to the problem. 

&amp;gt; Acting smug won't help you actually realize progress.

Progress? I thought this was a street brawl. The goals of a street brawl are entirely different and I’m happy at this point to respond to these folks in the style they seem to be more comfortable with. 

&amp;gt; Your tactical effectivity and your personal commitment to the cause are two entirely different elements.

Sure. But you have yet to demonstrably show that the approach you advocate for will do anything but cede ground to these poor stewards of the American experience. 

&amp;gt; How am I "playing into the hands of the reactionary" by giving tactical advice to counter their rhetorical strategy?

I’m glad you asked. By treating their messaging as having more social import than we have seen, their ‘movement’ as having any kind of validity in the debate, and by inflating the threat that they pose to BLM. 

&amp;gt; Of course, we all know. But you needn't preach to the choir. You need to get the less informed people in the middle on your side.

Again, the middle is already largely in the side of equality. It’s not even close.

&amp;gt; No. The silent middle is where it's all about to obtain political power. You're not going to convince the hard core of either ideological extreme. It's the people who might change opinion, or might change between active and passive opinion, that swing the power balance.

I have heard this term “silent middle” bandied about but have yet to see any evidence that it exists. Especially while tracking regional political leanings while volunteering for democratic campaigns the last two cycles and knocking on doors directly. Can you point me to the data you have on these folks?

&amp;gt; Do you realize how ironic that is? You yourself divide people into good and bad here.

Yup. Racist = bad. I didn’t think that was controversial. 

&amp;gt; With that attitude, there really is no other way for you to gain influence than a civil war to kill off some of the others.

Sure, if that is the point that they need to take it to to have it beaten into their understanding that black people are people too, well then I can’t be held responsible that they couldn’t be convinced of that at any point prior. That’s not on me. 

&amp;gt; You can't even properly defend the right to abortion. I don't call that "well past the tipping point".

Defend against what? A party so bereft of a moral framework and sputtering into outright fascism that they stacked the highest court in the land with unfit ideologues who would actually disregard one of the fundamental elements of our whole system of justice by overturning what is effectively super-stare decisis? How do you defend against that? Considering that same precedent is protecting our right to bear arms, I don’t think this is going to be ideal for any of us, since no prior judicial decision, even when affirmed multiple times by the Supreme Court, is settled law anymore. Interracial marriage? Bye bye. Butt stuff in the privacy of your home with a consenting adult? Toodles. A whole host of other rights not specifically outlined in our founding documents? Up for grabs. All we have to do is play just like the Republican Party does, and if we get creamed in the midterms simply stack the courts and deny the Congress any practical power to legislate except through the courts. What’s good for the goose and all that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766162852.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>I think I've made my point clearly enough, and you seem to double down on denying that you do anything wrong, and everyone and everything you disagree with will just disappear on its own. Meanwhile, Donald Trump has been elected (that was a *joke* in the 90s) and the reactionaries have used that opportunity to gain real political power, among other things by stacking the deck in the judiciary and creating a voter block that didn't go away. But sure, continue to wallow in your feelings of moral superiority and ignore your failure to translate that in political power. But let me tell you one thing: reality isn't a Hollywood movie, and there is no scripted happy end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39766260081.0" user="-KRGB-" delta="False">
    <text>Huh? Who is looking for a Hollywood happy end? I am well aware of the messiness and chaos that has been integral to the formation and maintenance of our democracy. I’m fine operating in that space and under those conditions, and I’m motivated to do whatever it takes to stand up for my fellow citizens and defend the most vulnerable among them. 

I never said that I don’t do anything wrong, so I don’t know where you are getting that. As for making your point clearly, you didn’t even answer the majority of the questions posed to you so you must have a different threshold for making points. 

Yes, the right wing in this country are easily duped by obvious conmen, and they vote them into positions of incredible power. The democrats do this too just to a lesser degree. The problem is that Republican voters not only elect the dangerously stupid to political office, they then openly cheer on when those politicians harm our democracy for short sighted and self enriching motivations, as long as they target anyone that they perceive as the enemy - in this case their fellow citizens. 

And yes, I consider myself morally superior to racists. Can you tell me why you feel that is something worth your derision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757717853.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>How does "all lives matter" transmit the message that is trying to be transmitted?

You're falling into the same trap people dealing with the right wing have fallen into for decades: pretending they actually care about the criticisms they make. They don't complain about "black lives matter" because they think it is a bad message, but if only you said it the right way they'd be on board, they complain about it because they are against the root idea. Changing how it is marketed wouldn't matter, and they would pull the same rhetorical attacks against *anything* anyone came up with.

Just look at kneeling at sporting events. Kaepernick initially just stayed seated, but was told that that was disrespectful and taking a knee would still send a message while being respectful. Then everyone lost their minds when he knelt, because **it wasn't about what they said it was about**. It wasn't about the sitting or the kneeling, they just hated the message. But they know that "black lives don't matter actually" isn't something they can get away with directly saying (yet), so they just pick the things they can attack around the message.

They aren't acting in good faith so trying to win the "find a message they won't attack" game is impossible and just playing into their attempts to delegitimize any discussion of issues they don't like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759089775.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How does "all lives matter" transmit the message that is trying to be transmitted?

Because the goal is equality before the law, duh.

&amp;gt;You're falling into the same trap people dealing with the right wing have fallen into for decades: pretending they actually care about the criticisms they make.

I'm analyzing how their rhetorical strategy works.

&amp;gt;They don't complain about "black lives matter" because they think it is a bad message, but if only you said it the right way they'd be on board, they complain about it because they are against the root id

That goes without saying. Again, I'm just analyzing how their rhetorical strategy is hampering that effort.

&amp;gt;Changing how it is marketed wouldn't matter, and they would pull the same rhetorical attacks against anything anyone came up with.

That doesn't mean you should just accept you're going to lose the rhetorics and let them dominate that aspect. Slogans should be robust and not rely on context, and this one was obvious and avoidable.

&amp;gt;They aren't acting in good faith so trying to win the "find a message they won't attack" game is impossible and just playing into their attempts to delegitimize any discussion of issues they don't like.

They will attack, so please don't give them an easy win. "Black lives matter" played into their rhetorical framework that there is a competition between races, and allowed them to claim the moral high ground by claiming the "all lives matter" slogan. That's an avoidable mistake. Never lose track of the basics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759136070.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;Because the goal is equality before the law, duh.

And how does "all lives matter" communicate that currently not everyone has equality before the law? What is to keep someone from seeing "all lives matter" and saying "yup, they do, no problems to solve here"?



&amp;gt;They will attack, so please don't give them an easy win. "Black lives matter" played into their rhetorical framework that there is a competition between races, and allowed them to claim the moral high ground by claiming the "all lives matter" slogan. That's an avoidable mistake. Never lose track of the basics.

I feel like you just ignored everything I said. There is no such thing as an "easy win", because they will do the same thing for every movement they don't like. Every critique you can come up with will still apply to every other thing *because they are not operating in good faith*. You say you understand that but your whole comment seems to ignore it. Your complaints fundamentally rely on an assumption that they are acting honestly when we all know they are not. Saying that if we choose the wrong slogan that "allows them to claim the moral high ground" is nonsense, **because they will claim the moral high ground no matter what**.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759226494.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And how does "all lives matter" communicate that currently not everyone has equality before the law? What is to keep someone from seeing "all lives matter" and saying "yup, they do, no problems to solve here"?

Well, if you want all lives to matter, then that implies currently not all lives matter and that has to change.

&amp;gt;I feel like you just ignored everything I said. There is no such thing as an "easy win", because they will do the same thing for every movement they don't like.

That does not mean you must make it easy on them.

&amp;gt;Every critique you can come up with will still apply to every other thing because they are not operating in good faith. You say you understand that but your whole comment seems to ignore it. Your complaints fundamentally rely on an assumption that they are acting honestly when we all know they are not.

But that's the whole point. They will be trying it. Be prepared. 

&amp;gt;Saying that if we choose the wrong slogan that "allows them to claim the moral high ground" is nonsense, because they will claim the moral high ground no matter what.

They'll always claim they have it, but when they are able to steal away the literal expression of the end goal of a movement fighting for equality, that's a real rhetorical victory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754356694.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It can be white fragility. It can also be an intellectual discussion.

I personally don't think this exists. It is my opinion that what people want to call 'white fragility' is merely a rebuttal or rejection of guilt by association. 

In the same way it is completely unfair to call all young black men criminals (despite statistics showing it disproportionate number), it is equally wrong to clump 'all white people' together when discussing other issues (despite the statistics). It is just less politically correct for a 'white' person to do this. 

In my completely honest view, this concept of 'white fragility' is just as bad and the concept of 'white privilege' when pushed. It is very commonly used to translate society wide factors to individuals who quite commonly don't share that experience. Just as the 'Young Black Male' should be mad to be automatically assumed to be a criminal, the 'white' individual should be allowed to be mad about the automatic assumption they have benefited from their race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755165606.0" user="charlsey2309" delta="False">
    <text>I think liberals in general are terrible at messaging. In the same way that calling an inheritance tax a death tax is a great example of effective conservative branding of ideological ideas, phrases such as white fragility are a great example of the counter-productive marketing liberals fall into.

I think most groups of people would be offended by such a broad term and much of the language that is used to talk about white people if it were directed at them. I don’t think casually throwing around the term black fragility would go over very well.

The immediate reaction of most people to being told theyre fragile (a derogatory and condescending choice of words) is going to be negative at an emotional level and they will react negatively to it. By phrasing the discussion in this way you immediately turn people off of whatever message you are selling, regardless of the nuanced view you might be pushing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755173189.0" user="handynerd" delta="False">
    <text>White dude here looking to learn more. So in your "not all men" example, fragility would be if I _introduced_ the concept of "all men" when we're talking about just a guy or two, not if I'm countering an argument that "all men" meet some stereotype, right?

I ask because the words, "Not all men are pigs" has definitely come out of my mouth, but only because someone I was debating with stated "all men are pigs."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755307167.0" user="thecorninurpoop" delta="False">
    <text>I would also argue with someone who said something like "all men are pigs," I would be very offended on my husband's behalf, but if someone is like, "why do men send freaking unsolicited dick pics all the time" and you came in with "not ALL men!" that's where the groans come out...because they do not mean every single man in existence and it just detracts from the conversation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755398526.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but if someone is like, "why do men send freaking unsolicited dick pics all the time" and you came in with "not ALL men!" that's where the groans come out...because they do not mean every single man in existence and it just detracts from the conversation

In my personal experience, from reading leftist spaces an hour to several hours a day, around 1/5th of people who say "why do men" *really do* mean most men in a gender essentialist way.  There are several anti-patriarchy subreddits in that sphere I follow where at least once a month there's a meme that is upvoted but...fairly blatantly blames men *en banc* for something.  Thankfully, in the last maybe two years, it's becoming less acceptable but I suspect that's because of the growth in size of the subreddits.  I was actually banned from a subreddit once for saying--and to be clear, with no hostility/namecalling/etc--that men aren't *more* responsible than anyone else for other men's actions by virtue of their gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755693547.0" user="handynerd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; around 1/5th of people who say "why do men" really do mean most men in a gender essentialist way

Yeah, I think we're at risk of putting too much weight on the inclusion of the word "all." People's language, especially online, is not precise.

To me, both of the following statements are equally wrong:

"Why are Muslims so violent?"
"Why are all Muslims so violent?"

I'm not even Muslim, but if I fight back at the first does that expose some hidden Muslim fragility where the second wouldn't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755750559.0" user="handynerd" delta="False">
    <text>This is interesting. 

To me, regardless of whether or not "all" is included in that statement, it sounds like a generalization and would annoy me. And that's regardless of whether or not we're taking about a category I belong to (I'm also annoyed with comments about "why do women do x?" or "why do Muslims do y?")

So I guess either, A) I'm guilty of male fragility, female fragility, Muslim fragility, as well as a whole slew of other fragilities, or B) people use and interpret subtlety in language differently.

I'm rolling with the latter. Especially online, I'm willing to bet there's a significant overlap between the people ignorant enough to be bigots and the people whose use of language isn't precise enough to always include key words like "all."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755222841.0" user="Slomojoe" delta="False">
    <text>The only time i’ve ever seen someone shift the discussion to something like “not all men”, to go along with your example, is she responding to someone saying “yes all men”. And then they get accused of fragility for defending an entire section of humanity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755390477.0" user="BiPoLaRadiation" delta="False">
    <text>So if I got thus correct, fragility is when someone ties their individual identity to a group identity to the point that they take criticisms against the group as attacks on themselves and respond defensively.

I've talked about this but always from a slightly different angle and without the concept of fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757258412.0" user="SeanV2oh" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I thought we'd gotten passed this in the 90's and agreed to treat people as individuals. This increased focus on imprecise proxies like race feels like a backslide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757661959.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yeah, I thought we'd gotten passed this in the 90's and agreed to treat people as individuals. 

What in the world would give you that idea?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758725328.0" user="BiPoLaRadiation" delta="False">
    <text>Well people are dumb, reactionary, stubborn, and lazy. The lazy means people don't really bother to qualify their statements to be specific enough for everyone to be happy (and honestly why should they? It's easy enough to figure it out). And the rest comes together along with the current 24 news and the rise of Fox news to lead to people getting all upset over things that they've been told is a big deal but really isn't to anyone but them. It's honestly not that surprising considering the state of education funding throughout the US and the rise of modern, 24/7, always on you and in your face media.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757652791.0" user="ParanoidAgnostic" delta="False">
    <text>Vilification of a group you belong to is vilification of you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758702430.0" user="BiPoLaRadiation" delta="False">
    <text>Well its not really the same if the 'group' you are talking about isn't a opt in group, one in which you choose to be a part of it, but instead a demographic or categorical group, one you are put into by virtue of something you were born into.

For example you can say that the most common perpetrators of far right terrorism in the US are white males. Does that mean all white males are far right terrorists? No. Does it imply that being white and male would make you likely to commit far right terrorism? No. It is simply describing the demographic make up of the group you are talking about. Being part of the larger demographic does not imply you are part of the more specific group. So when people say "men always cat call me" they are referring to the demographic make up, not making statements about you specifically because you also happen to be a man.

On the other hand you have participatory or opt in groups. For example Republican leaders are much more likely to be rapists and pedophiles. Because it is a group that people join out of choice they implicitly endorse the actions of those leaders. So if someone said "Republicans support child rapists" and you are a republican then yes, you should feel personally called out. You can argue that you don't personally support those specific child rapist republican leaders or that not all Republicans are child rapists and that's a fair thing to say. But you would have to say that or people may think you do support child rapists. Where as if people said "child rapists are often men" no one would expect you to suddenly say "well I personally am not a child rapist" because they weren't referring to you or talking about you as a group and by saying that you are either acting suspicious or displaying fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755497060.0" user="chronotriggertau" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, the only disingenuous aspect of what you're saying is that you're not admitting how many make blanket statements and ascribe fault to an entire broad group of people and act like that's the way it should be. Your example of a crime committed by a man to a woman needs to be corrected before it can be considered analogous to the question at hand. You have to not omit the aspect of those with pitchforks railing against all men because of the case in your example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755517534.0" user="shawn292" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is a double edge sword would pointing out that "black lives matter" at a keep the peace/love everyone rally be black fragility?

  Is critiqueing blm (tge org) for fraud and extortion while trying to push the idea that BLM (the idea) is more divisive than helpful and pushing togetherness with the nuaice of identification of actual problems Fragility?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755732770.0" user="jaam01" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The concept of "white fragility" "argument" should be dismissed right away, because is just a fallacy by itself. It's a Kafkatrap, a sophistical rhetorical device, in which any denial by the accused person, is used as if was evidence of guilt.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Examples "You deny been a witch? Then you're a witch, because that's what a witch would say"  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;It's circular thinking and a specious way of shifting the burden of proof (because you don't have any evidence to prove your acussation on the first place). Its a gotcha, like "damn you if you do (admiting you are a racist), and also damn you if you don't (deny that you are a racist)"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756235888.0" user="moby__dick" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t those conversations usually shift when someone, in the context of that conversation, chefs it from “this man did a terrible thing” to “men are terrible”, which is then followed by “not all men”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756339184.0" user="ihaveredhaironmyhead" delta="False">
    <text>This is just a fancy way to justify discrimination. So men shouldn't be offended when people talk about men and crime because men commit more crime. Do you apply this reasoning to race as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756389292.0" user="manicmonkeys" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But if we were discussing a crime perpetrated by a man against a woman, and some guy feels the need to shift the discussion from the victim to “not all men…” it’s not really about whether it’s all men. It’s fragility.

If a guy randomly blurted out "Not all men though!!" When a story about a man doing something bad was mentioned, sure, I'd agree he's an overly defensive weirdo/it's "white fragility", whatever. 

However, I have seen that scenario happen FAR less than I've seen a man say "Not all men" in response to a woman making a sexist generalization about all men. The more common occurrence is more worthy of consideration and discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756909972.0" user="ChaosintheSnow" delta="False">
    <text>So I heard the All Lives Matter thing when the BLM stuff started, can you explain to me why it's seen as a bad thing? It sounds like it should be a good thing like "I believe all lives are equal and we should look out for everyone" but the prevailing theme seems to be it's not a good thing to say</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757754387.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>It's a bad thing because its only being used as a response to "black lives matter". It's being used to trivialize/ignore the issues that "black lives matter" addresses.

It's similar to the idea of "race blindness"/"I don't see race". Yes, sure, in a perfect world we don't need to even think about someone's race. But we don't live in that world at the moment, unfortunately, and so pretending race doesn't impact things in people's lives just encourages people to ignore those issues, meaning we can never try to solve them.

Saying "all lives matter" as a response to "black lives matter" is just saying "all lives matter, all lives are equal, therefore we don't need to do anything to ensure that black people's lives matter as much as anyone else's, because they already do".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758962006.0" user="ChaosintheSnow" delta="False">
    <text>Ah that makes so much sense, thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756954385.0" user="Sydney_Gamer" delta="False">
    <text>This is an utterly vacuous statement. “I like this apple” could be said by a Nazi. But it has nothing to do with being one. 

Calling out a dumb fuck statement is never fragility. It’s calling out a dumb fuck statement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757019438.0" user="ass_explosion_69" delta="False">
    <text>Well. That *also* depends on context.

If someone say shit like “year men are trash” then it shouldn’t be wrong to defend a bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757061637.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it's not fragility to say "not all men" do or don't. It's not fragility to say "all lives matter". It's fragility to interrupt conversations about the experiences of women at the hands of men with "not all men." It's fragility to interrupt discussions BLM of the incidents that lead to them with "all lives matter." The contextual timing is incredibly important and seems to be entirely what most of the people tend to miss. "Not all men [do bad thing]..." and "all lives matter" are perfectly fine and reasonable objective statement *entirely on their own.* They are wildly inappropriate statements when they are not on their own and are instead used as responses to specific different conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757772426.0" user="ParanoidAgnostic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's fragility to interrupt conversations about the experiences of women at the hands of men with "not all men."

When that conversation drifts (as such conversations frequently do) into generalised vilification of men, stepping in to challenge it is totally valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39761312967.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>When you perceive generalizations about the experiences of women men as villification and take it personally that's fragility. 

Women have their experiences. They perceive what they perceive based on their experiences. Generalizations are commonly shared experiences between them. If all of one woman's experiences are with villainous men then she is not wrong in generalizing that from her experience. If an experience is extremely common between many women then that is also a valid generalization from their experience. 


So you really have to worry about yourself. Are you being villified? Do YOU do bad things? In past experiences (like dates youve been on and the women you interact with) have you been a guy a woman might describe as a villain? Is it about you or is it about other people who aren't you? 

In a way it's stuff that's in the past too. You can't defend all the men who have already contributed badly to womens' experiences. Arguing against that can't change anything in the past. All you can do is ask yourself what you can do in the present and how you can be a positive future experience for women in or who may one day enter your life. 

Read that again. Or rather anytime you feel that "fragile" response to what you are perceiving villainous generalizations read what you're reading again and remember it's not about you it's about (an)other dude(s) who is/are responsible for the experiences on which those generalizations are made. It's not a generalization and if it is its based on real experiences. It's about those experiences first and then generalizations follow. 

You need to understand that's always where the conversation begins. I like when people explain themselves but you really can't expect everyone on the internet to articulate themselves like I do. Most of them have lives. Most of them have explained themselves a multiplicity of times. I like when people properly explain themselves but it just can't be expected. On the flip side of that you have to put some work in "keeping up to speed."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757796927.0" user="StillSilentMajority7" delta="False">
    <text>Does this apply to all races and genders?  Or just men, and white people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758025489.0" user="FlippinSnip3r" delta="False">
    <text>So it all boils down to "read the fucking room".

Yes anyone can do that. But in r/whitepeopletwitter you're literally asked to feel guilty for being born a certain race and that's imo worse than those who pity you for being born another.

That's absolutely vile</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39758166460.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>One point you make leaves out the context that sometimes people don't bother making the distinction and other times people go out of their way to say they don't care whether it's "all of this group" or not.

If they marched to All Lives Matter then they would have to throw out quite a bit of chants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39763573813.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Whether pointing out that a white person shouldn’t feel guilty for the actions of other white people is an example of white fragility depends heavily on context.

Really?  There is a context where people *should* feel guilty for the actions of other people of the same race?  Explain please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40249822894.0" user="widget_fucker" delta="False">
    <text>In the example above, didnt the commenter that OP was responding to move the conversation away from the buffalo shooting and toward white guilt.  OP was reaponding to the broadstroke of white guilt.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
