<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755054765.0" user="gwankovera" delta="False">
    <text>White fragility is a concept created by self avoid racists that push the idea that all white people are racist.  
I don't know about you but I do not let the thoughts of a racist dictate how I think about myself or my actions. 
when you view the world through a racist lens then every action becomes racist. White people moving into a neighborhood gentrification, white people moving out white flight.  
Ultimately you can no control how other people perceive you or your actions, all you can do is stay true to your core beliefs. You cant control how people who are not you act. You can only control how you act. 

I should not feel guilty that a person shot other people, unless i actively did something to make that happen. I do and should feel bad that it did happen. But how can i be responsible for actions taken by someone I do not know or even live near?  
I take responsibility for my own actions and I do what I can to foster friendship and comradery with the people i interact with. If someone does or says things I find objectionable I will bring it up and then depending on their reaction to my objection either help them improve themselves or move on with my life.   
Life is unfortunately not safe, but we live in the illusion of safety that our society has fostered. One that actions like the buffalo shooter distorts for a short time revealing that we do not live in a safe and fair world. Once the ripples dye out then that illusion is there again. Then people just live life until the next ripple shatters their illusions temporarily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755096633.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I personally believe that everyone is a little racist (same with sexist, homophobic, etc.) and I don't think it's the people trying to call out discrimination who are the people discriminating in nearly all cases. 

I feel quite safe and mass shootings don't change that for me. I don't own a weapon either. Case in point most gun deaths are suicide so the most dangerous person to any given gun owner is themselves. 

I am with you on what guilt is though. I don't think one should feel guilty unless they are in some way responsible for a given act. The worst thing I've done is contributed to a society that fosters the sort of thinking the shooter espoused but that isn't anywhere near a direct responsibility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755235545.0" user="gwankovera" delta="False">
    <text>I will respectfully disagree with you on everyone being a little racist, etc. I also use the original definition of the word which is the prejudice +action. I will agree that everyone has some prejudice gained from their own life experiences or lack there of, but not everyone acts on those prejudices. That right there is the difference. Acting upon or not acting upon prejudices. 
The other thing on prejudice is how someone presents themselves or how a culture presents itself can shape someone's prejudice.    
A good example of this is gangster culture. This actually has spread far outside of just one race. But it is often associated with black culture because of actions taken by the government that broke up the black family (cia getting people addicted to drugs and then arresting them) and then you had that lack of family filled up with gangs. Then you had the rise of gangster rap and that culture thrived, but that culture is also one of violence and criminal activity.  So you see someone wearing gangster styles and your prejudice of the culture/stereotyping that was evolved to keep us out of danger rings warning bells, no matter what the skin color. Infact that culture has spread to every ethnicity so if you see someone with sagging jeans and wife beater and a backwards hat your gonna be more wary than if you see someone dressed in a suit and tie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755352110.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>You're using the same definition I do for interpersonal racism.

I believe thoughts and words are a form of action and there's no difference between the mind and the body.

I do not believe it's possible to harbor a prejudice and not let that influence your actions (since thoughts and words are themselves actions).

I have to say I listen to a lot of "gangster rap" and if you actually listen to the lyrics 60% of the time they're calling out systemic racial issues and the plight of the disenfranchised people within those communities. There is a lot of misogyny among other things which is pretty endemic to the genre though. 

I try not to judge people differently based on how they dress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755456612.0" user="gwankovera" delta="False">
    <text>I again fully agree with you on that. The culture that a person grows up in does not actually define them, it just provides a general mold that each individual takes and makes their own. 
You have the tough looking guys that are some of the sweetest and nicest, you have the nice looking assholes. you have the showy extroverts that are really shy and introverted.  
Every person is a unique blend of their experiences and their choices. And the potential that people have is truly amazing.  
A lot of cultures actually do stifle that potential, and so the people who do rise to the top and become something amazing and successful are even more impressive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
