<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755709426.0" user="SingleMaltMouthwash" delta="False">
    <text>One of the weapons the right uses on the biddable and paranoid is the suggestion that acknowledging racism, targeted police brutality, the history of minority oppression and white privilege is intended to, or should indeed, make white people feel bad about themselves. 

And of course, this is nonsense. 

If the white people in question are, in fact, racist scum there is nothing that can be said that will make them accept responsibility for the evil they do or feel bad about it. 

If the white people in question are not racist scum then they shouldn't feel personally responsible for the racism they do not perpetuate and they shouldn't fall for the racist doctrine of Collective Guilt

Tagging ALL white people with responsibility for the contemptible behavior of a minority of them is exactly the kind of racist crap that racists apply to non-whites. It's exactly the principle of collective guilt some of them use to justify their hatred of Jews because they claim Jews killed Jesus 2000 years ago (even though the story makes clear that this was done by Romans, not Jews, but I digress).

That said, complacency is also a sin. If these blameless white people (let's include me in that group for the sake of argument) fail to oppose conservative candidates and scams at every opportunity are we perpetuating racism? If we continue to do business with AT&amp;amp;T and any company that sponsors FOX News are we not supporting the rise of fascism just a bit? How much is too much?

But let's please be clear about who the enemy is, where the danger lies and what needs to be done to save ourselves and each other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
