<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755296967.0" user="Yuo_cna_Raed_Tihs" delta="False">
    <text>It is white fragility if it's also accompanied with (and it often is) feeling pride for the good things white people did.


Eg, if you feel proud that the US saved Europe from Nazis but don't feel guilt or ashamed at the massive amount of racism in the US, that's white fragility</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755671400.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>I halfway agree with your point, but you seem to be implying that a lot of people aren't nationalist at all--do you think black people shouldn't feel proud that the US saved Europe from Nazis?  I think nationalistic pride is more or less just a harmful thing, but I don't think everyone agrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756238913.0" user="Yuo_cna_Raed_Tihs" delta="False">
    <text>I was just choosing a random yhing that people take pride in their "group" doing despite not individually contributing to it. The fact that it's nation based rather than race based was an error on my part but the point moreso is "if you feel pride for accomplishments of your group, also feel guilt"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755786394.0" user="jaam01" delta="False">
    <text>The concept of “been prideful of what your country did” is more associated with patriotism, to create (IMO an artificial) sense of unity, so you are more likely to align your opinion with what’s “good for the country” (actually what politicians wants you to support). IMO you should only be prideful/shameful of things you personally did, because two persons (even siblings) can have the same conditions and still one be successful and the other not, due to life choices.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
