<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39877340832.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited.

Well this is just incorrect.  [Public schools can and do declare bankruptcy and close](https://www.debtfreeohio.com/bankruptcy-information/bankruptcy/can-a-public-school-district-declare-bankruptcy/).  So the idea that a teachers' union can place unlimited demands on school district and they have to be met regardless of the consequences is false.

&amp;gt;Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen.

The entire point of a union is to have a say in the governance of the organization.  School districts are governed by school boards, and anyone who lives in the school district can vote in the school board election.

But both unions and corporations publicly back candidates in governmental elections, so there's no real difference between a public union and a private one in that regard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877366872.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Police and schools are not subject to the same profit incentives. “Unlimited” demands is a poor choice of words by me. They can place higher demands with less accountability as the profit motive is absent in the public sector. 

A private worker that owns no stock cannot vote in corporate governance. A public worker will always be able to vote in their governance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877406906.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A private worker that owns no stock cannot vote in corporate governance.

Unless they're - wait for it - in a union.  There are more ways to have a say in corporate governance than voting in shareholder meetings.

&amp;gt;A public worker will always be able to vote in their governance.

Only if they live in the school district or municipality they work in.

&amp;gt;Police and schools are not subject to the same profit incentives. Unlimited demands is a poor choice of words. They can place higher demands with less accountability as the profit motive is absent in the public sector.

I'm not sure what profits have to do with it.  If a private union or public one places excessive demands on the company or municipality, people lose jobs.  Either the company goes under or the municipality fails to pass a budget and can't pay anyone.

"Profits" are an incentive to pay as little as possible to produce a product.  Public services don't have profits, but they do have budgetary constraints.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877425875.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Public sector workers are represented at several levels of government. 

Municipalities do not go bankrupt as often as corporations do.

Profits are an incentive to act as efficiently as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877450659.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not.  Corporations are relatively easy to form and have a high rate of infant mortality compared to municipalities.  But none of that has anything to do with unions.

You edited your comment.

At what levels of government are public sector employees represented that private employees aren't?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
