<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39877241081.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic, we should abolish corporations. 

No. Punish the bad actors. Don't violate the right of free association.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877260530.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>The police unions and teachers unions are full of bad actors. They should be abolished as unnecessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877404718.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>Excellent, let's abolish corporations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877418740.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Corporations create wealth. The government redistributes wealth. That’s how this works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877792422.0" user="marciallow" delta="False">
    <text>Wealth is a construct. 

We all agreed on the value of money. A corporation as an entity does not create anything, labor creates. 

And that labor should be entitled to the same rights as a person who owns a company, which is to say they have thet should have same rights to collectivize and bargain as an entity. A worker of the government is no less a human being than someone who works for Amazon, and I think you know that they don't have meaningful individual power to argue within their own job against bad wages, bad health coverage, bad sick leave, lack of safety policies, sexual harassment policies, etc. 

When I was a young student, I worked somewhere where I was fired for being gay. It was a government job, but the specifics of my role, being a student, etc, meant I was not represented by a union. Of course, firing someone for being gay is illegal!!! But that doesn't really mean anything if you don't have the money to sue, and if the money you would get in lost wages is barely anything, and if it would take months to over a year to even try that ...and that's all assuming it's provable. As an individual, I had no power compared to a business without even considering the much greater impact firing has to an employee than an employer. 

I got a seasonal job later on for the government and this time I was union eligible. The first time my boss at that job hinted at an issue with me being gay my union rep got HR to demote them and implement a new policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877881941.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>No, workers create wealth, corporations make sure to make as much of that wealth reach the top of that corporation, unions make sure to make as much of that wealth reach the bottom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877891782.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Oy vey! If the workers produced wealth then worker owned co-ops would dominate the market place. Where are all the co-ops? Must be those big mean corporations out competing them. The entire corporate structure is what produces wealth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878009912.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>It's almost like if wealth accumulation allowed wealthy individuals to wield more power with their corporations and win the struggle against the workers (which will have even less strength without an union).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878031996.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>There is nothing stopping workers from creating co-ops. It’s a free country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878046390.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there is, you need wealth and means of production to start your own company. Most workers have none.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878073020.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>What a joke. Regular people start small businesses all the time. If they worked, some of those small business would turn into worker owned co-ops. If the co-ops were workable, they would gain market share as a corporate structure.

Where are all the co-ops?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878119826.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Regular people start small businesses all the time

No they don't. Regular people don't have the means to do that. I'm gonna assume you are American so I will use American numbers: [59% of Americans are one paycheck away from not being able to pay rent](https://invisiblepeople.tv/59-of-americans-are-just-one-paycheck-away-from-homelessness), those people can't simply quit their current job and start their own business since they don't have enough savings to pay for basic things until their business starts making a profit, and this is without even considering things like lack of health insurance or the business not making a profit in the first month.

&amp;gt; If they worked, some of those small business would turn into worker owned co-ops

Why would a private business owner give ownership to their workers forcing them to share more profits when they can instead keep the ownership themselves alongside a bigger cut of the cake?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878163198.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Some of those small business owners are Americans living pay check to check as there are 31.7 million small businesses in the U.S. 

Maybe they want to share some of the risk with their employees. Maybe they are all doing equal work. Maybe some think similarly to you and believe in the co-op as the ultimate form of corporate governance. 

The lack of success for co-ops over the last hundred years is deafening silence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878216732.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 31.7 million small businesses in the U.S.

You do realize that's less than 10% of the US population right? It's almost like if most people can't simply start their own business.

&amp;gt; Maybe they want to share some of the risk with their employees.

Employees already share the risk. If the business fails the employees are gonna become unemployed.

&amp;gt; The lack of success for co-ops over the last hundred years is deafening silence.

Or maybe it's evidence that business owners prefer to keep the benefits for themselves. Regardless of that, there are many successful co-ops in the world. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_cooperatives</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878262926.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>If anything, these are the exceptions which prove the rule, just like law firms and medical practices. Co-ops are not as efficient or effective as corporations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878286022.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Efficient or effective at what? At creating wealth or at accumulating wealth for it's owner/s?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878296873.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Either, both</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878344761.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's because co-ops are not meant to accumulate wealth for their owners. Contrary to corporations that are made by the owners with the sole purpose of accumulating wealth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878360236.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>A co-op, a business owned by the workers, is not supposed to accumulate wealth for the owners? They are selling their stuff at cost? 

This is why everyone else hates Progressives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878412209.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>There is a distinction between generating wealth and accumulating wealth. When you accumulate wealth is because you are receiving more than you need and you start accumulating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878425460.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>The reason a business/owners accumulate wealth is because they are good at providing goods and services and should be trusted to manage resources as to provide more goods and services, thus raising the standard of living for everyone. 

Corporations create wealth. The government redistributes some of that wealth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878440189.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The reason a business/owners accumulate wealth is because they are good at providing goods and services

No, they are good at taking a bigger share of the wealth created by their workers.

&amp;gt; Corporations create wealth.

Name me one corporation that creates wealth without workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878471208.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>The more wealth they create the more wealth they can take from the workers. It’s a win-win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878479620.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It’s a win-win.

Unless you are a worker.

Also I'm still waiting for you to name me a corporation that creates wealth without workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878492852.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Workers are required to generate wealth. They are part of the corporate structure that creates the computer you’re using now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878523990.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Then you agree that wealth is not created by corporations but by workers.

We have:

* corporations + workers = wealth
* workers (in coops) = wealth
* corporations = no wealth

Therefore, wealth is created by workers, not by corporations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878567452.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>In order for co-ops to function the workers all need to do more or less equal work and be agreed on the amount of risk and direction the organization should take. 

Very few business meet this criteria. Lawyers, medical doctors, agricultural producers, are all basically doing the same job so it makes sense for them to form a cooperative to share the labor and the risk. 

This is not the case for a business that makes, let’s say, computers. A business that requires a hierarchy of workers and managers will never all do the same job and never agree on how much risk is acceptable. It’s not possible to achieve many technological, capital intensive feats without the corporate structure that assigns rewards based on the complexity of a job and the amount of risk an individual takes on in the venture.

Sorry the world is more complex than your three line proof.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878668395.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A business that requires a hierarchy of workers and managers will never all do the same job

There are plenty examples of businesses with hierarchy of workers in the list I sent before. So you are factually wrong here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878744043.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>There are millions of businesses in the US and a handful of co-ops. These are the exceptions that prove the rule.

I’m sure that some on the list like Land of Lakes are farmer owned, but the farmers still employ and take advantage of agricultural laborers.

Who creates the wealth for Land O’ Lakes, the farmers that make up the co-op or the laborers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878860210.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There are millions of businesses in the US and a handful of co-ops

Again, that's because most people can't start their own business and business owners are motivated to keep the ownership of their business.

&amp;gt; Who creates the wealth for Land O’ Lakes, the farmers that make up the co-op or the laborers?

Both? Or are you now a physiocrat?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878930811.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>I’m just pointing out that even among the handful of co-ops you pointed out, at least one exploits farm workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878992764.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>I never said co-ops do not exploit people. Co-ops are still part of capitalism and capitalism requires exploitation to work.

My point is that a co-op will distribute more of the wealth for the co-op's workers while a corporation will distribute more of the wealth for the owners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879006064.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>To the farmers, the people who own the capital, not the workers. That’s like saying law firms distribute the wealth to all their attorneys and not just partners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879028651.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>To the workers of the cooperative. Not the workers outside of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39881435446.0" user="shouldco" delta="False">
    <text>Without a distinct owning class separated from the workers, no there is a significant difference.

A company that outsources its support staff can cut costs and make shareholders money. A co-op is responsible to those employees as well. Increasing profit at the expense of employees is not something you can justify when you don't just have a fiduciary responsibility to act on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878132376.0" user="shitty_idiot" delta="False">
    <text>How does a corporation create wealth without workers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878174664.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Why haven’t workers started their own co-ops to compete with corporations? 

The corporate structure is the design which produces wealth including both capitalists and workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878193152.0" user="shitty_idiot" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't answer my question. How does a corporation create wealth without workers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878195909.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t. All parts of the machine are necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39886012464.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>Workers cannot reasonably do that in 2022 in many industries, because the capitalists got there first, and they are still there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878872538.0" user="Justviewingposts69" delta="False">
    <text>So because corporations are more successful than co-ops that means they should be allowed to be exploitative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878912817.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, I am for private unions as they are an important check on the power of corporations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878887863.0" user="Justviewingposts69" delta="False">
    <text>Also traditional forms which include corporations have a higher rate of failure than worker co ops</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878920548.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Because there are tens of millions of small businesses being created and failing. 

Co-ops are not even competitive enough of a form to be compared.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880436463.0" user="Justviewingposts69" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know what rate means?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40102942731.0" user="Demotay" delta="False">
    <text>Your entire argument is saying that coops aren’t as good as private corporations, yet here you are saying that there aren’t enough coops to compare them. What a hypocrite. You also have no clue about the statistics if you actually think it’s comparing totality rather than per capita.

Your entire argument is fucking wrong anyways, and you don’t have any clue about economics if you’re truly arguing against co-ops in the way you are doing right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40102992036.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880107202.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>That's your own assumption. Maybe no some agree, but one does not lead to the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880096436.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>People create wealth. That's how this works. Corporations are a legal form created by people in order to get limited liability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883504066.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Limited liability is the single greatest innovation in business. It allows people to take risks. Risks create prosperity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883575273.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>Innovation creates prosperity. People can take risk if they want, but we should really be wary of having government intervention in creating moral hazard. It's a lot of heads I win, tails you lose element of it in there. It took, and still takes, a lot of regulation to limit the negative spillover effects of the limited liability of corporations. 

I often wonder what a world without corporations would be like, where it was all sole proprietors and partnerships. Less risk taking in aggregate, perhaps, but probably better risk management - you'll manage your money and business much better if you could lose your house on a bad business decision, rather than just inflicting your mistakes on your debtors and investors. Less skin in the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883818704.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Implementing innovation involves risk. Business is the act of implementing innovation. Innovation really means nothing without commercialization. Commercialization is achieved by putting a cap on the amount of loses any implementation can incur, the amount invested (and/or borrowed). 

The best way to help people is not by limiting what risks they can take, but by slightly easing the cost of failure. Social programs like universal health care or affordable education would allow more people to start businesses without the fear of losing everything.

It’s important to advocate for increased investment in the people without losing sight of the framework that creates the prosperity we enjoy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883951435.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with social insurance, but it's likely to be more effective at the societal level, where it's about risk pooling catastrophic personal risk. 

Very leery about letting cowboys run around blowing up companies, and leaving the costs to the rest of us. If they run the risk of blowing themselves up only, if works out and they get rich, fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877719797.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>The whole problem with unions is that you cannot punish the crappy employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880128021.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>No. 

You can be still fire bad workers, but it has to be with cause, or for operational reasons. Something like what happened to James Damore wouldn't be impossible, but it'd be harder had he been part of a union.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880288433.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, that's why it's so easy to fire bad teachers, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880453859.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>I can't speak to your personal experience with teachers. But it's absolutely possible to discipline underperformance in an environment with collective bargaining. You just can't fire without just cause, documented underperformance, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880499214.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>It’s pretty widely regarded how hard it is to fire people in unions. The employer should not need anything documented. They should be able to fire any one they don’t want working there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880522348.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>But the employees shouldn't be allowed to bargain and create a contract with their employees laying out termination procedures? Pretty big double standard there. Also "it's pretty widely regarded" isn't an argument. Please provide actual examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880533013.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Groups of employees can certainly try. But employees should also be able to choose not to be a part of the union, which is prohibited in many places. There should be no laws forcing someone to be a part of it, it should all be negotiated. And employees should be free to say nope, no union workers here period if they choose to. 

No talented employee would want to be in a union anyway. It protects the bottom tier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880548558.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>So they can't bargain to create a contract governs hiring procedures, but of course the business can do whatever it wants. Another double standard. Also notice the lack of evidence for your claim that unions make people almost unfirable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880554949.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>There should always be a double standard. The group *paying* someone should always have more power. And I showed studies separately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880568296.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why should they?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39881610107.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>Unless that's something that's negotiated by the union and the employer. But then government action bans closed shops in some areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880538777.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.edweek.org/teaching-learning/study-its-far-too-hard-to-fire-bad-teachers/2016/12 

You’ll find plenty of articles and discussions about how impossible it is to fire teachers in certain districts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880583170.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>That article is full of fluff, it basically says "it's hard pls believe us" while barely outlining the procedure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880614250.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>You ignored some pretty key points that illustrate my point perfectly:  “Length of the dismissal process: In 12 of the districts, it takes at least two years to dismiss a teacher for poor performance. In San Francisco and Los Angeles, it takes at least five years.”  

Anything beyond a month is *absurd*. 

“In 11 districts, teachers must be observed as many as six times before they can be let go. (In New York, it’s a minimum of eight times.) What’s more, many districts have contracts that allow teachers to appeal a dismissal on any grounds. And in 21 districts, teachers can appeal a dismissal more than once” 

The concept of being able to appeal is ridiculous. 

“In 17 of the 25 districts, state law allows teachers to gain tenure and keep it, despite poor performance reviews”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880629588.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it "absurd".for a firing to take more then a month? Why is the concept of an appeal "ridiculous" (they exist in court for a reason), what is wrong with tenure? These all seem like perfectly reasonable things to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880647746.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Any employer should be able to fire you same day, for any reason. Full stop. An employee should have *zero* say or recourse period. 

The tenture point illustrates my point verbatim. Shitty people can’t be fired easily. That’s my whole point. And the single biggest negative of unions. 

There no point to being a good employee when you get the same results as a shitty one. It encourages people to be awful at their jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880665029.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? You lay down all these arguments  like they're hard fact, but they're actually your opinion, and countries that implement strong labor laws, places like France are usually happier then the US and I value people's happiness over an abstract concepts "rights", why am I wrong? And when did being a good vs shitty employee net you the same results? Last I checked the McDonalds cashier is making a whole lot less then the NASA engineer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880685087.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>They are opinions.  

Those are different types of employees. The shitty teacher makes the same as a great teacher with the same experience. A shitty plumber makes the same as a great plumber in the same union. 

That’s the problem. 

I’d much rather be in the US than any European country. Much more opportunity for success.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880731708.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>And you think that nepotism doesn't exist? That favoritism doesn't exist? If you honestly believe that then I have a ski slope in Honolulu to sell you. Corporations aren't some perfect specimen for meriocracy. Unions offer a clear and transparent process for advancement and accountability, and it is possible to discharge bad workers, idk where you got that from.

And personally, I'd rather live in Europe and I'd move tomorrow if I could, the opportunity to make 150k instead of 100k is more then outweighed imo by the possibility of going bankrupt from using an ambulance, or being fired because your boss doesn't like your hair color or whatever. There is a reason Europe is happier then the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880750998.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Who cares if nepotism exists? That’s the right of the employer. I just showed you a study detailing how school districts with unions make it incredibly difficult to discharge a bad worker.  Know what it takes me to fire one of my employees? 5 minutes. 


I’m not interested in making 150k. That’s just a mediocre lifestyle. The chance of making millions in the US *far* exceeds anywhere in Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880778248.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>You just explained how shitty employees will be paid more with unions, but they ALREADY ARE with the current system. The drawback of unions you mention already exists, and your article was full of fluff.

Why should everyone else enjoy a lower quality of life so you can make millions? Personally I think we need much higher taxes on anyone making 650k or higher. With that extra money quality of life would greatly improve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880794224.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>I see we will never agree. 

The people at the top already spay the lions share of taxes. While half the country pays nothing. 

Taking from the most successful, to give to the least motivated will never make a fundamental change except to piss off the wealthiest. 

And no, my article showed concrete examples of district counts and timelines what were ridiculous. 

I am arguing that the current system is a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880811203.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed we won't, clearly you value your own greed more then the quality of life for the millions of other people you share a planet with, to you they are just a number to hire or fire at will in your quest to reach the top tough shit if they can't feed their families or make ends meet. Die on the street. That is disgusting to me and I will never agree with that perspective.

Good day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880828612.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone has that opportunity to be successful. And people who assist you along the path are rewarded well for it (my employees make hundreds of thousands a year). 

Those who cannot be bothered don’t have my sympathy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39881604326.0" user="Dontblowitup" delta="False">
    <text>By that standard, employees should not need anything to walk off the job. They should be able to do that as part of a coordinated move anytime they want. But that's called a wildcat strike, and is usually banned, as are sympathy strikes and pattern bargaining, depending on what the laws are in your area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880512493.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Bad teachers stay in because the US has a massive teacher shortage right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880515097.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>No, it prevents your from being fired for arbitrary reasons. That is an important distinction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880519872.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Which should still not be a thing. Employers should be able to fire you for any reason, or no reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880562182.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? Why should corporate rights be considered more important then actual people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880567936.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Because they are paying the people…not the other way around. Same as any relationship where someone is paying. Employees are free to leave and go elsewhere</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880575171.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>And? The employee/employer relationship is unique so idgaf what rules apply to other relationships. Personally I'm quite glad we have OHSA and labor laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880581382.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>How is it unique? The companies should have the power to pay who they want to pay, in the same reason that I shouldn’t be able to force you to give me money just because I want you to pay me when you don’t want to. There is no difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880591789.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why should they though? What's wrong with forcing the companies to pay more then they want? Corporations aren't people and don't have rights. I see it as unique because people are much more reliant on their employees then random gifts from their friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880602332.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Corporations are legally people, and do have rights. They also directly represent their owners.  

No one has any right to their money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880616469.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>The Supreme Court got it wrong. And why doesn't society have a right to "their" money? Using your argument it clearly does because tax exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880637363.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Because society didn’t earn it. In the exact same way your money is not my money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880651199.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? Unless these business owners are operating in the jungle they use public roads, the public court system, public institutions like the police, rely on a publicly educated workforce, all provided by society. Why shouldn't the corporations pay in for the benefits they've received from society?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880661134.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>They do. Through taxes.  Not some magical jobs giveaway program.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880673557.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Which is literally taking some of the money they "earned", which is what you were just arguing against.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880693938.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>We have a law that says they need to pay taxes. We don’t have a law that says they need to keep shitty people employed for good will. 

And beyond all this, one of the biggest issues of unions is public sector. Giving taxpayer money to bad workers. I don’t see how anyone can support that. 

You are literally paying for the worst teachers in America to continue barely doing their jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880709842.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>Then create more strict labor standards, and I'd argue we'd be better off with such a law. Personally I'm fine with protecting a shitty employee or 2 if that means all the normal workers are protected too. It's the same reason I support welfare even in spite of one or 2 welfare queens popping up. I'm not paying to protect America's worst teachers, I'm paying to protect teachers in general and allow them to do their job without excessive harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880739849.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>I want less labor protections, not more. Good employees don’t need extra protections. No employer in their right mind is going to fire a valuable employee. 

I am not worried about welfare queens. No one needs welfare in America. There are unlimited ways to support oneself if they are not lazy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880755139.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>I want more labor protections not less, a rising tide raises all ships and providing a good minimum ensures that companies don't exploit workers, and workers are disposable at any level but the top.

And that second point is literally not true, many people work very hard 12 or 14 hours a day and still end up homeless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880783283.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>*many* people do not work 12-14 hour days and become homeless. 

The vast majority are unemployed. 

Workers can’t get exploited with how easy it is to find other work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880793625.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>And many people do, that's a non argument. My point was that many people work hard and become homeless, while you say it's impossible. The vast majority of people who receive welfare are employed.

I'd also counter that it's easy to find work, it really isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880803224.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>In a given study of a city, 83% of homeless respondents were unemployed. https://www.hchmd.org/sites/default/files/wysiwyg/HCH%20Employment%20Report_final.pdf 

I have no clue what world you’re in that it’s hard to find work. It is exceptionally easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880817104.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>The world where normal people live, I've applied to 150 places and gotten 0 jobs so far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880823025.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>So stop applying for jobs and make money. You don’t have to wait for someone else to hand you a job. I think that will always be a fundamental difference in attitude between the successful and others.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
