<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39880177107.0" user="rainsford21" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of unions is to help the power imbalance between employees and employers.  Alone, an employee typically needs an employer far more than the employer needs the employee because the employee only represents a small fraction of the labor an employer needs, while an employer represents all the income an employee has.  An employee quitting has far less of an impact on the employer than getting fired has on an employee.  Collective bargaining turns it into a 1-to-1 relationship, where employees and collectively have as much leverage over an employer as the employer has over an individual employee.

If anything, the argument is even stronger for the public sector because many public sector employers have monopolies on employment that would not exist in the private sector.  Not only can a public sector employer take away the income of a public sector employee, but they might represent all or most of the jobs in that field, especially if you consider locality.  If you're a teacher or a police officer and the school or police department fires you, you're probably going to have to move to find another job unless you want to change careers.  This gives them even more leverage over you than a normal employer, making the argument for improving your own bargaining position even stronger.

But what about the fact you brought up that your employer is ultimately accountable to the voters (including you) rather than shareholders?  I'd argue that actually makes it worse.  Sure, you get a vote, but you're vastly outnumbered by other voters who are frankly often reactionary morons or assholes and at least half of them view you as the enemy.  If you're a public school teacher trying to deal with right-wing COVID or CRT rage or a police officer worried about "defund the police", you definitely don't want to be out there on your own where your livelihood is concerned.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
