<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39877279315.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Do you hav an example of a public union being corrupted?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877286594.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Any police union that allows police brutality to thrive.

Teachers shutting down schools during Covid forcing parents into impossible situations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877303151.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't corruption. Those are unions advocating for policies for their workers you disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877321851.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Paying someone who isn’t doing their job well or reassigning someone who broke the law isn’t corruption? It’s misuse of public funds and a breach of public trust. The stated goal of the organization is corrupted by the incentive to side with union members over what is right.

In the private sector, this is balanced by the fact that if a union doesn’t provide adequate work, everyone loses their jobs when the company goes under. 

No such thing can happen for teachers or cops.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877432299.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>No. That isn't corruption. It isn't a misuse of funds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877498833.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Misuse of funds is a form of corruption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877534889.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why I pointed out it isn't misuse of funds.

It isnt misuse of funds to incur additional expense interacting with the labor market and the costs of engaging with that market. If it were, basic health and safety items, like bathrooms, would be a misuse of funds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877554153.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>When a bad teacher or cop is protected by their union and they continue to be paid instead of fired, that is corruption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877570854.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>No, that isn't. That is what the union is able to negotiate.

Let's look at it another way. In a market without unions, it can still be that to competitively hire people they must compete with the contractual employment protections in the private sector identical to the ones in the union contract. Nothing prevents a future where that is true.

Is it corruption for the government to add that to employment contracts to remain competitive? Is the government required to remain unstaffed because they cannot add those provisions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877682105.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. My point is that public sector unions have improper bargaining power because their organizations cannot go out of business in the same sense as a private business. 

The union makes demands on tax payers and none of those demands are subject to the sustainability test of the free market.

Contractual protections negotiated one on one are not the same as collective bargaining agreements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877697750.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Which isn't corruption.

"The union makes demands on tax payers and none of those demands are subject to the sustainability test of the free market."

While unpleasant, is not corruption. The existence of a free market isn't the requirement of being not corrupt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877726159.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Leveraging unequal bargaining power to gain protections for members that reduce the quality of the product is corruption because those protections are not subject to the sustainability tests of the free market. 

It’s a politically powerful group with few checks on their power mandating protections for themselves at the expense of the tax payer. It’s literally corrupting the service of policing or teaching by leveraging power for benefits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877758159.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>"corruption because those protections are not subject to the sustainability tests of the free market."


That's not a thing. That is just a value you made up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877781270.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Leveraging your power to gain an unfair advantage is dishonesty if we operate under the assumption that negotiations should be fair. Negotiations with the public sector are inherently unfair. 

Private sector unions do negotiate with employers in a fair way because they are both subject to the risk of bankruptcy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877797827.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>You just made up out of nowhere that somehow risk of bankruptcy grants fairness.

You also just made up that unfairness is corruption</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877840143.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Bankruptcy creates fairness because the profit motive is the ultimate arbitrator, completely removed from the control of either party. Either you produce for the public at a sustainable price or you don’t. 

Leveraging of collective power over tax payers to obtain advantages that protect dishonest workers is corruption. 

The private sector union can only protect so many bad workers before it harms the corporation and thus harms the union. Because the public sector will be always be bailed out by the tax payer, corrupt public union practices go unchecked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877869043.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>If the whole point is that your view is based on whatever ideosyncratic ideas you have, that is fine.

But the idea that bankruptcy amounts to fairness does not track. That is your value and not universal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877880666.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Bankruptcy is universal though. Either you produce a product at a price that covers your cost or you don’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877900299.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Again, the idea that amounts to fairness is just your view, not a largely held belief by others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877903517.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Facts don’t care about your beliefs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877909760.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>That it is fair is not a fact....that is a value.

Fair is subjective, not factual</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877940554.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Life isn’t fair. The only thing we can do is try and use objective standards, like bankruptcy, to create a level playing field and try to rein in individual excess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877950586.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>again....that's just something you made up and isn't based upon some generally agreed upon ideas.

That is fine..But you are not hitting on some universal truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878050766.0" user="seanflyon" delta="False">
    <text>Police unions supporting violently criminal officers is corruption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878056383.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>A and B collude to rob C is textbook corruption</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878759359.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>.... wouldn't that be conspiracy to commit theft....not corruption?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878931128.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>why not both?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878986989.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Because your 10 words do not describe corruption</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879024668.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; corruption

Definition of corruption
1a: dishonest or illegal behavior especially by powerful people (such as government officials or police officers) : DEPRAVITY
b: inducement to wrong by improper or unlawful means (such as bribery)
the corruption of government officials
c: a departure from the original or from what is pure or correct</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879053210.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>which does not describe what you wrote</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879108451.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; dishonest or illegal behavior especially by powerful people (such as government officials</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879164563.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>We were not discussing powerful people or government officials.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879268024.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A and B collude to rob C is textbook corruption

A = Public union = union boss = powerfull people

B = Politican =  government offical 

C = taxpayer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879381144.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't define anything before</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39879390373.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>it was in another comment in this same thread</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880886487.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care if it is a comment I am not discussing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883912185.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>need a tissue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39883937644.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Yes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877643241.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>Idk about where you’re at, but where I’m at teachers fought tooth and nail to keep schools open and to reopen as soon as possible. State and county government ignored them and still shut schools down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39878044833.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.forbes.com/sites/adamandrzejewski/2020/04/27/why-illinois-is-in-trouble--109881-public-employees-with-100000-paychecks-cost-taxpayers-14b/?sh=3fc1cc3a7ee9</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
