<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39880294358.0" user="XKyotosomoX" delta="False">
    <text>Would you feel differently about public unions if a bunch of legislation was passed that neutered any and all ability they have to directly influence politicians, as well as passed legislation that would make it illegal for them to strike and intentionally inconvenience / coerce the public, as well as passed legislation preventing them from forcing employees to join their union?   What I'm talking about is making it so basically the only thing that public sector unions can do is voluntarily collectively organize to pool their time and personal resources together to spread awareness to the public about their plights and make their case to the public as to why the voters should vote for specific propositions / ask their politicians to take specific actions to provide the workers what their collectively asking for.  Would you no longer feel public sector unions should be abolished if that were the case?

Full disclosure I actually agree that as they currently stand they're absolutely horrible for the country, generally the only people who think otherwise are wildly ignorant and illiterate of even the most basic of economics, civics, and history.  HOWEVER the core issue is just that collective bargaining is done in favor of the bargainers' best interests and against the best interests of the employer (and usually the customers), and in the case of public sector unions; the employer is the American public, and we don't want our own public employees actively fighting against the public's best interests when it's literally their entire job to serve the public's interests (you mentioned cops and teachers, who are frankly two fantastic examples of public sector unions that have absolutely devastated our country).  But if you could make it so that's no longer and issue, I see no reason why they shouldn't be able to collectively organize.  I would argue that it's not that public sector unions need to be abolished, it's just that we need specific legislation curbing their ability to abuse the system in order to get what they want.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
