<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39877790669.0" user="MonocularBabylon" delta="False">
    <text>Tell this to my country's underpaid teachers working in underfunded schools...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880383458.0" user="XKyotosomoX" delta="False">
    <text>Here in America teachers being underpaid is a myth, their median income is like 50% higher than the average American's median income AND they're almost unfirable no matter how awful they are at their job AND they don't have to work for a forth of the year AND they tend to have all sorts of benefits normal citizens don't get access to like the pension which is basically tens of thousands of dollars a year every year for the rest of their life after retirement without having to do any work for it (all on the taxpayer's dime of course).  Of course much of this stuff comes as a result of them being unionzed to be fair, but without unions I'd be shocked if they weren't still making roughly median income and getting typical government benefits.  The teacher's union is not necessary to them getting paid well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880505883.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>That's a supply/demand thing. America has a massive teacher shortage and districts gotta pay up to get staff. That's literally the market working.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880600342.0" user="XKyotosomoX" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't say we have a general teacher shortage nor would I say we have a general surplus.  It usually goes back and forth year to year state to state not to mention depends where you're willing to work (super easy to get a job in the poor inner-city, super tough to get one in the rich suburbs).  Frankly anecdotally I've hard more teachers say that struggled to get hired than had an easy time but once again this is biased by where I live.  However the last couple years shortage issues are a weird exception due to the effects of the pandemic on the labor market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39882495989.0" user="MonocularBabylon" delta="False">
    <text>Who the heck said I'm talking about the US?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39880876001.0" user="jtvliveandraw" delta="False">
    <text>I am SO glad you wrote this. Seriously, thank you. 

People repeat “teachers are underpaid” like some sort of dogma. But in reality, they’re not underpaid at all.

I’m glad at least one person sees through the BS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40102985451.0" user="Demotay" delta="False">
    <text>The argument is that they’re getting underpaid compared to similar professions that require the same education and require much less work. It isn’t an argument of median pay. You can’t just say someone is getting underpaid because they make the median salary. You are supposed to compare them with similar careers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40103033310.0" user="XKyotosomoX" delta="False">
    <text>That's just objectively false.  There are tons of professions that require the same level or more of education/work yet get paid less.  Getting to be a teacher is a good job, maybe you can argue it's only because of the unions (fucking the American people so damn hard) fighting for such a sweet deal that it's a good job, but nonetheless it's still cushy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40103080835.0" user="Demotay" delta="False">
    <text>There is a reason why tons of teachers are stressed and leaving their jobs, buddy.

And I’m saying that they are getting underpaid because of the amount of stress and work they have to put up, compared to other professions. It’s the shit they have to deal with that makes their profession underpaid, not that the objective amount they get paid is low. I didn’t word it correctly at first.

Even if we look at objective salary amount, there are still many teachers that have 20 years of teaching experience and a doctorates, yet making 70k a year. That is way too low.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40103296689.0" user="XKyotosomoX" delta="False">
    <text>You: "They're getting underpaid and have more stressful work compared to other professions"
Me: "That is just objectively false"
You: "Well uh that's not MY truth"

Well great then I don't need to have a conversation with you because clearly you're stuck living in your own delusional little reality and don't want to admit how good they have it. Also 70K a year (with a MASSIVE pension AND much of the year off) isn't underpaid in the slightest what the hell are you smoking?  That's double what the average American makes, at least triple if you factor in the benefits I mentioned. Also they're leaving their jobs because there's a tight labor supply so they have more leverage to get an even higher salary (do you have no understanding of basic economics?).  Or just because they're lazy assholes considering many are the same assholes who refuse to go into work where they could give a proper education and would rather continue to prolong remote learning even though they know full well it's garbage for the kids. It's honestly pathetic, teacher's union is the single most damaging lobbyist group in America and to defend then is just ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40103320462.0" user="Demotay" delta="False">
    <text>Thank god conservatism is dying. Please fall off with it, buddy. Not sure why you went on a mad rant and started fighting instead of arguing, but I just guess that means you don’t have much of a tangent argument!

You act like a centrist, but you’re spouting right wing bullshit. I’d say some worse things on here, but I would be breaking reddit’s terms of service. Whatever it thinking of, I hope it happens to you. I’m tired of compromising with you fucks.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
