<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39891517608.0" user="RichardBonham" delta="False">
    <text>Callous disregard for the impact of one’s actions on one’s surroundings is problematic because of the attitude it reflects. 

The attitude of disregard carries over into other things and interactions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891714295.0" user="TheStabbyBrit" delta="False">
    <text>Many of the behaviours considered bad on Earth would be desirable elsewhere. If we want to make Mars habitable, we NEED greenhouse gasses! Dropping nuclear bombs on the poles of Mars might actually be a good thing for its environment, insofar as it could help make the planet habitable to life from Earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893034279.0" user="Koilos" delta="False">
    <text>≥Many of the behaviours considered bad on Earth would be desirable elsewhere.

I'm not sure this is particularly relevant to the argument being made. While many behaviors that are perceived as undesirable on earth may become desirable in a different context, the behaviors that humans are incentivized to engage in would probably change with the environment as well. A reckless disregard for the long-term consequences of collective human action would still be just as destructive in an environment where previously undesirable behaviors were okay; the specific forms of short-sighted greed would simply be adapted to the new conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
