<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39891467408.0" user="Tioben" delta="False">
    <text>Like you, I'm not so concerned about harm to the Moon.

However, I find it easy to envision a future where, after disregarding Leave No Trace-like policies, the consequences find their way back to Earth.

Materially, space junk won't necessarily all burn up in the fall, and the way we build spacecraft can impact the launch through Earth's atmosphere as easily as the launch off the Moon.  Edit to add: Moreover, how well we care for the space environment may impact our ability to exploit it in the longterm.  (As an example, early logging, herding, and fishing practices in U.S. wilderness areas have hampered contemporary interest in enjoying wilderness areas as recreation areas and natural reserves.  Who says we won't value a pristine lunar environment in 200 years?)

Psychologically, the way we train or socialize space travelers and space miners won't neatly compartmentalize when they return home.  Callousness towards the environment won't be neatly restricted to space rocks, because the power of "It's *ours*!" reaches further than that, and behaviors made habitual are not easily dropped.

On a more abstract spiritual level, as far as you want to consider that, the way we connect to the world shapes *us*.  It may be possible to grow in a fruitful direction as individuals and as a species while exploiting space to benefit each other, but perhaps only when we practice deliberate caring.  If we stop caring about our environment, we might harm our ability to care for each other by discounting opportunities to practice care.  Taking care of the environment in space could become just as important for our own growth as taking care of the environment on Earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892107068.0" user="RatherNerdy" delta="False">
    <text>These are great points beyond the physicality of space trash. We already exist as over-consumers on our planet, which is leading to environmental disasters, and to continue that process into space would be shortsighted and likely come back to bite us in the ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893529742.0" user="erutan_of_selur" delta="False">
    <text>This is a non-problem in space. Burning trash has always been a common practice, it's just not a good use of greenhouse gas emissions with what options are crucial to us.

But there's no such problem in space. We can offload all of our trash to space and incinerate it out there. It doesn't matter if there are greenhouse gas emissions out there, there's no Ozone to scrape.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39895849071.0" user="_zenith" delta="False">
    <text>If you want to do that, you're gonna need oxygen to do it. Needless to say, using valuable oxidiser for something that isn't propulsion is really dumb.

Just get better at recycling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892360757.0" user="whatever54267" delta="False">
    <text>You're not concerned about harm to the moon? 

What does the moon do? It circles us.

What happens when we staring  mining or blowing shit up on the moon? That shit will come to earth. 

Also, if we can't take care of our own planet how is going to another planet going to help? At some point we'll just become parasites moving from planet to planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892375716.0" user="Tioben" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps you should read the whole comment and you'll see how it generally agrees with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892987243.0" user="whatever54267" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I see that but you still don't care which is the problem. The moon literally rotates around the earth and you don't care. If we accidentally destroy it, guess where it's coming down. You say these things but your opening statement is I don't care  so which one is it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892833002.0" user="CamRoth" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;What happens when we staring  mining or blowing shit up on the moon? That shit will come to earth. 

Uh no, no it will not. I don't think you are comprehending the size of the moon or how far away from Earth it actually is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893175656.0" user="whatever54267" delta="False">
    <text>What you're not comprehending is humans are quite good at building destructive shit and we don't fully understand the inner working of the moon. No scientist will say that's its an impossibility. Also, the distance doesn't matter, the moon orbits the earth for a reason, ie gravity. The gravitational pull will bring any debris toward the earth and not all of that debris will burn off. 

Edit: Also wars happen on earth they will definitely happen. On the moon eventually</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893549354.0" user="CamRoth" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry dude but you are just not understanding the physics involved. 

Debris? What debris? From the moon? Anything from the moon would have to first escape its gravity in order to have any chance of making it to earth. Escape velocity on the moon is 2.4 km per second.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893700053.0" user="whatever54267" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not talking about now or the abilities we have now, but in the future. You're thinking in the short term and I'm thinking long term. It isn't impossible we just don't have the ability in the moment  and if we destroy the whole moon then the yeah it would. If I remember correctly if we can get it close enough to earth it will break apart and destroy us. I'm sure some time in the future we will be able to do this. There's ways a possibility and I'm sure we can find more inventive ways instead.

Nothing is impossible just improbable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39895376709.0" user="whatsup4" delta="False">
    <text>I think you underestimate how truly far the moon is. To send something from the moon to earth requires incredible precision. Things would not just accidentally make it to the moon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892912768.0" user="ProcyonLotorMinoris" delta="False">
    <text>To add to your comment, we absolutely do need to care about the moon. It could be a valuable "launch pad " for intra- and interstellar travel. It could be a place for scientific settlement and research (like the Lunar Crater Radio Telescope), refueling, supply storage, orbiting space stations and satellites, etc... We're just making it harder for ourselves but not caring about the consequences of our current actions.


PLUS the effects of the moon are essential to our daily lives. Tides, stabilizing out axial tilt and wobble, circadian rhythm. Preserving the moon is essential to human life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39898024696.0" user="SnooPets5219" delta="False">
    <text>Why aren’t you concerned about harm to the moon? Without the moon the earth would be affected in a lot of ways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
