<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39891443350.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Too much junk in space can lead to a Kessler Effect, where we block ourselves off from further space travel

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kessler_syndrome</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891643797.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>That's only for low earth orbit if we toss our junk outside of earth's orbit there shouldn't be any problem</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891684926.0" user="Raja_Ampat" delta="False">
    <text>Correct but that is exactely what we're doing right now. Meaning there is a real scenario we never manage to get outside earth's orbit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891694095.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure in the future lasers will be more than powerful enough to vaporize trash in low earth orbit (hopefully)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891734210.0" user="Raja_Ampat" delta="False">
    <text>That is not going to happen, even the smallest particles can cause damage. Like shooting mosquitos while driving a formula 1 car</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891779691.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>No human aims high speed weaponry these days.  It's all done by computers which could calculate the timing to fire the laser</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892084911.0" user="Archi_balding" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is that lasers don't make things disapear. They melt them at best, so now you have partly melted space trash instead of space trash, still not something you want to hit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892803911.0" user="BoringIrrelevance" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying it would work but the idea is sublimation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893227179.0" user="Archi_balding" delta="False">
    <text>That would probably require so much energy that it becomes less efficient than other methods. Also we don't really know the effect of meeting clouds of metalic gasses at high speed. It could solve the problem, make it worse or have completely unexpected consequences (on the top of my head messing with our communications).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39893458339.0" user="BoringIrrelevance" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah I have no idea how to make it work, I just agree that turning it to liquid wouldn't help, would have to skip that phase</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891689250.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>The same thing could happen around the moon or other planets as well.

Earth is just the current, most pressing concern.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891702074.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>Hopefully by then we know to shoot our trash in the direction of the sun</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891725282.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>“Hopefully”

But that doesn’t mean it’s stupid to care about these problems now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891824249.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize that we are talking about having the ability to travel to other planets and then getting to the point where there is enough people to live on that planet to the point where they have enough garbage to completely cover said new planets low planet orbit.

That is literally hundreds if not thousands of years away especially considering that human population is expected to peak around 9.5 billion.  

By the time all of those conditions are met thousands of years in the future garbage won't even be a thought in the mind anymore</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891839226.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>If it’s not a problem, it will be because someone devoted the time and effort into solving it.

Problems don’t magically solve themselves, some human will have to design, build, and field a solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891861143.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>Sure somebody has to solve them but your hypothetical situation is thousands of years in the future.  There's no point in worrying about something that far off when neither you nor I can even comprehend what type of technology will have been invented by that point.

It's one thing to worry about problems that could arise within at least 300 years but anything more than that is a waste of time to even think about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892000264.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Useful scientific advancements come from thinking about hard and complex problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892109841.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but there is a natural progression to things.  A modern day scientist no matter how smart they may be cannot build a computer if he was transported back in time by 1000 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892800463.0" user="UNisopod" delta="False">
    <text>This is likely to just slingshot it into some other orbit unless it's done with very high precision, and I'm not sure we can really do that all the time for trash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39894675491.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>As long as it ain't in low earth orbit we should fine</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39894765294.0" user="UNisopod" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is that we'd have no idea where it would end up going at that point. Arbitrarily creating extremely high speed projectiles within the solar system isn't a great idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39896731048.0" user="cocksucker9001xX" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see it as a problem.  The space within our own solar system is so astronomically large we would never run into the trash again</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39892800998.0" user="UNisopod" delta="False">
    <text>This is likely to just slingshot it into some other orbit unless it's done with very high precision, and I'm not sure we can really do that all the time for trash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39894667907.0" user="InfectedGold" delta="False">
    <text>Thats not how orbit works. To simpliy excessively, we would have to spend a huge amount of energy to fight against the current orbit of our solar system to throw trash into the sun. That also means that trash we just leave floating would eventually settle into to orbit of our solar system, so it doesn't just disappear. So in the distant future if humans are a space fairing society that just leaves trash and debris everywhere it would eventually build up to become an issue in the same way we are currently creating an issue with garbage in orbit. It would take significantly longer but if we just stopped caring about leaving junk in space it would create an issue eventually without some form of clean up which would be extremely difficult at that scale.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
