<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39895266893.0" user="4D4850" delta="False">
    <text>Here is my point of view (I know this sort of stuff has been in other comments, but I feel it's worth posting): Trash ***in*** space is bad, but trash on celestial bodies in space is not bad. 

Trash is bad floating around in space because of *Kessler Syndrome*, which is the name for a possible event where orbital-speed debris impacts and turns into more debris, resulting in rockets being unable to safely go through or be in areas where Kessler Syndrome has occurred. Fortunately, this has not happened yet (and if people start caring, may never happen), but it is still too big a risk to leave stuff in orbit. As said in other posts, debris with a higher relative speed is more dangerous, which means that leaving debris in a solar orbit (**Especially** in a low solar orbit) is extremely dangerous, due to the fact that orbital velocity in solar orbit is much higher than in Earth orbit, and to change the eccentricity of an orbit (for simplicities sake, how much of an ellipse it is) by an equivalent amount will take much more delta-V, and therefore fuel, in a solar orbit than in an Earth orbit. The high cost of changing a solar orbit is also why we can't send trash into The Sun; It would take more delta-V than is needed to leave the solar system entirely, or it would require lots of precise gravity assists (The method the Parker Solar Probe is using to reach The Sun), which would require maintaining full control of the debris for several years, and a suitable window to do the gravity assists. 

However, leaving trash on other planets and moons isn't very detrimental because (despite what some may think) we aren't actually running out of room on Earth. When taking into account that high-density urban areas can expand horizontally and vertically, and that low-density suburbs can expand horizontally, combined with the fact that the current population of Earth standing shoulder to shoulder can fit in an area around the size of Rhode Island or Los Angeles, we have much more room to expand on Earth. When you take into account how many planets, moons, and asteroids are uninhabitable **and** are high in (at least potentially) valuable resources, it makes them much more useful as resource extraction sites and/or landfills.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
