<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39892025855.0" user="Ghostley92" delta="False">
    <text>I think this largely depends on what your bounds for “the environment” are and how you plan to exploit it. 

Being within Earths orbit presents more obvious responsibilities. If we “trash” this area, it will be that much harder to clean up when we likely need to leverage it more in the future, and it’s currently very hard or impossible to clean up. 

Going inside earths orbit (mercury/Venus) shouldn’t shouldn’t present many dangers to earth. 

However, going outside of earths orbit (mining the asteroid belt) should be taken very seriously. Every perturbation is an opportunity for a future extinction event. 

If we do plan on terraforming anything, I think it’s best to keep the mindset of sustainability first rather than exploitation. 

It’s not that we can’t or shouldn’t do these things. We just have a bad history of serving ourselves first without long term goals being understood or established. This can greatly affect many things, including us.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
