<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39892346773.0" user="Any-Smile-5341" delta="False">
    <text>Here is an idea, ( I’m taking it to the extreme here, I know) what if we trash the space surrounding our orbit so much we can no longer see the sun. Or the moon. 
There are many ways that this can make life in earth uninhabitable. [the ways in which the moon effects life on earth.](https://www.nhm.ac.uk/discover/how-does-the-moon-affect-life-on-earth.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39895738008.0" user="Neghbour" delta="False">
    <text>Someone did an analysis of the expense and carbon usage of using ultra thin foil sunshades in orbit around the earth to block two percent of sunlight, with the aim of offsetting global warming, and found it to cost quadrillions of dollars and put far more carbon into the atmosphere than we have in our entire history.

So if we manage to block out the sun with space junk, that would be a huge achievement and will have solved our current climate crises many times over.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
