<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39893552171.0" user="only_personal_thungs" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t disagree with your premise that it doesn’t matter if we exploit the fuck out of some asteroids for resources or whatever. I’d just like to clarify where the frustration comes from. A lot of people who are very interested in space are just disappointed that space travel and exploration has become so monetized. Space represents progress and a better future for people, it represents coming together as a species for a larger goal, so to think about it purely in terms of profit and maximum resource extraction is a little disappointing because people don’t like their interest in science and wonder about something amazing like space to be reduced to profits and similar things. 

We first sent people to the moon to learn more about it and try to figure out what it is and how it formed. To see us now mostly discussing space as just another avenue for resource extraction makes it much less fantastical and interesting and takes some of the wonder out of it I think. A few years ago a lot of people were so hype for Elon Musk to ‘get us to Mars’ but now those same people coming to terms with the fact that A) he was pretty much just bullshitting about it and B) Mars colonization would involve just as much discrimination and similar bullshit as the rest of the world which ruins it. The Cobalt Mines in space would likely be just as exploitative and fucked up as the ones on Earth. 

I pretty much said the same exact thing in like 4 different ways but there it is. Hope this makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39895133985.0" user="QuasarMaster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We first sent people to the moon to learn more about it and try to figure out what it is and how it formed. 

We sent people to the moon to flex our missile technology on the Soviets. Science was an afterthought, to the extent that out of all 12 men who landed on the Moon, only *one* was a trained scientist. And he was on the very last mission.

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harrison\_Schmitt](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harrison_Schmitt)

People view the Apollo program with rose-tinted glasses because most of the people that can actually remember it were kids at the time. The majority of Americans at the time were against it and wanted it cut from the federal budget.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
