<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39892251848.0" user="SvenTheHorrible" delta="False">
    <text>So 2 things. 

Orbiting trash is life threatening due to speed and if we continue to let China shoot up whatever garbage they want into orbit then eventually we won’t be able to get through it all into space. 

Once we’re in space- why the hell would we want to ditch anything? It costs an absolute fuck ton of money to put anything in space. We literally pay scientists at nasa to optimize the weight of shit so that we can bring a decent payload into space with every rocket- you honestly think that we can be irresponsible and bring shit we’re just going to toss? 

And the other thing- why would we want to remove matter from our planet? Our planet is more or less a closed system, we have a finite amount of resources in the dirt, and if you float them off into space they’re gone forever- not in a landfill that we might be able to recycle someday, gone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
