<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1895092580.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vcaesk/cmv_kill_la_kills_second_half_ruins_the_show/">
    <title>CMV: Kill La Kill's second half ruins the show (spoilers)</title>
    <original_poster>Candycoatedmuffin3</original_poster>
    <original_post>The high school setting was perfect. It helped keep things grounded (as much as you could), and really tied into the themes of control vs freedom. Satsuki and her student council showed some of the appeal of tight governmental control (fairness, awarding exceptionalism, etc) without ever fully condoning it, but you \*understand\* why people would follow her. Plus, you have the moments where you question if Ryuko is actually making things better, or risks just turning into another Satsuki, which tends to happen very often whenever a revolution happens.

But then you leave the school setting, and then they throw in aliens, and world domination, and the stupid twists and Satsuki's mom who is just the most evil parent in anime, seemingly for no reason. Like, come on! It was so good! Why did they throw it all away?!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39929615615.0" user="YouKnowWhatSnowBears" delta="False">
    <text>For depth and backstory?

Ryuko is looking for the person who killed her dad - the person with the other half of the scissor sword.  The first half hints at conspiracy.  The second half fleshes it out.

From the first half we know that Senketsu is special.  We know that the scissor sword is significant for its ability to cut Goku uniforms.  However, we don't know *why* any of that is significant, or why Ryuko's dad was killed.

The second half of Kill la Kill delves into the conspiracy that *Ryuko is trying to unravel* as it pertains to her dad.  Turns out he was trying to stop the enslavement of humanity.

It also gives Satsuki an actual character arc beyond "ruthless, meticulous authoritarian high school president."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
