<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39970144358.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think pride or celebrations have impact on kids feeling unnecessary guilt.

I *do* think there's a growing contingency of progressives whom practice a particular brand of grievance politics where *every* complicated issue is cast in this simplistic oppressor/oppressed narrative where the former is automatically evil and the later automatically virtuous - an I think that's *really* toxic and needs to stop.

But that brand of identity politics has nothing to do with celebrations or pride - you can have the parties without the bullshit virtue signaling.

Incidentally, while we don't celebrate 'white' we do celebrate many white sub ethnicities and nationalities. Like, St Patty's Day / Bastille Day / Oktoberfest and so forth are pretty widely celebrated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970181398.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I maybe shouldve tried to explain this better. I'm not saying the actual pride festivals themselves are anti anything. I'm not saying to stop them either. You maybe right where I am talking more about grievance politics combined with all of the other celebrations that brought me to this view.

As for the other holidays while the majority of their citizens are white its not a white holiday also we all know they aren't pride days more like a day to drink. I would throw cinco de mayo in that category also. Like you're just celebrating a holiday from another country</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970210778.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>I would suggest that St Patty's day is rather Irish Pride - try spending it in Chicago or Boston some day.

I suppose, but you're dedicating a lot of words in your post to celebrations (which I maintain are not a problem) but very few to the root issue of more toxic identity politics. I think if you made no call out to celebrations, and instead brought up problematic terminology or arguments I'd have a substantially harder time changing your view.

I think like feminism's adoption of the term "toxic masculinity", for example, is a better embodiment of the problem you're articulating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970269979.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>it's more of a holiday. I dont think you can compare them or put them on the same level as what im talking about. Its to observe the death of st Patrick. Either way, I know its celebrated on a massive scale i just dont think the meaning behind it compares. 

I dedicated alot of words to celebrations because I wanted to make sure people knew this wasnt an anti celebration or pro white pride post. I didnt make the comparison to toxic identity politics until you brought it up. 

I did bring up terminology though as the main catalyst to my view. The prides were brought up only because i feel like they would be the cause on why someone would ask the question and receive problematic terminology. 

I think alot of it is on display on this thread. You're the first person to actually address the question for what it is. I mean the guy at the bottom of this thread got down voted to hell for saying he does think negatively of himself for it and everyone else just dismissed the issue and wanted to talk about how oppressed other groups were or like some that white people and the world would be better off if they thought negatively of themselves</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
