<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39972822431.0" user="Different_Weekend817" delta="False">
    <text>no i don't think so. just because there is no official celebration for straight white men doesn't mean they need one for their self esteem; got too many role models in powerful positions. there are more CEOs named John in America than there are women CEOs. look at political, judges, law enforcement, bankers, for example, the vast majority are straight white men. that's far more influential than an annual parade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972946098.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not about having a straight pride day. It’s about the side effects of the other pride days/movements. They are moving from being about equality to equality or outcome and not only are you put to the back of the line as a straight white male as of right now people won’t even acknowledge it’s happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40104582801.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>So you want, what, gay pride to equally acknowledge straight people or to go away because gay marriage is legal nationwide or what</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
