<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39972791537.0" user="Altruistic_Spring883" delta="False">
    <text>If I understand you correctly you’re concerned that as movements like BLM and pride shine more light on the oppression these groups have historically faced, innocent children who took no part in this history will feel unfairly guilty for it. So is this what will happen? Let’s take a look where this has played out in other countries. In Germany post WW2 the Germans thought it was extremely important to educate children on the actions of their parents and grandparents. They teach about the Holocaust around age 9-10 and view it as their responsibility to never forget the actions they took as a nation. German children are able to cope with this reality, are American kids not as strong when it comes to slavery and oppression of minorities. We hear fear mongering stories on fox about children crying after learning about slavery, but we were all kids once who learned about slavery. I personally felt sad that my country took part in that but I never blamed myself. I don’t think we give kids enough credit they really can understand these complex histories without much issue. It seems its adults who take the most offense to the idea. At the end of the day we need adults who understand the historical struggles of these groups. Ignorance is never a good thing even if you’re attempting to protect your kid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972800344.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Nope you do not understand me right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972918933.0" user="Altruistic_Spring883" delta="False">
    <text>Well then I’m a little confused because you say you are not advocating for straight white pride day but you also aren’t advocating for an end to gay pride/ethnic celebration. Are you simply saying we need to pat boys on the back more and tell them it’s ok to be white and straight? Because you say you don’t want straight white celebrations but you also say that is the root of the shame kids are going to feel. Your argument almost has an undertone of “I do want straight white males to have a parade but I also know society at large thinks that is inappropriate.” I think you are pretty clearly stating that you believe kids feel upset straight white male pride is considered messed up but what is the solution you propose? If it’s kindly explaining to children the history of oppression as the root for why minorities celebrate things like Juneteenth or Pride that would be very constructive. I’m not sure what else there would be to advocate for in the framing of your argument besides my previous post about eliminating telling the history behind these celebrations</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972956373.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Ok let’s put it this way. Do you think white males are current at an advantage or disadvantage with college acceptance and hiring?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972980894.0" user="Altruistic_Spring883" delta="False">
    <text>I would say as a group quite an advantage. Of course there may be individuals that are in poverty/have significant disadvantages however white people as a demographic are wealthier, in better schools, have generational legacy status.  However what does this have to do with your argument?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39973107859.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>You would be wrong, you can get into college with far lower SAT scores if you’re black or Latino. You are more likely to get hired because of things like diversity hiring or the push for women in tech. You just had the president of the United States say when it becomes time to elect a scotus justice I’m going to appoint a black female. 

Whether you want to admit it or not it puts white males in the back seat for a lot of things and as time does on i think these things will escalate. 

This is what I’m talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39973135468.0" user="Altruistic_Spring883" delta="False">
    <text>So are you arguing society gives things to minorities that it doesn’t extend to straight white males. Because then you should change your title. That is a different argument than children are going to grow up being ashamed and thinking they are racist and we need to fix that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
