<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969844421.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't see what the serious concern is here unless you extrapolate trend lines in ways that don't make any sense. Like, rereading your post, it seems clear that you don't think there's necessarily a problem *now*, but you have to use phrases like "in the future" and "in time". But it's not at all clear that whatever future you're imagining will come to be.

And I think it's just really easy to focus on what is changing and lose sight of how straight white males are still *all over the place*  in positions of power, authority, respect and admiration. Straight white boys are in no shortage of role models! Like, I know this isn't something that you used as an example, but a lot of people hem and haw about "wokeness" in the marvel superhero craze, and complain about how's it's all Black Panther this and Captain Marvel that. But as of Infinity War / Endgame, three of the biggest MCU stars were straight white guys named Chris.

And post endgame, we've got Black Widow, Shang-Chi, and a super diverse cast in the Eternals (and I enjoyed all three). But there's also straight white spiderman, straight white doctor strange, and another straight white Thor coming up. I don't think straight white superheroes are going anywhere. But it's easy to *feel* like there's this massive shift.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969936320.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>lemme handle the marvel stuff first.

I dont think anyone hemmed and hawed about Black Panther. That was a good movie. Captain Marvel sucked though but i loved wonder woman and no one complained about that.

The hemming and hawing about black panther was any time someone had something to say about it you were being racist.

The movies are based on comics, in the comics they are mostly straight white guys. Maybe its because im straight but the fact that their straight never really crosses my mind nor does sexual preference in general when i meet someone or see a character on a show. 

liked black widow, havent seen shang chi, and cant stay awake through eternals. Theres also black spider man and female thor coming up and i think a black captain america.

I'm not against diverse characters.

I guess it more how you are treated in viewed for having any kind of negative opinion on this. Even now as a straight white guy i need to be careful of what i criticize, most of the time just like on reddit in this post i need to spend most of my time proving im not racist or w.e. and bringing it up to shut down marginalized groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971566319.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Maybe its because im straight but the fact that their straight never really crosses my mind nor does sexual preference in general when i meet someone or see a character on a show.

Yes! This here is my point. As long as this phenomenon continues to be true, I don't really see your fears of the future ever coming to fruition. Straight white men are going to continue to look out and the world and see a sea of role models that look like them. So much so that they don't even really think about it! The hope is that this is increasingly true of *everyone*.

&amp;gt; Even now as a straight white guy i need to be careful of what i criticize, most of the time just like on reddit in this post i need to spend most of my time proving im not racist or w.e. and bringing it up to shut down marginalized groups.

I think this is true, but a different phenomenon with different implications. Yes, you *should* be careful what you say. Being careful is better than being careless! But you don't need to spend time "proving you're not racist". I'm also a straight white male and I spend very little time trying to do that. If you feel compelled to spend "most of your time" on Reddit doing that, it might be worth examining why that is and how why you keep finding yourself in situations like that, because it is not a fundamental part of being a straight white guy on Reddit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
