<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39975035348.0" user="coporate" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with your line of reasoning, and I actually believe that the cognitive dissonance created by the conflicting messaging that young white males receive is exactly what drives them towards extremist groups (just like how gangs do the same thing). The onus is on them/us to develop spaces and outlets that encourage positive impacts.

If celebrating whiteness was associated with inclusivity and fun events as opposed to larping as a militant fascist and screaming racist epitaphs, then it wouldn’t be considered racist.

If celebrating straightness was about expressing a wide range of positive sexual behaviours between heterosexual couples instead of the rigid traditional gender roles which again align heavily with fascist ideology. Then people wouldn’t have problem with celebrating straightness. In fact pride is all about it, that’s why there’s such a huge kink/fetish aspect to the events.

And if celebrating masculinity was about honouring positive male role models in all forms and achievements instead of insulting anything that’s even slightly feminine, people wouldn’t consider it misogynistic.

The issue is that hetero-white-male identity has been co-opted by a large contingency of homophobic racist supremacists. And there’s another large group that’s happy to support that narrative. Unfortunately they’re both doing a great job of marketing their brands and entwining their ideologies with identity.

Imo, the best way to fix it is to decouple each of those attributes from one another and positively support them for their own merits. Support men as gay/straight/poc, support healthy heterosexual relationships, support healthy contributions made by white men and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975166353.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>So if you're saying what I think you're saying you run into a bit of a paradox as how do we create events etc. that will be seen as the positive things for those groups without changing the culture and how do we change the culture without stuff like them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975289112.0" user="coporate" delta="False">
    <text>Or, we just do our best to limit the influence of bad faith actors who wish to promote toxicity, and stoke division. Be that misandrists, misogynists, racists, homophobes, etc.

The issue comes from all sides, you need to admonish extreme positions of hate and superiority, regardless of who is saying it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
