<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39970036530.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.

Really not following the logic here.  How are these kids getting from "there's no straight pride month" to "I'm homophobic?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970058309.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that they are homophobic, its that it is seen as homophobic to ask about straight pride. Again i also dont want straight pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970076891.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, people get mad about "why's there no straight pride month?" because stupid people think it's some killer gotcha and so say it *all the time* if you don't shut that shit down.  People assume it's homophobic because it's almost always done in bad faith in online spaces.

If I nine year-old asked that question, or any given person to was trusted to legitimately be asking to learn new information, no one would think that's homophobic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970092594.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>its not about a nine year old. I dont think a nine year old can really grasp the really concept of gay and straight 

Sure people do but ive made it clear in my post that i dont want that or support it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971037854.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>And a 15 year old is plenty capable of understanding why circumstances demand a pride month but not a straight people month. When is there this window that somebody will be criticized for asking this question in good faith?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39974951491.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>The point is more that it shouldn't automatically be assumed that an adult asking for it is doing it in bad faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975218545.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Is there anybody that does this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975361189.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see why not. I think it would be a net positive for everyone to have an equivalent event for straight people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39973939711.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I dont think a nine year old can really grasp the really concept of gay and straight

This is obviously untrue.  "Some boys love other boys; some boys love girls" is something kids grasp way younger than nine.

Regardless, I don't think you're reacting to my actual point, here: no one thinks it's homophobic to genuinely ask why there isn't a straight pride month.  People think it's homophobic when it's presented as a bad-faith gotcha, which is something that people try to do online all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39973604427.0" user="Quintston" delta="False">
    <text>I have to say, I have only read about this “pride month” on Reddit, and mostly to mock it and to ridicule the concept of an entire month dedicated to it.

I have noticed noticed absolutely nothing of this “pride month” in my daily life, with no one discussing it, and no stores commercializing it. It seems more invisible than word animal day.

There are various so-proclaimed “days” and “months” for everything, whether they are actually picked up by the population at large is another matter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
