<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969649888.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>Straight white males, such as myself, could do with having a negative image of ourselves. It would be a precursor to having a image of ourselves that closer to the truth, than the entitled one we have now. The planet would be a better place for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969733081.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I really dont know any white person my age or at all who feels entitled because they are white</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969834489.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>Feeling entitled, being aware of entitlement, and being entitled, can be, and in most case are, mutually exclusive.

I am entitled whether I like it or not. I have not suffered any of the things which people with pride days have because I'm entitled.

I don't feel entitled, but I'm aware of my entitlement.

You will find that most straight (insert race, creed, or color) males, have similar entitlement within their various cultures.

Becoming aware of our entitlement, or more accurately I believe, being asked to become aware of it, is not an attack on our sex, gender, or whiteness, it's a byproduct of others becoming aware of it.

It is out of our control, which I believe is the motivation behind the right wings "war on wokeness", which brings the vicious circle to original position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970272456.0" user="JiEToy" delta="False">
    <text>As a white person, have you ever had to think about how being white will affect something in your life? And I don't mean in a discussion like this, but in real life, when you apply for a job or walk in the street or go shopping.

I sure haven't. The privilege that white people have, is their absence of race. We are human. When we see ourselves, and other white people, 'white' is never a defining factor. While a black or Asian or Hispanic person is first defined by their race.

This makes life inherently easier for the white person. The absence of race means that we aren't discriminated against when applying for a job, we aren't profiled by police, people don't group us with the rest of the people of our race and have their prejudices ready. We can dress to express who we are. If a black man puts on a suit, they aren't just a businessman, they are a black businessman. And it's even likely that people think of that man as black first, and businessman second.

So no, white people don't feel entitled, because we never have to think about our whiteness, because it's never used as a defining factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970327702.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt; As a white person, have you ever had to think about how being white will  
 affect something in your life? And I don't mean in a discussion like   
this, but in real life, when you apply for a job or walk in the street   
or go shopping.

I have, i work in recruiting, i know being a straight white male is not seen as an attractive hire and they will most likely choose a diversity candidate over me if its a close race. I've seen this happen at companies as well. Most large corporations have almost every minority group over represented compared to the population and in some cases ridiculously over represented when it comes to how many people of that group are qualified in that role compared to others. Not saying its right or wrong but I definitely have. There have been time also where ive had to think about being white when certain subjects are being discussed because even though I know im not being racist my view point will be taken that way because of the color of my skin.

I really don't see what you're describing in America any more. Black people are accepted to college with lower sat score than those of other races. We cant dress to express who we are, i have to take into account dress code, or how i will be viewed by what im wearing. 

As far as being grouped by race or seen as a black business man I mean that's kind of whats being pushed by them. no one even say business man anymore. Being proud to be black and the collective black community isn't something white people enforce. 

Idk where people get these ideas that its like that now or that white people never have to think about their race. It's like when black people bring up how they are taught how to act when they get pulled over as if my white parents didnt have that some talk with me (yes sir, no sir, my reg is in the glove box do you mind if i open it, keys on the dash etc)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970417216.0" user="JiEToy" delta="False">
    <text>I really think you're overvaluing conscious decisions over unconscious biases. Yeah sure, when two candidates are equal, recruiters might choose the diverse candidate. But as a black person, to get equal to the white person, you'll have to be better.

For instance, it has been proven countless times that when sending a resume with a black sounding name, you have a much lower chance of being picked than when sending the exact same resume with a white sounding name. This is not because recruiters read resumes and cross the check mark of which skin color the name sounds like. It's not a rational process, for most it's not even a conscious process. But reading a black name activates the rather negative stereotype that people have of black people, and then reading the resume attached to that negative stereotype simply makes the resume 'feel' worse, that it would've with a white stereotype.

&amp;gt; It's like when black people bring up how they are taught how to act when they get pulled over as if my white parents didnt have that some talk with me (yes sir, no sir, my reg is in the glove box do you mind if i open it, keys on the dash etc)

So a black person would have a different talk than just 'be nice and listen to the officer'. A black mother to her child will tell her child to listen, yes. But they will also tell their child to preemptively show their hands, keep their hands out of their pockets, etc. They will tell their kids to not take their wallet out of a pocket without carefully telling the officer they are doing so.

The difference is that you can expect that the officer respects you as a citizen, as a human. But a black person has a good chance to meet an officer that sees them as a threat, as a criminal, even before they have any reason to. So a simple traffic stop can be completely different when it involves a white person or a black person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971273845.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't all the research into hiring say you are wrong. Heck, nearly every minority group has higher unemployment rates than white people. 

How could they be over represented in hiring?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971390810.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I said over represented in major companies so unemployment rate doesn't really matter.

Over represented has to do with a demographics of qualified people for that vs the demographics of people working that job. Like you cant say latins are under represented in software engineers because they only make up 20% of people in software engineering but 40% of the country because there may only be enough latin people interested in that industry to pursue a career in it based off personal choice.

Every company is pushing diversity hiring right now. The only way to push diversity hiring is to give preferential treatment to diversity candidates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971462597.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Black college graduate unemployment is twice as high as the college graduate unemployment rate.

https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/05/african-americans-with-college-degrees-are-twice-as-likely-to-be-unemployed-as-other-graduates/430971/

It seems like once we start looking at more higher qualified groups, the disparity persists. Do you have data supporting your conclusion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971504654.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>one again college graduate does not mean they made the right choice in degree and two that article is with data from 2013</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971643372.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>A) I have one from 2017 confirming that (while you don't have data supporting your position)

https://www.stlouisfed.org/on-the-economy/2017/february/why-unemployment-rates-vary-races-ethnicity

B) So now we have two levels of detail supporting that disparity. Without data, it seems illogical to conclude that the disparity is going to switch for more specific majors. It is more reasonable to deduce that the disparity is not going to flip when controlling for other majors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971715754.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>In this context, don't you have to assume that *all* the white people did make the right choice in degree in order to be doing so much better than black college graduates? Choices in degree doesn't account for that level of disparity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971854851.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>No it doesnt mean all. You can easily look up that black people arent choosing to pursue degrees in stem fields any where near as much as their counter parts. Also the more recent study he posted showed like a 3.8% white and like 5% black unemployment rate for people with a college degree. So idk what to tell you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975181865.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>If it's easy to look up, why not provide your source here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975205584.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>https://theconversation.com/amp/computer-science-jobs-pay-well-and-are-growing-fast-why-are-they-out-of-reach-for-so-many-of-americas-students-150419</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975370364.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>"These disparities do not begin when a student steps onto a college campus and chooses a major." 

Then the person argues for a series of measures to make it easier for Latino and Black students to succeed in this area in high school, acknowledging that they are structurally alienated. He's not saying Black and Latino kids are missing out on this field due to their own individual choices. This article doesn't support your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975414570.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>That’s his opinion and he also does say it’s systemic racism. 

The data does say this though. Out of all of the students receiving computer science degrees 8.9% were black. At google 9.4% of the tech team was black and at apple it was a mix of 14% black and Latino. So only 8.9% of computer science graduate were black but hold a higher percentage of googles tech team. So it’s pretty hard to argue discrimination there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975462959.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>This is not a response to the point I originally made, which was about the context of Black college students' choices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975494176.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>No it doesnt say more students wanted to but weren’t able to. It gave the percentage who chose that major and the professor was giving out ways he wanted to encourage for black kids to take up computer science. It wasn’t that those were the only qualified black kids for that degree, there just isn’t an interest at this time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975983036.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>He wants to encourage groups that are *institutionally discouraged*. People think that they're just not interested but it's much more complex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976009097.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Omg whatever. Everything is much more complex than that when it comes to stuff like this. We’re also acting like all black males are in poverty and not how the majority of the black population lives above the poverty line where they have access to good schools where they are institutionally encouraged.


Bottom line is those are the amount of people who choose to go into software development.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41065805141.0" user="seedless01" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;in a general sense not saying people who immigrated from Jamaica or Africa by traditional means aren't celebrated.White people as a whole in a particular part of the world don't have this kinda of experie

Young women are uncomfortable working with white men.  It's easier for a woman to get a job because women are seen as more trustworthy than men. Childcare , nursing , and the corporate world all apply here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971734119.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>I am a white person who jaywalks, and my assumption that this won't be used as a pretext to harass me is a form of entitlement. We see this all the time when white people are mistreated by law enforcement -  white people are especially shocked by stuff POC have come to expect as normal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971778240.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>no we dont its just not reported on. Around the same time as george floyd cops did the same exact thing to a white guy who actually called the cops on himself because he was having a nervous break down.

You are also comparing how black people are treated by cops in predominantly black neighborhoods with high crime rates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975177749.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying white people aren't murdered by cops, I know of a few who have been. But the overall culture of never breaking a tiny rule because you are expecting cops to seize any opportunity is not evenly applied across ethnic groups. White parents don't counsel their children to avoid police violence the way Black parents do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975194970.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Yes they do. I was given the talk on how to act when pulled over. Ask if i can reach in the glove box, keys on the dash, yes sir no sir. Its something you should teach your kids, I’ve gotten out of way more tickets for being compliant than I’ve seen people get out of for being disrespectful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975343457.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>I've had this conversation with many people, not a single white person I know was ever given the same instructions to be hypervigilant because of cops targeting them. My parents said nothing to us because they took for granted that we wouldn't be targeted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975349145.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Your parents never taught you how to act when you got pulled over?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975414214.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>There is a massive difference between being told how to interact with a cop when you get pulled over, and being taught at 9 or 10 that you need to be extremely careful around police, with absolutely no minor violations like jaywalking or loitering. 

Even in the context of driving, my parents did not teach me to be super careful about reaching into the glove compartment, lest a cop think I was reaching for a gun. They basically said 'you'll have to show license and registration, if you get a ticket you have to do x y and z to pay it.' The idea that a cop might target me for unfair reasons was totally inconceivable to my parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41065814637.0" user="seedless01" delta="False">
    <text>I have no empathy for anyone who gets pulled over by the police. I cant afford to drive a vehicle, it's a huge waste and pissing away of money . Unless you are making over 80k a year it's not worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970333530.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that throwing other people with your demographic, who have lower self-esteem under the bus and setting them up for mental health and identity issues? People generally say this to win some sort of social praise or admiration from liberal/leftist circles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970414261.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>No. I'm as far left as most people are likely to encounter, but I still think kids need a healthy dose of reality to toughen then up a bit and prepare them for the real world. like a vaccine against future mental health issues.

And they need truth, so they can understand why we (S-W-M) are not the world heroes we like to portray ourselves as, and teaching them imperial history at school, were all the bad shit is conveniently omitted (UK at least) is not a way to treat our children, it is simply lying to them for the sake of nationalism. It adds to their confusion when they meet and converse with people in possession of truth and facts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970540213.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think having a negative self image of oneself is ever a reason that someone would commit suicide?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970711944.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and those people have mental health issues way beyond the scope of \*Pride celebrations.

A negative image of the controlled society that SWM have engineered over hundreds of years, is essential to personal image an mental health.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970744492.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>I mean given this:

&amp;gt; Straight white males, such as myself, could do with having a negative image of ourselves.

and 

&amp;gt; No. I'm as far left as most people are likely to encounter

And this being the internet, it's really not likely at all that you are who you say you are. 

But you should know that when you say you are super far left and that white people should feel bad about themselves, you've played into the hands of the right wing. Most likely this is either a right-wing trolling tactic, or a person who really is on the far left devoid of human empathy or self awareness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970884992.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>I wish my empathy was less than it is, I feel other people's pain and joy as though via telepathy.

But I'm not concerned about whether or not someone on the internet believes me when I describe an attribute of my ego.

But I appreciate your analysis nonetheless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970932565.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>But, you've said that you think certain people (numbering in the millions or hundreds of millions) deserve a lower self esteem, even though you'd admitted this would increase their risk of suicide.

If millions of people followed your advice had low self image based on immutable characteristics, a certain percentage of them would obviously commit suicide.

If this were serious, it would actually indicate an immense LACK of empathy.

Is your point of view common, or at least widely accepted in your social group?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971125633.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>I never said anything of the sort. you've twisted what I said, and even added stuff to them.

For that reason alone.. Over and Out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971133908.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>"I've been beaten, and in saving face I will add one last reply which contains no information."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971143491.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>You:

&amp;gt;Straight white males, such as myself, could do with having a negative image of ourselves

Those are *your words*.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Do you think having a negative self image of oneself is ever a reason that someone would commit suicide?

Also you:

&amp;gt; Yes, and those people have mental health issues way beyond the scope of *Pride celebrations.

There's no twisting here. This is what you straight up said in plain language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971100610.0" user="Gagarin1961" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	But you should know that when you say you are super far left and that white people should feel bad about themselves, you’ve played into the hands of the right wing.

“Playing into their hands” makes it sound like this is plan they devised. In reality, right wing people bring it up because these radicals *do* exist and, as you found out today, they are not ashamed to tell you straight up that **they want to attack peoples self esteem based on race**. 

If a right wing groups were whispering about that, we’d see it all over Reddit all the time. It’s only when the shoe is on the other foot is it framed as “a trap.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971159727.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>This exchange has admittedly been disturbing, but it's a consolation to me that it's now up here in plain language for everyone to see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40813964671.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40815189282.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>That's dynamite.

Print yourself a medal for participation, so you can feel good about yourself just like all the other kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40815208786.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40815287184.0" user="eltegs" delta="False">
    <text>Let me guess, reddit generated username.

Say something funny, or this is my last engagement.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
