<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39971357248.0" user="Chairman_of_the_Pool" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you feel these celebrations are exclusive and not inclusive?  are You banned from attending any of the these events?  Are you afraid to go?  Are you completely uninterested in learning about other cultures?

let’s say we have a straight white male pride month.  Exactly what would be occurring that month that doesn’t usually occur?  Extra focus on straight white male history?  Introducing your community to straight white male pastimes, hobbies, cuisine, art, because it has so often overlooked?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971397145.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i never said they aren't inclusive i also said i do not want straight pride month. Its literally the first two bullet points I wrote</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972213352.0" user="Chairman_of_the_Pool" delta="False">
    <text>What could possibly change your view?

&amp;gt;If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic)

what is white?  Northern European ancestry?  I live in the US, and there are plenty of events celebrating those heritages.  Being straight, there are plenty of places to mingle with women, and show public displays of affection without judgement.  Male - you can celebrate your maleness anywhere you like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972322986.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What could possibly change your view?

Honestly?

If a few people would have at least acknowledged that being a straight white male is currently seen as a negative view or that straight white males have been increasingly looked over for the sake of equality of outcome. It probably wouldve changed my view because atleast people are aware.

I made a list to make sure that people knew this wasn't about canceling pride or the need for pride or importance of it or pushing for straight white pride. It's literally all people focused on. One person understood what i meant an tied it to toxic identity politics. I mean one dude literally said he already felt negatively about himself for it and he got downvoted till the comment was hidden.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
