<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969775813.0" user="Archaea-a87" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're saying conceptually, but I don't think there is any evidence that is happening or will happen. For one thing, it is quite easy to explain why pride celebrations exist for other groups and not for white, cis males. Pride celebrations are about recognizing and appreciating groups that have been/are marginalized. They are not an attack on white, cis men; at least I have never seen them as such. 

As the mother of a very curious and inquisitive 9 year old (white, seemingly cis male) boy, I have had many a conversation about the celebrations and months that honor various groups. I have never needed to use the word "misogyny" or "racism" in any way that he felt was directed at him personally, nor do I believe he has ever been left with the impression that these celebrations take anything away from him or are a negative reflection on his self worth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40434836253.0" user="Time_Most_8895" delta="False">
    <text>There’s no attack on straight white males? Is that a joke?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40434977321.0" user="Archaea-a87" delta="False">
    <text>Well, my comment was specifically in regards to pride celebrations, holidays, etc. that recognize marginalized groups and in that regard, I do not see it as an attack on straight, white males. Do you disagree with that part or are there other things that you see as an attack on this demographic? It's not a topic that I have invested a whole lot of time or energy into, so I would be curious to learn what other perspectives are. For me, social justice issues do not seem to pose a significant concern, especially in comparison to current global, economic and public health matters. As a cis, white female, I don't think my perspective and experience is super relevant to the conversation, whether I agree or disagree with the trajectory.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
