<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969600231.0" user="jazzorhashzzz" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda like how minorities and blacks have been socially sabotaged since they were enslaved here in the usa. We still havent fixed that issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969609546.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>idk how it relates or what you are trying to prove with this comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969680619.0" user="jazzorhashzzz" delta="False">
    <text>What i am trying to say is there are people in our society that have been feeling sad and insecure about who they are and what society says about them for hundreds of years….. we still havent helped them get over it. 

White people and families , statistically speaking are better off economically and have many role models to look at. If they are feeling depressed from words from the liberal media. 

Idk what to say bud.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969711446.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely think we are taking steps to help that. We're on a holiday right now just recently established helping that. 

Also regardless of that knowing its a problem why would you want anyone else to experience it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969731133.0" user="jazzorhashzzz" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is laws were made against blacks, asians, latinos, lgbtq+ community. 

Not whites, there is no anti white issue in america. America is mostly white, if anyone is hating on whites its other whites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969739533.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>again i already said I get why those months are there and im not arguing that they shouldnt be or that I want a white, straight, or male month</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969858111.0" user="jazzorhashzzz" delta="False">
    <text>Bruh.  A pride day aint going to to do shit when generations of minorities have been sabotaged economically and socially. 

That hasnt happened to whites which is why I disagree with your points and hope you change your view.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
