<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969738745.0" user="BeBackInASchmeck" delta="False">
    <text>White, Straight and Male are mainly not being celebrated because they're the status quo.  In general, people don't have an instinctual fear or doubt of straight, white males.  At least, not in a rational way.  If you see what you consider a "typical" straight, white male on the street, you aren't concerned that they will harm you.  If you are in business and you encounter a straight, white make, you might not immediately, and prejudicially, assume that he is incapable, dishonest, or incompetent.  However, many people across many different backgrounds will have prejudices against people who aren't straigth, white males.  Of course, they might not publicly vocalizes these prejudices, but they are certainly thinking about it.

When people have "pride" or "heritage" months, on the surface, sure they are meant to celebrate those people.  But at the core, these months are meant to help curb some of the prejudices that these people encounter, often unknowingly, throughout their lives.  They're also meant to shine a light on the really fucked up things that people did to them throughout history.  It really is a pity party.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969776345.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not arguing for white straight males to be celebrated. I said in my post i understand why groups are and why groups arent. Just because I feel that way though doesnt mean it could have that affect on certain groups in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969861913.0" user="BeBackInASchmeck" delta="False">
    <text>But you're trying to suggest that there will be a disproportionate surge of straight, white male children with identity issues in the future because these other children are being celebrated.  In reality, those other children are being celebrated mainly out of pity, and it shouldn't be that difficult for straight, while males to rationalize that.

This really is no different to the trends over the past decade of how kids with disabilities have been getting voted as homecoming and prom kings and queens.  Back in the day, only the most popular and attractive students won.  The popular and attractive kids of today aren't thinking negatively of themselves for not winning those award.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975071507.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>But being gay, black or a woman is not a disability. That's the whole point. It can't be about pity because there is nothing wrong with those things in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975003773.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>Not being discriminated against is not the same as actually being celebrated, though. It's in this sense that those groups could end up feeling left out.

It's true that those events are also meant to fight prejudice, but that's because of the world we live in. Ultimately, what they really should be about is celebrating the thing itself. It's like Mother's Day and Father's Day. It would make no sense to say we should stop celebrating Father's Day because there is no discrimnation associated to it. It's just not what it's about.

Also hard disagree on you calling those things a "pity party". It sounds extremely condescending, and is the very opposite of what they are meant to be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
