<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969757228.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>My family is from the southern Louisiana.

extended family gets together every year to boil a bunch of crawfish.

as a white individual, why would I celebrate my vague "whiteness" instead of my cajun roots?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969766161.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i dont want whiteness to be celebrated. did you read my post at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969792330.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>you're saying that white heterosexual men will feel left out because they won't have a celebration of their heritage.

I'm saying, as a white guy, that my culture heritage is cajun, not merely white people in general.  that kids can celebrate their heritage without celebrating whiteness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969809959.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>No, and this is the problem with reddit. I'm saying in the future as celebrations like this grow and grow i believe children not men will start to think negatively of themselves not because they arent celebrated but because of why they arent celebrated. I am also a white heterosexual man and none of this affects me at all this is just an opinion ive been playing around with in my head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969821803.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>have you considered that your perception of the trajectory of where the celebrations are headed is flawed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969841128.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I mean its possible but they have historically been growing. I haven't seen a movement by a marginalized group ever say "ok were good now". I also dont mind if they continue to grow. This isnt about stop progress for straight while males of the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971054150.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  haven't seen a movement by a marginalized group ever say "ok were good now"

Irish and Italian people in the US. Left handed people. The disabled, to some degree. Catholics.

Why would women, black people, or gay people say "okay we are good now" when all three groups obviously have not achieved equality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971076801.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying women, black, and gay people have not achieved equality in a country that has had a black president, black female vice president, and a gay guy who is the CEO of one of the largest tech companies in the world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971155883.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. And this is evidenced by distributions in outcomes across major institutions like education, medicine, policing, justice, and careers as well as by legislation in a number of states that specifically targets gay people and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971238677.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Equality of outcome isn't equality. You cant say because this group is underrepresented here that must be due to oppression. You are not legally allowed to discriminate against anyone due to their race, religion, gender, or sexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971407117.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You cant say because this group is underrepresented here that must be due to oppression.

That's true. Fortunately, academics don't stop here. 

&amp;gt; You are not legally allowed to discriminate against anyone due to their race, religion, gender, or sexuality.

First of all, for sexuality, this has only been federally true for a couple of years. But more importantly, this is not the bar for actual equality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971493826.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that its only been it hasnt been that long but its still here now. 

As far as the law goes equality has been reached. If you are talking about equality within the eyes of society I can see that but i dont think you achieve that through pride, like you cant say you want to be looked at and treated like everyone else while not acting like everyone else. I dont bash or condone ending pride stuff because its not my place but i do hold the opinion that it is hurting people of that community being seen the same as everyone else. Samuel Jackson say similar things about black history month</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971646345.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If you are talking about equality within the eyes of society I can see that but i dont think you achieve that through pride

You literally achieve it through activism. There is no other mechanism to achieve it.

&amp;gt; Samuel Jackson say similar things about black history month

Jackson is not the God of black people. He is not a historian, or a sociologist, or a politician, or a community activist. He is an actor who happens to be black. Why would you take his opinion as valid over the opinions of the many people who disagree with him?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971734340.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>You don't achieve social acceptance through activism. Activism helps get you the rights and laws you need to make sure you aren't discriminated against. Italian, irish, asian, even latin people to a pretty large extent all gained social acceptance just through living not activism. There still hasnt been an Italian president. In reality outside of (lgbt) because that is kind of new the ones people say are discriminated against the most are the ones still pushing activism. Anything you push for after equal rights start a dangerous game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972590646.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Italian, irish, asian, even latin people to a pretty large extent all gained social acceptance just through living not activism. 

This is not an accurate understanding of history.

&amp;gt; Anything you push for after equal rights start a dangerous game.

Should black people have stopped everything after 1964? Or in 1868, when the Constitution provided equal rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972691567.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Probably some where in between it being federally illegal to discriminate against them and before asking for preferential treatment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39983858688.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>And when were they asking for preferential treatment? The first time they started asking for something white people had by default?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39983872909.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Affirmative action.

You can’t punish white people now for something they had nothing to do with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971051291.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Is your view honestly "thing X is going to cause serious problems but we shouldn't do anything about it?" Everybody is assuming that you want to take some sort of action because it makes little sense for your post to not advocate for some change.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
