<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969568846.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969632282.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>Don't let people talk down to you and make you feel bad about your race.  It's literally racism, and those hating on 'straight white men' are genuine racists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970115235.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>stuff like this is the reason for my view</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970173735.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I have noticed such negative thoughts and feelings about myself due to pride culture 

Do you get similar feelings when other cultures hold their cultures pride day?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970279453.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;constant negative association with being straight, white and male.

Who's is constantly telling you these things are bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970378392.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly when is the last time you heard anyone say you should be proud to be any of those things and if someone did how fast were they labeled a racist? White people in America as a whole are blamed for slavery when the vast majority of white Americans living here came to this country well after slavery. I mean as a white straight male i am responsible for the atrocities of all of the straight white men before me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970426002.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I mean as a white straight male i am responsible for the atrocities of all of the straight white men before me.

This is your interpretation. I'm a straight white male from Britain. I don't take any responsibility for the actions of people who came before me. I'm quite happy that anyone who tells me I should is being an idiot. That doesn't stop me from accepting that the British empire did horrific things. It's in your power to feel the same.

Edit: why do you *need* to feel pride in being a straight, white male? The common factor in gay pride, etc is that those groups have been oppression for centuries. Pride is a direct response to that oppression. Straight white men have almost always been the ones in power in Europe for millenia and in countries they colonised for hundreds of years. I haven't had to overcome being white *or* straight *or* male.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970431469.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>come to america its not that way. I also dont feel shame because i know i wasnt responsible for this stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970479288.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>I'd be very surprised if that's the real life experience of most straight white men as they go about their daily lives. 

It may have more to do with the bubble you are in and the media you consume or maybe that's affecting my view too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970518204.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I mean i wouldnt say its a daily thing but you would be mistaken if you thought i didnt have to think about my sex, race, or sexual preference before commenting on something. Also if youre in disagreement with something about race how white straight males have always ruled the world its time for xyz to have a chance as if I was running the world</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970594564.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>We often have to consider the best way to comment. I had to think just now on an email to a partner organisation about how I phrased an email. That had nothing to do with gender, race, etc but just how best to communicate my point. I think we would have better communication all round if we did think about how our experiences have shaped our view.

&amp;gt;Also if youre in disagreement with something about race how white straight males have always ruled the world its time for xyz to have a chance as if I was running the world

I'm really not clear on what you're saying here. I'm not interested in the race, gender or sexuality of the people in charge as long as they're the right people. Huge numbers of people have historically been denied that opportunity based on things they haven't had any power over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970642191.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>im not talking about effective communication. i'm talking about me have to think about my race gender etc before commenting on something or whether or not im allowed to. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

On the job thing for example we can use the new scotus justice. Biden specifically said we would only appoint a black female. To say it is wrong to only take people of a certain race and gender into consideration as a white person you are automatically racist and you should be ok with it because white men yada yada. Then if you questioned her experience at all even if it were about prior rulings and such that was also racist. I dont care if he did nominate a black women as long as he took all other candidates into consideration and she was the most qualified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971036181.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Major_Banana3014 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Major_Banana3014&amp;amp;message=Major_Banana3014%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/-/id0ukpa/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
