<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39971014298.0" user="Mantismanta" delta="False">
    <text>I can see some children getting confused about the lack of white male events. I hope their adults can help them understand they have nothing to be ashamed about. As a society, we are trying to lift those communities that have been oppressed for all our history. Everyone is supposed to join in the celebration. One hypothetical that may help these young kids: Imagine 100 years from now - applicants who are ethnic minorities, gay, female get chosen for jobs, housing over white men. And white men on average make 75 cents to the dollar compared to other groups. White men fear that groups within law enforcement will assume the worst because of the color of their skin. Over generations, the loss in potential wealth has affected their neighborhoods in visible ways. Members of their own group will try to pass as gay or a minority to avoid discrimination. At that point, a healthy society should find ways to lift them up and hold celebrations and events for white men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971058781.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>minorities are already being chosen over white men for jobs. They are over represented in almost every major corporation and the push for diversity hiring continues, black and Latinos get into college with lower sat scores asians are actually most discriminated against here, the president of the united states of america was allowed to campaign on saying he will put a black female in the scotus, the 75cent on a dollar thing is bs you cant accurately measure that stat the only think you can do is combined all incomes of a group, average it and compare which only proves collectively white people make more not that the make more for the same job, a gay dude is the ceo of apple.

There has to come a time when people start recognize this, its not the 60s anymore. We keep pushing this narrative that minorities are facing some crazy oppression and no one is doing anything about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971125985.0" user="Mantismanta" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; minorities are already being chosen over white &amp;gt; men for jobs. 

Do you have a source for this? My source says otherwise: https://www.umass.edu/employmentequity/race-states-and-mixed-fate-white-men

I think we hear a lot in the news when the bias is overcome or reversed, say with elite college admissions. 

&amp;gt; the 75cent on a dollar thing 

Well that was a hypothetical, but it is close: 

https://www.stlouisfed.org/on-the-economy/2020/september/taking-closer-look-marital-status-earnings-gap

&amp;gt; a gay dude is the ceo of apple.

I can find anecdotes of white straight males being CEOs too. 

&amp;gt; We keep pushing this narrative that minorities &amp;gt; are facing some crazy oppression

So there it is. What do the facts say? Is oppression still real or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971186733.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Your source is references data from a 2016 report which means the data is from 2015. Look at demographics of major tech companies and then look at the demographics of qualified applicants

well yea why would anyone be ok with bias?

The wage gap wasnt close because again it is just showing overall earnings not earnings for the same job at the same company.

I'm sure you can. im not saying there isnt straight white males that are CEOs im saying its hard to say people are being oppressed for being gay when you have a gay ceo for one of the largest tech companies in the world.

The facts say there is no law that allows for discrimination of any kind in any part of society. A black person has been president, black female vp (in fact a black female vp before a female white or any other race vp). Anything else that being pushed is for equality of outcome</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975074536.0" user="Mantismanta" delta="False">
    <text>I’d love to see a link to sources of the assertion that discrimination against traditionally disadvantaged minorities is not happening, or that anything has changed since my source was published in 2016. 

Claiming that one black person being president means the end of systemic discrimination against black people in the workforce is logically false and proven by this same source from 2016, published 2 and 6 years after a majority of voters (not Americans) elected him president. By extension, one gay ceo of a major tech company doesn’t mean gay people in general face less discrimination in society either. 

So is it really that you don’t agree with celebrating these minorities because you don’t feel they are at any disadvantage? Your concern for young white boys is beside the fact?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975160939.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Idk how you can prove discrimination in the work force. There are laws against discrimination. What else do you want. Go through what percentage of black people who graduates with a college degree majored in computer science and then compare that to the demographics of software engineers at that company?

You have no actual evidence of discrimination you just take a birds eye view snap shot of some stat and twist into what you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39979712097.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>You could try to demonstrate that anything meaningful has changed since 2015. It’s not valid to discard a study demonstrating discrimination by saying ‘nah things must have changed since then.’</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39979855337.0" user="zimbabwe7878" delta="False">
    <text>If you are using the election of a black president as part of your point how do you feel about electing someone who openly questioned that president's citizenship as the next president? Surely there are still some barriers that aren't codified into laws but still affect the lives of minority groups.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
