<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39976072312.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>Well we can’t celebrate everyone. Pride month is celebrating people who have had to deal with discrimination.

So we can’t give a cookie to everyone. Straight white males had all of history to be praised and they still are. 

What is your solution to this? Take away pride or add straight pride because you said no to both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976088423.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>Keep pride, keep black history month, no white history month. Stop treating them as oppressed groups</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976142960.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>So keep things the way that they are BUT lie and say they have never been and are never oppressed? I mean just take a look at the hate crime stats to see that lgbtq people are in fact still oppressed. Not to the extent that they were before of course but just because things got better doesn’t mean they’re where they should be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976147965.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I never said anything about them being oppressed in the past but idk where they are oppressed today</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976162117.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>Again look at the hate crime stats. Look at parents kicking their kids out for not being straight. Look at people making fun of other people. Look at countries where they literally will kill you for being gay. Look at the fact gay people couldn’t get married until recently and they still have a harder time adopting than straight couples. Look at churches shunning gay members.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976241785.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t get how hate crime stats (don’t by citizens where know race or gender is left out), parents kicking their kids out, or getting made fun of means you’re oppressed. Or that labeling yourself as oppressed will some how fix it.

Sure countries where you can get killed for being gay they are oppressed. Doesn’t mean you need to classify them as oppressed here.

They can get married now so we’re good there. Adopting a child i again don’t know how that makes them oppressed or how it’s would help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976532770.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>Dude it doesn’t matter what race or gender you are if you commit a hate crime against gay people lol 

Are you saying that absolutely nobody is oppressed in the US?

“Oppression [is] the social act of placing restrictions on an individual group, or institution.”

Social not legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976595024.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>There are anti white hate crimes does that mean we’re oppressed? Like literally there are hate crimes for every group imaginable. 

Honestly by that definition no. I don’t think as a society we place restrictions on individual groups or institution. Sure there will be one off douche bags but that will never stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976604215.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>So are you gay or black? Have you experienced these things? I knew someone not too long ago who was literally kicked out of their school for being trans. How is that not oppressive? The school got away with it because they said she wasn’t wearing the boy’s uniform not because she was trans specifically but because she wore the girls uniform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39976648548.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>See now you’re moving the goal post. 

You don’t have to be gay or black to see oppression against them.  Now sure you can pop off some anecdotal evidence but everyone can do that.

Did the they kick them out because they walked in the next day and said I’m another gender or was it because they wouldn’t let them use the bathrooms or locker rooms they wanted to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977029219.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>I just told you why they were kicked out. They wore the girl’s uniform instead of the boys and when they asked why and she said she is trans they said too bad you have to dress like a boy. She wore the girl’s uniform again the next day and begged them to reconsider with notes from her therapist but they said no and then expelled her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977047681.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I mean idk if she handled it right just showing up one day a new gender if it is as you say though they can sue the school. Thats how it works</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977472381.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not how it works lol. Private schools don’t have to let you wear the uniform you want. They will tell you to go to public school. I was almost kicked out of the same school years prior because of my depression. They said my work in poetry class was too sad and would ruin the other students’ moods. I didn’t write anything violent or scary. They said if I don’t sign an agreement to have a therapist then I will be expelled. They even made me do my therapy sessions in the school’s band room lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977692310.0" user="Dell-Monoco" delta="False">
    <text>So who exactly is doing that to gay people and trans people? Placing restrictions on them I mean? I’m not I bet OP isn’t and I’m sure ur not so who then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39980181369.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>Society as a whole. Just because some people don’t doesn’t mean everyone doesn’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39980311397.0" user="Dell-Monoco" delta="False">
    <text>Well yea not all of any race or demographic of people are gonna be all one way or believe the same that’s low IQ thinking…so you say society is oppressing some minority groups right? Meaning the people in that society are actively looking to oppress or are oppressing minority groups…is that correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981018103.0" user="abbaabbaaa" delta="False">
    <text>I’m saying some groups are being oppressed. It may not be actively done but it does happen. Even classes can be oppressed. People in a lower income bracket can be oppressed too. It’s not specific to anyone one single person. Also as a world as a whole it’s impossible to deny women and lgbtq people are oppressed. Just because the states are better in general about it doesn’t mean people should just forget about people in other countries. Those ideologies can not only spread but can cause lots of violence and death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981032620.0" user="Dell-Monoco" delta="False">
    <text>Can’t argue with that…thank you I appreciate you explaining it I was just trying to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
