<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969624972.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a straight white male teen myself and frankly nobody serious is saying that they hate all men or white people or whatever. You'll notice that these kinds of movements are always targeting specific things like specific expression of racism or whatever. Never "white people" in general. I used to live in one of the most blue states in one of the most blue cities in the nation and I never once felt that I was racist or homophobic or misogynistic or anything of that nature. I don't see why other people having a pride month would mean I start hating myself. It makes no sense.

I don't need to be actively validated since I'm essentially the default in most of society/pop culture already, while black/gay people have only recently gained equal rights and societal acceptance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969650301.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>im not saying any movements are targeting white people in a negative way at all. Like i dont think the movements advocate for this i more see it as a product of so many different movements.

Anecdotal evidence doesn't really prove anything while i'm happy you dont feel that way there is someone in the comments who does. I am also referencing more to the future as I feel like celebrations are becoming more and more mainstream.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39979678824.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>In the US, the status quo is and has been to celebrate and vindicate whiteness. White people hold most of the economic and political power in modern American society, and have dominated social norms for the vast majority of American history. There’s a good quote that applies here: 

&amp;gt;	When you’re accustomed to privilege, equality feels like persecution

The view you’ve expressed here fits this idea to the letter. White people, and especially children, probably will start to feel more and more like they don’t occupy a privileged position in American society. They will think of themselves ‘more negatively’ than white people of past generations, but *that’s a good thing* because they should think of themselves as equal to people of other races and ethnicities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39988876991.0" user="abrahamthejew" delta="False">
    <text>This implies that white CHILDREN are walking around thinking  “ yeah look at all these n-words in my class..god I’m better I will have a better career and just generally I have a higher social standing” nah dude they’re thinking it’s pb&amp;amp;jj day in 2nd grade. Whaat people like you don’t understand is every white person and especially child DONT think of themselves as better than anyone. What you imply is the in ability to see exception.

You lump all white people into a pattern of behavior. That’s the definition of racism. 

By making children hyper aware of racial issues younger you are setting them up to see color, the constant emphasis on RACE RACE RACE allll the time is going to create racists. Especially when you tell the little white boy who’s never done anything in his life yet. That he is somehow bad (because that’s how a child will interpret this) and celebrate minority races….you don’t think that could end badly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41065263114.0" user="seedless01" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Anecdotal evidence doesn't really prove anything while i'm happy you dont feel that way there is someone in the comm

All that matters are median figures. Asian people have significantly higher incomes and net worths than white men. Especially if you look at the under 35 age range. 

A poor white man will never become wealthy. Every single wealthy white man had parents who were wealthy or had serious connections.

Companies view white men as a liability due to the fact that many young women are woke and uncomfortable working around white men.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

A</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972242237.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don’t need to be actively validated

The fact that you think this shows the negative effects of this kind of culture. Being actively validated is a fundamental need.

Negative perceptions of yourself can exist without you knowing it an you have just proved that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972346219.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>I should have said actively validated by society for my race/identity. I can get validation from my grades/parents/grandparents/friends/etc. I don't need a giant parade celebrating whiteness for me to be happy and I think I know my perceptions of myself more then you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972545104.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>My point still stands. Take an example of siblings. If all siblings but one are constantly validated, the one sibling will develop shame around himself. Likewise with any aspect of identity such as race, sexuality etc. 

I have no doubt you can be happy without white race parades. That is not my point, nor am I advocating for it. My point is that people can have negative views about themselves without them even being aware of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977464272.0" user="heighhosilver" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't white men constantly being validated? They hold most of the levers of power in government and business. If you've always been the golden child and everyone knows it and your sibling now gets praised one month out of the year and ignored for the rest of the year, do you really collapse because your parents don't shout your virtues from the rooftops all the time?

It's such a fragile mindset.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39980423527.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>You are confusing a tiny minority of white men with all white men. I am also not saying that white men never have been validated; that is obviously false. 

It depends on the individual of course. But the culture around progressive social justice in the modern age will and already have caused more shame for individuals from these groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39980988631.0" user="heighhosilver" delta="False">
    <text>Asking them to acknowledge that minorities haven't been recognized as much for their contributions or that there has been harm to minorities based on structural racism and asking for meaningful change isn't shaming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981148097.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>No, of course it isn’t shaming. But a culture that celebrates most races, genders and sexuality except your own is one that *will* cause shame in the excluded groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981193911.0" user="heighhosilver" delta="False">
    <text>They get celebrated all the time! We don't need a white man's month because they hold all the power and celebrate themselves. They are overwhelmingly present at the highest echelons of government, business, and even culture. White male actors are pretty much the standard for Hollywood. Look at those Most Beautiful Men lists and it's overwhelmingly white men. White men by dint of being in the highest level of government get to set the rules for everybody. White men also are overwhelmingly in leadership in big companies and their voices are usually the loudest in society. 

Celebrating minorities is just to highlight their contribution and to remind society as a whole they exist because they can't get recognition for the other 11 months. Geez. Just let minorities have something without worrying about how a white man's ego might be hurt because he doesn't get a month too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981288641.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you are confusing a *tiny* percentage of white men with *all* white men. Most white men are not actors or in positions of government. Most white men are just average people. 

You do bring up a good point that a majority of actors/people who hold power being white may contribute to validation in a sense, I don’t disagree with this. However, whether or not that compares to a complete lack of celebration otherwise that borders on *blaming* an entire race/gender for injustices is something else entirely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981348651.0" user="heighhosilver" delta="False">
    <text>Women's History Month's alter ego isn't "Anti-White Men's Month". Same for all other months celebrating minorities. The only ones who see a month celebrating women or other minorities as simultaneously blaming white men that are the small amount of white men whose egos are more easily bruised than an overripe peach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981455699.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>I am simply saying that the mainstream narrative can and does cause shame around being white, male, and straight. Nothing more, nothing less. You can’t call that having a fragile ego without saying humanity in general has a fragile ego (which I wouldn’t actually disagree with).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39982077607.0" user="heighhosilver" delta="False">
    <text>Fine. Let's say it's shaming for them because you won't let this go. If these white straight men feel such shame, the best way to get rid of it is to be an ally and to advocate for changes to racist, sexist policies instead of whining that they're being shamed. Maybe some introspection about how they could make things better for those who are less powerful and less visible can help them take their attention off their wounded ego and more on helping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39982157264.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>I agree on the introspective part, however I would say it is important to be introspective to understand how negative self-perceptions you have of yourself may have been imposed on you by society. 

Why must you say things like “wounded ego?” Feeling shameful about who you are because of society has nothing to do with that. I mean, isn’t that what pride and equal rights is fighting against? You wouldn’t call that having a fragile ego, would you?

It seems like when I say white men are being shamed, you go further and think I am talking about white men that complain, are against equal rights etc. That is not what I mean. Quite the opposite. Most white, straight men who do feel shame because of those things are likely quite unaware that they do. This is coupled with the fact that a lot of shame can come from what *isn’t* done, rather than direct shaming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975114757.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>straight white men have been actively validated since the beginning of time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39980431619.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>In American culture? Yes. But that doesn’t count as “since the beginning of time,” lol. Nor does it mean that it can’t take a turn to be the opposite in the modern age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981065642.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text> no it doesnt mean that it cant change but it hasent and currently still is happening</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981155881.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>What are you talking about? That’s exactly what mainstream culture is right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981733950.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>is that why white people dont face systematic racism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39981872929.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Why does everyone assume I’m saying something I am not? I am simply saying that the mainstream narrative can and does cause shame around being white, male, and straight. Nothing more, nothing less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39982466698.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>if white people dont face systematic racism than no they do not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39982720111.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Systemic racism is not negative self image imposed by society lol, it’s much worse than that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39983701324.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>if something is imposed by society its systematic which doesnt happen to white and male people regardless of if you call it racism or not which is irrelevant because again, there is no societal negative belief. white straight males are the ones given the most positive view in society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39984057637.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>You’re just playing with words at this point. I’m saying that mainstream views can and do cause shame in people who are straight, white, and male of varying degrees. Whether or not that’s considered systemic, I do not care.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39985175069.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>youre the one playing with words, something being mainstream in society is literally what societal means and would be considered as. im sure you dont care because it weakens your argument, but saying you dont care about my counterargument doesnt suddently make you right and what i said irrelevant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39987195023.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument was that societal=systemic, and systemic can’t equal shaming white people. You’re argument is purely semantic and has not logically proven anything.

I am not saying I don’t care about your counter argument. I have pointing out that your counter argument is just forcing me into certain words and definitions. I said I don’t care about whether or not you label my point as being “systemic,” because it is not relevant to my argument.

You’re saying white people can’t be shamed because it would be systemic racism. And systemic racism can’t happen against white people. Therefore, white people can’t be shamed.

It’s circular reasoning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39988709993.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>what do you think systematic means? it literal means societal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39988845276.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so why is it impossible for mainstream societal norms to cause shame in straight, white men?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39990027970.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>it isnt impossible, it just isnt happening. it being possible or not is irrelevant, your point is that its happening</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39990052439.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Cool. You say it isn’t happening, I disagree, because I have observed it and have inducted reasons and ways that it is happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39990221522.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>great but anecdotes arent proof or evidence so youre welcome to actually provide real proof of it happening on a societal level</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39990284266.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>Anecdotal evidence in this context is not insignificant, especially since you denied it happens at all. 

Furthering: the underlying tone of mainstream views on social problems is that white, straight, and men are to blame. It is far from unreasonable to conclude that this will cause shame in those groups at a societal level. This is my proof. 

Funny how you ask me for proof, yet provide none yourself except to say “it isn’t happening.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39991806118.0" user="Long-Rate-445" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Anecdotal evidence in this context is not insignificant, especially since you denied it happens at all. 

except im saying its not societal and/or systematic so anecdotal evicence is exactly the type of evidence that is insignificant as there is a very specific method of determining in statatistics if samples represent populations and arent biased or have mitigating variables. 

and further, straight white men claiming they feel shame does not mean that it actually happens. privileged group feel like they are being oppressed and harmed as they lose privileges and things become more equal. their shame is most likely based in ignorance and wanting attention like actual oppressed groups get to address and end that oppression. it says absolutly nothing about society or views towards men

&amp;gt;Furthering: the underlying tone of mainstream views on social problems is that white, straight, and men are to blame

prove this, because like i just said, reducing your privileges and making things more equal while acknowledging the systematic oppression their group causes another group isnt saying you "are to blame" or victimizing you. you just think it is, which is why annecdotal evidence is useless

&amp;gt;It is far from unreasonable to conclude that this will cause shame in those groups at a societal level. This is my proof.

your opinion is the exact opposite of what proof is. youre free to link an actual scientific article. your entire argument so far is just your feelings



&amp;gt;Funny how you ask me for proof, yet provide none yourself except to say “it isn’t happening.”

whats funny is that you just gave your feelings and called it proof and then act like im a hypocrite for not providing evidence either when you are the one who made the claim. it is not my responsibility to research and disprove your claim for you. if you make a hypothesis in science, it is just a guess and is not true until evidence is found that supports it. you dont get to just say random things based on your feelings and act like its true unless people disprove it.

i hope one day men like you stop victimizing yourself for no reason, its just a waste of emotional labor</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39992519538.0" user="Major_Banana3014" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;their shame is most likely based in ignorance and wanting attention

You realize **you just agreed with me** here, right? You refer to "their shame." 

&amp;gt;prove this

The proof is in how mainstream progressive societal views treat straights, whites, and men as if they are a/the problem. This is done by generalized statements such as "whites oppress minorities," "men oppress women," etc. It is enough to shame, but little enough so that said groups are *also* gaslit about it (your stance would be a good example of this if my thesis were true, for example).

I will completely disregard your claims of my lack of evidence, since you have completely failed to refute my points and even further provided zero evidence of your own. You just say that I'm wrong, that isn't evidence.

&amp;gt;if you make a hypothesis in science, it is just a guess and is not true until evidence is found that supports it.

This statement is incorrect, because you are confusing epistemic means with ontological reality. This means that a theory or fact didn't "become true" when we discovered it, the only thing that changed was our knowledge of it. 

It is hilarious that you expect my thesis to have been made a full-fledged scientific theory before it can be considered as truth. Nobody, not even reputable scientists, does *or even can* take this approach when trying to figure out what is true for themselves, let alone a **reddit thread** lmao.

My evidence is more than anecdotal, I have given my reason and examples. That is proof. Either **respond directly to my points** by telling me where I made a logical or observational error, or do not reply.

Besides, anecdotal evidence is how people form most of their views. You have views about the world based on anecdotal evidence. Everybody does. Evidence is not necessarily wrong or false because it is anecdotal, and this does not help your case.

&amp;gt;whats funny is that you just gave your feelings and called it proof

This is not true. I gave my observations, and my reasoning. There is a big line between that and giving my feelings. 

What even is your point? First you flat out said that societal shaming of straight, white men simply does not happen. Now, you said they are shamed, and that makes them ignorant and attention seeking. 

**I will not reply** unless you **make clear what your stance is and where you disagree with me,** as well as **point out the direct flaws in my reasoning.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41249265441.0" user="Icy_Elevator_7886" delta="False">
    <text>This guy can't back up what he is saying with evidence, you are providing him with evidence and he refutes it, typical feminazi bs. They are traitors to true feminists who believe in equality and don't wish to create another "archy".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41249252904.0" user="Icy_Elevator_7886" delta="False">
    <text>Irish people face it everyday in multiple countries</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41249241418.0" user="Icy_Elevator_7886" delta="False">
    <text>I'm half Irish and the Irish men have been oppressed for centuries!

Serbians and Armenians as well!

Check your history and your bigotry</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
