<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969959519.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>Do St Patrick's day celebrations cause non-Irish people to feel bad about themselves? Huge numbers of non-Irish people join in and far as I can tell the only problem they have is the hangover the next day.

Who is being left out? There's nothing stopping you from ~~taking part~~ attending ~~in~~ a pride parade. 

&amp;gt;If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic).

Because many people who ask that aren't being sincere. It's a common dog whistle used by conservatives agitators. They know these events happen as a response to centuries of oppression but they want to stir up negative feelings to further their agenda. It's not Pride and similar events that are causing the negativity. It's the right wing propaganda telling their audience that *they* are now the ones being persecuted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969994356.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt; Do St Patrick's day celebrations cause non-Irish people to feel bad   
about themselves? Huge numbers of non-Irish people join in and far as I   
can tell the only problem they have is the hangover the next day.

We all know in america st paddy's is just an excuse to go get hammered. It's like cinco de mayo. 99% of people dont know why they are celebrating it but know its an excuse to drink.

See its only things brought up by white straight males and what relates to them that can immediately be denounced. This post is proof, most of it i am trying to explain even though i wrote it above that this isnt an attack on any prides or that i want any prides. If a black person brings up a black issue you cant denounce it or label it as something derogatory or you will be considered racist and that goes for all the other groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970061429.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We all know in america st paddy's is just an excuse to go get hammered.

And why should Pride be any different? It's a celebration. Nobody is stopping you from joining in.

&amp;gt;See its only things brought up by white straight males and what relates to them that can immediately be denounced. This post is proof, most of it i am trying to explain even though i wrote it above that this isnt an attack on any prides or that i want any prides.

Are you really complaining about having your views challenged on a sub called "Change My View"? I never once said you were attacking pride events.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970082135.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>You aren't challenging my view though. You brought up people supporting pride as if you couldnt support pride at the same time almost like people with white guilt. Then you basically said anyone who does feel this way is a racist or looking for a way out. You're talking about white people as if we either support pride or we are some authoritarian racists who are worried about preserving white dominance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970134964.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You brought up people supporting pride as if you couldnt support pride at the same time almost like people with white guilt.

I'm not even sure what you're trying to say here with the "white guilt" bit. I brought up supporting pride because you were saying straight, white men are being left out:

&amp;gt;Not only is it the only group of people left out of this

You have a choice to join in these celebrations or not. Nobody is excluding you.

&amp;gt;Then you basically said anyone who does feel this way is a racist or looking for a way out.

No I didn't. I complained about conservative commentators.

&amp;gt;You're talking about white people as if we either support pride or we are some authoritarian racists who are worried about preserving white dominance.

I never said that but I would question why people wouldn't support a pride event. They may have legitimate reasons, just like I'm sure some people have legitimate reasons to not support a St Patrick's day parade. They may of course just be prejudiced. Are you denying that racists and homophobes do object to these parades and use "white pride" and "straight pride" as a rallying cry?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970222864.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I think you some how got part of an answer from another comment with the white guilt thing.

I support pride events to the extent that i dont want them cancelled. I have a gay brother who doesnt want to be associate with pride or the gay community but i guess thats his thing.

I'm not denying that racists have used straight pride and such as a rally cry, i would also that some people who arent racist have brought it up to prove a point when talking about getting rid of them. You may think thats racist but Samuel l Jackson is an opponent of black history month. My step brother of pride. So if people within those groups can feel that way there isnt any reason a person outside of that group can come to the same conclusion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970274340.0" user="karmacarmelon" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying people can't question these events. You stated:

&amp;gt; If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic).

I responded to give a reason why people get frustrated with questions like "why isn't there straight pride". It's too often been used by the cynically manipulative to sow division. If someone sincerely asked me that, I would give them a sincere answer, but all too often it's a loaded question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970345518.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>It would be racist. Im not denying that it wouldnt be. Having a day or month dedicated to the accomplishments and pride of being a straight white male would at least seem racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970336981.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Samuel l Jackson is an opponent of black history month

We know why Jackson isn’t a fan of Black History Month and it has nothing to do with how it makes non-black Americans feel</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970352804.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i understand that and im not saying that's why he feels that way. My stepbrother doesnt dislike pride for how it makes straight people feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39977616690.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39994581350.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Dell-Monoco – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Dell-Monoco&amp;amp;message=Dell-Monoco%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/-/id5n2gi/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
