<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969656140.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>Your conclusion is wrong because the answers to your questions are wrong.  We don't have a "white heritage day" but there are still plenty of celebrations of *specific*  European ancestries and cultures.  St. Patrick's Day (Ireland) and Oktoberfest (Germany) are two in particular, but there are events celebrating Italian American heritage,  like [Feast of St. Joseph parades](https://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/03/18/519987433/move-over-st-patrick-st-josephs-feast-is-when-italians-parade#:~:text=In%20the%20early%201970s%2C%20the,came%20out%2C%22%20says%20Fonte.) And in small towns in the Midwest you can probably find events where people celebrate their Norwegian, Swedish, or Polish heritage.

As for heterosexuality, Keep in mind that homosexuality only became widely accepted less than 15 years ago.  Barack Obama didn't endorse gay marriage in his 2008 campaign because it was believed to be too far left/polarizing for the average American voter.  Trans people have only been accepted for less than 10 years.  Even then, there are still a broad group of people that rail against LGBT issues, so it's very hard to believe a "straight pride"  event as a sincere/earnest celebration of one's personal identity, without any homophobic undertones.

I think you could make a similar argument for celebrating maleness.  It would be very hard to organize something without bringing out the most toxic elements of men's communities out of the woodwork.  MRA, TPR, incels, MGTOW, etc.

As far as having s negative self image, as s straight white male, i don't associate my personal identity with slaveowners, wifebeaters, or lynchmobs.  Sure, *other* straight white men may have done those things, but I can only control and only be held accountable for my own actions.  I can also recognize the privileges i have being born to two caring parents who raised me in a stable middle class home where we always had food, electricity and heat, and money wasn't a huge issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969685966.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;our conclusion is wrong because the answers to your questions are wrong.  We don't have a "white heritage day" but there are still plenty of celebrations of   
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;specific  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;  European ancestries and cultures.  St. Patrick's Day (Ireland) and Oktoberfest (Germany) are two in particular, but there are events celebrating Italian American heritage,  like   
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Feast of St. Joseph parades  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt; And in small towns in the Midwest you can probably find events where people celebrate their Norwegian, Swedish, or Polish heritage.

There arent that many people who still have their full European ancestry blood intact nor are either of these really a celebration of nationality.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I dont want a straight pride even at all. I dont want any straight white or male pride events. I'm not arguing for that at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971540912.0" user="murderousbudgie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There arent that many people who still have their full European ancestry blood intact

What's the relevance of this? Why would it be illegitimate for someone to celebrate part of their ancestry even if they're mixed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971593809.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>the relevance is as time goes on we arent going to associate with a European country any more. I already dont actually know how many different european countries my ancestors came from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971612431.0" user="murderousbudgie" delta="False">
    <text>So what would a celebration of "white" culture, divorced from any particular European ethnicity, look like to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971643207.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i think in either the first or second bullet point i posted I said i dont want a celebration of white culture. I just don't want being a straight white male to grow to be looked at more than it already is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971668025.0" user="murderousbudgie" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? If you're not homophobic or racist or a misogynist, nobody's looking at you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971865026.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>If a straight white male says biden openly campaigning on electing a black woman for the scotus is discriminatory and wrong you will be called a racist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971874162.0" user="murderousbudgie" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying it's his actions that cause the judgment, not his identity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971891313.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>no because a black person saying it wouldnt be called racist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39972124109.0" user="murderousbudgie" delta="False">
    <text>Really? Pretty sure people are coming down on Candace Owens and Hershel Walker for that reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39983837346.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>And if you-as-in-OP meant a liberal black person it's because there'd be a shared group identity so they wouldn't be seen as speaking from an outside perspective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975169413.0" user="xXCisWhiteSniperXx" delta="False">
    <text>As a white guy, maybe just get a thicker skin about people saying your opinion is racist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975180658.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I mean i don’t care. Racist is thrown around so casually it’s losing its weight anyway. It’s just more about the direction we’re headed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971720406.0" user="C0smicoccurence" delta="False">
    <text>However, your point rested firmly on the idea that celebrating non straight white male things is going to have a negative impact on said youth.

The point is that there are already a bunch of holidays and celebrations that revolve around white culture.  Since you didn't address those as presumably damaging to people of color, it really feels like there's a disconnect in your ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39975137351.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Your conclusion is wrong because the answers to your questions are wrong. We don't have a "white heritage day" but there are still plenty of celebrations of specific European ancestries and cultures. St. Patrick's Day (Ireland) and Oktoberfest (Germany) are two in particular, but there are events celebrating Italian American heritage, like Feast of St. Joseph parades And in small towns in the Midwest you can probably find events where people celebrate their Norwegian, Swedish, or Polish heritage.

And if more black people knew their specific heritage we'd have less-if-not-no need for general "black heritage" stuff</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
