<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969912084.0" user="Responsible_Will_819" delta="False">
    <text>Historically and presently speaking, straight White men have responded to the push for equality with derision rather than self-hatred (or even appropriate reflection). So I don't think there's grounds for your worry on a broad scale.

Sure, there are individual men who choose to have a "whelp, guess I'll just die!" attitude in lieu of doing the bare minimum, but that's because this provides them with an out. They don't have to take responsibility for their beliefs and actions if they can tell themselves they're being bullied into it. Furthermore, if they equate social equality with self-hatred and social inequality with self-love, I think that says a lot about who they think has a right to dominate society. That's exactly the kind of oppressive attitude that renders their so called "self-hatred" unsympathetic. For them, the only real form of self-respect is backed by absolute power.

As far as children go, raising them with humility and empathy along with an understanding of basic power dynamics should prevent them growing into people like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970044057.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Historically and presently speaking, straight White men have responded to the push for equality with derision rather than self-hatred (or even appropriate reflection). So I don't think there's grounds for your worry on a broad scale.

It's not about supporting other groups its also not about associating equality with self hatred. 

In a small way its almost about your response. I asked you about the effect it could have in the future and someone feeling negatively about themselves, stated i dont want to hinder celebrations, said nothing about stopping or slowing the progress of these groups. All you've done is dismissed it, any then applied any self hatred they may have to their want for social dominance or acting that way to have an out. I dont know any white people talking about white people as a group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970150503.0" user="Responsible_Will_819" delta="False">
    <text>If that's what you took from what I wrote then it's clear to me you lack the necessary historical and sociological context for this conversation. Not a sin--just read up on it. Have a good night.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
