<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969685249.0" user="doireallywannadothis" delta="False">
    <text>Here's the thing:  Kids aren't dumb.  They can smell propaganda a mile away.  Moreover, young people don't watch much TV anymore; they get their entertainment online, and they're pretty good at filtering out advertisements and other unwanted propaganda.

So about all those celebratory months for this or that demographic... kids just don't give a shit.  I haven't asked my teenage kids, but I'm pretty sure they're vaguely aware "pride month" is a thing but they've totally tuned it out.

My older son has a few gay/lesbian friends.  I'm pretty sure they don't give a shit about pride month either.  Like I said, they can smell propaganda a mile away.

So why would it affect them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969723553.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i find it hard to believe they are vaguely aware of pride month. Also i get that some kids dont give a shit. This isnt really about know but more about the future as things evolve. It becomes a bigger and bigger deal every year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969786760.0" user="doireallywannadothis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This isnt really about know but more about the future as things evolve. It becomes a bigger and bigger deal every year.

There's no reason to expect current trends will continue.  Trends come and go, right?  They're shaped largely by demographic and economic circumstances.

The economy is going to be getting worse for awhile.  Eventually, that will force businesses (and hopefully universities?) to trim some fat and operate more efficiently.  Who do you think will be the first to go?  Engineers and accountants, or DEI officers?  In other words, as conditions get more difficult, in order to survive, firms will have to revert to stuff that's actually productive.  

You know the saying: good times lead to soft men; soft men lead to bad times; bad times lead to tough men; tough men lead to good times.

All the good times (i.e. lots of economic surplus) have led to grifters squabbling to grab as much as they can.  When times get rough, they won't last, and we'll see big cultural shifts in a more pragmatic direction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40104574488.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Then why not force the economy into so much of a downswing no one's ever woke again but they can't get too tough or times get so good the grifters crop up again</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
