<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1901912554.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/cmv_straight_white_males_mostly_children_will/">
    <title>CMV: Straight white males mostly children will think negatively of themselves in the future and we should try to combat it sooner than later.</title>
    <original_poster>7he_Devils_Adv0cate</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me begin with a few things

1. this isn't me looking or justifying the start of any kind of white, straight, or male pride day

2. this isnt me trying to cancel any pride day or month

3. please dont try to convince me of why your pride day or month is important or needed. I understand them and why they were created, etc.

I think that's it for the beginning. I just want to make it clear im not attacking any of that.

As prides and celebrations start to grow and become for celebrated I can't help but feel like it will become a problem for straight white males in the future. Not only is it the only group of people left out of this (which again I dont want it) its more about what you are told when you ask why it isn't. If you ask why being white isnt celebrated (its racist), straight (homophobic), male (misogynistic). So i think in time as kids start to ask why they have nothing like that and are told why they will automatically start seeing themselves as racist, homophobic, misogynists through no fault of their own and will then have a negative image of themselves.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39969587719.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969614696.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>and you wanted to share that here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969656155.0" user="johnly81" delta="False">
    <text>[Analogy Examples With Simple Explanations](https://examples.yourdictionary.com/analogy-ex.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969662188.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971030373.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/7he_Devils_Adv0cate – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%207he_Devils_Adv0cate&amp;amp;message=7he_Devils_Adv0cate%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/-/id0wkq4/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969685943.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>The point being, diversity is diversity. Another group losing some market supremacy doesn't make it bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969695758.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I dont care about market diversity this has nothing to do with that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969739120.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>But you do care about it. Even if you don't want pride gone, you're resenting the increase of celebrations for other groups as if it causes a lack for your own group (I assume) but it's just celebrations trending back towards equality.

We still have states and nations attacking homosexuality so that team needs support, but none of that makes being straight a bad thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969761795.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>I am not resenting celebrations nor do i want them cancelled, as i said in my post, I am also not someone who feels negativity about myself. This isnt about me. This is a view i have formed from observation.

You need to put your personal feelings aside to understand this. You havent even addressed my view point once.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969775939.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>I said "even if you don't want pride gone."

And I did address it. We still have states and nations attacking homosexuality so that team needs support, but none of that makes being straight a bad thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969785136.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>im not saying the efforts of the gay community make being straight a gay thing and i dont resent what they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969903444.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>Then you have a broken path between the current day and how someone will end up thinking negatively in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39969960365.0" user="7he_Devils_Adv0cate" delta="False">
    <text>i do not. It doesn't live in a vacuum. There are unintentional effects to everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39970418039.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>No,  I mean I don't get how you get from a to b. You're saying you have no issue with pride events and don't want them gone and agree that doesn't make white cis straight to be bad, but somehow that becomes negative feelings in the future?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39971035066.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Kakamile – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20Kakamile&amp;amp;message=Kakamile%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/vgcl4a/-/id0uz9j/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
