<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1909216941.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vkp57x/cmv_josé_mourinhos_playing_style_and_tactics/">
    <title>CMV: José Mourinhos playing style and tactics aren’t boring and they need to be more appreciated.</title>
    <original_poster>Noerig15</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do often here that Mourinhos tactics are boring, but I do actually enjoy to watch his teams play football.

Mourinho are a football genius in my opinion and I think that people should appreciate him and his tactics more.

I enjoy watching his teams because they counter attacks like no other teams and they have a solid defence.

I enjoy his teams fantastic counter attacks because the main goal in football is to score more goals than the other and why would you use unnecessary much passes that doesn’t lead to anything to score like most managers do when you can score within 5 or 6 passes. 

I do also like Mourinhos tactics because when they counter attack most of the opposing players are on Mourinhos teams half and therefore Mourinhos teams can come to great chances easy.

My dream is to become a football manager and one of my “role models” in the footballing world is Mourinho.

I don’t know what could change my view but I would like to have a conversation about it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40014543108.0" user="daveSavesAgain" delta="False">
    <text>Mate, forget the results for a minute.
 
If you are a football fan, you are there to enjoy football.
 
Liverpool lost the 2021-22 UCL final, and Roma won UECL.
 
For same football, if the results were reversed; Roma fans would have been much more devastated in the hypothetical scenario than Liverpool fans in real life.
 
Also, if you speak about trophies, then you are against OP’s arguments, as any team has only 4 - 6 games a season, where an actual trophy can be lifted.
 
For the rest 38-50 games a season, Mourinho-ball can be described as *enduring* at best.
 
PS: That being said, the best ever counter-attacking (exciting to many) was developed by Mourinho at Real Madrid in 2012, with Khedira, Alonso, Ozil, Di Maria, Ronaldo and Benzema / Higuain as the front six.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40014599863.0" user="Noerig15" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, I think Mourinho is an amazing manager!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
