<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1909216941.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vkp57x/cmv_josé_mourinhos_playing_style_and_tactics/">
    <title>CMV: José Mourinhos playing style and tactics aren’t boring and they need to be more appreciated.</title>
    <original_poster>Noerig15</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do often here that Mourinhos tactics are boring, but I do actually enjoy to watch his teams play football.

Mourinho are a football genius in my opinion and I think that people should appreciate him and his tactics more.

I enjoy watching his teams because they counter attacks like no other teams and they have a solid defence.

I enjoy his teams fantastic counter attacks because the main goal in football is to score more goals than the other and why would you use unnecessary much passes that doesn’t lead to anything to score like most managers do when you can score within 5 or 6 passes. 

I do also like Mourinhos tactics because when they counter attack most of the opposing players are on Mourinhos teams half and therefore Mourinhos teams can come to great chances easy.

My dream is to become a football manager and one of my “role models” in the footballing world is Mourinho.

I don’t know what could change my view but I would like to have a conversation about it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40012685704.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>As a Spurs fan, I absolutely hated watching us under Jose. I love a well organized defense and I love the beauty of a counter attack. What I hated was the constant pressure on the backline. So many times we would get an early lead and then had to absorb pressure all match. Eventually the defense gave in to pressure and we would lose the lead or even the match. I dreaded the start of the second half because of the inevitable collapse. 

One of the reasons counter attacking football can be so exciting and effective is because the other team gets desperate when they go down and it can open things up for more counters. But with Jose, opponents learned they could stay disciplined and put our backline under constant pressure and get a result from a losing position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40012701883.0" user="Noerig15" delta="False">
    <text>you got a great point. As you say the counter attack is beautiful and I do still think he and his tactics isn’t appreciated enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40012801729.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I’d say that his tactics are appropriately appreciated. He was great but his tactics have been found out a bit. He needs to have more variety in attack and not be so reliant on just countering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40012841544.0" user="Noerig15" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, I agree that he needs more variety but it’s definitely not boring to watch his teams play in my opinion! he is one of the greatest ever in my opinion!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
