<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1909216941.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vkp57x/cmv_josé_mourinhos_playing_style_and_tactics/">
    <title>CMV: José Mourinhos playing style and tactics aren’t boring and they need to be more appreciated.</title>
    <original_poster>Noerig15</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do often here that Mourinhos tactics are boring, but I do actually enjoy to watch his teams play football.

Mourinho are a football genius in my opinion and I think that people should appreciate him and his tactics more.

I enjoy watching his teams because they counter attacks like no other teams and they have a solid defence.

I enjoy his teams fantastic counter attacks because the main goal in football is to score more goals than the other and why would you use unnecessary much passes that doesn’t lead to anything to score like most managers do when you can score within 5 or 6 passes. 

I do also like Mourinhos tactics because when they counter attack most of the opposing players are on Mourinhos teams half and therefore Mourinhos teams can come to great chances easy.

My dream is to become a football manager and one of my “role models” in the footballing world is Mourinho.

I don’t know what could change my view but I would like to have a conversation about it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40012946935.0" user="LondonDude123" delta="False">
    <text>Compared to other world-great managers (Klopp, Guardiola), Jose IS boring. But boring =/= bad. In fact, I (Fulham fan) firmly believe that Jose was exactly what Man United needed at the time, and the players got rid of him because he wouldnt bow to their pressure.

To use those two as an example, Guardiola and Klopp both attack their opponents directly and on the front foot thought either intricate or direct passing, or team play and positioning. Jose could not be more the opposite. Hes someone that plays possession football to wait for an opening, absorbs pressure, and exploits weaknesses in the other teams positioning during an attack. Jose's football isnt "boring" to someone who likes football, but it certainly is "boring" when you compare it to other managers, and its easy to understand why a casual viewer would see it that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40014613920.0" user="Noerig15" delta="False">
    <text>that’s true and Mourinho was the right man for the United job.

I wouldn’t say that his football is boring compared to Guardiolas football. Guardiolas football can be fantastic to watch at it’s best but it’s a bit boring when they just pass sideways and it doesn’t lead to anything.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
