<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="191285880.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/35vx4o/cmv_the_away_goals_tiebreaker_in_soccer_is_silly/">
    <title>CMV: The "away goals" tiebreaker in soccer is silly and should be done away with.</title>
    <original_poster>elvish_visionary</original_poster>
    <original_post>In some big soccer tournaments, particularly the champions league, knockout rounds are decided by two games ("legs"), one at each team's home stadium. Whichever team has the most goals after both games (called the "aggregate" score) advances. For example, if team A beats team B 2-0 in the first leg and then loses 0-1 in the second, team A will advance on 2-1 aggregate.

In the event of a tied aggregate after both games, the "away goals" rule is used. Whichever team scored more goals at the other team's stadium advances. So if team A wins 1-0 at home and loses 2-1 on the road, they will advance even though the aggregate is 2-2.

I believe this is a silly way to break a tie. It would make much more sense to play a 30 minute overtime if the aggregate was tied after the second leg, followed by a shootout if necessary. This would be a much more dramatic and less arbitrary way of breaking a tie.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27768828869.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>I see where you're coming from, but I also get why they wouldn't want to add extra play time onto a tournament for a sport as aerobically exhausting as Soccer since the players are already being stretched to their limits, and a shootout is essentially a coin flip anyway, so you still have the arbitrary winner if it comes to that(my favorite description of the shootout is that it's like deciding a baseball game with a homerun derby).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768906408.0" user="StreetOtter" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite related to OP's point, but penalty shootouts aren't luck at all. It's about preparation, kickers ability and goalkeepers reflexes. 

If it was chance how could you explain the ridiculous save % of great penalty keepers, like Diego Alves for example?

Or the swap the netherlands team made in the world cup before the shootout for a goalkeeper better suited to save penalties?

A huge part of it is the GK's studying the shooters and their body posturing/paterns, and also be fast enough so they can wait until the shot is made to jump vs the shooters ability to not be affected by the pressure and the skill to kick the ball near the corner fast.

Sorry but it just annoys me when people say that penalties are pure luck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768918566.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>[They aren't pure luck, but they're about as close to it as anything that decides the victor in a sporting match](http://fivethirtyeight.com/datalab/extra-time-isnt-a-crapshoot-in-the-knockout-round-but-penalties-are/).  Unless the matchup is lopsided to the point that a PK shootout is almost impossibly unlikely, the chance for each team hovers around 50%, getting up to 60-40 on the high end of matches that could conceivably be tied at the end of overtime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768952864.0" user="StreetOtter" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem with the approach from the article is that it uses the prediction beforehand (which is based on the favourite to win in the regular time), not on the favorite to win the penalty shootout. 

So the only thing it shows is that it is "close" to random if you try to predict based on how well a team plays in the regular time.

But having a team that is great on penaty shootouts can be an advantage, since the worst team at penalties has to make a bigger effort not to draw.

For example I was trying to predict the likehood of Valencia winning a penalty shootout using the same chance of them winning in regular time, it would be way off. But if I consider that their keeper saves more than 40% of the penalties shot his way (16:37) and that they have decent kickers, I'd bet on them winning agaisnt pretty much any team in the world. Specially vs a team that might have great offense but a worse keeper

It's not random, but it does become way more about the keeper than the regular game.

Anyhow, short of infinite overtimes it is the best solutions for ties (ar least in single games, and I actually like away goals as a tirbreaker)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768986332.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>That's kinda my point though.  Shootouts end up having games decided on something that is tangential to soccer, but not really based on overall soccer skill.  It's kinda like deciding the game based on a juggling contest.  Sure that's kinda related to soccer, and some guys might be better at it than others, but deciding games based on it would likely end in a random distribution of wins where objectively worse teams win about as often as they lose.  It doesn't determine which team is better at the game as a whole.  It's just a way to end the game because if they didn't people would start collapsing from exhaustion and someone needs to move on in the tournament.

I actually think it's a good solution to the problem of advancing in a soccer tournament, in that it's about as not-bad as it can be.  It's not really a fair solution, but I don't think one exists so they might as well use the one that's really exciting to watch.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
