<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="191285880.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/35vx4o/cmv_the_away_goals_tiebreaker_in_soccer_is_silly/">
    <title>CMV: The "away goals" tiebreaker in soccer is silly and should be done away with.</title>
    <original_poster>elvish_visionary</original_poster>
    <original_post>In some big soccer tournaments, particularly the champions league, knockout rounds are decided by two games ("legs"), one at each team's home stadium. Whichever team has the most goals after both games (called the "aggregate" score) advances. For example, if team A beats team B 2-0 in the first leg and then loses 0-1 in the second, team A will advance on 2-1 aggregate.

In the event of a tied aggregate after both games, the "away goals" rule is used. Whichever team scored more goals at the other team's stadium advances. So if team A wins 1-0 at home and loses 2-1 on the road, they will advance even though the aggregate is 2-2.

I believe this is a silly way to break a tie. It would make much more sense to play a 30 minute overtime if the aggregate was tied after the second leg, followed by a shootout if necessary. This would be a much more dramatic and less arbitrary way of breaking a tie.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27767962970.0" user="LostThineGame" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that by not having an away goal rule you (far more) arbitrarily give a large advantage to the team that has the home game last. In sports you want to give the teams as much of a possibility to demonstrate they are superior, rather than giving a coin flip advantage to a weaker team. Away goals are one way in which two closely matched teams can show they are superior as it is mych more difficult to score away than it is at home. It also rewards attacking play. Without it the away teams would be far more inclined to park the bus and play for a 0-0 draw. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27767989109.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The problem is that by not having an away goal rule you (far more) arbitrarily give a large advantage to the team that has the home game last.

I don't see the problem with this. The team playing at home second is typically the higher seeded team, and I don't see a problem with the higher seeded team getting the chance to play a potential extra time at home. At least it's better than deciding using an arbitrary metric.

I'm not sure how away goals gives more of a chance for a team to show superiority. If two teams play a 1-1 draw and a 0-0 draw, you can't really say that the team that scored the away goal was superior. On the other hand, extra time gives teams the chance to actually win by scoring more goals.

Finally, while it may encourage attacking play for the away team, it also discourages attacking play for the home team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768180256.0" user="LostThineGame" delta="False">
    <text>The Champions League decides the home/away order for Quarters onwards on the draw (drawn first from the ball pit you play at home first). It's luck. Round of 16 home/away is decided by coming first/second in your group however. 

There's been studies on the home advantage in football and it [makes you 10% more likely to win at home than away.](http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3827749/) It's a huge advantage to have based purely on luck of the draw. Especially when major factors such as the crowd and psychological effects are most potent in extra-time. 

&amp;gt;I'm not sure how away goals gives more of a chance for a team to show superiority. If two teams play a 1-1 draw and a 0-0 draw, you can't really say that the team that scored the away goal was superior. On the other hand, extra time gives teams the chance to actually win by scoring more goals.

Well, away goals is based on over 180 minutes of play, as opposed to 30 minutes of play. 

If  team A goes away and gets a 6-6 draw when they're at a 55/45 disadvantage and then gets a 0-0 draw when they're at a 55/45 advantage do you not think team A is clearly superior over the matches? 

Away goals at least act to balance the home advantage a bit. Without it and just having an extra-time you give a random and major advantage to one team. If you're going to get rid of away goals, then you should get rid of the double legs and just play a single match in a neutral ground like in the final. Rubbish for the fans but great for the fair play purists. 

&amp;gt;Finally, while it may encourage attacking play for the away team, it also discourages attacking play for the home team.

But importantly not in equal measures. The away team is more encouraged than the home team is discouraged. When you have the  home advantage you naturally want to press that advantage. If you can't win the home leg you're very unlikely to win the tie. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768193907.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If team A goes away and gets a 6-6 draw when they're at a 55/45 disadvantage and then gets a 0-0 draw when they're at a 55/45 advantage do you not think team A is clearly superior over the matches?

No. Why would they be superior? Both teams scored the same amount of goals.

&amp;gt; Well, away goals is based on over 180 minutes of play, as opposed to 30 minutes of play.

It's not 30 minutes of play, it's 180+30 minutes of play. And again, I don't see how you can say one team was superior when aggregate is tied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768239016.0" user="LostThineGame" delta="False">
    <text>If team A goes away and gets a 6-6 draw when they're at a **55/45 disadvantage** and then gets a 0-0 draw when they're at a **55/45 advantage** do you not think team A is clearly superior over the matches? It's not the number of goals, it's the relative difficulty of those goals. 

&amp;gt;It's not 30 minutes of play, it's 180+30 minutes of play. And again, I don't see how you can say one team was superior when aggregate is tied.

Take a 6-6 and 0-0 example. The second game is done and now we decide how to resolve the situation. I'm saying that by using the away goals you're basing your assessment over both games (180 minutes). Your way the tie is decided by 30 minutes of unequal gameplay. In general, it's preferable to look deeper into the original 180 minutes of gameplay, rather than creating an unbalanced 30 minutes of gameplay. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768242637.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If team A goes away and gets a 6-6 draw when they're at a 55/45 disadvantage and then gets a 0-0 draw when they're at a 55/45 advantage do you not think team A is clearly superior over the matches? It's not the number of goals, it's the relative difficulty of those goals.

I still don't see your logic here. You seem to think that it's harder to earn a 6-6 draw on the road than a 0-0 draw, which is very subjective and doesn't really make sense to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768266414.0" user="LostThineGame" delta="False">
    <text>Two match tie

Match 1 (Team A **Away**): 6-6

Match 2 (Team A **Home**): 0-0

Match 1 is far more impressive because you're scoring against the home advantage. 

Edit: Imagine there's a game of football being played on a massive hill. One goal is at the top of the hill and the other is near the bottom. The game starts with Team A shooting downhill and Team B shooting uphill. The half ends 5-0 to Team A. They swap sides and the second half ends 6-6 (effectively a 1-6 half). Who played better?

The goals were the same in number but Team A scored 5 going downhill and 1 uphill, whereas Team B scored all theirs going downhill. Surely the uphill goal would count as more if you were to try and value each goal? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768317001.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>So you think Team B played better because they scored all their goals downhill?

What about the fact that Team A didn't concede any uphill goals? Why is that not a factor.

The only truly objective measure is to count the number of goals.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768692889.0" user="LostThineGame" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So you think Team B played better because they scored all their goals downhill?

No. I'm saying Team A is better because they managed to score when it was considerably harder to score. 

&amp;gt;The only truly objective measure is to count the number of goals.

That's the *first* thing we try, we're both agreed on that, but when that fails we look at the detail of the goals. **Away goals are objectively harder to score because of the home advantage**, just like uphill goals are objectively harder to score. 

What I'm saying is that it is a better measurement of which team is better than having a 30 minute period of football where one team has a large advantage. In my example it would be like deciding to let one team play for 30 minutes shooting downhill, which is objectively easier. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27769140580.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, I can see what you mean now. Sorry for mixing that up.

But shouldn't Team B get credit for only allowing 5 downhill goals, while Team A allowed 6? While it's harder to score uphill, it's also harder to defend uphill, and Team B did a better job of that. 

I don't see how you can objectively say it's more impressive for Team A to one more uphill goal than team B than it is for Team B to allow one less downhill goal than team A. In the same way that it's hard to score uphill, it's equally hard to defend while the other team is going downhill.

So in your 6-6/0-0 example, while one team managed to score 6 goals on the road which is impressive, the other managed to concede 0 goals on the road, which is also impressive if the home team has a scoring advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27769467724.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Away goals are objectively harder to score because of the home advantage

And home goals are objectively harder to prevent because of the home advantage.  These balance each other out exactly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768853091.0" user="EnfieldMarine" delta="False">
    <text>No, Team A is better because they managed 1 Uphill goal while Team B had 0 Uphills goals. That is objective. (That Team A didn't concede any Uphill goals is the converse, so makes the same point but confuses the argument.) While both teams scored the same total number, ALL of Team B's were easier to accomplish in respect to the chosen variable (uphill v downhill). That issue is whether the chosen variable is objective or subjective.

You aren't using the word "subjective" properly. It would be subjective if the tiebreaker were given to the team that scored the most beautiful or creative goal.

Scoring away goals is statistically more difficult than scoring goals at home. It's not a massive difference, but it is a noticeable and significant difference.

By your reasoning - that only the base number of goals is objective and home/away does not matter - you would expect, over time, that home and away teams would score almost exactly the same number of goals. (This would be especially relevant for soccer, where nearly every league, including the CL, has each team play a home &amp;amp; away series, so there's essentially zero chance of error because good teams play at home more often.) HOWEVER, the actual stats demonstrate that home teams are more likely to score. Therefore, using away goals as a tiebreaker awards the team who more often achieves the less likely outcome. That is completely objective, borne out by history and statistics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768617441.0" user="chicagofirefifa3" delta="False">
    <text>actually match 1 is much less impressive because giving up 6 goals shows you played pretty terrible defense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768855462.0" user="EnfieldMarine" delta="False">
    <text>Both teams gave up 6 goals. So both teams played terrible defense that day. That observation still provides zero reason to choose between them when deciding the tie. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768955662.0" user="chicagofirefifa3" delta="False">
    <text>i agree. 6 goals scored on the road also means the other team allowed 0 goals on the road which is also an impressive feat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768392693.0" user="zebediah49" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't see the problem with this. The team playing at home second is typically the higher seeded team, and I don't see a problem with the higher seeded team getting the chance to play a potential extra time at home. At least it's better than deciding using an arbitrary metric.

So you prefer an actually unfair decision system to one that's somewhat arbitrary?  The existing rule treats both teams equally, and does have some reasoning behind it.  I might be convinced that there's a better way, but something that's blatantly unfair is not it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27768603601.0" user="Deansdale" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; At least it's better than deciding using an arbitrary metric.

It's not arbitrary, it is based on the (rather objectively true) idea that it is harder to score in away games.

&amp;gt; you can't really say that the team that scored the away goal was superior

It's not really a question of overall superiority, it's just that in those 2 games they performed better. And scoring more away goals **is** performing better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
