<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1919527693.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vqu51p/cmv_downfall_of_news_networks_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing</title>
    <original_poster>mindtug</original_poster>
    <original_post>News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors. It’s important to know what’s happening but global networks such as CNN and Fox are too sensational for me to support. Should I feel sad they’re dying?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40076755112.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors.

&amp;gt; Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing 

Your view should probably be limited to specific news networks, stations or programs, and not news networks in general.

The fear mongering and sensation seeking behavior, while typical for some of the larger, private US networks, is not inherent in news reporting. News doesn't have to be presented that way. It happens mostly when news is driven by profit, because this incentivizes boosting viewer/listener numbers using attention-grabbing strategies.

Many of the major news networks in Europe are not profit-driven. The news here can be quite boring at times even. The closest in the US are probably stations like PBS and NPR. (Disregarding their political leanings and potential biases for the sake of argument.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
