<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1919527693.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vqu51p/cmv_downfall_of_news_networks_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing</title>
    <original_poster>mindtug</original_poster>
    <original_post>News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors. It’s important to know what’s happening but global networks such as CNN and Fox are too sensational for me to support. Should I feel sad they’re dying?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40074481291.0" user="AlwaysTheNoob" delta="False">
    <text>Please don't refer to 24/7 entertainment networks as "news".

The Associated Press is news.  Reuters is news.  NPR is news.

CNN and Fox are opinion and analysis sponsored by commercials, with the occasional news thrown in in order to pretend it's anything other than entertainment. 

The downfall of interest in news is not good.  A public awakening to the difference between news and ad-supported opinion pieces, on the other hand, is welcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074503852.0" user="mindtug" delta="False">
    <text>Aren’t they branded as news stations? I mean it’s fine if their technically opinion and not associated press but I wouldn’t know and neither would most redditors</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074531633.0" user="Crack4Supper" delta="False">
    <text>So one issue is most people don’t bother learning which news is reliable. Another is that we live in a capitalist society. News like Fox and CNN are just doing what’s profitable. If people didn’t respond to fear mongering they would not do it. And if they stop other news networks selling fear will replace them. That’s what a competitive news market looks like.

Listen to NPR for awhile.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074563403.0" user="mindtug" delta="False">
    <text>I like that though that doesn’t that mean I’m right? News will push for fear mongering and bias because it’s profitable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074686375.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; News will push for fear mongering and bias because it’s profitable

Except when their funding is not via advertising. 

As the main comment listed, organizations like Reuters, AP, and NPR are not 24/7 sellers of advertisements. They are news organizations. They don't benefit from the same revenue streams that FOX/CNN do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079704057.0" user="nauticalsandwich" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	Except when their funding is not via advertising 

It isn't that simple. It's about the incentives of the revenue model, but it's not as clear cut as you've made it out to be. 

The news delivery model in the 20th century, which actually relied MORE heavily on advertising, actually led to LESS fear-mongering, political-bias, and polarization. It was still biased, but it was more of a monocultural bias that leaned in favor of mainstream culture, government, and entrenched business. This is because the technology governing the model was different. Newspapers and other news services could sell news directly to the public, because reading a physical newspaper or listening or watching a news broadcast was the only way to get information other than word of mouth. The capital requirements and  logistics of procuring and delivering the news to people led to several key conditions that minimized political divisions and emphasized a more positive portrayal of the world. Primarily, it meant a model reliant on big advertisers reaching as many eyeballs as possible. Under this model, Newspapers had strong incentives to appeal to the broadest audience possible, and the incentives to "fear-monger" and create outrage for attention were tempered by the desires of advertisers, who, generally speaking, desired a happier and more content audience (because ads perform better, and are better for a brand's public associations, when they are encountered in a more positive context).

This model was virtually destroyed by the internet.

The internet meant that the general public no longer had to pay for the news, no longer had to consume the news through physical or broadcast media that favored big, capital-intensive "gatekeepers," and had much more choice overall in news consumption. Advertisers found far superior outlets on the internet outside of news publications, and news companies quickly found that without their prior, distributional advantage, they could not maintain the revenue streams necessary to continue their operations. Many formal news organizations died or were swallowed up by larger, more well-known publications. Local newspapers virtually went extinct. The news that survived did so by pivoting to a new model.

This new model relies far more heavily on an enthusiastic base of readers/supporters/members and "user-engagement" than on standard advertising. Newspapers and other news services can no longer sell the news (with the exception of organizations that do not sell directly to the public, ala AP and Reuters), because the public already knows the news and gets it for free. They must sell something else, so they sell narratives and "causes." This, along with the amplification of hyper-individualized consumer choice in information consumption, within an attention-scarce environment, creates positive feedback loops of confirmation bias and outrage induction that drives extremism, tribalism, and political polarization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079790686.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>While I disagree with some of your claims, I don’t see where you disagree with me.

My claim was that the revenue streams of these organizations are grossly different. On the one hand you have multimedia companies based around 24/7 television channels and on the other hand you have predominantly written text and radio.

One is clearly incentivized to increase sensationalism and stoke constant user engagement more than the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079938095.0" user="nauticalsandwich" delta="False">
    <text>I disagreed with the implication that advertising is the defining characteristic in whether or not news is sensationalist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40076403106.0" user="HappyLong9896" delta="False">
    <text>It's not only fear-mongering its also the entertainment aspect, the news segments are short and meant to grab the audience's attention which is generally bad especially when issues are complex and require more than just a 3-minute-soundbite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40081025726.0" user="TheAntidote101" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't NPR falsely claim Gabby Giffords was dead? No station should be trusted completely, that's why you should get your news from a variety of sources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40077208527.0" user="randomgrunt1" delta="False">
    <text>Fox new legally can not refer to themselves as a new organization. This is due to a legal ruling, during a case a judge rules that due to the lack of any news on the network it must label itself as entertainment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40078579675.0" user="SalaciousSlug" delta="False">
    <text>This was an April fools joke like a decade old. Fox News is a news organization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079030135.0" user="Bigmouthstrikesback" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what they said in a lawsuit. Why lie?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079062845.0" user="SalaciousSlug" delta="False">
    <text>What lawsuit are you referring to? I’ve only seen the April fools joke and when Tucker Carlson used the Rachel Maddow defense. Are you referring to something else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079090416.0" user="Bigmouthstrikesback" delta="False">
    <text>Smartmatic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079115113.0" user="SalaciousSlug" delta="False">
    <text>That case is still ongoing… and doesn’t say they can’t refer to themselves as a news organization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079122488.0" user="Bigmouthstrikesback" delta="False">
    <text>But they're not a news organization, no reasonable person would think that's news.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079167570.0" user="SalaciousSlug" delta="False">
    <text>That is an opinion. Not a legal ruling. Sounds like you’re spreading lies after all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40079170729.0" user="Bigmouthstrikesback" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. Not an opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074537425.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  NPR is news.

NPR as "news" has been as bad as CNN and MSNBC for at least 5 years. Literally the only source of news that's not biased (as far as US politics is concerned) is CSPAN.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40074765115.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;NPR as "news" has been as bad as CNN and MSNBC for at least 5 years

Strongly disagree. They aren't shy about correcting a story they got wrong. I've heard an on-air correction plenty and seen just as many in print. 

I've also routinely heard them provide a disclaimer that the subject of a story they are covering donates to them, publicizing any financial connection prior to the story. 

For being so blatantly partisan, [NPR's Terry Gross](https://www.phillyvoice.com/terry-gross-reflects-awkward-exchange-hillary-clinton-gay-marriage/) made Hillary angry during the years prio/runup to the 2016 election because they held her to her previous record inconsistencies. They asked about her position on gay marriage and why it changed, received a non-answer, and pressed her on the issue.

Every time there is a partisan issue, they will have both a GOP and DEM strategist/politician present to weigh in and serve to moderate the discussion between the two sides. They also routinely bring in experts with differing opinions.

In what possible way is NPR equivalent to those other two. Any examples at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40075185158.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In what possible way is NPR equivalent to those other two. Any examples at all?

The Hunter Biden laptop story. It took *months* for them to issue a mea culpa about their statement that the story was "discredited" by intelligence officials. NPR is every bit as bad as CNN and MSNBC. They just do a better job of hiding their bias.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40075218553.0" user="LLKKSSII" delta="False">
    <text>NPR often selectively and deliberately chooses what they say and what they don't. So they can deliberately present a misshapen and deceptive  narrative without actually "lying"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40075794190.0" user="HijacksMissiles" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The Hunter Biden laptop story.

This was a joke. A literal meme. There has never been a single piece of evidence to be scrutinized. It all relies upon believing that a laptop Giuliani was waving around contains what he claimed it contains. 

And the entire story of how they came in possession of the laptop reads like a children's novel with how *coincidental* everything was.

The fact they didn't run the story is an indication of their credibility as a news organization, not their partisanship.

And their Mea Culpa?

&amp;gt;A previous version of this story said US intelligence had discredited the laptop story. US intelligence officials have not made a statement to that effect.

This does not acknowledge there is any legitimacy to the laptop story. It is in no way any sort of admission they *should* have run the story. This is admitting that Ron Elving reported incorrect information. It could have been Ron telling a lie, it could have been errors in communication, it could have been any number of things. But all that is happening there is NPR posting a correction. They post corrections all the time. That is what happens in reporting the *news*. 

&amp;gt;NPR is every bit as bad as CNN and MSNBC. 

This has yet to be demonstrated. If the Laptop story is all you've got, you've got nothing. That story remains unsupported. By every indication a reasonable person would see it as a manufactured story attempting to sway an election and nothing more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40076027898.0" user="captainvontage801" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what they used to be though. That changed over time into the partisan trash very few people now watch anymore. Thank god for that. They've now done more to divide us than frankly anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40078666045.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; NPR is news.

Have you listened to them in the past few years? I used to be a fan, but their slant has been pretty indefensible.

If a comet was hurtling towards earth to wipe out all of mankind, AP would get most of the story straight, FOX would question the comet’s existence, CNN would have experts weigh in on Trump’s reaction to it, and NPR would talk about how the collision will disproportionately affect people of color.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
