<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1919527693.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vqu51p/cmv_downfall_of_news_networks_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing</title>
    <original_poster>mindtug</original_poster>
    <original_post>News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors. It’s important to know what’s happening but global networks such as CNN and Fox are too sensational for me to support. Should I feel sad they’re dying?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40081009119.0" user="TheAntidote101" delta="False">
    <text>*"For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low"*

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Growing up with Magic School Bus, I was more afraid of bee sting anaphylaxis due to undiagnosed bee sting allergies than of getting kidnapped. Would you count Magic School Bus as bad for kids too, on account of it keeping people like me indoors?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

As well, the Internet has its own forms of fearmongering. Fearmongering about "bad boys" dominating the dating world and, in turn, the gene pool, comes to mind, even as someone who defended my sister when my dad accused her of dating "bad boys". (I didn't even think he was that bad!) That one didn't even cross my mind from years of TV news.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Yes we need alternatives to TV news. But it shouldn't be a competition exclusively between Internet podcasts and other Internet podcasts. We need competition within each medium, but between different media as well.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

The Internet shook the TV world to its core. What we need *now* is not to finish them off, but to make their continued survival contingent on emulating the *best* aspects of Internet culture and rejecting the *worst* aspects of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
