<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1919527693.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vqu51p/cmv_downfall_of_news_networks_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Downfall of News Networks is a Good Thing</title>
    <original_poster>mindtug</original_poster>
    <original_post>News thrives off fear mongering which has been detrimental for America. For instance ‘stranger danger’ caused kids across America to be locked indoors which isn’t great for development and mental health because the fear of some van taking them away, while the likelihood of your kids being kidnapped is actually extremely low. Same thing with tough on crime that went overboard causing mass incarceration and lengthened prison times making America have the biggest prisoner poppulation in the world. News talk about “How we’re more divided than ever” but they’re probably the biggest contributors. It’s important to know what’s happening but global networks such as CNN and Fox are too sensational for me to support. Should I feel sad they’re dying?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40074803711.0" user="MuffySpooj" delta="False">
    <text>Say what you want about mainstream news  but 'alternative media' is worse. General main stream reporting is  pretty decent all round. Reputation means something and if your network is known for being shady in terms of reporting it will bite you on the ass (which it has).  I don't think the same level of scrutiny is held to someone like Tim Pool probably down to having a more insular echo chamber viewer base but partly because he's one guy with a small team. 

Pundits are a different story though, I'd say there's wackos in both mainstream and alternative spaces- both push agendas and have their motives.  News is more than opinion pieces though  and we should recognise the destinction between raw reporting and an editors opinion. Mainstream news just has the more consistent reporting, and I'd  take a mainstream publication over any 'alternative' source because of that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
