<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40162510247.0" user="LogicalSpecialist7" delta="False">
    <text>Humans have been on Earth for a few million years now.  Homo Sapiens have been around for about 200,000 years, but Homo Erectus was around for over 1.5 million years before that.  And there were also other ancient human species.  

Only in the last 10,000 years did we develop agriculture, however. Prior to agriculture humans got the vast majority of their calories from meat.

In other words, human beings evolved on meat — it is the diet that we most naturally thrive on.

Also, people who think they aren’t causing harm to animals because they are vegetarians or vegans just don’t understand how agriculture harms animals, whether through pesticides which kill the insects that the birds feed in, thereby killing the birds, or through straightforward destruction of habitat, or through the harvesting combines chewing up all the baby deer and mice and ground-nesting birds, and so on.

Eating animals is natural and healthy for human beings and it is also environmentally sustainable, but agriculture is driving the sixth great mass extinction while also creating foods that are less healthy for human consumption.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
