<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40155387634.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>Taking the an animal to the vets is worse.

It harms the animal. They might need a painful operation

The animal didn't consent. How can it?

It's unnatural. There's no vets out in the wild!

It contributes to climate change. All those resources looking after a pet for no rational reason.

Vet hospitals use up land which could be used for something else.

Some people at the vets get paid a crap wage.

Okay my point is that it's the outcome that matters. Taking an animal to the vet has a positive outcome for the animal so it's worth doing. Eating a chicken has a worse outcome for the animal because it dies, but it suffered less (in some cases not all) and eating meat means I'm healthier (in a balanced diet and not in all cases). Fucking a chicken is just fucked up. The chicken lives after so it's scarred for life and tbh I don't really get much out of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157123645.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the outcome is what matters; see my post responding to the user who likened raping/killing animals to keeping pets for more discussion of this.

I don't know how you think farm chickens don't suffer before they're killed. I'd encourage you to look it up but tl;dr the pain inflicted on chickens while they're raised seems not at all commiserate with the happiness a person gets from eating some chicken, let alone all the externalities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157296598.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>But you have the option to buy free range.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157636340.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, there're obviously ways to make eating meat more morally palatable, but the same goes for bestiality. I'm sure most people would agree having sex with an unrestrained horse that can walk away it it wants isn't as bad as tying up and cat and hurting it badly in the process. It seems unreasonable to compare the best moral scenario for eating meat vs the typical/worst case for bestiality, especially when so few people eat meat that way anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157661605.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but they aren't even morally comparable. There isn't an equivalence.

Having sex with a horse is not the same as eating a free range chicken.

The best case of bestiality is...well I have no idea, but it's not good. Maybe it's better than eating a battery farmed chicken. (strong emphasis on maybe).

Do you really think those two things are at the same moral level? The best case bestiality versus the free range chicken?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158196746.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>It's unclear to me why you think these things aren't comparable.

In the beat scenario for eating meat, you raise a free range chicken and then murder it to eat. Not terrible, but you did still kill the chicken which isn't great and obviously harms the chicken.

In the best scenario for bestiality, you raise a free range whatever animal and then have sex with it without restraining it. Again, not great, but it does, y'know, keep the animal alive, and arguably the animal didn't have a huge problem with it if it didn't stop it by simply walking away or kicking you or something. 

It also seems unlikely to me that animals would have the same trauma as a result of this that humans often do (if you have a source that says they'd do I'd be interested though!) so it doesn't even seem particularly harmful to the animal, but even if they did it's not prima facie obvious that they'd prefer to be dead than traumatized.

Obviously both eating meat and bestiality are usually worse than the scenarios described, but for any given level of intensity it's unclear to me that bestiality is worse, and we do the meat thing much more intensely these days regardless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158242863.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>Culturally speaking, rape is seen worse than murder. Raping animals (which is what bestiality is) is therefore worse.

If you want me to explain why, culturally, rape is morally worse than murder I can try to do that for you.

The second thing is that it's not murder. Killing for food is not considered murder (as long as its not a person). It's "required" to survive therefore morally justified AND can be done with minimal suffering. We bred these animals to die which makes it even less of a moral problem.

Don't get me wrong. Minimising suffering is good. But I don't think the suffering is equivalent between the two. I think animal rape has way worse net effects (on ther person doing, on the animal etc etc).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158390157.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>It's unclear to me that rape is worse than murder, or that this is society's general opinion, but i'd be happy to hear your case for that. Either way I don't think it matters, they both obviously cause pretty much the same harms so it seems more helpful to simply evaluate which set of harms is more intense/worse rather than splitting hairs about which is intrinsically worse 'culturally speaking.'

1.5 billion people disagree that meat is required to survive, they seem to do fine for themselves.

I'm sure you can find some definition of murder that excludes killing for food, it's unclear to me why this is important. Regardless of if you call it 'murder' you've still harmed the animal, which is my issue, not whether or not it falls under a given definition of murder.

It's also unclear to me why raising animals to kill them makes it better. You're still causing them harm by killing them, and it's not obvious that they're better off this way.

Yes I agree reducing suffering is what matters most, but like I said, it seems like killing the animal results in more suffering even in the best case scenario, let alone the current factory farming situation.

If you want to elaborate on the harms to the animal and human caused by bestiality you're welcome too, but I suspect we'll just circle back to my original point that any reason bestiality is bad also applies to eating meat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158608950.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>I fundamentally disagree with two major things.

The first is that those animals wouldn't be alive if it wasn't for us eating them. So isn't it worse to have not bred them in the first place, rather than breeding them, letting them live a life, and then eating them?

Secondly, bestiality is more harmful because its damaging to the social fabric.

Name a society that practices bestiality at a large scale. You can't. We can name societies that don't eat meat. But the very fact not a single large society practices beastiliaty, should make it clear that they are not morally equivalent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158782167.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>If we're keeping the situation symmetric, presumably the animals used for bestiality also wouldn't be alive if they weren't being used for that case. If it's acceptable to cause animals harm if they wouldn't be alive otherwise (and it may well be) why doesn't that also apply to having sex with them? It seems tough to argue that an animal who was raised in healthy conditions and was subsequently raped is worse off than one that was killed instead.

Here's a [vice documentary](https://youtu.be/_VKWLC87Uzw) of a bunch of people who fuck donkeys, they seem by and large pretty normal and well adjusted to their society. Maybe you could argue their social fabric is damaged or whatever, but unclear how or why this practice is responsible for it.

*the vice documentary is pretty surprising and I was skeptical, but I did some googling and found some corroboration from other sources and no one debunking it even when I explicitly looked for that. If you have evidence vice is misrepresenting what's happening I'd love to see it, but I don't think it effects the underlaying issue much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158919934.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>A bunch of people fucking donkeys is not 1.5 billion people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40159027566.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>1.5 billion people refers to the approximate number of vegetarians in the world, illustrating that meat is not a necessity to survive. Unclear to me how this is relevant to the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40159113974.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>How is this unclear??! 

No one practices beastiality. Many people practice no eating meat. Those aren't equivalent moral things clearly. This is ridiculous if you can't see the difference tbh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162206698.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>It also used to be the case (and still is in many countries) that women were treated as property rather than equals. That doesn't mean that it was morally better than treating woman as equals, or even remotely morally acceptable. The number of people who engage in a practice is not proof that it is moral or immoral (and tbh bestiality is probably just really impractical for a lot of people, but I wouldn't be surprised if it used to be way more common than we currently think it is due to religion), especially given OP's many reasons why bestiality would be morally acceptable by the same logic that makes meat eating acceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163893028.0" user="YogurtclosetTough610" delta="False">
    <text>It's not proof. But it's good evidence. You can't just sweep it under the rug. You can't just put your hands up and say "well that means nothing".  THAT is illogical.

If most people thing murder is immoral you don't think that means anything? 

We are talking about morality which is basically the same thing as general reasoning. If you say "well we can't look at what the general consensus is" then you can't assess what morality is as far a I'm concerned.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
