<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40158559036.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat.

Bestiality is bad for the human, and it is the sign of a seriously maladjusted mind state in any human who would do such a thing. It is a serious deviation for a human to be sexually attracted to an animal. But even if the bestiality is not based on attraction to animals, and is just a person looking for a semi-willing receptacle without the ability to resist, that is a fucking huge red flag as well. All my reasons for why it is bad are based on what it indicates about the human.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158745280.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>This seems culturally dependent to me. The people who like bestiality are really weird and maladjusted because society stigmatizes enough that normal people won't partake. Here's a [vice documentary](https://youtu.be/_VKWLC87Uzw) of a bunch of people who fuck donkeys, they seem by and large pretty normal and well adjusted to their society. 

To be clear I think bestiality generally should be stigmatized such that only weird people do, just that eating meat should be as well.

But to get to the meat of your point, even if fucking animals is a huge red flag, I don't think that alone makes it worse than eating meat. Just because you can infer someone is a bad person by the fact that they do something doesn't make the thing itself more bad than it orherwise is. For instance, maybe people who habitually speed are generally bad people, this doesn't in my view make speeding worse than it already is due to safety issues and whatnot. 

*the vice documentary is pretty surprising and I was skeptical, but I did some googling and found some corroboration from other sources and no one debunking it even when I explicitly looked for that. If you have evidence vice is misrepresenting what's happening I'd love to see it, but I don't think it effects the underlaying issue much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158898265.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This seems culturally dependent to me

There is not one single society or culture in human history where sex with animals was the norm. And, I don't even think there are any where it was even tolerated. 

&amp;gt; they seem by and large pretty normal and well adjusted to their society.

Except for the sex with animals part.

&amp;gt;just that eating meat should be as well.

So then make your case for your real view. Don't backdoor people with a bizarre gotcha argument that presupposes all sorts of things about the reasons why people are opposed to bestiality. Your point is that people can not be for eating meat and against bestiality right? But, that only makes sense if people make the vary particular arguments that you already imagine them making. 

To be blunt. I don't care about the animal much in the bestiality equation. I care about the person doing the animal fucking as mistreatment of animals is one of the best indictors that a person may mistreat humans. 

Eating meat is a morally neutral act in my opinion. It is neither moral or immoral in and of itself. It could be either. If you kill your neighbor's dog and cook it up: Immoral. If you kill some deer each fall because they have no natural predators left so they don't overpopulate and spread disease and eat the meat after: Moral.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
