<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40154936831.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>I'm gonna speak from the culture I'm raised in for a bit.

Humans simply hunt and kill animals for food, and had been so for ages. If you kill animal for food, there is nothing ethically wrong with it - ***given you do not torture them***. That is the difference between ethical and unethical killing.


Now onto the environmental effects: eating meat itself doesn't make that big of an effect, ***farming*** is. ***Ranching*** is. ***Animal factories*** is. While I think eating meat isn't ethically wrong, I do think animal farms should be abolished. Now, that is easier said than done because in my area we keep free-range chickens. In an urban scenario, I'd imagine it would be difficult to find ethically sourced meat.


Additionally, in most parts of the world it is the only option (economically speaking).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155361231.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; humans simply hunt and kill animals for food, and had been so for ages.

Your argument "people did X for ages" is totally irrelevant... X could be replaced by "raping, murdering, enslaving, ... other humans" that doesn't make those things not immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155394204.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>We can't clump them all together as *"things people did for ages"*. People did both bad and good things for ages - but I do understand your perspective. 


What I think is immoral is torturing animals, treating them poorly, and needlessly murdering them, which is why I'm against animal factories. Consuming meat for your own survival has no positive or negative moral value, the same goes for eating non-animal products. Eating a papaya doesn't make you a good person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155421796.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Sure we can make that distinction, If you hunt, kill and prepare your own meat that could be moral. But I am assuming that is not how you get your meat. (or how we as a society are getting our meat)

Do you consume animal products you buy? If so you are supporting animal factories.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155445747.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>It's kind of economically inescapable to most people to buy at least something from an animal factory. I rarely get chicken nuggets or any of that since we (my area) grow our own chicken, though, but I know that's not something everyone could afford.


I think you can understand how you cannot equate this to someone raping an animal - at least not the people consuming them.


Personally, I'm hopeful for sustainable meat alternative. But for the time being, you can't replace the efficiency and low-cost of animal factories, as sad as it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155482329.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's kind of economically inescapable to most people to buy at least something from an animal factory

It is really not, unless you live somewhat secluded. 

Nobody needs chicken nuggets that bad. 

Eating a chicken nugget is probably morally worse then raping a chicken. The harm done to chickens to get to a point where a chicken nugget exists is probably a whole lot worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155504065.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>In third world countries it ***is*** actually inescapable. For what's equivalent to 1 USD, you can get a bowl of rice, chicken breast, veggies on the side, and iced tea; it's a no brainer and it's how 90% of our people lives. I am ***telling*** you, it is actually impossible to replace **in the current economy**. There is a reason why veganism is very rare in this part of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155517707.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know enough about conditions in third world countries to have that conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155530904.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I do since I live in one - **that's why I'm telling you**. We make up the majority of the world, so "banning meat" isn't something first-world countries can do simply for moral reason. There is a huge economical impact you should consider.


That being said, I think banning unethical production of meat is doable in first world countries. Doing so could set a new standard the other countries could slowly, but surely aim for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155545084.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I can't have this conversation. There is no reason for me to believe you or not believe you, I simply lack the knowledge to take an informed position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155566444.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't believe me, you can always do a 30 second Google search. I mean this is CMV, we trade opinions here.


Now you know why you don't equate eating meat to animal rape 🤷‍♀️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155574099.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>I can have the conversation if you really want to, but it is going to be very hard for you to convince me of anything because all the gaps in my knowledge i will fill with assumptions that support my position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155609012.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>I kind of admire your boldness, but I think making a strong point based only on assumptions is never a good idea... and nothing good ever comes from equating *anything* to animal rape... 💀

I hardly think anyone totally change their mind in CMV. We gave you our information and opinion, it's entirely up to you what you do with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155635013.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Alright lets do this. Gloves off (I am now going to defend my position as if I am 1000% correct on everything)

You are wrong.

Most people in the west make the same arguments you do, adjusted for the conditions here, and they are all bullshit. But give me your best shot, why are animal factories necessary, give me something good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155657836.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying they're absolutely necessary. I'm saying they're necessary ***for the current economy***. Let me make this clear: I'm ***not*** in the defense of animal factories, I've made it clear - I am in defense of **not collapsing the entire third world economy**.


&amp;gt; adjusted for the conditions here

Obviously I was going to adjust for the third world countries, which is the majority of the world. If you're thinking more of a nationwide thing in a first world  country, as I've said before, is clearly doable to abolish unethical practices.


The one reason I think stopping the world (where the first world nations are not expect of) is economical. Animal factories are highly efficient, which unfortunately is why businesses like McDonald's and KFC swarm the entire globe. Cheap resources, high availability, and easy to serve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155672927.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Just a quick question to know what direction my arguments should go, are you against or in favor of capitalism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155684919.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>That shouldn't matter when it comes to **morality**. But I am a centrist, leaning slightly to the left. As much as I dislike megacorps, they're a part of our lives. I think I'm a centrist left? All in all, I value human life more than animal life - which I think is one of the major differences we have?

+ You should point out/quote me when you said "you're wrong", just so I don't misunderstand anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155730238.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>I value human life more then I value animal life. What I actually value is "the capability to understand your own suffering" I think all beings suffer, but not all beings can conceptualize that suffering. I think humans are more capable of understanding their own suffering so the suffering of humans is worse then the suffering of animals. But the animals we eat understand their suffering enough for us to take into account their suffering. To the point where we should not enslave them for our benefit. I think the animal industry is worse then rape because the animal industry includes raping animals for reproduction purposes on top of enslaving, torturing, and eventually murdering those same animals. 

That is my position, I think this position is true regardless of where you live in the world. 

Now specifically to your conditions.

Where does the meat come from that you can buy? where is it produced?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155773124.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think the animal industry is worse than rape

I personally think the animal factories are awful, but I wouldn't throw the word rape around so lightly in regards to actual rape victims. **However, what's the reason that normal people who eat meat should be considered animal rapist?** This is the headline of your statement that bothered most people here I think.



&amp;gt; The animals we eat understand their suffering enough for us to take into account their suffering

The wording ***take into account*** is difficult to understand exactly. Is it enough for us to shift our entire economy and the food industry? I put my money on no.



&amp;gt; where does the meat come from that you buy?

Personally, I buy local chicken. Most people here keep chicken in their backyard, and sell/eat them when they grow - mostly because they're fresher, and I get to support the local economy. ***This isn't a luxury a lot of people can afford***. Factory chickens are MUCH cheaper, and so most people buy them.


I have no qualms about killing animals for food, obviously. I've personally taken care of chicken in the past. What I do have problems with is unethical treatment of animals. ***THOSE TWO AREN'T THE SAME***. As far as I've understood, your reasoning is because the factories are bad, that eating meat is worse than rape. ***Why blame your fellow people? Why not blame the mega corporations designing these animal prisons?***</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155817430.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>I have to say, I am not the original poster. I am just a random who replied to your post. 

With "take into account" I simply mean that we have to consider them. 

&amp;gt; Why blame your fellow people? Why not blame the mega corporations designing these animal prisons?

I am not blaming you or anyone that eats meat. I am telling you "this thing you are doing is wrong". I am an anti capitalist so I do believe those big corporations should not exist. I don't even believe borders or private property should exist.

I believe your acceptance of the status quo is also immoral. I think reducing human and animal suffering go hand in hand. Especially in places like third world countries that are heavily exploited by the west. Building towards a system that creates independence for the people living there from the west and its big corporations is the bigger goal. And I believe this goal can be best achieved while also getting rid of most animal exploitation. The amount of land and water needed to grow plant based food is magnitudes smaller compared to what you need to produce meat (for the same amount of calories).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155856325.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>Agriculture is some of the most difficult jobs to perfect in practice, especially since the climate around the globe vastly varies. Especially in asian third world countries, agriculture takes the #1 spot for water consumption. I won't get to the nitty gritty, but we do live by agriculture and farming - and let me tell you that agriculture itself isn't enough. I do believe we should transition in the future, but in the current climate, it's simply **not economically viable**.



&amp;gt; acceptance of status quo

I don't feel strongly about eating meat or vegetables, but I do believe we should abolish animal factories. If what you mean by status quo is eating meat, then I have no plans of changing that - there is no moral tie-in for me in that regard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155885920.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you believe it is not yet economically viable in your country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155898296.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>Because that's just how it is. The cheapest meals are typically rice and chicken. The climate makes it easy, chickens aren't prone to harvest failure. I'm sure there's a whole load of other reasons, but that's just how the reality is here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155957091.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>how would people survive without the existence of these factory animal products you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155967136.0" user="Underhanded-Blitz" delta="False">
    <text>As I stated way earlier, I believe in the future of sustainable meat substitute. It's a far from perfect atm, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40156021608.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>ok, I think I am done. Unless you want to ask me something or cmv still.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162286673.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I also have no right to be talking about third world countries, but why isn't beans a viable, cheap way of obtaining protein? Beans are WAY cheaper than chicken here in the states, and I think of beans and rice as such a quintessential dish among poor families and third world countries. How are beans not also a much cheaper source of protein in your country? It seems like this would be perfectly viable for many third world countries.

Disclaimer: I believe it is morally acceptable to kill an animal if you absolutely need to in order to survive, but I am having a hard time believing that it is necessary in this case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40171669214.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  but why isn't beans a viable, cheap way of obtaining protein?

Beans aren't a complete protein.

&amp;gt; I think of beans and rice as such a quintessential dish among poor families and third world countries

Which is lacking in critical micronutrients that cause health issues if left without. Like cobalamin, a deficiency of which leads to pernicious anemia and can *only* be obtained from animal products.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40171680236.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen from multiple sources that beans and rice when eaten together do form a complete protein: https://www.livestrong.com/article/351077-the-protein-in-rice-beans/

And I have a friend who pretty much lived off of beans a rice for months at a time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40171711719.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>Beans *and rice* are complete. Beans on their own are not.

&amp;gt; And I have a friend who pretty much lived off of beans a rice for months at a time

Doesn't mean it's healthy. Like I said, beans and rice are deficient in cobalamin. It's deficient in the following:

* Fat (of all kinds, including essential fatty acids that you will die without)

* Vitamin C

* Zinc (because phytates in rice inhibit zinc absorption)

* Copper (for the same reason as zinc)

* Vitamin D

In fact, your friend was at *serious* risk of developing scurvy during that period if he ate nothing but beans and rice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40171794687.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, I see. Since we were talking about this in the context of chicken and rice, I thought beans and rice together was implied. 

I'm not a dietician - however, looking up the nutritional content of chicken, it doesn't contain any vitamin C, vitamin D, copper, or zinc. So I'm not sure how eating eating chicken instead of beans is suppose to fix those issues. As for fats, my friend typically used olive oil in her cooking.

I don't know why vitamin b12 didn't end up being an issue for my friend. But that seems like a perfectly valid concern without the access and money for things like fortified cereal, nutritional yeast, or other pricey vegan substitutes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40171824167.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hmm, I see. Since we were talking about this in the context of chicken and rice, I thought beans and rice together was implied.

Maybe if you eat the skeletal muscle only, but organ meats are insanely nutritious. A single 100g serving of chicken liver contains:

* 222% of your vitamin A requirements.

* 30% of your vitamin C requirements

* 20% of your B1 requirements

* 105% of your B2 requirements

* 62% of your B5 requirements

* 43% of your B6 requirements

* 276% of your B12 requirements

* 50% of your iron requirements

* 49% of your Niacin requirements

* 25% of your copper requirements

* 18% of your zinc requirements

* 30% of your phosphorous requirements

* 5% of your magnesium requirements.

And it's a complete protein (providing 1/3 of your protein requirements)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40316250167.0" user="HelenEk7" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Okay, I also have no right to be talking about third world countries, but why isn't beans a viable, cheap way of obtaining protein?

Legumes are more expensive than eggs, poultry and pork in low income countries. In mid-income countries eggs are still cheaper than legumes. So only in some of the wealthiest countries legumes is the cheapest protein - with some exceptions; I live in one of the worlds wealthiest countries, and here eggs are cheaper than legumes. (Probably because of our climate - its too cold here to grow most of them)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
