<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40154852040.0" user="thatvampigoddess" delta="False">
    <text>I think that people think it's worse to rape an animal than to kill it because nobody needs to rape an animal to survive but eating is needed to survive.

While it is possible to survive on a diet that excludes meat. It is, in large not very attainable for most people to lead a healthy active life on one. It requires putting effort and thought in what you eat which is not something a lot of people want or can do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40155428129.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>What about people who it is attainable for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158560830.0" user="thatvampigoddess" delta="False">
    <text>I honestly wouldn't know. I know less vegetarian/vegan friends than I can count on one hand where I live and even those don't think it's something you can just hop into and do and most of them transitioned for years until they reached a point where they cut all animal products.

I've asked them and most of them would say to not do it unless you really know what you're doing because you might really mess your body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157016939.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's pretty clear humans don't need meat to survive, something like 1.5 billion of us are vegetarians. This doesn't seem unattainable either, many said vegetarians live in very poor countries and don't have much access to resources, if they can do it, most people can.

Besides, 'need to survive' doesn't reflect how most people seem to eat meat. It's one thing to eat a few servings a week to round out your macros or whatever, but in my experience most people don't do that, and in fact eat meat whenever they think it would taste good without much regard for how much it helps them live a healthy life.

Edit: typo; meet --&amp;gt; meat</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158521683.0" user="thatvampigoddess" delta="False">
    <text>I think that a lot of people either grew up in a culture were vegetarianism is the norm or they just don't know how to do it properly.

You brought up a really good point about survival not playing a huge role for a lot of people which is true I think there are people who would even eat too much.

I think my initial statement still stands as to why eating meat seems to be more ethical in people's minds than rape.
A good amount of people also don't seem to care for animals in general.

I think that raping an animal seems to be more of an issue to some people not necessarily because "oh poor animal" but because the aftermath of what people would think of the human involved. Those usually don't hold much regards for the animal in question but rather boils down to "oh that person is a weirdo" and that seems to be enough to stop some people because they care about their image.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
