<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40154956690.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>What sort of metric or criteria do you have in mind to compare the relative wrongness of two things? It's seems easy enough to say they're both wrong in qualitatively similar ways.

FWIW the externalities of climate impact and food energy waste would also exist for the animals you'd be raping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157068133.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>I'm evaluating wrongness from a utilitarian perspective, ie how much they increase/decrease net suffering.

You make a good point that iff bestiality was as widespread as eating meat it would have much worse externalities. The obvious response here is that is not in fact the case, in times/places where bestiality was legal not that many people seemed to partake, and even where it was more popular it's never been industrialized to the extent meat production has.

But it is probably fair yo consider the least convenient world where people are as enthusiastic about banging animals as eating them. This still seems not as bad to me because animals can be used for sex more times than they can be used for food so you'd need less to provide people with what they want. Also, I imagine conditions would be better/cleaner at least if people are having sex with the animals but that's just speculation on my part.

Either way the point about bestiality having worse externalities if it was more widespread was interesting and I hadn't considered it, I'll give you a delta when I figure out how.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
