<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40159091735.0" user="JenningsWigService" delta="False">
    <text>The issue with comparing rape to the act of killing, whether the victim is an animal or even a person, is that there are some reasons for people to kill that provide them with material benefit, and that's more acceptable than perverse gratification. Meat provides calories for the body, the possibility of veganism can't change that. Rape does not provide something the body absolutely needs. Humans can satisfy sexual urges by masturbating, they cannot summon calories out of thin air. 

There are cases of murder in which people financially profit, and we tend to separate those from murder for sexual gratification. Some murders *aren't* about the pleasure of killing. So someone who shoots someone during a bank robbery is seen as more understandable than Jeffrey Dahmer. *All* rape falls under the Dahmer category. No one financially profits from rape. Rape can never be justified in any circumstance.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
