<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40154898385.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>did any animal consent to be a pet? Is it therefore a form of kidnapping and false imprisonment to keep pets? Anthropomorphizing animals leads to all sorts of issues</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40157102573.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>I agree consent is a bad frame to evaluate what can/can't be done to animals. The reason I mentioned it in my post was because I thought it would be some folk's objection to bestiality, so I wanted to point out it applied to eating meat too.

The reason I think having pets is good (or at least acceptable) but eating meat and bestiality is not is because the former tends to decrease net suffering while the later seems to increase it. It seems to me that the median pet is better off than it otherwise would be, while the median farm animal (or animal used for bestiality) is not, with the later also having all the externalities and negative impacts on humans I mentioned in the post.

I could certainly be convinced that having pets is also bad, but it at the very least it seems not as egregious as murdering or raping animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158228059.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a vegan and I argue with people a lot on the beastiality vs meat eating part its a good gotcha to see if someone is acting bad faith but I get the pet owning one a lot. There's nothing you can do you just have to bite the bullet and say pet ownership is immoral, I can't own pets because it would collapse my belief system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162129053.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this argument will convince very many people, then, since the vast majority of people think it's okay to own pets. You might be able to convince yourself, but I doubt you'll have much luck converting others with this argument. (Fellow vegan here)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162279527.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't quite fleshed my ideas out fully if you could help me but isn't it like once I admit owning pets isn't immoral, then wouldn't I have to concede that beastiality is not immoral since consent from either can't be asked or granted. I think we have different end goals for argumentation I think I have to have it be %100 logical argument while I think you're just more focused on making more people vegan. Not saying there's anything wrong with that pov but like I couldn't make it 100% logical saying owning them is not immoral no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162476051.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have an airtight argument by any means, but I would take a similar tack as OP and argue that owning pets is morally acceptable when it is in the best interest of the pet, even though it cannot be overtly consented to, whereas bestiality is wrong because it can be physically and emotionally damaging to the animal. Anyone who is a cat or a dog owner knows that they often seek out affection and like to play with their owners, clear signs that the relationship is symbiotic, whereas the alternative would be living on the streets without regular food or medical care. On the other hand, while I've never bothered studying animals who are ducked by humans, I think people would agree that most of the time (if not all the time) it is not enjoyable for the animal, and it therefore counts as abuse to even attempt such a thing, regardless of the outcome. Not to mention that stories I've heard about chickens being ducked are pretty... graphic, so it can certainly be physically damaging to smaller animals.

Obviously, when it comes to zoo animals it is much harder to tell if they prefer living in captivity, and in truth I don't have a very strong opinion on this matter one way or the other, but I think zoos are important in saving endangered species whose habitats are disappearing. In these cases, zoos are often the lesser of two evils, though it's genuinely unclear to me if it should be morally acceptable to, say, capture giraffes to put them in captivity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163191497.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think the consent part of the argument still does it for me. Does a pet ever truly consent or is it just placed in a house or environment and lives because that's all it can do is live. I mean you could point to things like tail wagging on dogs to show they are happy but what if someone who partakes in beastiality is going at it with their dog and their tale is wagging, does that then mean it's okay to go ahead and do it. Or like the seeking out part you say they can seek out affection from their owner but what if a dog goes and humps an owners leg, I mean technically they are seeking out something sexual right. Then there is the point where you say its unenjoyable most of the time but what about the times it is enjoyable, does that make beastiality okay in those circumstances. I think most would agree that releasing all pets into the city and starve would be a worse outcome for them, but then you could argue to stop breeding pets and house only the last ones until pet ownership is over. I think the path of argumentation your on probably does more good for the world as a whole because I think it reaches more people like you say, but I'm too autistic for this and I think when you run into someone like me who will run you down this train you'd ultimately lose and have to bite the bullet on pet ownership. Sorry if this doesn't read well I just got off an 11 hour shift, but I appreciate the time you're taking to respond to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163703307.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>First, there's a big difference between consent for sex for one thing and sex for another. With humans, for example, consent for fingerings does not imply consent for penetration, and so to a dog humping their owners leg, while an expression of a desire to hump someone's leg, in no way implies a desire to be ducked.
Second, my position is that because bestiality is most likely not enjoyable for the animal and even downright physically and emotionally damaging, this is enough for it to be abuse. Even though theoretically an animal might enjoy this once it happens, that doesn't excuse the act of initiating it, because you are initiating something which is likely to be traumatizing for the animal. This is true every time bestiality occurs because an animal who enjoyed something once (and was not injured) won't necessarily be into it the second time.
If you think everything which I have said so far is reasonable, then I have presented a coherent world view in which bestiality is bad because it is usually harmful and owning pets is not. You can still dispute that it is okay to own pets without consent, but the point is that I formulated a stance where I claim bestiality is bad but can still reasonably justify my view that owning pets is okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163775991.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What about the inverse of letting the dog duck you, that's purely the intent of the dog is it not? No physical damage it's a completely natural process. The dog is aroused you get naked lie still on the ground and the dog does what it wants, say theoretically you literally just don't move at all so there's absolutely no accountability for you to physically injur or motivate the dog. This would have to he justified in your world view then would it not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163806877.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>I genuinely don't see a moral issue with this. I don't think you would have a moral issue with this, either, since you claim bestiality is wrong because of consent. And I think it's more palatable to say that while weird and probably dangerous for the human, I can't think of a reason why it would be morally wrong to get ducked by an animal, even though I claim that it's morally wrong to duck an animal but morally acceptable to own pets.

Any reason why you ask?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163841998.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No I just lost track of the greater conversation I'm a bit slow I'm just trying to flesh out my ideas more but philosophy is not my strong suit. I think the best way to do this is to argue or discuss things with people online. In the end I might look stupid but it's just an anonymous reddit account so I'm safe to live my life. I got sidetracked looking for a gotcha where you admit to some beastiality being okay because that's funny to me. Sorry about that I don't really have any greater arguments against you though so I think you ultimately won</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40163815301.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But wait letting the dog duck you breaks my original promise of both being immoral due to the lack of consent. I just justified letting a dog duck you in my moral system in real time. Reddit is truly amazing. This also means though that in your moral system letting the dog duck you would also be okay. Brother... what have we done...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
