<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1932623288.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/vymto8/cmv_eating_meat_is_morally_worse_than_bestiality/">
    <title>CMV: Eating Meat is Morally Worse than Bestiality, and it isn't Close</title>
    <original_poster>SortWalk</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems like any reason that bestiality is considered bad applies equally to eating meat. 

It harms the animal? Yeah, so does killing it, turns out. 

The animal didn't/can't consent to it? I've never spoken with a farm animal, but I can't imagine they're very enthusiastic about their predicament. 

It's unnatural? There's nothing natural about 96% of mammal biomass being farm animals, or much else about how we produce and consume meat these days really.

I don't think this is surprising either; murder is typically considered a worse crime than rape, it's unclear to me why a different moral standard should apply to animals.

Eating meat also has much more severe externalities, including:

* Significantly contributing to climate change
* Wasting land and resources by being much less efficient than just eating veggies; it takes 10 calories of feed to produce one of meat
* Horrific worker abuse, especially in meatpacking and adjacent industries

I realize these aren't necessarily intrinsic to eating meat and are more related to factory farming as a practice, but realistically it's how most meat is produced so seems fair to count it as part of the moral impact of eating meat. Besides, even if the meat is organic/ethical/fair trade/whatever, an animal was still killed and mutilated to produce it, so it seems weird to get that upset about someone sticking their dick in said animal instead. 

I don't fuck animals; I do eat meat. Go figure.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40157676542.0" user="Jeff_Bezels" delta="False">
    <text>Consider:

1. Most people who abstain from eating animals do so for consequentialist reasons. You yourself are comparing the consequences of eating meat to beastility.

2. If you think people should take actions that result in less animal suffering, which you do, then you should also apply that standard to the arguments you publicly give to treat animals better.

3. Appearing to argue that beastiality is not so bad to make a provocative comparison between it and meat-eating is unlikely to be persuasive and is likely to be counter-productive to the cause of animal wellbeing.

4. Therefore, you shouldn't do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158228301.0" user="SortWalk" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao fair enough, but I seriously doubt anyone is going to eat more meat or rape more animals (or really change any other behavior) because of this post, so I'm willing to weigh the subjective enjoyment I (and hopefully others!) get from the discussion higher than those marginal effects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40158267061.0" user="Jeff_Bezels" delta="False">
    <text>What if it's a contributing cause? The meat-eaters see the post, maybe it gets cross-posted, and people roll their eyes and think, "crazy vegans," making them less likely to consider the plausibility of the view.

I mean, I'm a vegan and not a consequentialist, so I don't really care. But I think it's worth considering if you think the ultimate aim to be pursued is an overall reduction in animal suffering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162331013.0" user="perceptron3068" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but meat eaters who want to ridicule vegans already have plenty of fodder, and this post gives vegans additional ammunition/talking points when talking to stubborn (but generally intellectually honest) meat eaters.

It also just might spark interesting thought/discussion among people and get them thinking about veganism in a more intellectually rigorous manner? idk now *I'm* talking crazy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40162939396.0" user="Jeff_Bezels" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe. I doubt making provocative comparisons that are relatively easy to push back on is that valuable.

Isaac Bashevis Singer was a Yiddish author and writer about the Holocaust ~~survivor~~ who compared animal farming to the Holocaust. That's *not* a popular position to take in my experience. (I've been vegan for decades and remember campus arguments over PETA's "Holocaust on your plate" campaign.) And that's a comparison that Singer, at least, had some moral authority to make, so it's not completely easy to push back on. I think it's much easier to come up with dissimilarities between rape and killing where someone could argue that animal rape is impermissible but animal killing is permissible.

Also, these arguments are go-nowheres with humans, too. Ever imagine how the argument "which is worse, rape or murder?" would go? Not well.

I think rationally explaining your views, avoiding provocative arguments, and setting a good example are the best ways to go if you want to persuade people to be vegan.

(Edit: I was going off memory to say Singer was a Holocaust survivor, which I learned is wrong. He has written novels where the main characters were involved in the Holocaust, and reflected on the implications of the Holocaust for Judaism. I think not having actually experienced the Holocaust somewhat undermines his moral authority, but that's a tough call. Interesting thinker, nonetheless!)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
