<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40177206570.0" user="brokedown_gotreddit" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that it's not really "painting" in the traditional sense. However, it is art and it is expression. It's valid, but I don't respect it. It doesn't depict anything other than colorful swirls and speckles. It's doesn't paint a picture. It just expresses what the artist thinks looks cool. Which is valid if not basic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40178988412.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>Wait. So it’s only painting if it’s representational? Was Mark Rothko not a painter? Was Thomas Kinckaide a better artist because his paintings convey a thing, not a feeling?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179210192.0" user="brokedown_gotreddit" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between Rothko and splatter painting is that Rothko makes more intentional choices. By the the very nature of splatter painting, the artist leaves a lot to chance. You can't pick and choose where the splatter goes. You can only guide it, which is a valid artform, wherein Intentional choices can be made, just fewer. I never said that a painting has to convey a thing. I just respect it more when it does. Because it's hard to represent a thing with splatter painting. Now. If you could do both, I'd be impressed.

I'm just generally not a fan of modern art. I've seen the blue square. Yes, the drapes are blue. It's all very interpretive. The ideas are vague and lack context. Leaving the viewer to do most of the work. This is perfectly valid, but I think it's more impressive to make a specific idea relatable to many people. I suppose it's a question of internal or external dialogue. It's easy to draw from the self, but to see someone else's perspective is more difficult. If a painting can do guide it's audience to towards an external dialogue, then I'm impressed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179904493.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it is all matter of degrees. If you watch how Rothko painted, he allowed the brush and the canvas to do a lot of the work as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
