<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40176534122.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>I mean any usage of paint is 'wasteful'. We could live without paintings. It feels strange to say that one particular usage of paint is wasteful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40176696208.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>True but pictures and master pieces wouldn't exist. For me it has more to do with how the paint is conserved vs how much is thrown away. If you want to make a splatter paint go ahead. If I see the wall covered in THICK huge blobs of nothing for nothing then ya I'm kinda upset.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40177217978.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>And what happens to other painting types that use 'too much' paint?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40177549115.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really care about style as much as just conservative what you can. Look at the link I provided as an example of what I mean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40177745521.0" user="Frankl3es" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't really care about style as much as just conservative what you can.

The thing is the style itself can very well be excessive use of paint. In the video, those shots of big globs of paint splattering around are a part of the art. If they didn't use a ton of paint, they wouldn't get that same effect. 

There's a lot of art that you can say expends needless resources. Arguably, almost all art is unnecessary and wasteful. I'd want to know how you would differentiate the waste in the video with art installations that cost hundreds of thousands of dollars or expensive Disney CG animation. If you see no distinction, why single out this specific style as wasteful?

At the end of the day, what you're asking to change your view about is a taste (if I'm going by the title alone) which can be impossible to have an argument against. If it's "I don't like this art style" then that's a taste thing and I can't change that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40180835193.0" user="Sad_Basil_6071" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not sure it’a how much paint gets used, as how much gets wasted. Like a ratio of paint used on the canvass vs splattered and spilt everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40178972829.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest, as an artist myself, this all sounds like sour grapes to me. Do art people like if you want to get social media likes. Or don’t. But don’t be salty when people doing commercially-viable styles of work generally get more market attention. It’s always been the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40180140255.0" user="Tcogtgoixn" delta="False">
    <text>what about motor vehicle idling for convenience? at some point resource usage for utility gained becomes too inefficient to be considered acceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40185047972.0" user="brother934" delta="False">
    <text>True asf</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
