<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40176889777.0" user="Sorcha9" delta="False">
    <text>So, let me get this straight, you are trying to gate keep methods of art? 

There is a lot of art that I just don’t like but see the value in what the artist has produced. Personally, I cannot stand watercolor. Basic art history and every class I have taken on the topic emphasizes the acceptance of all expression. I do not like techno music, but appreciate that there is a market for this craft. Same theory. 

I would also point out that Jackson Pollock has a large following for this type of art.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40193184053.0" user="lightacrossspace" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't understand his perspective, the fifties, sixties where all about liberating art. OP wants to bring back the age of repression? Freedom is a core tenet of art. 

OP, you don't have to agree with how other do their art, we all have art we find harder to connect with.  Personally I hated 17th-18th century Dutch paintings until I understood the the boringness was the whole point in an era of turmoil. But dismissing it as bad because you don't like it rather limiting. The world of art is bigger than our own perceptions.

The waste does not really hold, we all have parts of our lives where we are wasteful, and we can all do better, but accusing paint that does not land on a canvas as wasteful compared to if it lands on a canvas in the end it still is used paint. I'd rather we use our cars less or work on food wast that start nitpicking art projects .It is several orders of magnitude more effective.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
