<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40185648595.0" user="WIRblog" delta="False">
    <text>When you work with children between the ages of 6 and 8, you realize how trivial the word waste is because an excessive amount to a 7 year old would be on an entirely different level than what an adult would consider to be excessive.

I watch kids use every single color and...they make a blob. A collage of every single color mixed together. It normally ends up as this greyish purple color on the entire page. I have watched time and time again so many children do this that all I can say at this point is, "Art is subjective...and that is why you must always look for the beauty in it."

There is no such thing as wasteful to a child.

They see the world one way and an adult sees it another.

What there is, is a lot of control.

We think waste implies destruction, but waste is a part of the creation process.

You can't waste the emotions behind a picture, or the movement of your body as you create something with your own hands. You can't waste the energy and focus and motivation. And with each drop that touches the ground you are adding to the experience of life. Life is messy. Life is excess. Life is abundant.

A child cannot see what art isn't because art isn't meant to be controlled. While it may be difficult to change belief systems and reframe waste as necessary. It is important to understand that art is no less a form of expression than the displeasure you have, thought put into words, written within this post.

You see something in art that is not what other people see. You see a need for control. For steadiness. For cleanliness. For order. For security. For preservation.

What a remarkable way to view art.

It is because of these beliefs that you do not view art for pleasure, but you view art for criticism.

You compare forms of expression to climate change.

You liken them because to you, beauty is within the confines of order and harmony.

When there is disharmony, you push back against, and flat out reject it. However, all it does for you is separate you a little bit more from seeing how another person's expression may not be equal to your idea of beauty, but it is in no way equal to disaster.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
