<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40176530805.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, what about those movies that cost hundreds of millions of dollars? From a certain perspective you could also say they are wasting lots of money and resources. Art is in the eye of the beholder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40176679338.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>They do but I'm not talking about movies.  I believe there should be more regulations on them like many things. However most of the things they use such cameras are reusable for long periods. Wasted paint can't be recovered or gathered up again for reuse. It's a one time only thing which is why it shouldn't be thrown around for kicks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40176712378.0" user="phenix717" delta="False">
    <text>But who is to say what is done for kicks and what is not?

Maybe the guy who does splatter paint truly enjoys what he is doing and feels like he is making profound art, while the guy who does realistic paintings is just coldly executing techniques in order to impress other people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40178991783.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>Explain how these regulations would be created and enforced. And explain who gets to decide and why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179075058.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not for regulation. I think that's a crazy level of micromanaging. However social norms/standards are something I believe would work best. Just discouraging the type of use of paint like the girl in the tik tok would work to help a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179141274.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>What? You just said “I believe there should be more regulations on them like many things.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179150510.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>I was referring to movies and other big budget areas (cars, planes, factories, and etc (since that is what you brought up) but not your common paint.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
