<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40176666112.0" user="Tnspieler1012" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;honestly your not really making art.

Of course they are. They are applying creativity to a medium to express ideas. You may not personally like it, or might be unimpressed by it (find it derivative or amateurish), but nothing about being "art" dictates that the artist has to be talented, or that everyone has to find it profound, original, or tasteful.

Which is not to say that I share these points of views. I find paint-heavy works by Jackson Pollock, Mark Rothko, Gerhard Richter, Clyfford Still, Barnett Newman etc. really engrossing and powerful. Minimalism and spontaneity and the allowance for chance expresses ideas and feelings that more realist and subtle works cannot. Most people appreciate rock music, classical piano, dance, and lo-fi hip hop in ways that don't require putting these into a hierarchy (they just have different purposes and things to say).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40176874652.0" user="-paperbrain-" delta="False">
    <text>I also disagree with OP's stance and I agree with you these pieces are art. I'm not sure I would go so far as to say it all applies creativity and expresses ideas. An awful lot of it, is simply copying a method and there's no personal expression intended or delivered, aside from "I can make a thing that looks like the thing that other dude made and maybe get followers/money".

Is it art? Sure, but we're not talking about Pollock or Rothko here, we're talking about people copying a method they see on tiktok, to post elsewhere on tiktok adding nothing. Maybe the first person to make any of these particular methods contributed something.

I'm very much in favor of a huge variety of art and approaches, high art, low art, outsider art, little old ladies trying to paint still lives, teenagers drawing skulls in notebooks. All of that has value.

But the particular trend of pouring paint using the exact method other people use to pour paint to try to become an influencer, I class that differently. I think it contains less thought than the doodles middle managers make in their margins during meetings, and obvious uses many more resources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40177046085.0" user="Tnspieler1012" delta="False">
    <text>I fully take the point about the cynical incentives of certain tiktok artists. I have seen a LOT of kitschy cheap, thoughtless stuff online and in touristy art shops in a variety of styles beyond splashing paint. And if the argument is that many tik-tok artists are crap, then I don't think anyone would disagree. My point was mainly about calling out the specific medium.For the sake of discussion though, I think we have to be careful about contrasting imitation with originality.Anyone who has walked through a baroque or renaissance exhibition knows that famous paintings were frequently repainted, reproduced, and imitated, (and even then, different portraits in the same period were incredibly similar in terms of the materials, geometry, basic technique, genre conventions  etc. compared to those of other eras), and sometimes only in order to make money (nothing necessarilly wrong with that; people need to eat) .

Jacques Louis David made several replicas of "Death of Marat" that now hang in different museums with nothing meaningfully altered. Andy Warhol famously copied and reframed newspaper prints and pop culture portraits, but clearly, going to an Andy Warhol exhibit is a markedly different experience than reading a paper or staring at Elvis. Someone imitating Warhol now might seem super kitschy, but someone might see that as interesting meta-commentary or repurposing.

All to say that, there are different levels of originality e.g. (interpreting or adapting a screenplay vs writing one), but that I would argue that even very derivative works *can be* respected as creative and artistic.

Is that the case on tiktok, probably not. But it can also be the case that a high school student's cheap imitation of Pollock might be really rich and meaningful to them, even if it looks really lame from my perspective. Even an influencer might think that they are doing something beautiful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40179015102.0" user="bongdok" delta="False">
    <text>Well said</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
