<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1936192255.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w0rbi7/cmv_people_that_do_splatter_paint_or_overly_heavy/">
    <title>CMV: People that do splatter paint or overly heavy paint styles are kinda terrible.</title>
    <original_poster>NeonXEExperiment</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm sorry but as an artist and painter it grinds my gears when I see all these tik toks with artist wasting paint. I understand splatter painting to a degree. A few droplets aren't going to kill anybody but when it is just people throwing paint cans and it ect it's ridiculous. It's pretentious and honestly your not really making art. Your making just a mess and it's incredibly wasteful. 

In the age of environmental destruction paint is one of the worst and most toxic things you can emit into the world. There's been multiple articles and studies on how it facilitates climate change and all manner of other issues! If you're going to use a resource like paint use it efficiently!

If you don't you're kind of an ass.

Shit my link wasn't saved. What I mean by wast is this art trend https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRM7gN4y/?k=1</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40183596578.0" user="EmpyreanMiquella" delta="False">
    <text>Ironic of you to call it pretentious yet you can sit there and say it's not really art but a mess.

So here's the thing, something being bad for the enviorment of people doesn't remove it's purpose as being art.

Something not following a method of what you deem to be artistic, doesn't remove it's purpose as art.

Art is subjective, it's based in opinion. You're not the first to do this. You call this a mess. It's still art. Some people call digital art fake and easy, it's still art though. Some people call abstract work that isn't landscapes or portraits to also be fake art, it's still art. And at the end of the day, you're still creating something. Resin is actually far worse for the enviorment in comparison to paint as the majority of resin in modern day is synthetic, oil based, and not natural, in which it causes adverse affects in marine life and humans, leeches toxins into the water systems and enviorment when not disposed of properly. And it's used in a LOT of crafts, readily available.

About paints in the enviorment though, it's entirely dependent on the type of paint for it to cause damage and when you actually do some research, the main paints brought up that cause enviormental damage are:

1.) Heavy metal paints, paints with Lead, which is banned in MANY countries. Primer paint for automobiles called Chromium (Zinc Chromate), but this is rarely used now. Antifouling paint used for boats hulls (this isn't used by artists). 

Another note, the issue with paints was in regards to VOC's which released into the ozone, cause indoor and outdoor breathing issues, allergies, etc. And while we haven't eliminated VOC paints entirely, it IS important to note that when they are talking about paints in our enviorment, VOC from paints refers to architectural paints and oil based paints.

However there are now stricter government regulations and more awareness from consumers, so most paints especially for household use are little to no VOC because they are water based instead of oil, as well as using more natural alternatives. 

So now that we've addressed the enviormental impact, the idea of heavy splatter art comes back full circle to your CMV, which is that the wasteful, messy heavy splatter art is done by terrible people and to that I say:

Are they though? Or do you just want to call them terrible because they aren't following your personal set of rules for usage of art supplies? And is it really any less of an art piece?

The answer is no.

Your dislike of a method isn't a valid reason to determine if something is art or not, and people are not terrible because they want to throw paint all around the room. Art isn't limited to cleanliness and there are no rules to follow. You can hate the style as much as people hate abstract, but your view on it being the act of a terrible person is what you should change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40183790373.0" user="NeonXEExperiment" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps the word terrible is harsh. People are multiple faceted but the waste isn't something that people should be ok with. What I see more often then not with these performances are people doing this stuff for no reason and not really because the method requires it.

What I mean more then anything is wasteful for no real reason. Method doesn't matter if the results are the same. In my example the girl literally sat down and actually traditionally painted but ONLY after she had already thrown multiple cans of paint. 

As I said above I understand splatter paint or even techniques that use a certain level of sculpting. However if the method is messy just for presentation/fun it's not something that should be celebrated. 

I'm not going to pour cans of resin in my backyard and have it uncontained and without direction for "fun". If it's going to be used use it properly. That's the point of this post. Use what you have to make whatever you want but try and be a conscious when you do. 

As for paint it mostly matters the type. Water based paint is far more environmental friendly but for traditional art (like that in the example) mostly acrylic or oils based paints are used. Which depending on the brand and type can worse or better for the environment. Oils have become a bit better overall but acrylics are still lagging. In the end it's the pigments used which are the problem and most people don't use things like natural coloring when they do this stuff.

^Also nice Elden Ring name. I'm excited for the dlc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
