<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1939632337.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/w2t1w1/cmv_triscuits_are_the_best_crackers/">
    <title>cmv: Triscuits are the best crackers</title>
    <original_poster>Cooltific</original_poster>
    <original_post>Triscuits are simply superior to those other “crackers”. Wheat Thins, Ritz, Saltines, Goldfish, Chicken Biscuits, Graham Crackers, etc are all inherently incapable of matching the greatness that is the Triscuit. Think only to this fine cracker’s taste and texture: A strong mix of stringed wheat along with various subtle flavors ranging from garlic to tomato w olive oil to Gouda cheese. It would seem absurd to me to think there’s anything that matches this ALPHA/S-Tier cracker’s obvious dominance in the snack hierarchy! I haven’t even mentioned how well it mixes with meat and cheese. Salami + Sharp White Cheddar + Triscuit is PRETTY good I’ll say! 

(I’m sure this subreddit can appreciate a light and humorous post… And yes I do see triscuits this way.)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40196577747.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>To me, eating Triscuits is like eating wicker furniture with a fair bit of salt on it. They taste like desperation at sea. 

Ritz crackers are light, airy, buttery, wafers of joy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40196625544.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40196692547.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I thought I would have never seen the day where someone of reason such as yourself lended description to my sacred snack as akin to wicker furniture!

This is not my [original observation.](https://cdn.trendhunterstatic.com/thumbs/triscuit-chairs.jpeg?auto=webp) We are legion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40196718742.0" user="Cooltific" delta="False">
    <text>Well now I’m simply scared… Have a good day my man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40196756242.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>For what it's worth, crackers should stand on their own without toppings. [I didn't buy them because they're little edible plates!](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cfqaf7YV580)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40196783620.0" user="Cooltific" delta="False">
    <text>Certain Triscuit flavors are decent stand alone, but not all. I’m not generally a fan of plain crackers (Chicken Biscuits aren’t bad though), but I see the logic certainly. Also lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40199921275.0" user="LucidLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>**Hello /u/Cooltific, if your view has been changed or adjusted in any way, you should award** ***the user who changed your view*** **a delta.** 

Simply reply to their comment with the delta symbol provided below, being sure to include a brief description of how your view has changed.

&amp;gt;∆

or 

&amp;gt; !delta

For more information about deltas, use [this link](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=usertext&amp;amp;utm_name=changemyview&amp;amp;utm_content=t5_2w2s8). 

If you did not change your view, please respond to this comment indicating as such! 

*As a reminder,* **failure to award a delta when it is warranted may merit a post removal and a rule violation.** *Repeated rule violations in a short period of time may merit a ban.* 

Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40202198821.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Cooltific – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 4: 

&amp;gt; **Award a delta if you've acknowledged a change in your view. Do not use deltas for any other purpose**. You must include an explanation of the change for us to know it's genuine. Delta abuse includes sarcastic deltas, joke deltas, super-upvote deltas, etc. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_4).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%204%20Appeal%20Cooltific&amp;amp;message=Cooltific%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/w2t1w1/-/igs16rs/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
