<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27811600577.0" user="Gertiel" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I never lit on this one due to the common usage I see.

Trailer Trash is typically used to designate a specific type of attitude among the people I typically hear using it, never a socioeconomic or racial group. These are people who are racist and bigoted, people who prefer violent solutions, people who have had opportunities to learn or to become informed but willfully refuse. They think people who are accepting of other ideas are delusional and stupid and will stick to their racism, bigotry, and what have you like it is a badge. No trailer involvement in the discussion or in the life of the person it is used about is necessary.

White trash is typically more a polite term for druggie whore. Far back enough, I can recall conversations that started talking about how someone was a druggie whore, and someone would say they were just white trash. Eventually we all just started using it as shorthand.

Now that you point it out, I can see it would be better to maybe not talk about those people, or use a more descriptive term that isn't so misleading.

Edit: I started delete this as I think I'll probably get a lot of downvotes, even though I meant this politely. I genuinely never thought about it, even though I'd never use the word "ghetto" due to exactly what you'd expect. These terms have evolved as a label for specific attitudes and behaviors in my area, so I never thought about the origins as maybe I should have. I'm glad OP brought it up, I feel like I've had my view changed. I'm new here. I try to be a good person. I did not expect to have my view changed this quickly here and I'm rather impressed with this whole sub as a result. 

Cheers all!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
