<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809569097.0" user="funchy" delta="False">
    <text>Being white trash is defined by behavior not by race or gender.     I know of white low income people who work hard, value school, and have good manners.  And I know some not so poor whites who you'd think were white trash by how they speak and act, and it comes as a shock to see them living in a clean $600k home.  Since there's overlap between whitetrash and rednecks in my semi rural area,  we just call them "hicks with money".    Money, especially new money,  does not buy class! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809841469.0" user="macrocephalic" delta="False">
    <text>A common phrase in Australia is 'cashed up bogan'.  Someone who has come into some money, but spends it on beer and doing up their ute (truck), probably holidays in Bali.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810281327.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>What is bogan?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811350702.0" user="macrocephalic" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bogan</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811728858.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A similar argument is made by David Nichols, author of The Bogan Delusion (2011), who says that people have "created this creature that is a lesser human being to express their interclass hatred".[16]

Oh.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
