<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809194800.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs.

All I can say against your view is that this is the reason it *hasn't* been dropped from common vernacular in the same way that many other bigoted/racist slurs have. 

However, as someone who frequents the dreaded "SJW" circles, let me tell you that these kinds of statements are viewed as similarly despicable. There aren't targeted campaigns against the terms' removal because of the (lack of) history you mention, but as our culture becomes more sensitive and educated about respecting identity, terms like these will fall out of practice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809204839.0" user="JSmurfington" delta="False">
    <text>You are probably correct.  Of course, the history of poor whites in this country is extensive, but the term white trash is not on the level of other slurs in terms of a historically oppressive term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809377610.0" user="berrieh" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I think the term "white trash" is offensive against non-whites more than the actual people you're labeling; it suggests the default state of "trash" (as people) are non-whites. As such, I sort of agree with you, but also sort of disagree with your reasoning. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810254231.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>No, it suggests that the defaut state of "whites" is "affluent."  Nothing about the default state of "trash."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810412390.0" user="chillin223" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but it implies that if you're white you should be acting better then that. If you're "white trash" you're acting below you're expected "level" of behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
