<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27812780018.0" user="Pleb-Tier_Basic" delta="False">
    <text>I was born into a 'white trash' area and grew up with 'white trash'; However, I'm not white trash; I got out as soon as I could and haven't looked back.

One thing I came to realize is that being white trash has nothing to do with economic class and is only marginally related to race. Being white trash is a lifestyle, and after a certain age, it's a lifestyle you choose to stay in. 

Being white trash is intentionally drunk driving, as a form of entertainment. Being white trash is brewing your own moonshine. Being white trash is working on a farm, and calling the Mexican farmhands "beaners". Being white trash is receiving farm subsidiaries and continually voting rightwing. Being white trash is threatening to beat your wife. Being white trash is having a beer gut at 22. Being white trash is getting high before work. Being white trash is driving everywhere. Being white trash is dating highschoolers. Being white trash is driving a pickup truck. Being white trash is knowing dozens of truckers. Being white trash is loitering in McDonalds. Being white trash is being proud of working at said McDonalds because it's one of the only honest jobs in town. Being white trash is growing dope in your parent's backyard. Being white trash is hanging out in garages all the time. Being white trash is drinking a 24 of Coors Light in a night. Being white trash is spending your entire life around the same 500 people, all of them also white trash. Being white trash is speeding everywhere. Being white trash is burning crosses on front lawns. Being white trash is gossiping about every little thing. Being white trash is never leaving your little town, unless it's to camp or hunt. Being white trash is never leaving this lifestyle, even when you can. 

This has nothing to do with economics. Many of the people I now know to be white trash come from stable, dual income families. Many had every opportunity  to leave, and didn't. Some even left, just to come running back a few months later. This isn't to say all white trash people have money; many are dirt poor and stuck in this lifestyle. But the assumption that socioeconomics are solely responsible isn't 100% accurate. 

I guess what I'm getting at is that is that, imo, while white trash is a slur, I don't think it's fair to categorize it as a racial or bigoted slur. Being white trash is a lifestyle, not a circumstance forced on a person by socioeconomics or racial discrimination.

To look at it from a different angle, one can be a poor white person living in the country, and not be white trash. One can be a rich white person living in the city and still be white trash. White trash is a state of mind.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
