<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809247765.0" user="ablanchard17" delta="False">
    <text>The simple fact is that it's *not* an offensive slur that society doesn't tolerate. Or on the same level as any other slur we have.

Drop the N word in public, and people will be looking at you. Even if you weren't saying the word at someone, or in description of someone. (For example if you were just talking about the history of the word itself). Just hearing the word at all will shock people.

We have decided as a society that the N word is very very serious and isn't tolerated.

the phrase "white trash" simply does not have the *power* of the N word.

People will not be shocked to hear "white trash" 

It's just not the same. And it never will be.

Yes, by definition it is a racial bigoted slur. But it simply doesn't have the historical relevance or seriousness as other slurs we have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809263989.0" user="kingswee" delta="False">
    <text>This only holds water _at this time_ and assumes that pur conceptualizations of slurs won't change. There was a time when the n word was spoken freely and wasn't seen as offensive by most people. The same with retard and faggot. Society's value changes and the language it uses changes accordingly. The fact that people use the word (relatively) freely right now isn't a convincing reason to think that isn't offensive or shouldn't be changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809301932.0" user="ablanchard17" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This only holds water at this time and assumes that pur conceptualizations of slurs won't change.

Yes. I said what I said because I think the OPs title really means 
"Saying "white trash" should be as serious as saying the N word"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809313078.0" user="kingswee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I said what I said because I think the OPs title really means 
"Saying "white trash" should be as serious as saying the N word"

In the body of OP's argument he specifically mentions that is not and will probably never be the case.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809383345.0" user="ablanchard17" delta="False">
    <text>That's the message I got. That's the message I responded to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
