<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809602554.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it doesn't seem as bad to me because the racial part isn't the insult. Calling someone "trash" is very explicitly an insult. Calling someone **white** trash doesn't really add to the insult. It's never been a word that paints an entire race with a broad brush. It's clearly not a knock on white people in general, and it doesn't even apply to all poor white people. It's just such a specific type of person that it describes,  and the insulting part of it is so overt. I mean, it's definitely disparaging, but I don't see it in the same class as racial slurs </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810720672.0" user="fathionitha" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine calling a black person living in a trailer park black trash. Same scenario, much more uproar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810740398.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that's just it though. I have a hard time imagining that, because I can't imagine why anyone would ever say that, especially without more context. It's just a bizarre thing to say. I think it would be met more with puzzled looks than outrage. The phrase doesn't evoke anything besides the two words that make it up. Calling a black person black isn't weird. Calling a person trash is mean, but not racially charged. Combining the two into the phrase "black trash" doesn't really *mean* anything to anyone, because no one says that. 

So I don't think your analogy really works. For example, the phrase "monkey business" means something beyond just the definitions of its constituent words. But if I instead utter the phrase "alligator business", there's no way to interpret that other than a business related to alligators. The two phrases are just understood in fundamentally different ways due to one of them having meaning as a *phrase* while the other is just a pair of words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811902322.0" user="ababypenguin" delta="False">
    <text>I think that by specifying that they're "white" trash implies that it's something special for white folks to be trash, so it's sort of a put down for non white folks as well</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811921630.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>Totally! I agree that in a sense, "white trash" is almost more derogatory towards black people than it is to the actual subject of the phrase. But in a different and more indirect way than a typical "slur". But honestly, I don't think the modern usage of the phrase really implies that. The origins are sketchy, but I think "white trash" evokes a very specific image, and doesn't generally evoke any imagery about non-white people unless you really think about it and dig into the etymology.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
