<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809350352.0" user="XxX420noScopeXxX" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree that based purely on logical standards, "white trash" is just as bad as any other racial epithet. However, I think the reason most people don't find it offensive is because white people tend to focus less of their self identity on race. 

When I see people talk about how evil or greedy white people are, my reaction is something like "Eh, if I was in their shoes I'd probably feel the same way." Now if you say something like "Oklahoma is a shithole." I will be offended. I love my state, I've grown up here and it's part of my identity.


If nobody is offended, then there isn't really an impetus to change it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809421342.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I had someone leave a restaurant screaming at (someone, might have been me, I don't remember) who used that term (and not even about them, just used it to refer to, well... white trash). 

So I'd say that we on reddit might not be the demographic that is likely to be offended by such a term, but that doesn't mean no one is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809429239.0" user="XxX420noScopeXxX" delta="False">
    <text>My bad, I didn't mean literally nobody.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
