<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809206527.0" user="Philitian" delta="False">
    <text>OP, before I would like to tackle changing your view, I would assume that you also hold a similar sentiment for the word "ghetto" being used to denote poor conditions of a black neighborhood? Am I correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809215740.0" user="JSmurfington" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, "ghetto" can definitely be used as a slur against blacks and those of a certain socioeconomic status.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809245828.0" user="Philitian" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. There's a memoir by Langston Hughes I read a while back in which he stated that his dad would constantly say to his children "don't be a nigger!" Among the black race there are distinctions between uneducated and rowdy people and, well, upper-middle-class folk like the Hughes. 

By the same logic, a middle class black can say about another family "they're ghetto" and easily transcend race lines to further their status in society as better educated people. My dad did this *all the time* with my neighbors who he called "white trash" because, well, it was a household with a lot of teen pregnancies and a messy yard. These are people in the same neighborhood, with similar incomes, but through creating a distinction based upon their appearance one can be separated from the other.

This therefore allows individuals to consider themselves at a higher status in society through appearances alone, which is a point of motivation when a good job or good income doesn't make the distinction. So if we as a society continue to associate sloppy appearances with wealth, one can imagine himself better off by simply appearing "neater" rather than actually richer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809498169.0" user="pm-me-uranus" delta="False">
    <text>And you find this an acceptable means to raise one's status in society? Even if it does simply come down to name-calling?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809593402.0" user="chronolockster" delta="False">
    <text>What? It's limited to race? I've always known it to refer to location  (neighborhood) or behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
