<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809219179.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>True or false: some people fit the stereotype perfectly?

If true, then give me a alternate term to use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809281818.0" user="SkyrocketDelight" delta="False">
    <text>True.

Careless Consumers of Crap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809309275.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>That's closer to "Americans". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809667988.0" user="very_old_guy" delta="False">
    <text>I believe the accepted alternative these days is "underprivileged".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809797311.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>There's a huge difference between "underprivileged" and "white trash". You're kinda making my point for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809862096.0" user="very_old_guy" delta="False">
    <text>And you're making mine for me.  Not sure if you're doing it intentionally, but if so then you get bonus points for subtlety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810091675.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>You can be underprivileged and behave in exemplary ways without being white trash. You can be rich and behave in intolerable ways and be white trash.

Underprivileged doesn't work and has nothing to do with it, it is how you act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27814462322.0" user="very_old_guy" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for clearing that up.  So, can you think of any socially acceptable terms similar to "white trash" that apply to other races?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27814720129.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I don't think this is racial slur to begin with, it's associated with a specific kind of person and they happen to be white. Because culture and race are so closely linked it can be hard to tell the difference if we try to differentiate at all. 

Similarly anybody can be ghetto even if minorities make up the majority of that group. People associate the terms with race and I think that is a mistake because it is a correlating factor but not a causal one. 




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27814813148.0" user="very_old_guy" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, that's fair.  "White trash" and "ghetto trash" are probably on about the same level when it comes to demeaning a person.  Back to OP's point, it's hard to see how *both* of these are not offensive slurs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27814858455.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>They are absolutely offensive slurs I agree with you, I guess it depends what the OP means by "tolerate". 

They are also accurate ways to talk about certain cultures or actions. If I call a pedophile a sick pervert the, "sick pervert" part is an offensive slur but accurate because I don't agree with his actions.

Likewise if you act trashy I think we should be pointing that out in an effort to get people to stop/ discourage others from acting that way. Sometimes slurs are needed to get people's attention and I don't think they are inherently bad.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
