<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809210582.0" user="jwil191" delta="False">
    <text>what about just "trashy"? Is that too offensive to use? 

Some people are just trashy fucking people, who do trashy things. It has way more to do with people's action than anything else</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809214234.0" user="JSmurfington" delta="False">
    <text>I think "trashy" is used in a different context than "white trash". Trashy is just a (not very nice) pejorative that can be applied to anyone.  White trash is a very specific slur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809505057.0" user="pm-me-uranus" delta="False">
    <text>This brings up an interesting point. You wouldn't say "black trash" or "asian trash" or "latino trash". They just don't have quite the same connotation as white trash.

Though I still wouldn't quite compare it to other bigoted terms like nigger, or faggot. In fact, I daresay that no phrase can be deemed bigoted if it doesn't have at least one 'g' in it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809596840.0" user="epic93" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; no phrase can be deemed bigoted if it doesn't have at least one 'g' in it.

Wetback. Redskin. Beaner. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809712356.0" user="pm-me-uranus" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. Not bigoted at all. I don't see any g's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809848801.0" user="TheGreatNorthWoods" delta="False">
    <text>Because black trash, in the logic of slurs, sounds redundant. You can say stop acting black, or stop acting trashy, and mean the same thing. White trash is a slur, but it's one where the people that it's directed at need to be split from the larger group they might be a part of. Acting white and acting trash are not synonyms, so white trash isn't redundant.

I don't endorse these stereotypes, I'm just trying to explain how they work. Also, now I'm sad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810080791.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can say stop acting black, or stop acting trashy, and mean the same thing.

WOW, I would never say that about anybody, I might say stop acting trashy but I would never say stop acting (insert race).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810284837.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>Well plenty of people would and do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810405663.0" user="TheGreatNorthWoods" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, don't get me wrong, neither would I - but it doesn't mean people don't say it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809796073.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>To me there is a significant difference between white trash and trashy, which makes agree with OP more than I originally thought.


You don't say black trash or Asian trash or whatever it is because it's not a special case. Mentioning that trash is black is like mentioning that a tiger is orange. It's just assumed, it at least it was when the phrase came into use. If you want to talk about the rarer white tiger you have to call it out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810215404.0" user="jwil191" delta="False">
    <text>You don't say Asian trash or black trash because it doesn't roll off the tongue well. We have different insults for them </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810275570.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>That is completely arbitrary. If you had grown up saying black trash instead you'd probably feel the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
