<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="196041139.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/38pub7/cmv_white_trash_is_an_offensive_slur_and_should/">
    <title>CMV: "White trash" is an offensive slur, and should not be tolerated in society just as we do not tolerate other bigoted slurs.</title>
    <original_poster>JSmurfington</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has bothered me for a while. The term "white trash" or "trailer trash" fits all the criteria for being a slur which should not be widely acceptable for use. But I have heard the term dropped casually in conversation, and no one seems to treat it like the slur that it is.

It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status. It is meant to be derogatory. This to me is the definition of a bigoted term.

I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27809251832.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>The "white" part of this slur is not a slur toward whites.  The point is that they are trash, and white is thrown in there to say that they are trash *even though they are white.*  

So the offensive part of the phrase is "trash."  Now is that bigoted?  It's certainly an insult, but it's not inherently bigoted.  

If you say "poor white trash" that's offensive and bigoted, but only because it is associated with poverty and the poor.  Without "poor," it's not a *bigoted* slur.

Furthermore, even terms that are intended to insult whites rarely provoke outrage, because, as a group, at least in the U.S., whites have not been an underclass.  [As comedian Louis CK says](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6CmzT4OV-w0), "cracker" takes him back to owning land and people.  So you can't equate "cracker" and the "n" word.  You can't even put them in range of each other, they are different in kind, because of the history of abuse brought up by the "n" word, and the history of privilege brought up by the word "cracker."  

So, the term "white trash" is not inherently bigoted, and even if it were it cannot be equated to the "n" word, it's not even in the same ballpark.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809258858.0" user="Mahnogard" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The "white" part of this slur is not a slur toward whites. The point is that they are trash, and **white is thrown in there to say that they are trash even though they are white**.

(bold mine)

So then, wouldn't that mean it's a slur toward non-whites? Sort of saying, "You're as trashy as (insert non-white group here)"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809262440.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know any non-whites who take offense to the term?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809283598.0" user="Mahnogard" delta="False">
    <text>No, but then, I'm pretty sure I've never personally heard it said in front of them to gauge a reaction. 

However, the OP states:
&amp;gt;It is a term that denigrates and stereotypes a group of people based on their race, appearance, and socioeconomic status.

I don't think your analysis of the term refutes the above in any way. It's still a slur that fits the quoted description. It ties race and socioeconomic traits into an insult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809808500.0" user="MrJebbers" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who is a minority, when some people get really mad, they will use the fact that you are a minority as an insult. So calling someone white trash ties them not just to poor, rural, white people, but also to a person that would use that insult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809817977.0" user="coolasafool462" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely have heard black people taking offense to the word because, as you said, it implies that other races, particularly black people, are inherently trashy but only a small subset of white people are trashy. they believe it supports the idea of white supremacy as opposed to being directly directly demeaning towards other races</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809895292.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Simple reductio. "Barack Obama is black subhuman garbage" Forget honestly, can you even assert with a straight face that that sentence is offensive to Asians because it implies non-Blacks are inherently subhuman?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810326811.0" user="coolasafool462" delta="False">
    <text>that's a bad comparison, though. we're talking about a very common description that is being used, and I'm referring specifically to the context in which the word came about. I'm not arguing that this relationship exists at a semantic level, but a cultural one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810473552.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think Occam's Razor makes that explanation unlikely. I would be more inclined to buy that if ALL poor ill-behaved white people were described accordingly. As it stands it only refers to poor rural white southerners. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809895490.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Simple reductio. "Barack Obama is black subhuman garbage" Forget honestly, can you even assert with a straight face that that sentence is offensive to Asians because it implies non-Blacks are inherently subhuman?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810084431.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>I kind of see where you are coming from but that is pretty insane that one race would get offended over a pejorative meant for another race.

That is assuming that "black" and "white trash" are on the same level and they just aren't.

Many times a simple description of a person, "This black guy came in and donated 50 bucks." is not even close to the same thing as saying, "This white trash person came in and donated 50 bucks."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810328087.0" user="coolasafool462" delta="False">
    <text>I'm referring to where the term comes from</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810332652.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>Are you assuming that the term arose in comparison to other races or is that proven somewhere?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809788674.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>It's more to say that normally we would be talking about some minority if we just said trash, so you need to tack white on there so no one gets confused.


That doesn't mean all non white people are trash, just that all trash are non white people... except for the special case of whoever it us we're talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809893875.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This is the problem with "Ideology" in the sense of Kenneth Minogue. It is a set of rules that wherever they are applied, always reach one predetermined conclusion, that domination is occuring.


Simple reductio. "Barack Obama is blach subhuman garbage" Forget honestly, can you even assert with a straight face that that sentence is offensive to Asians because it implies non-Blacks are inherently subhuman?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810141663.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with this comparison is that people don't usually call *anyone* "subhuman garbage". There's no need to let everyone know that we're talking about problematic white people, for once. If "subhuman garbage" were to become as widely used as "trash" it would then have built up its own connotations that need to be overcome when using it in a different way.

"White lie," "white hat cracker” (as opposed to the criminally minded cracker), "brown rice," "white collar crime" "white/dark chocolate"... These are all examples of things that invoke the wrong assumptions and imagery without the additional hint. It changes the meaning of the main word. "Black subhuman" and just "subhuman" don't mean different things the same way "dog" and "brown dog" don't mean different things. Contrast with "my friend" and "my black/white friend." Where the latter is only used by people who only have one and are talking to people who probably have none and need them to understand that that the person they are imagining is not black/white, despite being a friend.

I think in modern usage "white trash" has become the default, see /r/trashy, but certainly when the phrase came into usage this was not the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810291456.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's true though. "Brown dog" is a synthetic statement. Contained in my idea of "Dog" is not necessarily "brown". If that were so, the negation "no dogs are brown" would be not empirically false but actually logically incoherent, much like saying "there exists a married bachelor". I have added to my conception of a particular dog "brown".

White trash refers not to any poor white person engaged in socially unacceptable behaviors but to a very specific variety, generally poor rural southeners. I never heard Eminem called white trash, for example. The reason to add "white" is because there are a lot of non-southern, non-rural "trash" of all races, where "trailer trash" is nearly universally white, so the only thing which differentiates this particular variety of trash from others is not that they are white, but exclusively white. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809799063.0" user="MrJebbers" delta="False">
    <text>It's not racist to acknowledge the real racial power structure that still exists in our country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27810087108.0" user="oversoul00" delta="False">
    <text>No, not in the least, it is simply a non racially driven slur and that is why the white part is added. If the term was just trash nobody would know if you meant ghetto or redneck or whatever. Anyone can be trashy but white trash is a specific breed of trashy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809550043.0" user="the_television" delta="False">
    <text>So it's actually a compliment!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809566843.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>Not really, but "that's mighty white of you" was once considered a compliment.  Now it's considered in bad taste, a remnant of colonialism and perhaps racism (although it's not clear it was originally referring to race).  Still, it's not considered a racial slur, even if it is considered vaguely racist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809785137.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>I had an old lady say this to me when I held a door for her. It would have been cute if it hadn't been depressing. I'm not white, but I sure can try!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809930954.0" user="Uneje" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So the offensive part of the phrase is "trash." Now is that bigoted? It's certainly an insult, but it's not inherently bigoted.
&amp;gt; If you say "poor white trash" that's offensive and bigoted, but only because it is associated with poverty and the poor. Without "poor," it's not a bigoted slur.

The implication is 'poor'. That's like saying "wetback isn't a slur unless you say *Mexican* wetback" or "faggot isn't a derogatory unless you say *homosexual* faggot". It's part of the very definition. See the second urban dictionary definition of white trash (the first is just an insult towards Paris Hilton):

&amp;gt; Slang term for white people that usually live in a trailer park with low incomes...

So you can see that even though "poor" isn't explicitly part of the term, it is part of the definition and is how the word is most commonly used.

&amp;gt; even terms that are intended to insult whites rarely provoke outrage, because, as a group, at least in the U.S., whites have not been an underclass

Like you said, it's not about being white, it's about being poor despite their race.

&amp;gt; So, the term "white trash" is not inherently bigoted, and even if it were it cannot be equated to the "n" word, it's not even in the same ballpark.

OP never claimed it could be equated with the n word. See:

&amp;gt; I'm not arguing that the term has as much history behind it as other racial or bigoted slurs. But in our modern society, we should still abandon the term altogether.

They only think that it should be abandoned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27809970094.0" user="jesuslovesmeslowly" delta="False">
    <text>I used to agree with you, but now I don't. I think white trash is a derogatory term for a specific cultural group (namely poor rural, largely southern, whites). The history of bad blood between those sorts of people and and northern (now coastal, really) elite-types has been going on since before the Civil War. So it's still a slur, close to the term hick, and should be considered in offensiveness to hick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811567163.0" user="RU_Crazy" delta="False">
    <text>So "black thug" wouldn't be a racial epithet in your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811610803.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>Would you consider "white thug" to be a racial slur?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811931869.0" user="RU_Crazy" delta="False">
    <text>No</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811967310.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose "black thug" could be considered a racial slur if you inferred that the two were being linked, i.e., "just another black thug" would definitely be a racial slur.  But I would not consider "the thug who robbed me was black" to be inherently racist.  Therefore, I can't really say whether "black thug" would be a racial epithet without some context.  Which I suppose means it isn't, unless the context makes it so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811983158.0" user="RU_Crazy" delta="False">
    <text>The point was many people do find that to be a racial slur.  So its a double standard

Personally,

1. I don't find either "white trash" or "black thug" to be bigoted
2.  I don't think any words should be totally off limits 

This isn't kindergarten.  Having your feelings hurt doesn't mean shit to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27811988385.0" user="wjbc" delta="False">
    <text>I think many people find "black thug" to be a racial slur either because of the context, or because they infer the context, i.e., "*just another* black thug" is inferred.  And I suppose there are people who consider "white trash" to be a slur against the poor, with "*poor* white trash" inferred.  

It's hard to control inferences, or to contradict subjective reactions.  "You find that offensive?  Okay, I can't dispute that you find that offensive.  But that doesn't mean it is, objectively, offensive."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
