<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344051610.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, objectively, having any sort of college degree raises your earning potential. There is no such thing as an 'unusable major'. This is literally statistics. Most people don't have jobs that are directly in their degree's field of study anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344181974.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you that it's useful but I think you are mistaken about the stats. Just because studies show that people with any degree get higher pay potential doesn't mean every person with a degree with get higher pay potential.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344233007.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>No, but I never said they did. Just getting a degree means you're more likely to get more money. It doesn't matter what the degree is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344577270.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>No getting a degree does not necessarily make you more likely to get more money. Do you know of any studies backing that idea?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344821248.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>It can't account for correlation vs causation, but [the lowest-paid majors](https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d19/tables/dt19_505.06.asp) had a median income of about $45k ($40k for early career, age 25-34) in 2018, compared to [about $35k](https://www.bls.gov/careeroutlook/2018/data-on-display/education-pays.htm) for high school graduates at the time (all ages).  So about a $10k/year premium for *the lowest-paid* degrees (it's over $20k for the median graduate).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346393832.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>That's a pretty interesting thanks for sharing. Like you said the causation isn't proven so my guess is that people who tend to get any degree, get higher paying jobs and do better in the workplace but not necessarily because they have those degrees. Still the data you showed does make me question it a bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347816652.0" user="theantdog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;my guess is that people who tend to get any degree, get higher paying jobs and do better in the workplace but not necessarily because they have those degrees

That's a bizarre guess. Jobs requiring degrees generally pay more. Wouldn't that be a more reasonable and demonstrably true explanation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348979297.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Not all jobs do though. Lots of degrees are not directly used or required by jobs. The argument the person above was saying was that any degree improves the money you will make. 
I was specifically talking about degrees in which lots of people get them but not many people actually use them in the workplace.
For most degrees the degree is directly applicable so what I said is partially true but the value of the degree is probably a bigger factor in getting paid more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345342831.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.bls.gov/emp/chart-unemployment-earnings-education.htm

Median income increase is $24k a year for degree holders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346370883.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>That does not imply "getting any degree means you're more likely to get more money" it implies "people with degrees make more on average than non degree holders".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346378251.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No getting a degree does not necessarily make you more likely to get more money. 

Except it does, as the stats have borne out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346430755.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what the statistics prove. There is a big difference between people with any degree tend to make more money and getting a degree will likely increase your income. The causation is not proven by the stat and so we can not know if the people with degrees getting paid more would have been paid more even if they never got those degrees.  
It's like if I said that people who scored 130+ on IQ tests make more money. Is it actually taking the test that is increasing the money made or would they still have made that extra money if they never took an IQ test. There is a selection bias when talking about people getting degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347827539.0" user="theantdog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There is a big difference between people with any degree tend to make more money and getting a degree will likely increase your income. 

Please explain this big difference. The truth of the matter is that with a degree an individual will have more career options and, on average, earn a lot more money over the course of their career.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348984496.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>I did explain the difference. You do not have causation so the second statement is not verified while the first is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349958580.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; doesn't mean every person with a degree with get higher pay potential.

It pretty much does, depending on what you mean by "potential".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350154261.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>People who wear expensive clothing have higher average pay than people who do not. Does that mean that getting expensive clothing will raise your pay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350217543.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>It may well... as people with nice looking clothing are viewed by employers as better employees... same with college. 

But this really isn't just a correlation or a fashion statement. 

It's known that most decent paying jobs have a degree (any degree, actually) as a requirement, whether they "should" or not... but I'll argue they should:

That's because succeeding at college is a *strong* indicator that you can focus over the long term, make accomplishments, plan your time, be a self-starter, and learn effectively... and that someone is willing to test and certify that, and bet their reputations on doing it well... unlike prior employment records or anything else the prospective employer has reliable and non-biased access to. 

Now, if you could find *another* certification scheme where companies could be pretty sure you could do those all of those vital business tasks reliably for years... 

That could potentially replace college... but it's going to be very *similar* to college anyway.

(Note: in the trades, a successful apprenticeship does the same thing... they managed to find such a "certification" scheme that also works for that... and I'm not saying that's a bad alternative to college... it's just never going to be the majority of jobs, and you are locked into a pretty specific trade, so it's not as *generally* useful... also, if you think *colleges* have a nepotistic aspect to them, you haven't seen anything compared to how nepotistic trade apprenticeships are)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350673236.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Does trhat earning potential outweigh the amount of debt most people put themselves in? If i can make 40k with no college but have no debt vs 100k with college but 200k compounding debt, then some math is clearly required to determine if and when the benefit ouutweighs the cost. Not to mention, once youre in that debt, it’s difficult to switch your career if you have a change of heart whereas no debt allows for this freedom and flexibility</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40362210309.0" user="pdoherty972" delta="False">
    <text>Average debt at graduation is 30K.  Average grad makes 900K more over their working career.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40363334987.0" user="zacker150" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;i can make 40k with no college but have no debt vs 100k with college but 200k compounding debt, then some math is clearly required to determine if and when the benefit ouutweighs the cost. 

If these are the numbers, going to college is a no-brainer. 

Let's put it this way. You could go to college, live off the 40k you would have otherwise made as a high school graduate, and pay off your debt in 4 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371014899.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>My numbers were just arbitrary, they weren't based off any real numbers</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
