<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344938810.0" user="nighttimecharlie" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps not the right sub, but I'm so sick of people saying Liberal arts degrees are unusable or worthless. Social sciences are so necessary for the functioning of society that if everyone just studied pure sciences or finance, society would crumble. HR as much as we love to hate them, are necessary for companies unless the CEO is going to trawl through CVs, gender studies degrees can lead to many fascinating careers in and outside academia.  

Just because you know one person who works as a barista and perhaps they prefer the world of coffee and seek to climb the ladder utilising their degree in gender studies to promote female coffee growers, importers, roasters or to research on the impact of the coffee industry in the source countries- how cultivating coffee cherries keeps men in the country rather than having men travel for work. This is all work that can be done with a degree in gender studies and work experience as a barista. But who knows, maybe this person just likes to work in a cafe, why are you judging what someone is doing with their life. 

Educators push for people to pursue higher education because they work in education and want to see their students further their education. While not all students need or should pursue university degrees since trades and service jobs are just as good, educators should make this distinction. Universities are places where so much learning goes on, and not only in the classroom. We learn to manage our time, deadlines, our personal and professional goals. We might even engage in some introspection,  whether or not the degree we are pursuing is right for us. Of course, I'm not American so we don't go into thousands of dollars of debt to pursue education,  but education whatever degree we do is a good investment if we can use it in our lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348520663.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>I think the main issue is that there usually isn’t a straight forward career path with a lot of liberal arts studies. For example, a major in accounting means that you pass the classes, pass the CPA exam, and then apply to work at a company as an accountant. It’s pretty linear with minimal networking and internships necessary (not to say it’s an easy degree at all or that internships don’t give you a competitive edge). 

A degree in Art History or Women’s Studies, however, isn’t so linear. Aside from your coursework, you have to network within the community, find internships or relevant jobs while studying to gain experience in a particular field, and gain an understanding of how you want to use your degree. For example, Art History majors can go into design, Art restoration, or work in an Art Museum. And these are all jobs that directly deal with an Art History degree. This isn’t accounting tangential careers where Art history would be a beneficial degree to have but isn’t an obvious choice. 

I might be wrong on both accounts since I’m not pursuing any of the mentioned degrees, however this is my understanding of the greatest “flaw” with liberal arts degrees. It’s not that they’re useless, it’s that the path to a successful career isn’t as linear as medical school, engineering, accounting, programmer, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348750065.0" user="Random_Guy_12345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It’s not that they’re useless, it’s that the path to a successful career isn’t as linear as medical school, engineering, accounting, programmer, etc.

The main problem is indeed not that they are useless, they are not. The main problem is that they are oversaturated. And not by small amounts, in those fields supply is _way_ over demand. 

That means people with those kind of degrees end up working on something completely unrelated, thus making the degree seem useless. And i must admit that, if you consider education to be just "A way to get a job", you are right calling those degrees "useless".

There is also the tangential issue where with STEM graduates you can objectively assess who is doing a better job as those fields tend to have correct solutions you need to arrive at. Art is subjective. Is Mona Lisa a better or worse painting that Starry Night? No objective way to measure it. Nothing you can point at and say "This particular painting is definitely better than that one"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349270923.0" user="nighttimecharlie" delta="False">
    <text>In STEM there is room for debate and subjectivity. This debate fuels more research. I think if studying sciences were more accessible, there might be a similar saturation to arts degrees. But right now, in many countries the allocation given to PhD students is abysmal, and the hours of work they do is akin to a miner. Then there is the problem with networking and marketing yourself so your research can be funded or you can join a prestigious lab. Academia probably won't change and therefore many people who would have liked to work in a field of science are working in other fields because there aren't enough jobs, there's not enough money in research to pay living wages until you climb up the corporate lab ladder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350951636.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>I honestly don’t believe accessibility is a huge issue for a lot of STEM degrees. STEM students usually take on very complex and niche jobs that are hugely necessary in our advancing society. That means a lot of companies are willing to pay for your education—at the very least on the masters level. I would imagine maybe a degree in Mathematics or Applied Mathematics has a harder time getting funded at the PhD level because there aren’t as many directly translatable jobs that arise from that degree. But a PhD in Chemical Engineering??? Or Statistics (mainly Quality Control or Biostatistics)??? I would imagine there’s a lot of funding for those degrees because the skills learned are directly translatable in the work force.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351577110.0" user="nighttimecharlie" delta="False">
    <text>Postgraduate, PhD candidates and master students all work insanely long hours for very little pay. Even while working  for prestigious institutions or laboratories. Most PhD students make under minimum wage. How does one afford to work long hours if not compensated fairly? The bills need to paid, and there's no time for a second job. That's the accessibility issue prevalent throughout higher education. This is without considering trying to balance a personal life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351670638.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>I’ll take your word for it considering there were a lot of strikes for PhD students somewhere around the Fall of 2021. I just don’t know if those PhD students were a general population of all kinds of students or of a specific study. Regardless, I’m not very educated on the topic so I can’t really comment on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349951436.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Good thing linear arts degrees teach you how to think in a "non linear" manner much better than STEM degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350730813.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>This is a comment that can only be made by someone who has never taken more than one STEM class. The very device that you wrote this short sighted comment on was created and invented by the ingenuity, creativity, and “linear” mindsets of engineers, physicists, software engineers, mathematicians, and many more scientists. 

I didn’t insult liberal arts degrees—they’re all important in their own way and present different challenges. There’s no need to insult or diminish the complexity of a STEM degree to raise the value of a liberal arts degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350940552.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I went to Caltech... it's *very* analytical in STEM degrees. 

I can count the hours expended in teaching things that would help you figure out how to apply your degree to finding a non-traditional job for that degree, on... zero fingers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351119278.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re saying this, it must mean you wasted a lot of time in college. Not only do I know this from personal experience because I pursue Stats and Psych (both of which are directly translatable into management positions because you can apply both degrees in MANY different ways even if they don’t have to do with everything you studied) but my views are confirmed with experiences outside of my own. 

My boyfriend goes to Columbia where he studies Chemical Engineering and works hard every single day. If he wanted to, he could go the stereotypical route and work for an oil or pharmaceutical company. But he could also become an astronaut, work in Biotech companies, recycling firms, or even manage a company on his own. In fact, he discovered a passion for biochemical engineering and is exploring the possibility of creating a company that takes commissions to engineer bacteria for specific purposes (for example, engineering bacteria that can digest micro plastics into an eco friendly material, engineering bacteria to target cancer cells, etc). 

But he’s also exceptionally driven and just as intelligent. Let’s look at a scenario with an average joe who did well in physics. A classmate of mine got a degree in Physics in a State School that’s below top 50 and landed a job working at a bank by literally saying “If I can graduate with an A in physics, I’m pretty sure I can work at a bank”. It’s probably the most arrogant and dumbest way of getting a job but he got it and he works in finances now and he’s been climbing the ladder ever since. 

And these are just two experiences—there are MANY more. You just have to be creative and put in the work.  There’s more I can add but this is already pretty long lol. 

TLDR: You either lack the creativity to think of another job or wasted a lot of time in Caltech because if you put in the effort, there is no reason why you can’t get a job (assuming the market isn’t over saturated but that has nothing to do with your degree).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352437646.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not at all saying that STEM skills can't *apply* to other jobs... 

Nor that if you're smart enough to get a physics degree that you won't have the smarts to find a different job if you want.

I'm saying liberal arts degrees focus on skills like leadership, philosophy, people skills, non-technical writing, etc., which directly assist in *navigating* a non-linear *career path*. 

STEM degrees typically very strongly prepare you to work in STEM fields. 

And BTW, "Psych" is definitely very rarely taught during a STEM degree. It's way more of a liberal arts subject.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41271610634.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>and therefore that's why STEM people look down on those degrees as useless because the jobs aren't as directly tied the way they are with STEM</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350649029.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah social sciences are absolutely not crucial to the functioning of society. Evidence: there are societies in this world, outside of your narrow view, that dont have liberal arts programs and still function. Liberal arts is a product of luxury. Once society has become comfy enough for everyone (thanks to science, engineering, and hard work), THEN these things emerge and are allowed to be freely studied.

I guess we need to define social sciences tho because some do have real world value (albeit not critical to the functioning of society itself, as you claim), such as psychology. But personally i think that should be lumped into STEM</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350745410.0" user="nighttimecharlie" delta="False">
    <text>Please name a society without social science careers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370898394.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>You are aware there are literal tribes that function outside of modern-day society? Tribes that literally just live together and dont really put any effort into any sort of science whatsoever? Furthermore, even if every society had social science careers, it does not imply that they are necessary to the functioning of that society.

I will tell you what IS necessary for a functioning society: food, water, shelter, some sort of governing body. That's it. But if we were to "Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs" this shit, social sciences would clearly fit into self-actualization, the least necessary component for survival.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40381613505.0" user="God-Hound" delta="False">
    <text>The only thing “necessary” is in fact being able to hunt, move, reproduce, and maybe communicate to some extent, sure. The question is why are you bringing a conversation on what is necessary for humanity at its most base into a discussion about college degrees in an advanced and advancing context?

Unless you’re some return to monke, base humanity is best humanity type of person…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40382974451.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Im not the one who brought that up. Poster i replied to asserted that social sciences are necessary for a functioning society. I disagreed and made my claim. That’s it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40386705547.0" user="God-Hound" delta="False">
    <text>Got it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351175926.0" user="sara34987" delta="False">
    <text>First, I agree that Psychology should be lumped in with STEM. 

Secondly, I disagree that social sciences are not useful. I know absolutely NOTHING about legislature outside of the news and the few topics I’ve gone out of my way to educate myself on. I could never successfully represent myself in court, would probably suck as a state representative, and know nothing about managing state of affairs. All of which are heavily intertwined if not synonymous with social studies degrees. 

I’m definitely not the best public speaker and I’m not the best at debating either. The only reason why I have any skill with either of these is because of high school, but by no means am I proficient. 

I’m sure I could develop these skills if I put the time effort into learning them, but that’s what a degree is for. Other than presenting power point presentations and educating others on my results, I really don’t need those skills because I’m not pursuing a career with them. However, my lawyer better know how to make a good case because it’s their literal profession.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370967776.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>You make fair points. Just want to say tho that I'm not claiming social sciences are useless. I think they can be useful, but i do not see them as crucial to the functioning of society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40355928427.0" user="AppleForMePls" delta="False">
    <text>I love all of those scientists and engineers building and running functional governments as politicians, directing public and private finances as economists, lobbying and fighting for civil rights, and teaching/feeding/housing the next generation. Social sciences are important, and without them, scientists and engineers could not function properly without dealing with issues beyond the scope (budgets, setting regulations, worker safety, etc).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40381601105.0" user="God-Hound" delta="False">
    <text>There are societies out there without STEM programs too that still function; and this isn’t even the largest hole in your argument. Did you think about this for more than a few seconds?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40382960611.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>When did i say STEM was essential? But yes i see STEM as more necessary than social sciences, but i can also see the value in social sciences too. Just completely disagree on them being essential to the functioning of society. Also would like to define social sciences so i know exactly what we are talking about since certain things are lumped into different categories by different people

Ive thought thru my positions on things very thoroughly, if you dont have anything to add but an insult then let’s both move on with our days</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
