<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344040736.0" user="ZombieIsTired" delta="False">
    <text>You’re forgetting that a lot of higher paying, non-minimum wage jobs require *at least some degree*. It’s more so the notion of being educated. 

If you have a college degree, no matter what degree it is, you do have more opportunities, this is undeniable. Whether or not a liberal arts degree will make you bank is up to the person. 

My sister also has a degree in gender studies, however she used that to get a masters in teaching, and a masters in teaching administration, with an eventual goal to do research on gender studies. While she was in dept she payed it off by choosing to go to the higher career route using the degree she had. 

Getting a philosophy or “dumb liberal arts” degree doesn’t force you to flip burgers. Yes the jobs are less lucrative than stem on average, however you cannot deny the number of opportunities that just having any college degree can get you. 

If you’ve ever spent a long time job searching you’ll notice that almost every non-minimum wage job usually has a requirement of “at least some degree.”

There are other career routes, but at least in the US, it’s true that going to college can provide some groundwork and also give you more leeway with planning your future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344958327.0" user="NovaNexu" delta="False">
    <text>My union bricklayer buddy made 2x more than me when I was an accountant. No degree. Full health benefits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345331060.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>But he’s laying bricks. That kind of work is fine when you’re 28. Not so much when you’re 58.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346226094.0" user="NovaNexu" delta="False">
    <text>His dad's a full stack carpenter. Sure, it comes with pain, but they and their fams are pretty content. Just my observation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350590968.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>If he invests and spends wisely i bet he can retire before that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345847765.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>That's also extremely intensive work. Idk about you but I'd prefer to work on the PC in an airconed office then be out there laying bricks in the hot sun 8+ hours a day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346240402.0" user="NovaNexu" delta="False">
    <text>I come from a circle of electricians and other union workers. You and I may not like it, but it's degree-less and it does them pretty well. My fire service peers do work hotter than just being out, though complaints seldom come from the people who actually do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350525556.0" user="Wolf97" delta="False">
    <text>People always point to electricians and typically compare them to teacher salaries. Someone always brings up electricians in these conversations.

One of the highest paying trades with one of the lowest paying professions that require a degree. I know you didn’t compare to teachers specifically, you just mentioned electricians and thats half the statement that usually comes from these conversations in my experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352216487.0" user="NovaNexu" delta="False">
    <text>I think it makes sense. They're extremes of both arguments. It's unfortunate how low the gardeners of tomorrow's generation get paid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350595699.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>That’s your preference but someone has to do it and it pays well. Sounds like we are just encouraging the path of least resistance and not being honest about the function college serves in society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347881841.0" user="halavais" delta="False">
    <text>FYI, philosophy majors have among the largest increase in salaries from first job to ten years in, beating out most other majors. (Obviiously, engineers have the largest fist job starting salaries, but salary growth is surprisingly anemic for most engineers.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349155167.0" user="DerpyJimmy" delta="False">
    <text>unironic question what kinda jobs are philosophy majors getting that actually requires their degree</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349190150.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>Probably law, but it's very flexible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349846215.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>this is it - a friend of mine has a philosophy undergrad and a law grad degree. her undergrad and my engineering undergrad are from the same top school, her law degree is from a mid-tier school. she way out earns me, works in corporate law (40 hours / wk, no billing hours). and I don't do poorly myself. 

Certain industries pay more than other industries, but those industries also hire non-STEM majors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349268724.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>It’s less that they require that specific degree but that they require a degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349355673.0" user="missed_sla" delta="False">
    <text>All kinds of jobs. There are a lot of jobs that simply require you to have a degree, any degree, before considering you as an applicant. My theory is that they just want to know that you can do something for 4 years without quitting, and to ensure a base level of education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349468805.0" user="Big_ol_Bro" delta="False">
    <text>Fry cook, barista, starving artist. The list goes on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349659062.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of phil majors go into law. And law can make you a lot of money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353632529.0" user="halavais" delta="False">
    <text>A degree in philosophy isn't job training--there are very few professional philosophers. But the analytical and communication skills one learns in a philosophy program are widely applicable to many careers.

I would say this is true across many fields--many bio majors end up working outside of bio sciences and medicine, for example, but the set of analytical skills they gain are broadly applicable, for example. Not sure why philosophers do particularly well, but it is an interesting question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349280474.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Also, school is not just job training, and why shouldn’t common laborers have the chance to study things like art and politics?

Hyper-vocationalism is just aristocracy with extra steps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350424048.0" user="mckeitherson" delta="False">
    <text>What's stopping them from learning that at a community college? They have the opportunity if they truly want it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350577432.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>What’s stopping them is that the poster is ignoring that these people do not give a shit. They work, they do not have the time to fuck off at a community college for the sake of “knowledge”. Most working people would be like “oh this degree that id have to work years for provides nothing of actual substance to my life? Ill pass”
I hate to shit on college so bad cause i do see its value and i am a graduate myself. But some people need a reality check and being stern about it is the only way to convey that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351874255.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of people choose not to go to college due to the cost alone. 

Some people might choose to never go, but it is absurd to suggest that your claim applies to even a majority of people. 

Also, if we gave students a stipend we could remove the opportunity cost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370977209.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe state and private colleges, sure, because those cost a lot. But community college is rather affordable, especially for a working person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371053649.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think life is as clean as you’re suggesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371144462.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not suggesting life is clean. I am, however, suggesting that there are plenty of viable alternatives here that adequately fill the gap for people that cannot afford to go to state or private college. I've personally known multiple working people who went to community college while maintaining employment.

Essentially, the payoff of tax-funded college is not great enough to excuse the cost. And i believe things like community college provide affordable alternatives so that people aren't just left in the dust if they dont want to pay 40k a year for a degree. The community college i grew up around is about 4k a year for in-state residents. That is 1k less than most paramedic schools, which people here are not supporting funding thru taxes. I'd sooner vote for taxes to go toward training of public servants</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371666746.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>And I know people that couldn't go to community college, because they were too poor and had to work. And community college is not a replacement for a university (they don't even offer the same degrees, kid).

&amp;gt;Essentially, the payoff of tax-funded college is not great enough to excuse the cost.

Yeah, that's just an unsupported opinion you are spouting as fact.

Most of your argument is just circular. Not that I am surprised, since you can't tell the difference between Karl Marx and Adam Smith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40375155225.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>It's not an unsupported opinion im spouting as fact. It is my opinion that i am spouting as opinion. Nothing about my argument is circular, it is very clear: most working people do not want their taxes going toward things that they do not see as essential or greatly benefiting society, and many people think college is an investment that the primary beneficiary (the college attendee and soon to be graduate) should take the risk on (meaning they front the payment). College is not a place to go and learn for fun, unless you are rich and bored. There are other alternatives if just learning is your goal. The point of college is the degree which will help you find employment, hopefully. I would rather taxes fund schooling and training for police officers, emergency responders, and yes, teachers and nurses which I am aware are required to go to college, but we are in such need of them that I think their degrees should be discounted at this moment. 

Please tell me how my argument is circular and I can clear some things up for you if you'd like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40376469117.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is that college is expensive, so it should stay expensive. That is circular reasoning. 

And the reason people don’t see the benefit of public schools is propaganda and misinformation, like what you are spreading. People having a misguided beleif also doesn’t make it true. 

All you are doing is advocating for hypervocationalism and the aristocracy it creates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378175138.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I never said college should stay expensive. I think college should be nowhere near the price it is. But that doesnt mean i support lowering those prices thru taxes. Do not put words in my mouth, that wasnt my argument at all. I literally spelled it out for you.

I'm not spreading propaganda nor misinformation. I'm spreading my opinion. What have i stated that is false?

Like I said, I want to start funding training for public servants. I also would rather fund elementary and high schools before college. Plenty of kids get a shit education and that is the basis which they operate on as an adult. There are far more immediate concerns than "free" college.

I can see you dont want a civil discussion and just want to smear me because i have a different viewpoint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378205371.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>1. You did say it. You are just adding pointless caveats now. 

2. You can’t just arbitrarily switch between the end goal, and incremental steps to it. That k-12 needs more funding doesn’t negate that free college would be better for society than what we currently have. You are just bait switching the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378321434.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>When did I say college should stay this expensive? Please find it in my comment and reply to me so i can see. I'm not making any caveats, universities have inflated the f\*ck out of tuition, which is one reason I dont want taxes going toward that anyways. Why should regular workers pay for this ludicrously inflated price? I would love to see tuition go down nationwide, just not at the expense of taxpayers

I'm not bait switching the argument, either. I'm listing things I would rather our taxes go toward before college. I see those things as more essential and important. They either pertain to kids' education or the service of the public. College to me is an adult investment to prepare one for a career, hence why I have a different position regarding tax-funded college.

If all you have left to say is continuously nitpick things in my replies, assert things about me that you have zero clue about, and misrepresent what my position is, then I think we are done here. I hope you can learn to see different perspectives and have productive conservations with others in the future. Have a good one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351859558.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Because you are suggesting that community colleges replace universities which literally changes nothing but the place of study.

At that point why don’t we reform high school so that you graduate with a bachelors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351948351.0" user="mckeitherson" delta="False">
    <text>Well community colleges often have studies available for arts and politics if people are interested in learning that. They're more accessible and cheaper than universities, plus often have flexible scheduling. So if you're concerned about "common laborers" being able to take studies of interest, then they're a good option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351992698.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>At that point why don’t we reform high school so that you graduate with a bachelors.

You are not suggesting anything new, and just shuffling around tasks between the institutions. 

Ironically, the scope creep you are suggesting is the biggest challenge for community colleges as they become the catch all for everything. 

Also, you literally just admired that the problem is the cost of college to students. 

Community colleges rarely if ever offer advanced level courses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352315861.0" user="mckeitherson" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not suggesting anything new because we already have a system to serve everyone's needs. If they want to take classes to learn or improve themselves, they can. If they want to get a degree they can earn an associates then transfer for a bachelor's. You're claiming there's an issue when one doesn't exist. Even for cost, many college graduates leave with no debt, or there are state options to help make it affordable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352364387.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Our system very clearly doesn't serve everyone's needs, because we already see the rise of a new aristocracy just like Thomas Jefferson predicted would happen without free public colleges.

[https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/06/the-birth-of-a-new-american-aristocracy/559130/](https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/06/the-birth-of-a-new-american-aristocracy/559130/)

&amp;gt; The people have a right to the privilege of education, and it is the duty of the State to guard and maintain that right.

\- NC State Constitution</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
