<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344038625.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments

In general, a higher education is a good investment. 

It's worth paying the money in order to improve your own cognitive skills. 

Because it teaches academic skills that are both useful and transposable. 

Obviously there are caveats: college (in particular US) is expensive as hell and might cost more than it's worth, for example. 

&amp;gt;Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place.

Ah, you mean FINANCIAL investment. Only monetary costs and benefits. 

That makes sense. In particular in the US, most majors are not worth it financially: it costs more than it will offset your income.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344429874.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That makes sense. In particular in the US, most majors are not worth it financially: it costs more than it will offset your income.

This is [factually incorrect](https://www.newyorkfed.org/research/college-labor-market/college-labor-market_wages.html).  The overall premium for a bachelor's degree for a recent graduate is $22k/year and [in-state tuition](https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/paying-for-college/articles/paying-for-college-infographic) is on average $10k, so the total tuition over four years is just double the income premium.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344889827.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>That's just tuition and premiums. Going to college has more expenses. 

Covering these expenses usually involves loans, so interest plays a role too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344942167.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>Those expenses would apply regardless.  A typical room-and-board + textbooks cost of maybe $15k would be quite low for cost of living in most areas (if they didn't go to college), so that doesn't favor one approach or the other.  In both cases they may have the option of living at home, and a college student is also arguably less likely to need a car, since basic services are generally available on a walkable campus.

Unless you mean the opportunity cost (roughly $120k at median high-school-diploma income), but that total of $160k (opportunity + tuition) is offset several times over by a $22k premium over a full career - it just takes a bit longer.  This is evident in [net worth by educational attainment](https://www.stlouisfed.org/household-financial-stability/the-demographics-of-wealth/-/media/project/frbstl/stlouisfed/files/pdfs/hfs/essays/hfs-essay-2-2015-education-and-wealth.pdf?la=en&amp;amp;hash=249B891920ACC529C60BB854D58EE02C); in 2013 the family net worth premium (with someone 40 or older) for a bachelor's or associate's was about $200k, though they suggest that the correlation may be partly spurious.

Edit: the Internet tells me that typical payments to pay off the median $30k loan in 10 years would be about $300/month, so a small fraction of the income premium.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344889802.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.bls.gov/emp/chart-unemployment-earnings-education.ht

You’re wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344904012.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>How? 

A link is not a substitute for an argument/explanation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344975528.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Average student debt is $30k. Median increased yearly earnings due to a college degree are $24k a year.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
