<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344164656.0" user="kedr-is-bedr" delta="False">
    <text>There is a positive correlation between education level and essentially every statistic you can think to Google.

Health, Income, Infant Mortality, etc

Your argument is simply unsupported.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345170006.0" user="Suitable-Ad-8598" delta="False">
    <text>I did exaggerate a bit, I should not have said worse than high school. What I meant was, the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345276649.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>There's a job in the liberal arts field if you know what you want to do precisely.

I went for Film/TV Production because I wanted to do commercial work, but on the project management side. I could have gone for a business degree instead, but I didn't enjoy a lot of the classes there and performed poorly.

If you have no idea what you want to do, then liberal arts is a terrible idea. That's on the parents to tell their kid about that since most college-educated parents already know this.

If you consider Psychology a liberal arts class, my ex's sister in law makes around 300k a year being a trauma psychologist for families in ER. One of my friends went for an East Asian studies major planning on being a supply-chain consultant for brands to find manufacturing options in Asia. 

The degrees aren't bad, it's that the application isn't there if you have no idea what to do with it.

Outside of liberal arts, an econ major is bad unless you specifically want to work in business. If you never planned on working in business, your degree is about as useful as nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349247524.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is this insistence that the sole purpose of college is vocational training. 

Democracy requires educated citizens, and we should give every person every opportunity to get as educated as they can. 

I’d rather live in a society where plumbers can spend a few years studying Shakespeare and politics, than one where college is left to those born lucky enough to afford it. 

https://www.monticello.org/research-education/thomas-jefferson-encyclopedia/bill-more-general-diffusion-knowledge/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349779660.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with more educated citizens- but I'd say that the access to information today is magnitudes greater than any other time. 

At around 30-50k a year, college should be vocational unless you can afford it. If you can afford to attend when you already have a job, no complaints there. That price won't go down until we stop emphasizing that everyone should go to college.

It costs so dang much so paying for my own degree, I wanted classes that would directly help me/my future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349868252.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>That’s just an argument for free public colleges, instead of the neo-aristocracy that we are creating with this hypervocationalism.

Also, access to information is a double edged sword, as evidenced by things like vaccine conspiracies. Teachers help weed the forest of knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350306810.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>No, teachers push their own ideology which may or may not be biased. You just want people to be told what to think, not to think for tthemselves. College is an absolute waste of time and money if you are just using it to learn. Go on the web or visit your local library if thats your end goal. Or order some relevant textbooks on amazon. Easy done</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350697947.0" user="caffienatedstudent" delta="False">
    <text>You must have had some bad teachers because you fundamentally misunderstand the role of an educator. They are there to help guide you through the process of learning to make it more efficient. That way you don't waste time trying to find answers to questions that are already solved but hard to find. 

They'll help you find the proper textbooks so that you don't waste your time on irrelevant texts or ones that are above your level. 

They'll help you figure out the best order to learn a complicated subject in, so that the information flows and integrates with each other.

Those are just a few examples showing how teachers are an invaluable resource for learning. 

You are right that you can learn a lot online, which is great! I've done plenty of that myself even though I'm quite far along in medical school and graduate school. The caveat is that I don't have as great an understanding of the subjects I self taught vs. the subjects I had a formal education in</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370868869.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>You can find educators online for free or for a vastly discounted price compared to college tuition. You can find good textbooks online, and check forums to see which ones are actually worthwhile. You can find study plans online, on forums as well or thru a purchased course, again which will be much discounted compared to tuition.

I'm also in graduate school and what I have found is that if you want to learn something, you have to do it yourself. No matter how good the educator, they cannot hammer the info into your brain. You have to be willing to learn and pay attention. And if you have all those qualities and ambitions, you can honestly learn 10x the stuff you could in college via the internet and the library. That's why I dont see college as a "for learning" type of experience. It is to get a degree and a job. Now i'm not saying a good educator isnt valuable, jsut that it is not necessary if you are simply learning for knowledge sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351281517.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying we should increase how long kids stay in public schools or make colleges cheaper? Should we not use college as a way to train kids about certain fields? That would be extremely bad.

Are you saying there should be classes specifically for adults? Because those exists online.

Not sure what you're arguing for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351961386.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A vocation signifies any form of continuous activity which renders service to others and engages personal powers in behalf of the accomplishment of results. The question of the relation of vocation to education brings to a focus the various problems previously discussed regarding the connection of thought with bodily activity; of individual conscious development with associated life; of theoretical culture with practical behavior having definite results; of making a livelihood with the worthy enjoyment of leisure. In general, the opposition to recognition of the vocational phases of life in education (except for the utilitarian three R's in elementary schooling) accompanies the conservation of aristocratic ideals of the past. But, at the present juncture, there is a movement in behalf of something called vocational training which, if carried into effect, would harden these ideas into a form adapted to the existing industrial regime. This movement would continue the traditional liberal or cultural education for the few economically able to enjoy it, and would give to the masses a narrow technical trade education for specialized callings, carried on under the control of others. This scheme denotes, of course, simply a perpetuation of the older social division, with its counterpart intellectual and moral dualisms. But it means its continuation under conditions where it has much less justification for existence. For industrial life is now so dependent upon science and so intimately affects all forms of social intercourse, that there is an opportunity to utilize it for development of mind and character. Moreover, a right educational use of it would react upon intelligence and interest so as to modify, in connection with legislation and administration, the socially obnoxious features of the present industrial and commercial order. It would turn the increasing fund of social sympathy to constructive account, instead of leaving it a somewhat blind philanthropic sentiment.

&amp;gt; It would give those who engage in industrial callings desire and ability to share in social control, and ability to become masters of their industrial fate. It would enable them to saturate with meaning the technical and mechanical features which are so marked a feature of our machine system of production and distribution. So much for those who now have the poorer economic opportunities. With the representatives of the more privileged portion of the community, it would increase sympathy for labor, create a disposition of mind which can discover the culturing elements in useful activity, and increase a sense of social responsibility. The crucial position of the question of vocational education at present is due, in other words, to the fact that it concentrates in a specific issue two fundamental questions:—Whether intelligence is best exercised apart from or within activity which puts nature to human use, and whether individual culture is best secured under egoistic or social conditions.

-John Dewey 

https://www.gutenberg.org/files/852/852-h/852-h.htm#link2H_SUMM24

——

&amp;gt; Whereas it appeareth that however certain forms of government are better calculated than others to protect individuals in the free exercise of their natural rights, and are at the same time themselves better guarded against degeneracy, yet experience hath shewn, that even under the best forms, those entrusted with power have, in time, and by slow operations, perverted it into tyranny; and it is believed that the most effectual means of preventing this would be, to illuminate, as far as practicable, the minds of the people at large, and more especially to give them knowledge of those facts, which history exhibiteth, that, possessed thereby of the experience of other ages and countries, they may be enabled to know ambition under all its shapes, and prompt to exert their natural powers to defeat its purposes; And whereas it is generally true that that people will be happiest whose laws are best, and are best administered, and that laws will be wisely formed, and honestly administered, in proportion as those who form and administer them are wise and honest; whence it becomes expedient for promoting the publick happiness that those persons, whom nature hath endowed with genius and virtue, should be rendered by liberal education worthy to receive, and able to guard the sacred deposit of the rights and liberties of their fellow citizens, and that they should be called to that charge without regard to wealth, birth or other accidental condition or circumstance; but the indigence of the greater number disabling them from so educating, at their own expence, those of their children whom nature hath fitly formed and disposed to become useful instruments for the public, it is better that such should be sought for and educated at the common expence of all, than that the happiness of all should be confided to the weak or wicked:

-Thomas Jefferson

https://founders.archives.gov/documents/Jefferson/01-02-02-0132-0004-0079

——

&amp;gt; This group of men honor Mr. Washington for his attitude of conciliation toward the white South; they accept the “Atlanta Compromise” in its broadest interpretation; they recognize, with him, many signs of promise, many men of high purpose and fair judgment, in this section; they know that no easy task has been laid upon a region already tottering under heavy burdens. But, nevertheless, they insist that the way to truth and right lies in straightforward honesty, not in indiscriminate flattery; in praising those of the South who do well and criticising uncompromisingly those who do ill; in taking advantage of the opportunities at hand and urging their fellows to do the same, but at the same time in remembering that only a firm adherence to their higher ideals and aspirations will ever keep those ideals within the realm of possibility. They do not expect that the free right to vote, to enjoy civic rights, and to be educated, will come in a moment; they do not expect to see the bias and prejudices of years disappear at the blast of a trumpet; but they are absolutely certain that the way for a people to gain their reasonable rights is not by voluntarily throwing them away and insisting that they do not want them; that the way for a people to gain respect is not by continually belittling and ridiculing themselves; that, on the contrary, Negroes must insist continually, in season and out of season, that voting is necessary to modern manhood, that color discrimination is barbarism, and that black boys need education as well as white boys.

-W.E.B. DuBois

http://historymatters.gmu.edu/d/40

——
https://ccrc.tc.columbia.edu/publications/economic-power-schooling.html

https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/06/the-birth-of-a-new-american-aristocracy/559130/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353768750.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>You're not really bring up a position here- like providing quotes about historical schooling in the past which is radically different in modern day- heck, even general education has vastly changed in the past 20 years.

Are you saying we need more schooling? More classes open for public use? You can't bring up stream of thought and not provide concrete positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353872492.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>I have provided concrete positions. Then I backed up my concrete positions with historical context to show how we got to where we are today (vocational schooling started as a way to disenfranchise the freed slaves via the Atlanta Compromise). I also quoted experts on the topic whose explanations have lasted through the test of times.

Also, two of those sources are from the last decade (more or less).

So from my perspective you are just admitting that you didn't bother reading anything, and are just being disingenuous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353896379.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>While you're saying college shouldn't be for only vocational training, what exactly is the real world solution to that?

Not to mention expecting someone to read 4-5 articles on a topic that is on you to explain your position is a little much. This is an internet discussion, not a research debate.

You can't say "Vocational education is bad" without providing an alternative. If the alternative is not free education, educators need to be paid in accordance to their time to make it a competitive job market, and people also need to earn money to gain a living- what is the alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353956412.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>I see you still haven't bothered to read the sources which directly answer these questions.

And where the hell is this idea that teachers at public schools don't get paid come from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349290220.0" user="NeXtDracool" delta="False">
    <text>For most liberal arts disciplines it's trivially easy to find fitting jobs even without knowing what you want to do. The only difficult areas imo are the humanities and creative arts.

&amp;gt; If you have no idea what you want to do, then liberal arts is a terrible idea.

If you're using the term liberal arts correctly I'll have to disagree. There is no reason you shouldn't study e.g. neuroscience just because it is interesting regardless of whether you know what you want to do with it later. You will have to persist until a MSc before you are sure to find a job in the field though. (except for the humanities and creative arts, as mentioned)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349731589.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't being a doctor/studying neuroscience imply you're studying science which is the S in STEM?

I always thought people understood liberal arts to be anything that we consider art-adjacent. Things like business/econ aren't technically STEM, but they're their own category.

What I meant by the whole idea thing is that if you're studying something like Communication and find out later on you're actually interested in Architecture, that's a big ol waste of the money you spent on that Communications degree (unless you're only taking core classes by that point). 

An Architecture firm would not be interested in hiring a Communications major with no work experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350196514.0" user="NeXtDracool" delta="False">
    <text>A common misunderstanding, but that's not what liberal arts means.

Liberal arts are in contrast with the practical arts like trade and engineering in that they are a pursuit of abstract knowledge rather than the pursuit of practical skills. Biology, neuroscience, physics, mathematics and computer science are all liberal arts disciplines, but also economics, linguistics, sociology or literature.

It is rather frequently misused to only mean the humanities and creative arts with the exclusion of other disciplines though.

STEM is interesting in that it includes both liberal and practical arts, mostly centered around some kind of man made technology. I think it is a rather vague term and not all that useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350272644.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>I would presume while liberal arts might mean other things technically, the real-world use is different- like how literally now means figuratively due to the way we use that word.

I think while sciences fall under liberal arts, we've understood that they're special in the way that they're perceived as more valuable to society than something like a literature or gender studies degree. Same with Math and Comp Sci.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345286170.0" user="kedr-is-bedr" delta="False">
    <text>I do completely understand your point.

A 5 figure debt is tough but 6 figures is truly life threatening to most people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349272159.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>So we should have free public colleges.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350362387.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think you understand what the word “free” means. What you really mean is “paid for by others”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351559470.0" user="wafflepoet" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, subsidized by taxpayers, which includes all those who have had to drop out of university because of costs, those who have never been able to afford it and those who will never be able to afford it. I despise this lazy fucking take. The fact that people like you drive on taxpayer funded roads, use taxpayer funded hospitals, have access to taxpayer funded emergency services, among so many other things, without a fucking complaint, is simply infuriating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351890177.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t forget the Bayh-Dole act where tax funded research is sold to private companies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370943051.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, i use things that my taxes have gone toward and will continue to go toward. However, many taxpayers will never use this "free college". I dont see how this take is lazy. What do you mean by "people like you"? You realize most people who do not want tax-funded colleges are part of the working class?

Those roads and hospitals are significantly more necessary to society than college, would you agree or disagree? Everyone should be able to freely travel to work or elsewhere, and receive medical treatment. College is not necessary. It is a risk you take to further your own career interests.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346125952.0" user="Neither-Answer-7431" delta="False">
    <text>I think encouraging students to cultivate a plan, to consider their own nature and what truly suits them is important. 

Not every single high school student is suited for college. There are trades that pay well. 

My son didn’t go to college but is a very successful business owner. I realize this is anecdotal but yeah, college isn’t for 100% of the population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349263827.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>That’s what White politicians said to people like Booker T. Washington when they said black people should go to vocational schools. 

&amp;gt; A vocation signifies any form of continuous activity which renders service to others and engages personal powers in behalf of the accomplishment of results. The question of the relation of vocation to education brings to a focus the various problems previously discussed regarding the connection of thought with bodily activity; of individual conscious development with associated life; of theoretical culture with practical behavior having definite results; of making a livelihood with the worthy enjoyment of leisure. In general, the opposition to recognition of the vocational phases of life in education (except for the utilitarian three R's in elementary schooling) accompanies the conservation of aristocratic ideals of the past. But, at the present juncture, there is a movement in behalf of something called vocational training which, if carried into effect, would harden these ideas into a form adapted to the existing industrial regime. This movement would continue the traditional liberal or cultural education for the few economically able to enjoy it, and would give to the masses a narrow technical trade education for specialized callings, carried on under the control of others. This scheme denotes, of course, simply a perpetuation of the older social division, with its counterpart intellectual and moral dualisms. But it means its continuation under conditions where it has much less justification for existence. For industrial life is now so dependent upon science and so intimately affects all forms of social intercourse, that there is an opportunity to utilize it for development of mind and character. Moreover, a right educational use of it would react upon intelligence and interest so as to modify, in connection with legislation and administration, the socially obnoxious features of the present industrial and commercial order. It would turn the increasing fund of social sympathy to constructive account, instead of leaving it a somewhat blind philanthropic sentiment.

&amp;gt;It would give those who engage in industrial callings desire and ability to share in social control, and ability to become masters of their industrial fate. It would enable them to saturate with meaning the technical and mechanical features which are so marked a feature of our machine system of production and distribution. So much for those who now have the poorer economic opportunities. With the representatives of the more privileged portion of the community, it would increase sympathy for labor, create a disposition of mind which can discover the culturing elements in useful activity, and increase a sense of social responsibility. The crucial position of the question of vocational education at present is due, in other words, to the fact that it concentrates in a specific issue two fundamental questions:—Whether intelligence is best exercised apart from or within activity which puts nature to human use, and whether individual culture is best secured under egoistic or social conditions.

- John Dewey
——

College is not just job training, and why shouldn’t your son have been able to study something like politics just for the sake of being a better person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349367639.0" user="KieranCasey99" delta="False">
    <text>Because most people don't go to college to be educated  for the sake of being educated (by that logic, you could just do an online course), they go to study to pursue a career in the field that they wish to pursue or if they wish to advance in their career, they may go to gain more knowledge surrounding said career path as a means of progression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349456728.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350002942.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>u/serious_sarcasm – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20serious_sarcasm&amp;amp;message=serious_sarcasm%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/-/ijb0w2g/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351092952.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;why shouldn’t your son have been able to study something like politics just for the sake of being a better person?


He can. He just has to find a way to pay for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351905530.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Or we could have free public colleges. Instead of leaving the future of our nation up to whoever can afford it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352111655.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>This is what k-12 is for. If you think that anyone who doesn't go to college is too stupid to actively participate in the future of the nation you need to address k-12 not hand out bullshit fine arts degrees on my dime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352343708.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>High schools were created as remedial schools and college prep, though some did start as a terminal degree before evolving too. That's why a lot of the original high schools started on college campuses.

Our dime, kid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40361280264.0" user="pdoherty972" delta="False">
    <text>If you make college such that anyone can attend and graduate then you've watered it down to the point there's little benefit; it just becomes four more years of high school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40361627226.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Since you asked, if I were king for a day I would have k-14 as mandatory. After graduating high school all students would be conscripted (with reasonable exceptions), and go through basic training. Their work should be more like community service and support roles (professional soldiers are important on the front). After 6 to 12 monthes they should attend community colleges to learn a trade or vocation, and take more advanced general education courses. At the age of twenty to twenty one they would graduate. At that point they could apply to the military or a university (or both). There are obviously admission standards. Those who are accepted should at least receive a stipend. 

This isn’t very different than things that exist already. For example, in NC they require community service to graduate, everyone is in the State Defense Force from the age of 17, and the Governor appoints officers to the State Defense force from faculty of the state colleges. Admittedly, the state defense force is currently unorganized due to discipline problems in the 90s. And as for universal military conscription, you don’t have to have Korean levels of fucked up, and places like Switzerland do it fine. 

Of course, that isn’t going to happen overnight, and requires extensive reforms in other areas to even have a chance.

But we can address your concern more directly, because public colleges can still have admission standards. And really “four more years of high school” is what they said about common schools when high schools started popping up as remedial programs at colleges. Some colleges actually became high schools. And the community colleges have it the worst of all currently since they are the catch all for everything from remedial programs (transfer degrees), GEDs, local job training programs, and the slew of community classes; all while being terribly funded. The whole system really needs to reorganized. 

All of that while remembering that education is not a panacea. Turns out hungry, dirty and abused kids do bad in school in general. 

https://ccrc.tc.columbia.edu/publications/economic-power-schooling.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347866298.0" user="halavais" delta="False">
    <text>"Liberal arts fields" is a bit of a misnomer. My wife did her degree in Fine Arts and is now an attorney with an income several SDs above the mean. I did a degree in political science and worked in banking and finance, as well as in tech fields, before becoming a prof.

If you take a degree that isn't clearly professional preparation (e.g., engineering, nursing, architecture) you will need to do more leg work than those in those fields to connect to a career. I taught at a (small, private) university that required internships, and while that isn't easy for many students, it served them extremely well in their careers. I now teach in a large public university where students mostly have to figure that out on their own.

Nonetheless, those with a 4-year degree on average still make a million dollars lifetime income more than those without. They also are less influenced by economic conditions--right now we are at full employment so a pulse is necessary, but those without 4-year degrees are far more likely to be laid off.

Overall, you probably shouldn't go to NYU on your own dime, since you are unlikely to recoup the extra expense over a good public university. But even if you want to boot camp or trade school your way into a field, the four year degree will remain an advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349270663.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>We need to drop this perverse hyper-vocational bullshit. School is not just job prep.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349568757.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; School is not just job prep.  

Counter idea: for the vast majority of people, it should be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349609523.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Counter point - free public universities can still have admission standards, and limiting access to colleges is literally one way bigots disenfranchised minorities and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349617309.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>The discussion isn't about more degrees or less degrees, it's about *which* degrees. Degrees that train you for jobs versus ones that don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349643830.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>A vocation signifies any form of continuous activity which renders service to others and engages personal powers in behalf of the accomplishment of results. The question of the relation of vocation to education brings to a focus the various problems previously discussed regarding the connection of thought with bodily activity; of individual conscious development with associated life; of theoretical culture with practical behavior having definite results; of making a livelihood with the worthy enjoyment of leisure. In general, the opposition to recognition of the vocational phases of life in education (except for the utilitarian three R's in elementary schooling) accompanies the conservation of aristocratic ideals of the past. But, **at the present juncture, there is a movement in behalf of something called vocational training which, if carried into effect, would harden these ideas into a form adapted to the existing industrial regime. This movement would continue the traditional liberal or cultural education for the few economically able to enjoy it, and would give to the masses a narrow technical trade education for specialized callings, carried on under the control of others. This scheme denotes, of course, simply a perpetuation of the older social division, with its counterpart intellectual and moral dualisms. But it means its continuation under conditions where it has much less justification for existence.** For industrial life is now so dependent upon science and so intimately affects all forms of social intercourse, that there is an opportunity to utilize it for development of mind and character. Moreover, a right educational use of it would react upon intelligence and interest so as to modify, in connection with legislation and administration, the socially obnoxious features of the present industrial and commercial order. It would turn the increasing fund of social sympathy to constructive account, instead of leaving it a somewhat blind philanthropic sentiment.

It would give those who engage in industrial callings desire and ability to share in social control, and ability to become masters of their industrial fate. It would enable them to saturate with meaning the technical and mechanical features which are so marked a feature of our machine system of production and distribution. So much for those who now have the poorer economic opportunities. With the representatives of the more privileged portion of the community, it would increase sympathy for labor, create a disposition of mind which can discover the culturing elements in useful activity, and increase a sense of social responsibility. The crucial position of the question of vocational education at present is due, in other words, to the fact that it concentrates in a specific issue two fundamental questions:—Whether intelligence is best exercised apart from or within activity which puts nature to human use, and whether individual culture is best secured under egoistic or social conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349683180.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This group of men honor Mr. Washington for his attitude of conciliation toward the white South; they accept the “Atlanta Compromise” in its broadest interpretation; they recognize, with him, many signs of promise, many men of high purpose and fair judgment, in this section; they know that no easy task has been laid upon a region already tottering under heavy burdens. But, nevertheless, they insist that the way to truth and right lies in straightforward honesty, not in indiscriminate flattery; in praising those of the South who do well and criticising uncompromisingly those who do ill; in taking advantage of the opportunities at hand and urging their fellows to do the same, but at the same time in remembering that only a firm adherence to their higher ideals and aspirations will ever keep those ideals within the realm of possibility. They do not expect that the free right to vote, to enjoy civic rights, and to be educated, will come in a moment; they do not expect to see the bias and prejudices of years disappear at the blast of a trumpet; but they are absolutely certain that the way for a people to gain their reasonable rights is not by voluntarily throwing them away and insisting that they do not want them; that the way for a people to gain respect is not by continually belittling and ridiculing themselves; that, on the contrary, Negroes must insist continually, in season and out of season, that voting is necessary to modern manhood, that color discrimination is barbarism, and that black boys need education as well as white boys.

- W.E.B. DuBois
http://historymatters.gmu.edu/d/40</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349866237.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>no. it really shouldn't. There is a reason why professional jobs require continuing education. Because what is learned during a degree becomes out of date quickly. Focusing a degree on job training just makes a degree obsolete. I have an engineering degree, and none of it was job training. it was learning basics and problem solving, so that when I got a job I could learn the specifics of the field from my employer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350338815.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think you explained why college shouldnt just be a stepping stone to a job. You talked about continuing education but did not specifically rebut why college shouldnt be a vocational tool

It sounds like your engineering degree was job training. It gave you the tools you needed to actually learn the specifics of your job. That sounds like training to me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351046602.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>I'm  not saying it shouldn't be a stepping stone for a job - I'm saying it shouldn't be vocational training for a job. Vocational training teaches you how to do a task. Degrees are generally prerequisites for the training from your employer. A good degree is versitile and can be used in many professions whereas vocational training is very specific.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370958141.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe i've had the wrong idea of what "vocational" means. Thanks for clearing that up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349945697.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353606361.0" user="halavais" delta="False">
    <text>This is called an "example" or an "illustration." Yes, it is also a form of anecdotal evidence. It is intended to present to the reader an opportunity to understand the general statement: that is, that a liberal arts education is not job training but nonetheless often leads to a career.

It was followed by the more general observation that, on average, the person with a 4-year degree in the US is likely to earn more and to remain employed during economic downturns.

If your best effort at understanding an argument is to sniff it, perhaps there are other sources for the smell you perceive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40377106826.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/SultanDeSiberia – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20SultanDeSiberia&amp;amp;message=SultanDeSiberia%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/-/ijbbdcx/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349233228.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is that we don’t have free public universities. 

Why shouldn’t we live in a society where plumbers and baristas can get a liberal arts degree just to better themselves?

Segregation of people into vocational or college tracts is just aristocracy with extra steps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351112435.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Because they can get the exact same information online basically for free. Not going to college in no way hinders your access to information. 


Why should society fund their hobby?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351489933.0" user="wafflepoet" delta="False">
    <text>Who said anything about an hobby?

The fact remains that most careers - certainly those that pay well - require a degree *for the sake of a degree*. Until and unless that changes then your position is untenable. Put simply, university isn’t about learning things. The information one learns at university for most STEM degrees can all be found online just as much as as liberal arts degrees.

The purpose of university, at least these days, is to *teach* students the tools they need *to* learn. This includes critical thinking, how to write (don’t even bring up high school), and how to do fucking research of any kind, among other things. On top of this university is one of the few places where students are required to study subjects outside topics that might interest them, even insufferable STEMlords attending technical schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351511147.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>If your getting a degree to get a career then your higher career earnings pay for the degree. You don't need a subsidy. 


Also idk where you went to HS but we covered all those topics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351813164.0" user="wafflepoet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If ~~your~~ you’re getting a degree to get a career[,] then your higher career earnings [will] pay for the degree. You don't need a subsidy. Also idk where you went to HS but we covered all those topics.

I don’t give a damn about the way people write online, because who cares? When they’re helping to make my own point for me, however, I’ll take it. Low hanging fruit aside your argument is ridiculous. Outside of the medical profession - [and not even there](https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/19/health/medical-school-residency-doctors.html) - there’s little to absolutely no guarantee traditionally “high earnings” careers will be accessible. [Look at the top 25 highest paid careers and note how many will be covered in the previous link.](https://www.investopedia.com/personal-finance/top-highest-paying-jobs/) None of this even addresses the fact that people who *do* end up in high paying careers are *still* going to be stuck in entry level positions that may barely cover student debt payments on top of rent, car insurance (and perhaps payments), food, and everything else increasingly out of reach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352147756.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>You get the vast majority of the rewards of a degree, so you can take the vast majority of the risk. 


Make a good decision because I have no interest in bailing you out. 


The math on college degrees is still very much in favor of taking the risk, but like you said it's not guaranteed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351920371.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Libraries have existed forever, but somehow for thousands of years teachers have been important. It’s almost like they are supposed to teach you how sort and process the mountains of information in places like the internet to prevent you from gaining misinformation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352076585.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Then pay for the service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352334518.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>With taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352759062.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Hard pass</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352791646.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>And yet here you are using tax funded infrastructure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352998138.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Then fund it with toll structures. 


Just because we do something incorrectly now doesn't mean we need to extend that failure to all our spending.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353773113.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Now you are just lying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41271594343.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>unless wi-fi is free everywhere and the latest computers are free to everyone, online learning isn't as free as you think</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41301981199.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Yes the financial barrier of about $100/ month for a phone plan and new phone is clearly too high for an otherwise working individual and obviously justifes giving said individual tens if not hundreds of thousands of dollars of other people's money so they can pursue the lark of their choosing. 


Also computers and wifi access are free at basically any public library or through one of any number of low income grant programs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349954771.0" user="Spacemage" delta="False">
    <text>If you have any level of college degree, you will always be able to get a high paying job than someone with a high school degree though.

So even if you're not going to get a job in the liberal arts field, you're going to start at a high salary based on the fact that you have a college degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350373390.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I dont agree. This completely ignores the trades which often are paid way better than any of the jobs these abstract degrees could get you. You are also presuming that anyone with a college degree will be paid more than someone without one in a given job. This assumes the person can even get a job with the degree which is the exact point OP is addressing. Furthermore, a barista with a liberal arts degree is NOT paid more than a non-college degree-holding barista. Therefore your earlier assumption was wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351057779.0" user="Most-Leg1080" delta="False">
    <text>Where? When? 
Where in the world do you live that this is true?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350232344.0" user="Primary-Help2885" delta="False">
    <text>Zero educators say any of the kooky shit you claim. Not one high school counselor has ever told a student, "All college degrees are good investments." You're a crackpot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40360191616.0" user="hellotrrespie" delta="False">
    <text>Lol. People do talk about it but it pisses off all the art majors. If you want a good job get a good degree its really pretty simple</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346886731.0" user="JacksonRiot" delta="False">
    <text>This might not be causal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349077328.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>...why would it not be? People who are smarter live better lives on average, that's just common sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349381388.0" user="westcoastjew" delta="False">
    <text>People who are richer at birth have access to better resources and connections and become richer later in life on average, that’s just common sense. We do not live in a meritocracy as you seem to be trying to imply

https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/19/learning/how-much-has-your-zip-code-determined-your-opportunities.html

https://apnews.com/article/education-tax-reform-pennsylvania-pa-state-wire-technology-1d856cd98d4c491e8443576b3a817740

This is a neat website to check out: https://www.opportunityatlas.org/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349641602.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People who are richer at birth have access to better resources and connections and become richer later in life on average, that’s just common sense.

Don't you think part of that could be because they have better access to education?

Their lives aren't magically better just because they're rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349683248.0" user="Cendeu" delta="False">
    <text>As a poor person, i very much disagree</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349702776.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarify what exactly you disagree with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349749985.0" user="Cendeu" delta="False">
    <text>That their lives aren't magically better because they're rich. 

I was being cheeky as a joke, but doesn't being rich correlates with practically every indicator for health?

Now whether the money is because of the health/education or the opposite, is what those above are arguing about. 

But i would kinda define a correlation like that as "magically better".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349754604.0" user="lindymad" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Their lives aren't magically better just because they're rich.

Not magically for sure, but logically better just because they're rich. Someone who is born into money but has bad education still doesn't have to worry about things like being unemployed, being homeless or health issues. They will still be able to have luxury cars, vacations and so on.

Connections can come from many places that are unrelated to education (social events primarily).

&amp;gt; Don't you think part of that could be because they have better access to education?

IMO, having better access to education can supplement that, but I don't think it necessarily has to be part of it. The only part that having better access to education might affect is being richer later in life, but even that can happen without good education when you know the right people socially.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350403111.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Username checks out</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40354172569.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>The first and third link are both based on Raj Chetty's work. If you actually look at his papers you will see that the results of those studies are HIGHLY sensitive to his model assumptions and relaxing them only slightly results in very different interpretation of the data.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349626203.0" user="Lisentho" delta="False">
    <text>Common sense is often wrong, which is why we research things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350429218.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Define “often”

And no we research things to understand how they work, not because common sense is faulty. For example, common sense will not explain every phenomenon so we research them in people. It doesnt mean common sense is wrong, just that it’s an incomplete picture. Common sense is actually rather reliable on the individual level cause it represents our instinct and intuition. I will trust that any day of the week rather than a random scientist who could be biased or falsify results to create a narrative. If you want examples of this, look at the recent alzheimers scandal and the fact that sugar companies paid off scientists in the past to push fat as bad and sugar as good. Human’s “common sense” has helped us survive for millions of years buddy, you underestimate how smart we all are subconsciously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349651925.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>Common sense isn’t an argument</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349694173.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that I didn't think it needed explaining.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349713701.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>Do they live better lives because they’re smarter or do they have more access to education because of the situation they were born into

Of course it needs explaining</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349723156.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>Do you genuinely disagree that being smart makes your life easier? Are you just desparate to be contrarian here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349730535.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I’m genuinely asking you to explain</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349812709.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>Being smart means you can get a better job, do better at that job, and make better decisions. I didn't realise that needed explaining.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350135714.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>Yea but having an easy life makes becoming smart easier, so what causes what?

Easy life makes you smarter or being smarter makes your life easier</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350285728.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>How is that relevant? OP's question is about whether education is worth getting. I say it is because it makes you smarter, and you agree that being smarter makes your life better. Yes, being rich makes it easier to get smart, but that's not what we're talking about is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350325935.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>Causation vs correlation is the comment you replied to

How is it irrelevant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350419084.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>Because I explained the causation, and you agreed with it. Why are you still replying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350485300.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t agree with it.

Because most smart people already had an easy life to begin with, so how is that causal?

If I start with an easy life, become smart, and continue having an easy life, how did my smartness cause the easy life? I already had it before I became smart</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350672148.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>You literally opened your comment with "yea", then changed the subject:

&amp;gt;Yea but having an easy life makes becoming smart easier, so what causes what?

I explained to you how smartness gives you an easy life and you seemed to agree. If that's wrong, read my comment again and let me know why you think that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350987014.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  so what causes what?

did you read the word 'yea' and stop there? i explicitly challenged what you were saying in that quote lol

&amp;gt; I explained to you how smartness gives you an easy life and you seemed to agree.

i literally just disagreed with this: "If I start with an easy life, become smart, and continue having an easy life, how did my smartness cause the easy life?"

are you even reading the comments youre responding to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351007646.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;did you read the word 'yea' and stop there? i explicitly challenged what you were saying in that quote lol

You didn't though, the rest of you statement is about *why* people have access to education, which isn't relevant.

&amp;gt;i literally just disagreed with this: "If I start with an easy life, become smart, and continue having an easy life, how did my smartness cause the easy life?"

...what a bizarre thing to say. In this scenario you made up, it didn't? But smartness obviously makes your life easier, as I already explained. Wearing a coat makes you less likely to be cold, saying "but what about someone who's indoors??? Checkmate" isn't a counterargument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351058570.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  the rest of you statement is about why people have access to education, which isn't relevant.

how is access to education irrelevant when talking about the correlation between "smart" and "easy life"? if youre born into an easy life youll have better access to education which makes it easy to become smart.

&amp;gt; ...what a bizarre thing to say. In this scenario you made up, it didn't?

wait, you think being born into a good situation and then succeeding academically is some made up niche scenario?

&amp;gt; But smartness obviously makes your life easier

smartness and easier life are correlated but not necessarily causally linked

you cant just keep saying "obviously" and "common sense" and expect to be persuasive... these arent explainations</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351167081.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;how is access to education irrelevant when talking about the correlation between "smart" and "easy life"? if youre born into an easy life youll have better access to education which makes it easy to become smart.

We're talking about whether being smart implies an easier life. You're currently arguing against that, but haven't given any reasons why. You're just giving other reasons why your life could be easy.

&amp;gt;wait, you think being born into a good situation and then succeeding academically is some made up niche scenario?

...no? Where are you getting that from? I literally gave you a very simple analogy to explain why your comment was completely irrelevant.

&amp;gt;smartness and easier life are correlated but not necessarily causally linked

I explained why and you agreed. If you've decided to retract that agreement, or that you didn't mean to write it, that's fine but that means you have to address my original comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351266785.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We're talking about whether being smart implies an easier life.

no, were talking about whether being smart causes easier life or if theyre just correlated

&amp;gt; ...no?

ah so you agree that its possible that being born into an easier life causes smartness and not the other way around

&amp;gt; I explained why and you agreed. If you've decided to retract that agreement, or that you didn't mean to write it, that's fine but that means you have to address my original comment.

you misunderstood my comment it wasnt agreement. it was explicitly disagreement</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351323606.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;no, were talking about whether being smart causes easier life or if theyre just correlated

Sorry, I thought we'd already established they did, because I gave reasons why they did and you directly agreed. Again, PLEASE give reasons why being smart would not cause your life to be easier. Address my original point

&amp;gt;ah so you agree that its possible that being born into an easier life causes smartness and not the other way around

Of course? As I keep saying, that's irrelevant. Your position is "being smart doesn't make your life easier" and that's what I'd like you to address instead of moving the goalposts again.

&amp;gt;you misunderstood my comment it wasnt agreement. it was explicitly disagreement

You opened it with "yea", I even quoted you. You then changed the subject. Read your comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351336145.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>do you agree that if youre born into an easy life, become smart as a result, and then continue to have an easy life its not the "being smart" that caused your life to be easy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351357808.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>...duh? When have I ever said otherwise? It's just an irrelevant side point that you decided I was against. A strawman.

Now PLEASE address the actual point pls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351366313.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When have I ever said otherwise? 

when you said being smart causes easy life when most of the time its the other way around</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352363620.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>...what? You realise that two things can be true right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350441129.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I think you would need to prove that college mskes you smart. And before you do that, also define the word “smart” and what it means to be “smarter”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349917652.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>smart =/= educated

Some of the dumbest people I know are highly educated and some of the smartest people I know dropped out of high school and started their own businesses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349931095.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>Pointless anecdotal evidence. It's *possible* to be dumb and successful or smart and a failure (or to start yout own business which you apparently view as a negative thing somehow), but it's far more likely that you'll do better in life when you're smart.

Educated people get smarter, fhat's what education is for. If it was purely to learn facts then schools wouldn't waste their time teaching you such a broad range of subjects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350012222.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Pointless anecdotal evidence.

lol coming from the person saying 

&amp;gt;that's just common sense

lol k

&amp;gt;It's possible to be dumb and successful or smart and a failure

correct

&amp;gt;(or to start yout own business which you apparently view as a negative thing somehow)

uhhh what?

&amp;gt;but it's far more likely that you'll do better in life when you're smart.

again, what does being smart have to do with education and specifically higher education? You know like the topic we are discussing?

&amp;gt;Educated people get smarter, fhat's what education is for.

lol no. You knowing who wrote some obscure 14th century French poem doesn't make you smart. smart is not the same as educated. In fact, some "education" is a negative like CRT or other gender studies trash. 

&amp;gt;If it was purely to learn facts then schools wouldn't waste their time teaching you such a broad range of subjects.

huh? they get paid regardless of any outcomes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350036699.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;again, what does being smart have to do with education and specifically higher education? You know like the topic we are discussing?

Read my whole comment before you reply...

&amp;gt;lol no. You knowing who wrote some obscure 14th century French poem doesn't make you smart. smart is not the same as educated.

I don't think you realise what people actually do at schools. Did you go to school? Or university?

&amp;gt; In fact, some "education" is a negative like CRT or other gender studies trash. 

"I am racist and sexist"

&amp;gt;huh? they get paid regardless of any outcomes

What is it that you think school is for? Their aim is to make you better at picking up information, thinking about it and drawing correct conclusions. AKA, being smart. Education isn't just learning facts lmao, are you 12?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350064166.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "I am racist and sexist"
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

lol see you have proved my point

&amp;gt;What is it that you think school is for?

depends back in the day I might have agreed with you but now.....

&amp;gt;Their aim is to make you better at picking up information, thinking about it and drawing correct conclusions. AKA, being smart.

Their aim is to make money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350414831.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;lol see you have proved my point

What point? You said you hated kids being taught how not to be racist and sexist. What other conclusion was I supposed to draw? What is it you think CRT is?

&amp;gt;depends back in the day I might have agreed with you but now.....

But now what?

&amp;gt;Their aim is to make money

...do you not realise most schools are funded by taxes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350476604.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What point? You said you hated kids being taught how not to be racist and sexist.

big yikes

&amp;gt;...do you not realise most schools are funded by taxes?

lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350482046.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>What's the point in this reply? You didn't even say anything. Do I take this as a delta?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350527799.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350603016.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that yiu're insulting me and giving no counterargument says it all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351709286.0" user="ILoveSteveBerry" delta="False">
    <text>lol you started with le racist bud you are what you claim to hate. The projection is strong with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352396952.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>What projection? Are you now denying being racist after getting mad over CRT?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351118827.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/ILoveSteveBerry – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20ILoveSteveBerry&amp;amp;message=ILoveSteveBerry%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/-/ijbnuif/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350463601.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I went to college for a STEM degree and will testify college does not make anyone “smart”. It does give you opportunity to further your knowledge if you choose to apply yourself, but we literally do not need college for that anymore. Anyone can do it. Go to the library, order a book on amazon, read journal articles on the internet, buy a $100 course online. We do not need college as a simple educator tool. It is a vocational tool</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40360319882.0" user="pdoherty972" delta="False">
    <text>Ever heard the phrase 'the exception that proves the rule'?  Finding outliers doesn't invalidate the general rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346952534.0" user="azure-lane" delta="False">
    <text>Yet one of the things I learned from my education is that correlation =/= causation. Could it be possible that income level drives education, health, infant mortality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349253146.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>And the biggest indicator for income is…?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349315902.0" user="azure-lane" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not saying it is. The original post said, “education, income, health, infant mortality are all correlated.” I was saying that just because things are correlated doesn’t mean that education caused them. For example, it could be income that drives all of those.

It’s not enough to say that “education goes up, health goes up.” You have to show that education CAUSED health to go up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349876514.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>parents income?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351060362.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>And a major predictor for that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351795314.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>Their parents income? The income of your parents at birth has a way higher correlation to a persons final wealth status than anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351985066.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>That’s probably true, but since you can’t control your parents wealth, I don’t know if that really is a useful concept in this specific discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347411877.0" user="semper299" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but looking at your student a saying "you HAVE to go to college to be successful and trades or military is worthless" is an absolute shit bag move. My school counselor said it to me. I'd love to see her again and point out that going into the army and becoming a medic wasn't a wastes of time compared to a buddy who got a business degree (which is a dime a damn dozen) and can't find a job. Now I'm going through nursing school so yeah college helps but no, i didnt HAVE to go staright to college or really at all. Another buddy makes damn good momey welding without a degree - 6 figures. College isn't the only way to success and saying so to kids is close minded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349251235.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah but looking at your student a saying "you HAVE to go to college to be successful and trades or military is worthless" is an absolute shit bag move.

Yeah, I don’t think that’s a thing that’s said very often and I doubt anyone would really defend saying it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349083174.0" user="Teakilla" delta="False">
    <text>Correlation does not equal causation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349293424.0" user="obsquire" delta="False">
    <text>Positive correlation is not nearly good enough evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350986834.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. What kind of evidence would you need to convince you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40357873674.0" user="obsquire" delta="False">
    <text>Correlations are sufficient to completely describe jointly Gaussian random variables.  Outliers are vary rare for Gaussians, but many human phenomena involve "wide tails" (outliers are more probably than Gaussians).  Basically, there will likely be extreme situations, such as lots of education and little to show for it.

There's risk vs. reward: education is not a sure thing.  It needs to be a sure thing IMO as a necessary condition that it be funded and encouraged by taxes and gov't funded employees, and perhaps people be compelled to got to schools (not yet US policy for college, but it wouldn't surprise me in the next half century).  There's way more of a gambling dimension to the whole thing, kind of like carpet bombing.  By getting more people to be college education sure we'll have more people to fill certain roles that policy makers deem necessary.  The problem is all those people who don't get those choice rolls: they've wasted time, energy, youth to fulfill those policy makers' quotas.

The only moral choice is that all gambling is done by people with their own life, not government funelling people towards things which only a fraction will have the ideals fulfilled.

It's not that college is bad (done way too much myself).  It's the pushing towards it by people who aren't paying the personal price.

A similar argument can be made against this push by tech companies like Facebook and Microsoft to put more CS in the curriculum.  These companies are likely to get more good employees whose training is funded by gov't.  It may be good for the students, or it might not.  The key is that whatever choice is made is 100% for the students, not to fulfill some policy need (industrial or social or whatever).  The students' direct interests should not be sacrificed for any other need: teacher job security, industry, gov't admin, daycare, training for "citizenship", neighborhood development, whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40358754376.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>That's a lot of words that still doesn't even remotely touch: "what kind of evidence would you need to convince you?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40359758875.0" user="obsquire" delta="False">
    <text>I've have demonstrated my commitment here.  Sufficiency is your job.  That's the burden of changing someone's mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40360815007.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>How am I supposed to change your view when you don’t even know what would change your view?

You say “correlation doesn’t equal causation” when what you really mean is that you disagree with the conclusion out there so you’re choosing to ignore the findings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40365354877.0" user="obsquire" delta="False">
    <text>1. I'm not the OP: it's not my CMV.
2. People have their current beliefs, and some people can even provide some justification for them.  But they don't need said justification to reasonably maintain their view in the face of someone who wishes to change their view, for belief is not identical to justifications.  We may even believe things based on evolution, and not even have the intelligence to parse, let alone comprehend, the truth.  If you want to change someone's belief, it's a high bar.  That's just reality.

*By contrast*, I've given some background for my criticism of positive correlations as justification for universal college.  It boils down to: college works for some, but is a waste for many.

You realize, positive correlation of college and income (say) doesn't itself even demonstrate that college pays for itself for half of those who enter.  You can get such a positive correlation if a single college educated person earns most of GDP (I think half or quarter is enough... I need to watch double-counting; certainly there exists an income high enough that a single individual is sufficient to make the claim).

An analogous point can be made with simple averages: for any average wealth W, 99% of people can have 0 wealth if 1% of people are sufficiently wealthy.  So some people reject averages as a consequence, and some prefer medians.  Correlations are averages of products (years of education times income, say), so, like simple averages, are sensitive to outliers ("extreme values").

You want to know the evidence that I'd like to see.  It's unrealistic but here it is:  more education *always* pays off.  Every extra bit of education leads to a minimal extra amount of income, opportunities, wealth, social status, etc.  Or, at least for a specific criterion X that you can pick and write down in a covenant with God before getting degree D:  if you legitimately get degree D, then you will (100% chance) get result X.

But it doesn't work that way.  A fact I know intimately.

100% of people getting a physics / mechanical engineering / library degree should have the option of getting a job in physics / mech. eng. / library.  If you get higher degrees, then you should get jobs that \*require\* those higher degrees.

One massive problem is that the more education you get, the relevant jobs become more specialized, which usually means that they're only available in certain places, maybe only 10% of cities, especially as you consider master's degrees and doctorates.  That's unclear before you begin, or you lie to yourself.

That specialization localization becomes an even bigger problem if you get married to another person with similar level of education, but in a different field.  The decent jobs are in 10% of cities, but generally not the same cities for both people.  Or you luck out and find a place together, and then the opportunity ends for one member of the couple.  So to get another job, the other member must give up theirs or the couple has to physically separate.

Sure, maybe you can get *some* advantage ("positive correlation")  from the extra education even if you don't get employment that *requires* that education.  For example, you can use your quantitative skills from a physics PhD to help with making spreadsheets for selling used items on Amazon marketplace.  But many regard that as a tragedy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40365991799.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not the OP: it's not my CMV.

I can read usernames, so I realize you're not the OP. But, you don't have to be the OP to have a view challenged on this sub.

&amp;gt; But it doesn't work that way. A fact I know intimately.

So you have a hard and fast view that is 100% unchangeable because you want evidence that cannot and will not ever exist. Have fun existing like that, but I won't be part of that existence any longer because this is simply no better than you stating that you *feel* it's not true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350135226.0" user="ParticularBreath8425" delta="False">
    <text>Bro forgetting about the suicide rates that correlate with people who don't get a college degree</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350159237.0" user="HellaSober" delta="False">
    <text>That is because navigating higher education generally says important things about the underlying traits of the students. The sheepskin effect exists as well but it is not that large.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350764502.0" user="PoopSmith87" delta="False">
    <text>Eh... correlation is not causation. If you have access to education the likelihood that you have access to clean water, food, and healthcare goes up as well. I think it would be pretty easy to demonstrate that there is no actual causation between education and health issues. 

Obviously for some careers degrees are a necessity, and those jobs are often on the higher paying side... but we all know what the OP is talking about, and it is a good point. We have high paying trades that have labor shortages alongside lots of unemployed and overeducated young people.

We shouldn't make kids feel like without a degree they will be worthless, A- because it simply is not true, and B- you can do stuff to earn a degree that stays with you for life (like my wife's student loans, or myself joining two wars at 18 years old).

Furthermore, no one ever seems to address the elephant in the room: during the early 2000's teachers, school counselors, and big banks were all complicit in a scheme to push student loans or military service to absolutely every student that they could, this was done in public schools during school hours. Literally, you had kids, sixteen to eighteen years old, that were compelled by law to go to a place of education and sit and listen to propaganda for a money making industry, backed up by the adults they have been told to trust all of thier lives. How those loans are considered legitimate is honestly a mystery to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351097361.0" user="kathar7" delta="False">
    <text>I can't believe I have to say this but correlation =/= causation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351479925.0" user="moutnmn87" delta="False">
    <text>This is not necessarily a refutation of the op. The allegations made in the op are not mutually exclusive with education on average correlating with better outcomes. The average all degrees being better doesn't doesn't than none doesn't tell you that all degrees are better than none. I really haven't looked into it enough to where I would claim any specific degree is on average worse than none so I wouldn't say your conclusion is wrong or I have evidence to contradict it etc. Just pointing that the evidence you're appealing to doesn't necessarily support your conclusion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40384899520.0" user="bullish_taco" delta="False">
    <text>Correlation =/causation

Im comfortable saying that people with the ability to go to college are also a lot more likely to have support networks and other advantages</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
