<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344310992.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will **probably** make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. [Emphasis mine]

Because this is factually not the case.

[College graduate income](https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d19/tables/dt19_505.06.asp): the lowest median income at age 25-34 of any degree category is about $40k (in 2018). At the time, the median income for high school grads was [$35k](https://www.bls.gov/charts/usual-weekly-earnings/usual-weekly-earnings-over-time-by-education.htm). Meanwhile average total debt is [$30k](https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/paying-for-college/articles/see-how-student-loan-borrowing-has-risen-in-10-years). The Internet tells me that'd be about $300 a month for ten years, so less than the smallest income premium.

All degrees tend to pay off. If someone managed to take $400k of debt at an expensive private school, that's on them - typical in-state public school tuition is around $10k/year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345149825.0" user="Suitable-Ad-8598" delta="False">
    <text>I may have exaggerated a bit by saying "probably worse" than high school but you must keep in mind that the "type" of kids that go to college tend to have more connections and family support that might be contributing to these numbers. I guess my evidence is anecdotal but I am having a hard time not seeing this trend among my friends and others.

I am more complaining about the fact that nobody is telling kids to avoid certain majors that will bury them in a financial hole for a bit. For example, the chances you will be able to be a career actor or actress after being a theatre major is slim, yet this isn't being told to kids. I am sure there is some benefit to having a degree regardless of what it is in. I probably phrased the post poorly, I should have focused more on how the availability of jobs per major isn't being communicated to kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345202670.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I should have focused more on how the availability of jobs per major isn't being communicated to kids.

Is anyone telling people that there always *are* enough major-specific jobs available? Particularly since most jobs aren't major-specific; that's more or less limited to licensed fields, so if you aren't doing one of those you might as well just study what you find interesting.

Otherwise, I think it's reasonable to expect someone targeting a specific field to do their own homework on prospects in the field. They'll have to sooner or later, but they won't be screwed if they don't like what they find.

&amp;gt; you must keep in mind that the "type" of kids that go to college tend to have more connections and family support that might be contributing to these numbers. 

That probably plays a role - I don't know if any studies have tried to disentangle correlation and causation. Certainly there are large subsets of well-paid jobs that reasonably require a degree (e.g. for research and communication skills), but I don't know beyond that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345274822.0" user="Suitable-Ad-8598" delta="False">
    <text>It is one thing if there may not be enough major-specific jobs, but it is another if there are very few major jobs and/or your income would be the same as working in retail or something.

I just want reality to be part of the education process here. 

I grew up in a wealthy area, and many kids have their parents paying for them to live in an apartment in NYC before they've even gotten a job offer. These are the kids that I know who have gotten good jobs with liberal arts degrees right out of school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345291057.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; your income would be the same as working in retail or something.

This isn't the case. The median young graduates (age 25-34) *in the worst-paid majors* are making about $5k more than the median high school graduate (source cited above).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349374895.0" user="namelessted" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, the median of ALL college graduates. This discussion is about graduates with specific degrees.

And, you keep citing a median figure. Do you understand that the way the median works, it means that HALF of all college graduates make below that median figure.

So, if a person is saying that 10% of degrees are the worst degree in regards to income, and you come and cite a median income figure for ALL degrees, your statistic is literally completely meaningless when the discussion is the bottom 10%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349833625.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah, the median of ALL college graduates

No. The median of the worst-paid groups of majors specifically. The overall median is much higher.

The $40k is for Early Childhood Education, which accounted for about 260,000 out of 58,000,000 degree holders. That's much less than the bottom 10% of degrees.

&amp;gt; And, you keep citing a median figure. Do you understand that the way the median works, it means that HALF of all college graduates make below that median figure.

The same thing applies to the median high school graduate figure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349263969.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It is one thing if there may not be enough major-specific jobs, but it is another if there are very few major jobs and/or your income would be the same as working in retail or something.

That would be an issue if the data showed it was true, but the data shows it’s false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349362166.0" user="namelessted" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how it is now, but when I was in school every teacher emphasized going to college, no matter what degree. The general idea was that literally any degree you can ever get in college is better than no degree, regardless of whatever debt you accrue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349156090.0" user="Hates_rollerskates" delta="False">
    <text>Money isn't the most important thing in life.  Educations help improve your quality of life.  The higher paying jobs that do not require education are very demanding in terms of long hours, low tolerance to taking time off (i.e, you'll be replaced), physically demanding or damaging, and unstable work place (it could regularly move).  Those jobs can be few and far between so if you want to change jobs, it could be difficult to make a job change.  I received my education before prices were expensive but not as bad as today.  During the summers, I worked jobs at the higher paying non-degree jobs in my area at the local mills, factories, and in construction and determined that it wasn't for me.  To me they were mind numbing, soup-crushing jobs where I was just there for physical labor and unable to use mind. Everyone has a different view of the world, this is just my experience. If I had to do it again, I would still get a college degree but probably in something dealing with computers as you can make 6 figures within a couple years of getting hired out of college.

In regards to your warning about certain degrees, that's the parents job. My parents regularly warmed me about certain careers but ultimately it's up to the kids because it's their lives.  Just because you get a degree in one thing doesn't mean you're stuck doing that.  I have run into several people who have obscure degrees unrelated to the field they are currently working in.  In the end, study whatever makes you happy and try to do what you think will fulfill you and then figure it out from there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349311195.0" user="iCUman" delta="False">
    <text>If you have to backpedal this far off your post, that's usually an indication that one or more comments on here have changed your view, and they deserve a delta. That's how things work around here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349939597.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>**Hello /u/Suitable-Ad-8598, if your view has been changed or adjusted in any way, you should award** ***the user who changed your view*** **a delta.** 

Simply reply to their comment with the delta symbol provided below, being sure to include a brief description of how your view has changed.

&amp;gt;∆

or 

&amp;gt; !delta

For more information about deltas, use [this link](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=usertext&amp;amp;utm_name=changemyview&amp;amp;utm_content=t5_2w2s8). 

If you did not change your view, please respond to this comment indicating as such! 

*As a reminder,* **failure to award a delta when it is warranted may merit a post removal and a rule violation.** *Repeated rule violations in a short period of time may merit a ban.* 

Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350075278.0" user="s2k_guy" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re confusing specialists and generalists. Liberal arts degrees prepare the generalist for positions of leadership where they have to use the analytical skills they acquire in their “gender studies degree” to understand a situation and apply their critical thinking skills to build a solution.  They also tend to be strong communicators because they wrote extensively about a myriad of topics. These are the smartest dumb people you’ll ever meet. They sound smart because they know a little about a lot and can maintain a conversation about it. 

Specialists usually study a specific topic to build proficiency and eventually expertise in that specific topic or acquired skill. Think STEM. Engineers get the foundations of engineering and then go on to specialize in a type of engineering. Have you ever spoken to an engineer? Some of the dumbest smart people I ever met, they’re so focused on their niche they sometimes lose grasp of the world around them. But damn can they build impressive things!

With my liberal arts degrees (polisci undergrad and security studies grad cert) I may have no expertise in a single thing, but I can grasp the basic concepts of the topics the specialists who work under me have mastered. When they give me the options available and explain the pros and cons of each, I can make an informed decision that’s nested in the overall plan that will accomplish our objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40361956225.0" user="pdoherty972" delta="False">
    <text>A jack-of-all-trades, master-of-none, is oftentimes better than a master of one.

Putting the *whole* quote since a lot of people try to use the first half as if it's a standalone, when quoting it that way reverses the meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350712633.0" user="MrScaryEgg" delta="False">
    <text>I know it was just an example, but it's wrong to suppose that everyone, or even most people who do a theater degree want to be an actor. The theatre industry, and the live events industry more generally, is huge and employs a lot more than just actors. While a degree isn't always necessary, it's often a fantastic way to get the connections and experience you need to get into the industry.

I can't speak for what it's like in the US at the moment but here in the UK there are *a lot* of jobs available for lighting engineers and/or designers, sound engineers, tour managers etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349348930.0" user="namelessted" delta="False">
    <text>[Underemployment](https://studentloanhero.com/featured/college-grads-underemployed/) is another problem to also consider.

Sure, the average college wage might be higher than non-college, but that average is pushed higher by the high-end of college grads. 40% of recent college grads are underemployed in a job that doesn't require a college degree, and 30% of all college grads are underemployed.

You can cite the stat that college grads make more, on average, all day long. But, that is a worthless statistic to all the 30-40% of college grads that are making substantially below that average.

Like, if an individual college grad with a bunch of debt is working at Starbucks, telling them that other college grads have a job using their major and making more money is worthless to that person and doesn't help them in any way. They can't go back in time and get a useful degree, rather than be stuck with the worthless degree that got them stuck working a shit job.

The discussion is not about the average of all college degrees. The discussion is that certain degrees result in much worse employment outcomes. The majority of the 40% of college grads that can't find a job using their degree aren't STEM degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349872392.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sure, the average college wage might be higher than non-college, but that average is pushed higher by the high-end of college grads.

This is why I have consistently cited the median, not the mean.

&amp;gt; They can't go back in time and get a useful degree, rather than be stuck with the worthless degree that got them stuck working a shit job.

I cited the lowest-paid major, not the average graduate in any major. *All* majors tend towards higher median pay than high school grads. Not every individual graduate is so lucky, that's true, but then there are also all the high school grads making far less than their median. On the whole it's likely to pay off, regardless of major.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350609479.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>You used median income but average debt. What is the median debt number, for consistency?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350996342.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>Not dude you responded to, but a quick google search says between $20,000 and $24,999.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350851037.0" user="SerTimtheDuncan" delta="False">
    <text>Wayyyyy to many unmotivated, directionless kids are encouraged to borrow tons of money for no reason at all. It is very much entrenched in high school advice/culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40354041623.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen that assertion and I'd be open to data on it, but it certainly wasn't my experience (in 2017). College was very much framed as *a* path, not *the* path.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
