<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="54" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40353707903.0" user="Hooked_on_PhoneSex" delta="False">
    <text>Educators have been promoting an emphasis on stem field degrees for at least 15 years now. I don't think that it's ever been suggested that students should pursue a degree for the sake of getting an education. Further, career planning and educational guidance assistance are offered to students as young as 12(ish), and continue to be available to students throughout their university tenure.

Planning and counseling offers students the opportunity to plan an attainable educational path, understand that the post graduate requirements they will be expected to meet, and learn about the overall career opportunities in their firesides. Students who are approaching graduation, are generally provided with access to career placement assistance, letters of recommendation, career fairs and internships.

My firm, for example, hires inexperienced staff exclusively from summer internships and referral programs. We are only interested in high performing students graduating in certain STEM fields (the same fields that have been hyped since primary school). We are able to limit our recruiter to well-recognized institutions, so an appli applicant from Columbia would have no trouble landing an interview (as long as their grades were competitive and they graduated with said desirable degree).

By the time students make it through their core classes, they should have had multiple meetings with their guidance counselor. Through these meetings, the student should have gained a basic understanding of the functional benefits of a higher education. They should have had the opportunity to look at their planned career path, and identified a functional educational plan.

Your Columbia friend clearly didn't do that. She managed to complete two years of core classes and two years of degree specific courses, accrued 100K per year in debt at a university whose current annual estimate INCLUDING room, board and other expenses tops out at [80K](https://www.usnews.com/best-colleges/columbia-university-2707/paying). While that's still astronomical for a worthless degree, it means that your friend managed to blow an additional 80,000.00 in four years, even though all educational expenses, housing, food, clothing, transportation, school supplies, etc. were covered. I.e. this particular individual wasted her educational opportunities, and blew an insane amount of money on really stupid shit. She's not a barista because somebody lied to her. She's a barista because she's never chosen to do anything else.

That being said though, higher education is a for-profit industry. Employers demand a degree for career fields that truly do not need one, and do not compensate to match the educational requirements they demand. Degree programs are bloated with courses that have no benefit to the student's chosen career path. Students are forced to take these courses in part because said university is earning more money by forcing extra classes.

Career planning, placement and education all need an overhaul. But it isn't because of a false narrative that all degrees are a good investment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
