<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344738101.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349403760.0" user="Soyiuz" delta="False">
    <text>The statistics would disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349635342.0" user="omhaverly" delta="False">
    <text>What stats? Please show me. Everyone I know who got degrees for psych or education or lib arts are struggling, in debt in 30’s still, and can’t get good-paying jobs above living wage, keep needing more school or experience and are getting screwed by the recruiter industry. How is that payoff worth 120k+ of debt just for BA or BS? That’s just for the piece of paper! What about living costs? Healthcare? Childcare? Down payment on a home? 
Recruiters are leeches that take 20%+ pay. Cost of living and inflation means most of us are struggling, impossible to save. It’s even hard for engineers and Stem to find jobs. I know, as I’ve screened 100s of developers for one job opening at work. I got a sociology degree after switching from nursing. Only reason I’m not in school debt is because my gpa helped pay for my BA, and I worked thru school. My husband will retire with pension and benefits. We were able to just buy 10 acres with cash. You can make better money with trades and building a diverse stock portfolio and letting stable long term assets grow, which isn’t the reality for most of my peers. I’ve lived off of interests for years. The traditional route of school and work is dead for millennials and gen z. I’ll teach my gen alpha kids to start working and building wealth young. And don’t follow the crowd. Currently finishing my masters online and it’s $8000 for two classes not to mention buying the Harvard Business packs and software for courses and the books. School is a money-maker. It’s more about who you know and making connections and getting lucky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350190519.0" user="Soyiuz" delta="False">
    <text>I linked the study in my post. Think (and Google it?) before typing. "Everyone I know" is anecdotal. Perhaps your friends are particularly unsuccessful?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40354911715.0" user="omhaverly" delta="False">
    <text>Speak for yourself, your whole post text was anecdotes too.:) I agree with you, btw! I’m hot a bothered because it’s by chance I’m not in crippling debt and I feel for my peers who “did the right thing”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40377098952.0" user="herrsatan" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/omhaverly – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20omhaverly&amp;amp;message=omhaverly%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/-/ij87r5h/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
