<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40344038223.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Why do so many people think the only value of an education is financial?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344050388.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Because it is.

I live in Gainesville where University of Florida is located. You can freely attend any lecture. Nobody takes roll or makes sure that you are a student. But nobody does that. Why? Cause they are there to get a piece of paper not actually learn anything. Being there as a non student is a total waste of time.

Education exists for people to get jobs. Everything else is a very distant second.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344067770.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because it is.

What makes you think that? You didn't answer, you just repeated the statement. 

&amp;gt;Why? Cause they are there to get a piece of paper not actually learn anything.

Sounds like those people have a bad motivation. 

I've certainly attended classes I didn't get credit for. 

&amp;gt;Being there as a non student is a total waste of time.

Yes, that's the claim you keep repeating.

What makes you think that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344087107.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly... the way things are taught is full of fluff.

I needed to pass a test for a PowerPoint company I wanted to work for. They were hiring for $50 an hour and wanted a very specific skill.

I spent an entire weekend (like 25 hours) doing udemy courses and watching YouTube videos. On Monday I effortlessly passed the test. Prior to that I had almost 0 PowerPoint experience.

If I was to try to pass the same test using the college system. I'd likely have to take like 6 semester hours. Waste an enormous amount of time. Learning mostly useless nonsense. 

That is why I think anything beyond a piece of paper saying you graduated is mostly a waste. Because you can develop the same skills and learn 100 times faster.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344102536.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Honestly... the way things are taught is full of fluff.

More unsubstantiated claims..

&amp;gt;I needed to pass a test for a PowerPoint company I wanted to work for. They were hiring for $50 an hour and wanted a very specific skill.

&amp;gt;I spent an entire weekend (like 25 hours) doing udemy courses and watching YouTube videos. On Monday I effortlessly passed the test. Prior to that I had almost 0 PowerPoint experience.

&amp;gt;If I was to try to pass the same test using the college system. I'd likely have to take like 6 semester hours. Waste an enormous amount of time. Learning mostly useless nonsense. 

&amp;gt;That is why I think anything beyond a piece of paper saying you graduated is mostly a waste. Because you can develop the same skills and learn 100 times faster.

Anecdotal evidence isn't particularly convincing nor conclusive. 

What's the point point this anecdote is supposed to make?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344111847.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>The point that you can learn something much faster at the job. Versus going to college. Education tends to be very slow and full of useless facts.

I don't know how else to say it.

I see our society moving away from the college system in the next 100 years (slowly gradually). Because it is simply wayyyyy too wasteful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344122431.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The point that you can learn something much faster at the job. 

Please specify "something". 

You cannot learn nuclear physics much faster on the job. 

&amp;gt;I don't know how else to say it.

Frankly, that's your problem not mine. 

&amp;gt;I see our society moving away from the college system in the next 100 years (slowly gradually). Because it is simply wayyyyy too wasteful.

More unfounded claims. 

Why do you see this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344139765.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I work in IT.

I don't even have a degree. Everything I know I learned by doing. Every certification I got and college class I took on the matter contained 95% information that I completely forgot as soon as the class was over. Was a waste of time even learning. 

And yes you could totally learn nuclear physics on the job. Especially if it was catered to your specific task. My dad was a physicist. I used to help him do experiments when I was in high school. I didn't even have a HS degree and I picked it up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344161188.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't answer the question. Define "something". I will insist on an answer.

&amp;gt;I work in IT.

So do I. 

&amp;gt;I don't even have a degree. Everything I know I learned by doing.

Good for you. And I mean that. 

&amp;gt;Every certification I got and college class I took on the matter contained 95% information that I completely forgot as soon as the class was over. Was a waste of time even learning. 

I don't think this makes the point you think it's making. 

If you cannot retain information you've learned, that's on you. 

Edit: and of course, you cannot assess how important the information you forgot was. Because you've forgotten it. 

&amp;gt;And yes you could totally learn nuclear physics on the job. 

You won't be able to. Nobody will allow you near any nuclear work without a physics degree. 

&amp;gt;My dad was a physicist. I used to help him do experiments when I was in high school.

That's nepotism. That's something else entirely... That was your dad's job, not yours. You didn't learn "on the job".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344168872.0" user="theantdog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I didn't even have a HS degree and I picked it up. 

Nuclear physics? Fucking lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344182297.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need a degree to turn on a device and note down a bunch of numbers. Over time you can learn what they mean.

I was able to do it because I was just a helping hand making $0. If I wanted to get paid for it I would need a masters degree. Even though functionally I would be doing the same exact thing. See how stupid that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344281282.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I was able to do it because I was just a helping hand making $0.

This is called an "apprenticeship". 

As already established, you basically got an apprenticeship due to nepotism. You worked alongside your dad at his job. 

Just to be clear: that's fine. Good on you. I hope you're doing well. 

But it's still what it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344300489.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Nah it would only be an apprenticeship if it was intended as experience I could later put on my resume. I was literally just a helping hand making $0. I never had any intention if being a scientist.

The point I was making is that with 0 education I was able to do the same thing it usually requires a masters degree for. If I did it for a couple of years I'd likely learn what all those numbers mean. No need for 6-8 years of memorizing useless nonsense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344316958.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nah it would only be an apprenticeship if it was intended as experience ~~I could later put on my resume~~.

It was. You gained experience from it which will be beneficial to you. That's your entire point.

You only got into this position where you could gain this experience, because of your dad. 

&amp;gt;The point I was making is that with 0 education I was able to do the same thing it usually requires a masters degree for.

Only because your dad let you. Nepotism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349369293.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>School is not just for job training. You’d probably understand the dangers of vocational trading if you actually bothered with a proper education for yourself. 

&amp;gt; A vocation signifies any form of continuous activity which renders service to others and engages personal powers in behalf of the accomplishment of results. The question of the relation of vocation to education brings to a focus the various problems previously discussed regarding the connection of thought with bodily activity; of individual conscious development with associated life; of theoretical culture with practical behavior having definite results; of making a livelihood with the worthy enjoyment of leisure. In general, the opposition to recognition of the vocational phases of life in education (except for the utilitarian three R's in elementary schooling) accompanies the conservation of aristocratic ideals of the past. But, at the present juncture, there is a movement in behalf of something called vocational training which, if carried into effect, would harden these ideas into a form adapted to the existing industrial regime. This movement would continue the traditional liberal or cultural education for the few economically able to enjoy it, and would give to the masses a narrow technical trade education for specialized callings, carried on under the control of others. This scheme denotes, of course, simply a perpetuation of the older social division, with its counterpart intellectual and moral dualisms. But it means its continuation under conditions where it has much less justification for existence. For industrial life is now so dependent upon science and so intimately affects all forms of social intercourse, that there is an opportunity to utilize it for development of mind and character. Moreover, a right educational use of it would react upon intelligence and interest so as to modify, in connection with legislation and administration, the socially obnoxious features of the present industrial and commercial order. It would turn the increasing fund of social sympathy to constructive account, instead of leaving it a somewhat blind philanthropic sentiment.

&amp;gt; It would give those who engage in industrial callings desire and ability to share in social control, and ability to become masters of their industrial fate. It would enable them to saturate with meaning the technical and mechanical features which are so marked a feature of our machine system of production and distribution. So much for those who now have the poorer economic opportunities. With the representatives of the more privileged portion of the community, it would increase sympathy for labor, create a disposition of mind which can discover the culturing elements in useful activity, and increase a sense of social responsibility. The crucial position of the question of vocational education at present is due, in other words, to the fact that it concentrates in a specific issue two fundamental questions:—Whether intelligence is best exercised apart from or within activity which puts nature to human use, and whether individual culture is best secured under egoistic or social conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349359806.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>No.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344102461.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Quit projecting your values and motivations on everyone else 

I, personally, am thankful that I learned a bit about, say, statistics.  Because when I see, for example, some anti-vaxx bullshit, I can immediately recognize that it's bullshit

And if more people had that base level of knowledge they would also immediately recognize it as bullshit.

And that would improve their lives and the lives of many others</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344122826.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>You can learn statistics by watching a couple of YouTube videos. You didn't need to waste 100 hours of your life.

I'm glad you found it useful. But that doesn't make it not a waste of time.

People don't go to college to fill their head with a bunch of useless nonsense. They do it so they can get a job later on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344180088.0" user="rock-paper-o" delta="False">
    <text>I’m going to counter this. You can learn something about statistics in two hours on YouTube. For some (many) people that may be enough statistics for their lives. You cannot learn the same depth and breadth of any subject by watching a subject for two hours as you can from actively studying it for 100. In some subjects a motivated and intelligent person can do that active independent study solely from existing resources, but most people benefit from formal instruction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344196832.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of that "depth" is utter fluff though. You don't really need it to be functional. That's the point I'm trying to make.

You don't need to understand how a computer turns on to press the power button.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344213466.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>What you consider "useless nonsense", I consider an invaluable part of the human experience and understanding this universe that I have a brief moment to experience 

Different strokes for different folks I guess

Maybe, being a cog in the machine is all you're good for</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344231046.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I can seek those things out voluntarily. Not be forced to memorize it for some test. How many time do you need to prove you can memorize a bunch of nonsense? I've always been an elite test taker. And yes I just forget all that trash a day later. 

Memorizing nonsense several times a year is not part of the human experience. At least it doesn't have to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344252766.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>What?

Again, if you're taking classes to pass the test, that tells me something about you and nothing about the value of the class

Yiu come across as someone who may have gone ro school, but did not get an education</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344281928.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Of course why else would I go to class?

You think I actually enjoy learning pointless nonsense.

Not much of a market out there for Hearthstone, dota2 and fifa majors. Otherwise I might actually go to school for something other than getting it out of the way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344323320.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Again

You're projecting

What you consider pointless, someone else might consider profound

I reiterate what I said earlier

I'm sorry you went through college without getting an education</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344366207.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't they just find that profound knowledge on Youtube or Tik Tok?

Why should I be forced to memorize it? 

If it serves no function for me in the future. For instance it doesn't  help me get a job or make me a better employee. Why on earth waste the effort? Wouldn't it be better to fill my plate with things that actually benefit me? I can do all the profound mind blowing learning on my own free time. Nobody has to pay you to watch interesting stuff on Netflix. If it's boring it better be on a test or nobody will bother learning it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344465114.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh

I'm sorry that education has failed you so profoundly 

Good luck in life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344490974.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I can seek those things out voluntarily. Not be forced to memorize it for some test. How many time do you need to prove you can memorize a bunch of nonsense? I've always been an elite test taker. And yes I just forget all that trash a day later. 

&amp;gt; Memorizing nonsense several times a year is not part of the human experience. At least it doesn't have to be.

Good university programs do not require or test memorization, outside of a few niche cases where it's important.  Over five years (engineering BS+MS) I memorized next to nothing, ever - maybe a dozen equations and as many constants - and none of it was on purpose (just picked up through use).  Every single exam provided nontrivial equations and constants.  Even the engineering licensure exams don't require memorization; they provide a very detailed reference manual.

The idea in college is to develop certain key skills (e.g. research, quantitative reasoning, technical communication) - which, however you learn them, takes years of practice, whether that's guided by YouTube or a professor.  With a degree you have access to extensive personal feedback and guidance, a curated program, and, yes, proof that you can actually do it matters too.  That's why, while engineering licensure does often allow experience in place of education, it requires more than the equivalent time (e.g. 8 years' extra experience in place of a 4-year degree).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344531829.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know enough about engineering to really make any comment. I've been told that is the one field where you really do need to know a lot of nuances.

I always compared it to Computer Programming. That you can definitely learn much faster then a 4 year degree. You might not have as deep of an understanding but functionally you can actually be more useful then a person with a 4 year degree. If you say spent 2 years building real programs instead of learning theory. 

HOWEVER I admit. Engineering might be different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344613011.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I always compared it to Computer Programming. That you can definitely learn much faster then a 4 year degree. You might not have as deep of an understanding but functionally you can actually be more useful then a person with a 4 year degree. If you say spent 2 years building real programs instead of learning theory.

I spend a large fraction of my job programming, to the point that I joke that I'm an underpaid software developer - I've been a hobbyist programmer for 8 years and it's been part of my job for 4.  (My very first assignment in this job was application development.)

I'm sure I could do some software development roles - which often don't actually require a degree - but I am also clearly lacking in certain areas that a degree would cover quite efficiently.  My experience has prepared me to do things similar to my experience, so I'd be fine at basic debugging or writing data analysis scripts, but the big advantage of a degree is *general* preparation ("you'll only use 10%, but you don't know which 10%").  If I needed to do heavy lifting with algorithms and data structures, systems-level code, etc, I'd have to do the equivalent of a few courses on the fly.  Which I could, but it's pretty inefficient compared to just getting a survey of the key skills right off the bat.

In my actual field, I don't do anything with, say, road design, but *if I needed to I'd have a good basis to build on* - and while it's not relevant to my current job, it routinely comes up in job descriptions and it will be relevant to my next one.  It's useful for me to have that general foundation and it's useful to a prospective employer that I can prove it.

I don't think that's different between the genuinely degree-relevant* sides of engineering, programming, or those "any degree" fields a humanities major might go for.  The only difference - which is why I smuggled in the "genuinely degree-relevant" - is that a lot of programming jobs (like the ones I could do) seem to skew perceptions by asking for a software engineer with a degree to do debugging.  It's like if they wanted surveying technicians (run around with a prism to measure coordinates) to have engineering degrees, or the computer help-desk person to have a CS degree.  But that's on those particular employers, not educators or the university systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344678299.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I needed to do heavy lifting with algorithms and data structures, systems-level code, etc, I'd have to do the equivalent of a few courses on the fly. 

How long do you think it would take you to figure out those algorithms?

I wrote a poker calculator program. Completely without any training. I just wrote it. And after some time I adjusted the code to be more efficient.

Later I learned that the types of algorithms I was using have names. Bubble sort and something else. I didn't even know what the names were. I just came up with them because they were more efficient was to organize data and I needed to cut down on my processing speed.

The point I'm getting at I feel like ACTUALLY DOING is the learning. Just memorizing what a bubble sort algorithm is. I don't know if that would have been particularly useful. 

What I find is that college will have you memorize like 100 different algorithms. And at best you might use 2-3 of them. While the other 97-98 were just filling your head with what I call fluff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344725472.0" user="quantum_dan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How long do you think it would take you to figure out those algorithms?

To figure out any single algorithm?  Not terribly long in most cases.  To have enough background to effectively identify algorithms to use in novel situations?  Several months at best.

&amp;gt; Later I learned that the types of algorithms I was using have names. Bubble sort and something else. I didn't even know what the names were. I just came up with them because they were more efficient was to organize data and I needed to cut down on my processing speed.

That's well done, but you also re-invented the wheel.  If you'd applied the background to begin with, then just finding a library or implementing the algorithm to begin with would have saved substantial time.

&amp;gt; The point I'm getting at I feel like ACTUALLY DOING is the learning. Just memorizing what a bubble sort algorithm is. I don't know if that would have been particularly useful.

A good CS degree wouldn't have you just memorize what a bubble sort algorithm is.  In a good technical program (I don't have experience with upper-level CS courses), you'd work through a variety of projects - actually doing - to learn how to reason about good solutions.  It wouldn't be "this is a bubble sort and here's what it's for", it'd be "here's how to notice when a sorting algorithm might be useful and how to go find the right one" (with practice).

Edit: so I agree with actually doing, but a good program in any discipline *will do that* - in a curated fashion with lots of feedback and being sure to build a broad foundation in your field as a whole (not just your current job).  I spent a few hundred hours in the field or the lab surveying and testing soil properties, and about the same again doing design-related analyses and modeling.  A lot of what I actually did in class/lab is directly applicable to my current work and most job descriptions I see.  In a good philosophy class you write papers presenting novel arguments.  In a good economics class you analyze real case studies.  In a good mathematics class you work through proofs.  And the breadth lets an employer be reasonably sure you can transfer those skills and won't have to learn a new role from the ground up.

&amp;gt; What I find is that college will have you memorize like 100 different algorithms. And at best you might use 2-3 of them. While the other 97-98 were just filling your head with what I call fluff.

It wouldn't surprise me if some degree programs screw it up like that, but that's certainly not the full capability of a well-run curriculum.  I learned much more than that about reasoning about software in each of the three CS classes I took.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348609103.0" user="HoptamStruska" delta="False">
    <text>While figuring out bubblesort is definitely nice, it is still a fairly inefficient algorithm. Bubblesort runs in O(n^2 ), meaning its runtime scales quadratatically with the length of the input, yet there are significantly faster approaches, which can do the same on O(n * log n), for example merge sort.

Furthermore, a poker calculator is almost surely running over a fairly small, closed event space with predefined points of interest - this should immediately point us towards hashing. If you used a hash map to represent your cards, you can reduce the complexity down to O(1), thus getting rid of sorting altogether and simply checking each combination in constant time.

As a software engineer with 12 years of experience, you have most likely come across these methods before, and if told to utilise them, would probably be able to do so without much issue. However, this is exactly where college experience should come in - it should give you the theoretical background, in-depth knowledge to be able to look at a piece of code and recognize the problems it has, look at a problem and figure out the optimal algorithmic solution (instead of simply an algorithmic solution) et cetera. The job of college should not be to memorize exact solutions, but to understand the techniques behind them, broaden the range of approaches that immediately jump into your mind upon seeing the problem - as someone has said above, "you don't know what you don't know", and no amount of selective YouTube viewing can help you with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344771369.0" user="larlyssa" delta="False">
    <text>This is an inexperienced take that I often see from incoming computer science students. They’ve taken a couple HS programming courses and think that because they know *how* to program, that they’re essentially done. These students often show up to their first internship thinking they’re god’s gift to programming for knowing what an if-statement is. 

The problem is they don’t know what they don’t know. They don’t know *what* to program, how efficient or inefficient code is, algorithms that are applicable to a wide variety of problems, version control, integration/deployment of large projects, or how to write self-documenting code that is readable to future engineers. 

There’s a reason bootcamp developers are not in high demand beyond front end web dev. The coding skills are irrelevant. How to apply them, is. And is taught in college. It is extremely hard for 18yo self taught devs to learn where the gaps in their knowledge are. 

—

As an aside, from personal experience I want to talk about the limitations of self instruction. I taught myself a language on my own, through books, podcasts and pen pals. When I studied abroad in that country, I was placed into advanced classes. I had a lot of high level vocabulary that I’d learned over time, and could easily read articles about gender disparities in nursing or essays on colonialism. But I only knew half the colors. And it wasn’t until I was in a structured course at a university that I was forced to fill in the gaps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344795839.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The problem is they don’t know what they don’t know. They don’t know what to program, how efficient or inefficient code is, algorithms that are applicable to a wide variety of problems, version control, integration/deployment of large projects, or how to write self-documenting code that is readable to future engineers.

Wouldn't a far more efficient way to fill those gaps be to actually practice programming? To actually get a job and write stuff with a team? Versus just memorizing a bunch of nonsense where a large % of it will never be used again. 

This is my anti minimum wage argument. We've deleted all these jobs out of existence. Because it does not make financial sense for companies to invest $ into training people from nothing. Even if they had a good way of identifying talent. 

If you took someone straight out of high school who knows if and else statements. Then had them work on real projects with real programmers for say $2-3 an hour. After a couple of years they would have a much better grasp on programming then someone with a CS degree. They would also know if it's a field they want to work in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344957761.0" user="larlyssa" delta="False">
    <text>Not even a little. Because when they “practice programming” their approach will be incorrect and they won’t have the tools to recognize why. 

While you can learn things like CI/CD on the job, basic concepts like data structures and time/space complexity are expected knowledge. And if your self taught programmer can’t read others’ code, only writes code with an exponential time complexity and doesn’t know how to traverse a tree, they’re going to have an impossible time ramping up. All the while they’re adding problems and technical debt. Fixing these errors and teaching these fundamental concepts from scratch only distracts more knowledgeable engineers from projects they’re completing. 

That’s how you end up with a self taught programmer iterating over all item permutations for the Knapsack problem. Because they don’t know what dynamic programming is and don’t know how to apply it. 

If self taught programmers were equivalent, why wouldn’t FAANG simply tell their first year interns to drop out and go full time instead? I’ve worked full time for 2 FAANG companies and interns are ineligible for hire if they do not graduate, regardless of performance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345106041.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>That seems really strange. Why would they require graduating if the person was performing well? Seems like there's more at play here. It doesn't make sense to throw away quality engineers when they are so rare. Simply because they can't produce some ultimately useless piece of paper.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345144503.0" user="larlyssa" delta="False">
    <text>Because they recognize that higher level computer science classes are extremely valuable and these engineers have more to learn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345178839.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>But you can teach them the same thing. If a person is performing well. Why wouldn't you go through the effort?

What do those higher level computer classes teach you? I've been in IT for 12 years. 

What specifically can they learn in those classes that they can't learn on udemy or YouTube in a fraction of the time. If they knew what to look for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348305268.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>I would go for shit I liked, but I wouldn't go on top of other college courses or even I didn't already get that piece of paper (if I actually needed it for my field of work for example). 

I 100% agree jobs come first. I disagree that folks never go to college courses to learn about anything else though. I've been to acting classes and will probably take some cooking classes at my local university. There are also lectures and guest speakers that come out as well and those are always fun. I'm just not gonna pay the overinflated prices colleges charge to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349355420.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why we need to stop pushing hypervocationalism, and support free public education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344094998.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think many people think this is the only value. I just think it’s the most important considering how expensive it is to go to school in the United States. I go to school in the US, I don’t pay anything to come here. But I’m telling you right now. If you were to tell me that I would amass thousands of dollars in debt, than the most important thing to me would be obtaining my degree to pursue a profession that would help pay off my debt.

Not a lot of people have the funds to pursue higher education purely because they want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344122441.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>How manymof those classes would you NOT take if you were just improving your overall education?

Imdo agree that people put different values of wealth, knowledge and life experience</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344136144.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>How many of what classes? I will say, American school is different to where I am from. I think a lot of gen eds are unnecessary. But I think that’s more of a educational cultural difference versus my original point which is about finances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344224492.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>The classes needed to get a degree

The real value, IMO, to education isn't in those classes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344249196.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>Oh! If I was merely choosing a general interest to improve my education without the express goal of pursuing it as a career. I wouldn’t take general education classes because I don’t believe they are intuitive to what I personally want to get out of higher education. 

Or, I would rather take general education classes that are specifically geared towards what I’m pursuing to some manner. I would find the history of certain mathematical proofs for more interesting than the history of Europe. I personally find I tend to retain information more when I’m actually interested in what I’m learning versus I’m just doing it to get a grade because I don’t really care about the material of the class.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344261870.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Of course

Everyone has interests

But, knowing stuff outside of your interests is probably important too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344318197.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>That’s what secondary education is for.

It’s unspoken that higher education is you studying a specific field. Even when you take general education classes, in most American Universities by your third or fourth year pretty much all of the classes you take have something to do with your major. It’s not like I’m going to forget 12 years of schooling just because I don’t wanna take general education classes anymore.

Even further, I have found that the vast majority of general education classes I have taken while going to school in America are just a regurgitation of things I learned in high school. I’m not learning anything new or even more in-depth. But, that’s just my personal experience obviously everybody is different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344347613.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>If you went to school outside the US, sure.  You have to real8ze that the US education system sucks so universities have to teach everything the students should have already learned</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348290695.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. His view also applies to myself and many high school students. It is indeed just a regurgitation of the same classes you took in high school. If you went to a shitty school then that's where the difference may lie, but that's why they have ACT and SAT scores to help balance that in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348283589.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>You missed the part where he said he would rather study those in his free time and have to pay thousands of dollars for classes that have little to nothing to do with his job of choice. People act like college is he only means to an education or the only way to study about something. It's not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349301198.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>That’s just an argument for free public universities, and not for hypervocationalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349335242.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>What?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349451048.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That’s just an argument for free public universities, and not for hypervocationalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349481936.0" user="missihavegiantboobs" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t know what this means. I’m not arguing in favor of free college. I’m not arguing against it either.

I’m just stating how American university is very expensive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349637598.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Hypervocationalism is the idea that schools are for job training, and children should be highly segregated into vocational tracks, and gen Ed’s are worthless unless they teach a marketable skill. 

This is the book that coined the term: https://ccrc.tc.columbia.edu/publications/economic-power-schooling.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350535010.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Things are not “useless” if they dont teach a marketable skill. But things are somewhat useless in the context of college if they dont help you become a productive member of society. If you want to pursue those things just out of interest, then knock yourself out! But no one else wants t pay for it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351897427.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Whereas it appeareth that however certain forms of government are better calculated than others to protect individuals in the free exercise of their natural rights, and are at the same time themselves better guarded against degeneracy, yet experience hath shewn, that even under the best forms, those entrusted with power have, in time, and by slow operations, perverted it into tyranny; and it is believed that the most effectual means of preventing this would be, to illuminate, as far as practicable, the minds of the people at large, and more especially to give them knowledge of those facts, which history exhibiteth, that, possessed thereby of the experience of other ages and countries, they may be enabled to know ambition under all its shapes, and prompt to exert their natural powers to defeat its purposes; And whereas it is generally true that that people will be happiest whose laws are best, and are best administered, and that laws will be wisely formed, and honestly administered, in proportion as those who form and administer them are wise and honest; whence it becomes expedient for promoting the publick happiness that those persons, whom nature hath endowed with genius and virtue, should be rendered by liberal education worthy to receive, and able to guard the sacred deposit of the rights and liberties of their fellow citizens, and that they should be called to that charge without regard to wealth, birth or other accidental condition or circumstance; but the indigence of the greater number disabling them from so educating, at their own expence, those of their children whom nature hath fitly formed and disposed to become useful instruments for the public, it is better that such should be sought for and educated at the common expence of all, than that the happiness of all should be confided to the weak or wicked:

- Thomas Jefferson</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351130098.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Why should the public fund your hobby degree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351922218.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Whereas it appeareth that however certain forms of government are better calculated than others to protect individuals in the free exercise of their natural rights, and are at the same time themselves better guarded against degeneracy, yet experience hath shewn, that even under the best forms, those entrusted with power have, in time, and by slow operations, perverted it into tyranny; and it is believed that the most effectual means of preventing this would be, to illuminate, as far as practicable, the minds of the people at large, and more especially to give them knowledge of those facts, which history exhibiteth, that, possessed thereby of the experience of other ages and countries, they may be enabled to know ambition under all its shapes, and prompt to exert their natural powers to defeat its purposes; And whereas it is generally true that that people will be happiest whose laws are best, and are best administered, and that laws will be wisely formed, and honestly administered, in proportion as those who form and administer them are wise and honest; whence it becomes expedient for promoting the publick happiness that those persons, whom nature hath endowed with genius and virtue, should be rendered by liberal education worthy to receive, and able to guard the sacred deposit of the rights and liberties of their fellow citizens, and that they should be called to that charge without regard to wealth, birth or other accidental condition or circumstance; but the indigence of the greater number disabling them from so educating, at their own expence, those of their children whom nature hath fitly formed and disposed to become useful instruments for the public, it is better that such should be sought for and educated at the common expence of all, than that the happiness of all should be confided to the weak or wicked:</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344264654.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>It's what education is sold on. 

"You do not know what you do not know". 

Before I went to college, I didn't exactly knew what I would gain from it; I had yet to learn everything I was gonna learn. 

I wouldn't have been able to understand how differential calculus would improve my life, because I didn't understand differential calculus. 

The general narrative is "get a degree, you'll be able to get a better job and live a better life".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344307759.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Sure

I think think that's a bad narrative

" You don't know what you don't know" seems like a much better one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344322778.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think think that's a bad narrative

It is. 

What alternative narrative would you suggest? 

&amp;gt;" You don't know what you don't know" seems like a much better one

Yes, that will resonate well with highschool graduates /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344337740.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>That's why we have "you'll make money"

We need to make children's education better

As a teacher, I say that "school is amazing, it manages to take kids' natural curiosity and wonder and beat it out of them in 13 years".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344347580.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's why we have "you'll make money"

You yourself just stated this is a bad narrative...

What alternative narrative do you suggest?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344364084.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the narrative is the problem,


I think our education system is

By the time most kids get through with school they are bored out of their minds.  Out shitty education system has ruined it for them.  Of course they don't want to sign up for more of it

So they have to be bribed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344384187.0" user="BwanaAzungu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think the narrative is the problem,

That's what the post is about, tho? 

&amp;gt;By the time most kids get through with school they are bored out of their minds. Out shitty education system has ruined it for them. Of course they don't want to sign up for more of it

I agree, it's far from perfect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349306717.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>That’s because hypervocationalism has taken over American education systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344730146.0" user="imanaeo" delta="False">
    <text>Cuz if you want to know this just for the sake of knowing things, there are many cheaper or free options.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349350197.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>So we should make colleges free at the point of delivery instead of destroying the foundation of our Democratic Republic with hypervocationalism and ushering in a new aristocracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40344966788.0" user="NovaNexu" delta="False">
    <text>Because much of youth are gripping at straws in this economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345427617.0" user="TheEnsRealissimum" delta="False">
    <text>If it didn't cost so much, the other benefits would be more worthwhile, but a degree will cost tens of thousands of dollars. If you or your parents can pay it off with ease, then sure, do it for the fulfillment, but if you are going to take out loans for it, you should get one that will help you pay those loans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40345507704.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Being able to pay for the things you buy is good, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347079773.0" user="TheEnsRealissimum" delta="False">
    <text>That's why people focus so much on the finances of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349296713.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>While ignoring that we should just have free public universities. There’s a reason Thomas Jefferson thought founding UVA was the pinnacle of his achievements, and why North Carolina has had a fundamental right to education in its constitution since the founding of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350492407.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>How about you pay for it and i dont, ok?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351883244.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>How about we invest our taxes in our future instead of giving tax breaks to billionaires.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370981116.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>How about we dont give tax breaks to billionaires and we also dont pay for everyone else's college, deal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371076107.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>When the institutions, or public works, which are beneficial to the whole society, either cannot be maintained altogether, or are not maintained altogether, by the contribution of such particular members of the society as are most immediately benefited by them; the deficiency must, in most cases, be made up by the general contribution of the whole society. The general revenue of the society, over and above defraying the expense of defending the society, and of supporting the dignity of the chief magistrate, must make up for the deficiency of many particular branches of revenue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371128105.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Get your marxist quote out of here. I'm not a communist and i dont push for communist policy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40371641015.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>It is a quote from "An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations" by Adam Smith; more specifically, the conclusion of Book V. "OF THE REVENUE OF THE SOVEREIGN OR COMMONWEALTH", Chapter I. "OF THE EXPENSES OF THE SOVEREIGN OR COMMONWEALTH."

You do realize that Karl Marx was born 42 years after Adam Smith published "The Wealth of Nations"?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To be fair, I know you would do this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40375127210.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt say the quote was said by karl marx. I said marxist quote. Type that quote in on google and tell me the first search result bud</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40376444810.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>So Adam Smith is a Marxist, because Marx read Adam Smith?

Touch grass, kid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378154604.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I never said anyone was a marxist. But you can find the quote first thing on google, website is [marxists.org](https://marxists.org). I'm not a kid, don't belittle me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378176055.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Kid, you literally called it a “Marxist quote”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40378184990.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Kid, you literally can find it on [marxists.org](https://marxists.org) 

Does every racist quote come from a racist? Does every liberal quote come from a conservative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40346856263.0" user="Present_Slip_999" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of financial and education, I am a graduating student and one of our requirements to graduate is to finish our final project which cost thousand of PHP peso. IDK if I'm going to graduate bcs we are currently struggling financially. We can say at money = degree. I don't want to bother every one in the house about this. Can somebody help?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349289514.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>So we need free public colleges instead of destroying the basis of our democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349676034.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>"I had to pay for school, so out of fairness everyone including future generations should have to pay for it" - average redditor</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349728171.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>What gets me is that UNC and UVA were both formed under the principle that access to college for average citizens (of course, their idea of what constitutes a citizen was fucked up) was the primary bulwark against a [new aristocracy.](https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/06/the-birth-of-a-new-american-aristocracy/559130/)

There’s a reason that NC State Constitution declares access to education as a fundamental right, demands public libraries, and directs the legislature to create universities that are as free as practical (not that that stopped them from passing unconstitutional bills banning free tuition and requiring lab fees during the Great Depression, that they still enforce).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350510074.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>Why should ANYONE pay for someone else’s college? You guys are further validating the stereotype of the left being entitled grifters. Pay for your own stuff and if you cant afford it, then save up or take out a loan. Most working people do not want to pay for other’s college, especially when a sizeable chunk of college kids dont have a plan, take pointless classes, and party 4 days of the week. You want working people to slave away so people can go dick off on a college campus and “learn for fun”. Sounds like slavery and theft to me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350823016.0" user="iamsuperflush" delta="False">
    <text>Because an educated populace makes for a better society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351161009.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>Then do your duty to society and pay for your own education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351533212.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying you'd rather not benefit from:

* Better medicine

* Safer transportation (airplanes that don't fall apart in the sky, bridges that don't collapse when you drive over them)

* Good teachers to educate your kids

* Etc...

unless the people responsible for those things are rich enough to pay their way?

You're willing to pay for a finished product, but you refuse to help smart (but not wealthy) people actually get to the point where they can make those products for you?

There are lots of smart people out there who don't have the money to actually put their brain to good use. You're telling me you'd rather not see society benefit from what they have to offer, just because they're not rich?

It turns out that you're actually perfectly happy to pay *corporations* to come up with new things. You pay for gas, and your money funds new petroleum exploration. You pay for the device you're reading Reddit on, and your money funds newer and better devices. The list goes on and on. So you're totally fine with paying corporations to discover new things. But the moment you're asked to fund individuals and not corporations you lose your mind?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351554781.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;unless the people responsible for those things are rich enough to pay their way?


The increased wages pay for the degree. You don't need to be rich before going to school. 


This is why the US has similar rates of higher education as other developed nations without the same level of subsidy. 


&amp;gt;You're willing to pay for a finished product, but you refuse to help smart (but not wealthy) people actually get to the point where they can make those products for you?


This is what financing is for, and educational financing is very available, and considering the risk profile, very cheap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351579364.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The increased wages pay for the degree. You don't need to be rich before going to school.

The wages come *after* the degree... You need some money to get there.

&amp;gt;This is why the US has similar rates of higher education as other developed nations without the same level of subsidy.

Do we also have a similar rates of people having tremendous student debt, or is it perhaps higher than in other developed nations?

&amp;gt;This is what financing is for, and educational financing is very available, and considering the risk profile, very cheap.

You're telling me if you had a kid (maybe you do), you'd rather have them be burdened with student loans than receive a free or minimal-cost education? Just because you think paying for an education is a "duty to society" doesn't mean it *has to be*. Plenty of other countries get by just fine with free or almost-free education and they're not exactly in a state of collapse. And it turns out those countries have some pretty prestigious universities too, it's not like they're free but horrible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351614902.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The wages come after the degree... You need some money to get there


Financing. This is the purpose of financing in the economy. Ppl/businesses can borrow against future income to build their productive capacity to generate income. 


&amp;gt;Do we also have a similar rates of people having tremendous student debt, or is it perhaps higher than in other developed nations?


Hasn't stopped ppl from getting degrees which is apparently the desired result. More subsidy is therefore wasted. 


It also, correctly, puts the majority of the risk of investment on the prime beneficiary of the payoff of the investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351850421.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hasn't stopped ppl from getting degrees which is apparently the desired result. More subsidy is therefore wasted.

Ah yes, the old "well it crippled them but they survived, so clearly the system works. Helping them out would be a waste."

Why do you want the entire education system to be a gamble? You shouldn't have to take a huge financial risk at age 18 for the *opportunity* to get a baseline education</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352121290.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why do you want the entire education system to be a gamble? You shouldn't have to take a huge financial risk at age 18 for the opportunity to get a baseline education


It is always a gamble, it's just a matter of whose taking the risk. If your getting almost all the rewards you should be taking the risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370919399.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>99.99% of airplanes are not falling apart in the sky under our current system. Nor are bridges collapsing left and right. How could that be if college isnt currently free?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40370913064.0" user="BolbiStokeMeOffski" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure there are a lot of things that would "make for a better society" (ignoring the fact that everyone has a different idea of what "better" means in this context). That doesn't mean we all pay for it.

I'd even go so far as to argue that people getting free shit all the time is worse for society. It quite literally produces a large group of the populace that isnt part of the workforce and will continually ask for free stuff and will not contribute equally. If you want to get educated, then invest in yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351151590.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>All the information provided by public universities is available for free online. Their only value is information structuring and signaling to the job market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351930465.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Information structure is crucial. Just look at how much misinformation the internet spreads.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352059444.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, most of the most reputable texts are already well known. But even if you need the structure you can take lots of mooks for free or look up college course syllabus which are typically public or get it from Coursera basically for free. 


It's so trivially easy to recreate a college education online for little money. The only thing you don't get is the accreditation, which is only really relevant in the labor market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352331740.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>1. Those resources you suggest wouldn't exist without colleges.

2. I doubt you have a chemistry lab in your house.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352778058.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1. Those resources you suggest wouldn't exist without colleges


And yet without free college they all still exist. Just because some ppl won't pay for a degree doesn't mean others won't. 


&amp;gt;2. I doubt you have a chemistry lab in your house.


Then pay for access. Outside of a lab everything a college offers academically is available online.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40352795277.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>This is just absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353097644.0" user="y0da1927" delta="False">
    <text>That we don't give a bunch of free shit to ppl who don't need it and can replicate it almost exactly for free?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353787287.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Your baseless claims are absurd. Even online courses require more resources than just a text page.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349445025.0" user="Dd_8630" delta="False">
    <text>In my country, studen loans don't accrue interest or have to be paid off until you're earning at least 15k, and then repayments are automatically garnished from your wages. There's no real detriment to never paying it off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40347738174.0" user="ProtestOCE" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why do so many people think the only value of an education is financial? 

Because there is a cost.

A financial cost (tuition, housing etc)
An opportunity cost (3-5 years depending on the degree you chose)

Not considering the various cost and whether it's returns are worth it for YOUR situation is a foolish idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348243283.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>Well, in the sense of making someone pay 10's to hundreds of thousands of dollars for the piece of paper it definitely needs to come with a financial return to be worth going the traditional college route. If it doesn't it typically isn't worth going to college for. Particularly when for many if not most subjects these days you can learn for free and not go into debt hundreds of thousands of dollars for. Money is definitely at the forefront no doubt about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40348699803.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>No. It doesn't

People are so fucking weird about this

They don't apply it to anything else.

Well, I'd like a new gaming system, but it has to provide a financial return.

Man what a sweet car, but it's not going to provide a financial return, so I'm just going to really

That bed is comfortable, but I don't think it's a money maker

It's ok to go to college just because you want to and you think it'll improve your life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349327524.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>This “it cost so much!” argument is also just an argument for free public universities. 

I don’t know why people are so hell bent on destroying the very foundation of democracy - an educated population not based on wealth or status, but ability. 

&amp;gt; Whereas it appeareth that however certain forms of government are better calculated than others to protect individuals in the free exercise of their natural rights, and are at the same time themselves better guarded against degeneracy, yet experience hath shewn, that even under the best forms, those entrusted with power have, in time, and by slow operations, perverted it into tyranny; and it is believed that the most effectual means of preventing this would be, to illuminate, as far as practicable, the minds of the people at large, and more especially to give them knowledge of those facts, which history exhibiteth, that, possessed thereby of the experience of other ages and countries, they may be enabled to know ambition under all its shapes, and prompt to exert their natural powers to defeat its purposes; And whereas it is generally true that that people will be happiest whose laws are best, and are best administered, and that laws will be wisely formed, and honestly administered, in proportion as those who form and administer them are wise and honest; whence it becomes expedient for promoting the publick happiness that those persons, whom nature hath endowed with genius and virtue, should be rendered by liberal education worthy to receive, and able to guard the sacred deposit of the rights and liberties of their fellow citizens, and that they should be called to that charge without regard to wealth, birth or other accidental condition or circumstance; but the indigence of the greater number disabling them from so educating, at their own expence, those of their children whom nature hath fitly formed and disposed to become useful instruments for the public, it is better that such should be sought for and educated at the common expence of all, than that the happiness of all should be confided to the weak or wicked:

-Thomas Jefferson. 

There is a reason that the first things the leaders of the Democratic Republicans and Federalists did was to found The University of Virginia and The University of North Carolina.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350111903.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Yep</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349391863.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>A gaming system costs less than *one* thousand dollars, let alone *forty, fifty, or more* tens-of-thousands of dollars.

A bed isn't as expensive as college either. wtf.

Only a car might be that expensive, and cars *do* provide financial returns *and* are often necessary if you don't live in a city or somewhere with public transportation (which many, many people do)

It's cool that you're either so rich or so young you don't know how money works, but that's not true for most Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350127832.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh

Again, it's ok to pay for something just because it brings value, even if that value is non financial, to your life. That's true if the thing costs one cent or a million dollars</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350140466.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh

Believe it or not, I'm on your side in this debate. But, sigh, you still have to be realistic, sigh

Wanting an education doesn't give me thousands of spare dollars out of the blue, sigh

And, sigh, to compare the cost of University to a gaming console (etc.) is wildly disingenuous no matter which side you're on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350174260.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh

Let me see if I can throw the disingenuous argument you used on me back at you correctly

I'm glad you're so rich that you, unlike millions of people around the world, can just buy a gaming console without having to consider, even for a second, the financial ramifications</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350184285.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Your point is that because people buy consoles and beds (etc.), they shouldn't complain about paying for University. But you leave out the tens-of-thousands of dollar difference between their costs. They're wildly false equivalences.

Your reply actually supports what I'm saying and shows the non-practicality of what you're suggesting. Not everyone can get more education for its own sake, just like people can't always get a console for its own sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350227169.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>I said nothing of the sort 

I said education, especially university education, like lots of other things people purchase, has value beyond financial</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350236554.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Which I agree with. What I disagree with is your framing that if you can buy a $300 console, you can buy a $50,000 education: it just doesn't add up. 

You seemed to be suggesting that anyone can buy whichever and it's a matter of good or bad choices; but the cost difference is a huge—missing—factor in your critique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350292864.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>I also didn't say or suggest that if you can afford a gaming console you can afford a university education.

I said that people buy certain things solely because they believe that it improves their life, not because it is an investment they expect to make a financial return off of - you can look at an education the same way</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350313147.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>When you say "they don't apply this to anything else," one of the reasons is the cost difference, that's what's missing from your critique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350511806.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>No

There is no inherent law of the universe that says above X dollars a purchase has to be viewed as a financial transaction and the return must be viewed through a financial lens</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350642706.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>In theory, no; In reality, yes.

Comparing the way someone would think about buying a gaming console vs how they would think about going into tens-of-thousands of dollars in debt, for their own sakes, doesn't work in a realistic, day-to-day, decision-making scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351532349.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>You're saying that from a privileged place</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353005872.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Correct, but off-topic; maybe an attempt at ad-hominem. But if $300 and $50,000 expenses carry the same weight to you, that's a place far more privileged than mine.

Also, the topic at hand has been going to University *non-vocationally,* which is inherently privileged. 'The privileged' is the only group able to do what you're suggesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40353384354.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that "how much weight" a purchase carries is 100% irrelevant to whether that purchase needs to produce a financial return on investment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40357034766.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Right. I guess be more careful with your comparisons next time because saying "I don't get why people are like this about College but not Xboxes" communicates that they are of equal weight, which, we agree, is nonsense because it ignores the reality of the vast cost difference. 

It's that you seemed to be wondering 'why' anyone would think about these things differently when the answer is obvious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40357881281.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>It does not communicate that. At all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40359197473.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Strange because I'm clearly not the only one who read it this way; why might that be?

&amp;gt; People are so fucking weird about **this**

&amp;gt; They don't apply **it** to anything else.

"This" and "It" reference worry over the *massive debt* one would incur by going to College mentioned in the previous reply. You then relate this worry over massive debt to buying a game console. *You* conflated them without consideration of the real issue: the cost difference.

What you don't seem to understand is that the massive difference in cost will lead to different considerations. People don't think the same way about beds or games as they do College *because they're not the same;* simple as that.

You're just using the Avocado Toast 'argument' with different ingredients -- If millennials buy Avocado Toast, they can afford houses = If you buy a game console, you can afford University. This is not sound logic.

This is what is understood through what you've written. 

However, you might be thinking to yourself that this was only a thought experiment about there having to be a financial recompense for a purchase. But, again, leaving out the wild differences between the purchases and *then* 'wondering why' people treat these things differently is my issue. There is no 'wondering why' when you put reality back into the equation.

They're just such vastly different situations that your comparisons are kind of insultingly callous because your argument only make sense if you're in a highly privileged social class, which most of us are not. The thought experiment eats itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40359390791.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Nope

You're adding all kinds of shit I never said</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40359443901.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>I quoted you and provided the context of what you were replying to. I then laid out how that could be read by others (that University and Gaming Consoles are, from a financial standpoint, "the same"). 

I *also* talked about your view form *your* point of view (as a thought experiment about how necessary it is to get a financial return on an expense) and how that falls short because it ignores significant differences between  factors of the 'experiment' (cost).

I know what you were trying to say (now), but the fact is that you didn't say it clearly and the comparison falls short even after being made clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349434835.0" user="sarawille7" delta="False">
    <text>If you would have to go into debt for any of those things you listed, then yes there is a financial aspect to it and whether it's worth it will depend on how important it is to you.

New gaming system? Not a necessity, probably not worth going into debt for, but an avid gamer might think it's worth it.

Fancy new car? A car is a requirement for most people, but it's still important to get something you can afford. You wouldn't suggest a homeless person should buy the nicest new Ferrari, even if they really like it.

A bed is also a requirement, and having one significantly improves quality of life. So I would say, worth it.

Going to college is expensive, and it's not for everyone. If you or your parents have enough money that you can go to college and not have to worry about being in crippling debt for the rest of your life, that's great for you! For everyone else, it's only worth it if there's a payoff.

If debt was not part of the equation, then by all means, study whatever you want. Unfortunately, debt is still very much a big part of the equation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350145802.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh

So brainwashed

Yes. All those things have costs.  Some higher.  Some lower.  

An education should be for everyone.  Why are so many people saying that people should remain uneducated?  Curious that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40354955817.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'd like q new gaming system

A gaming system doesn't put 18 year olds in debt to 10's to hundreds of thousands of dollars. Not even close dude. You seem to be the weird one to think that is any any near the same type of deal. 

&amp;gt;That bed is comfortable

Beds don't cost hundreds of thousands of dollars dude. Like wtf are you on about here. You keep dismissing the fact that this shit ain't cheap and comparing it to very affordable items nowhere near that. You spend 10's to hundreds of thousands of dollars you damn straight you want it to pay off and saying that is weird is a dumb take on your behalf to be honest.

Only the ultra wealthy (which excludes literally 99% of people) have that luxury to not gaf. If they made less or even average wages (hell minimum wage for most people going to college out of high school) then of course they aren't going just to go dude. It's an investment and getting a return financially I indeed part of it otherwise just lewrn that shit on your own and/or in much cheaper ways. School doesn't dictate the only means of getting an education I'm something. 

&amp;gt;What a sweet car

You can get cars for much much cheaper than a degree dude. Cars also don't generally cost 100's of thousands of dollars but degrees sure can. I bought a 98 homda accord for $3500 that is estimated by 3 separate mechanics to last 10+ years. That is nowhere near the cost of school bud. 

For most people you need a return on the money. It's typically dumb to get yourself in debt just to do so. You can educate yourself for free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40355088885.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>One, check your privilege

Two, absolutely missed the point.  Things do not have to return financial value to be worth spending money on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40355637449.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>One what are you on about privilege? Aren't you the one on about how people shouldn't worry about going 100's of thousands of dollars in debt at all and comparing that to $300 console? Talk about privilege. You don't even get that those aren't even remotely in the same scope. Talk about privileged.

Two, it is you missing the point. When something costs 10's to hundreds of thousands and typically in debt most people certainly do care about financial return as they should. Especially for schooling when that knowledge can literally be free to obtain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40357872410.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Aren't you the one on about how people shouldn't worry about going 100's of thousands of dollars in debt

Nope.  Not at all.  That would be absurd.  And I've said nothing like that

I've said it's totally fine to buy something, an education, a game console, a bed, a car, a house, and not expect a monetary return on that purchase,</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40362153459.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>So basically you are the one saying that a $300 dollar console is the same as going 100's of thousands in debt. Pretty much troll levels of bad logic on your part. 

Only a fool would go 10's lf thousands of dollars in debt and not be worried about being able to pay it off at the end aka needing the financial backing at the end of the day. So your take is people shouldn't care about going 100's of thousands in debt and just do so without thought or considerations for money. Yeah, you're either extremely naive or just a troll confirmed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40362253884.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Nope.  Didn't say anything that any reasonable person should construe as that

Agreed - sorta.  I agree that people should worry about how they should pay for something.  And I didn't say anything that a reasonable person should interpret as me not believing that

Of course people should worry about how they will pay for something

My point is that with an gaming system, or a car, or a kitchen redecorating, the assumption isn't that THE SPECIFIC THUNG has to produce the income that pays for it.  

Thanks for helping me prove my point.

People have the idea that an education is only useful for reasons of employment so ingrained in them, that even when it's explicitly stated, they can separate them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40363032994.0" user="chickenlittle53" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah you pretty much did and several people have already called you out on it in fact. 

You just agreed that money is a big factor. If you wee being reasonable you never would have argued against me saying money is a factor that should play a part in the first place. Now that you are called our on on you are backing out, because you know thst was a bad argument on your behalf. 

We are talking about college which can costs hundreds of thousands of dollars not gaming systems which cost nowhere near that and thus aren't even relevant or in in same stratosphere. You bringing it up shoew how out of touch you are with the cost of things or how the real world works. 

Thanks for backing down and agreeing with my points. You already admitted money matters now so you indeed proved my point yet again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40363121274.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>Of course money matters

Point out where I have said otherwise




Look at my original comment

Just said that all of the value isn't financial

Then said that you can look at buying an education just like buying a game system, car, fresh watermelon, whatever.  You don't buy those things because you're going to try to make money off them.  You buy them because they have some other value.

But, yeah, you have to pay for both a university education and a new sofa, yes.

But you don't expect to make money off your couch

You don't have to expect to make money off your education either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349286483.0" user="serious_sarcasm" delta="False">
    <text>Hypervocationalization is a serious problem. 


&amp;gt; A vocation signifies any form of continuous activity which renders service to others and engages personal powers in behalf of the accomplishment of results. The question of the relation of vocation to education brings to a focus the various problems previously discussed regarding the connection of thought with bodily activity; of individual conscious development with associated life; of theoretical culture with practical behavior having definite results; of making a livelihood with the worthy enjoyment of leisure. In general, the opposition to recognition of the vocational phases of life in education (except for the utilitarian three R's in elementary schooling) accompanies the conservation of aristocratic ideals of the past. But, at the present juncture, there is a movement in behalf of something called vocational training which, if carried into effect, would harden these ideas into a form adapted to the existing industrial regime. This movement would continue the traditional liberal or cultural education for the few economically able to enjoy it, and would give to the masses a narrow technical trade education for specialized callings, carried on under the control of others. This scheme denotes, of course, simply a perpetuation of the older social division, with its counterpart intellectual and moral dualisms. But it means its continuation under conditions where it has much less justification for existence. For industrial life is now so dependent upon science and so intimately affects all forms of social intercourse, that there is an opportunity to utilize it for development of mind and character. Moreover, a right educational use of it would react upon intelligence and interest so as to modify, in connection with legislation and administration, the socially obnoxious features of the present industrial and commercial order. It would turn the increasing fund of social sympathy to constructive account, instead of leaving it a somewhat blind philanthropic sentiment.

&amp;gt; It would give those who engage in industrial callings desire and ability to share in social control, and ability to become masters of their industrial fate. It would enable them to saturate with meaning the technical and mechanical features which are so marked a feature of our machine system of production and distribution. So much for those who now have the poorer economic opportunities. With the representatives of the more privileged portion of the community, it would increase sympathy for labor, create a disposition of mind which can discover the culturing elements in useful activity, and increase a sense of social responsibility. The crucial position of the question of vocational education at present is due, in other words, to the fact that it concentrates in a specific issue two fundamental questions:—Whether intelligence is best exercised apart from or within activity which puts nature to human use, and whether individual culture is best secured under egoistic or social conditions.

-John Dewey.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349568693.0" user="TwoSmallKittens" delta="False">
    <text>Tell that to all the people complaining about how little money they make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350149692.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351122029.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/CBeisbol – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20CBeisbol&amp;amp;message=CBeisbol%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/-/ijbfqrg/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350068324.0" user="Hooligan8" delta="False">
    <text>Crushing lifetime debt is probably #1</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40350153686.0" user="CBeisbol" delta="False">
    <text>That makes zero sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40351289933.0" user="Jackofallgames213" delta="False">
    <text>When your paying hundreds of thousands of dollars you bet your ass that it should be used to help sustain you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
