<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="49" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40351154841.0" user="SayMyVagina" delta="False">
    <text>Education is a great investment no matter how marketable it is in the workplace. University is not a job training institution. And really there's few degrees that won't help you in life. People love to say it but either do in fact benefit from it or don't really do the work required. Take english. My friend wasn't able to get a good job with his English degree. He loves to talk about how school is useless. But like, he didn't do a masters or PHd to specialize in anything. Like say Library Science. Or education. Just got out of school and started applying for random jobs. So he took an IT course and is a systems administrator now.

But like... all degrees are not the same. Some take more schooling and some take less. A computer science degree you can get a quality job with right away. Some require a masters or more to really stand out. All degrees require you gain some sort of marketable specialization to be profitable. Even CS. So yea he didn't do any more schooling and complains that he can't get english jobs with people who did get more and did specialize. And to boot when he got his management track position at a hospital IT guy he told me they loved the fact he had an English degree and it helped him stand out from all the nerds who were applying cuz they liked video games. They knew his degree meant he'd be able to communicate with people better so they gave him the more sr positions.

University is very much worth it. It's just not what people expect it to be if they look at it as a career factory. It's not a career factory. You're actually the career factory and if you're having trouble with the career the blame is really on you not university.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
