<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1964912436.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/whuw50/cmv_k12_educators_push_a_false_narrative_that_all/">
    <title>cmv: K-12 Educators push a false narrative that all college degrees are good investments</title>
    <original_poster>Suitable-Ad-8598</original_poster>
    <original_post>Students in high school are bombarded with pressure to go to college by educators, with high emphasis on the ranking of the schools they are accepted into and no emphasis on the majors that they choose.

Nobody is warning students that picking liberal arts majors (unless they go to an ivy league school or something like it), will probably make them financially worse off then not even getting a degree in the first place. I know a girl that did gender studies at Columbia and is working as a barista several years out of college and is in about $400,000 in debt. I went to a way worse school than Columbia and nearly all of my friends with liberal arts degrees are stuck working as cashiers and in food service. I know a ton of people who went to community colleges (which was highly frowned upon in my high school culture) who are making six figures a couple years out of school (STEM and sales).

Why are we not being honest with these kids about the consequences of incurring student debt in unusable majors? I am not saying people shouldn't have the right to make their own major choices, but this is like handing children a pack of cigarettes and not telling them it causes cancer.

Edit: I probably exaggerated when I said worse than no degree if we are talking about long-term in their lives—I kind of meant in place of certifications or bootcamps.  What I should have said is that the lack of jobs in liberal arts fields seems to not be communicated to kids, which has significant negative financial consequences. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40349081768.0" user="hsteinbe" delta="False">
    <text>Not one of us would survive without people taking jobs that don’t require a full college degree… (and many of these jobs are highly highly skilled) Road maintenance, farming, plumbing, electricity, furniture makers, factory workers of all flavors, grocery store employees, pipe fitters, welders, construction workers, gas stations attendants, hardware store employees, clothing makers, daycare workers, and a million other professions. It takes all kinds of people doing all kinds of jobs to make a functional society. All jobs are equally valuable to our society. Unfortunately all jobs are not SEEN as equally valuable to our society…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349269866.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with the sentiment that it takes all types of jobs to make the world go round, but it's simply untrue that they're all equally valuable. Some are more valuable than others, which is why they pay more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349281200.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>Wage/salary can be very out of step with the value of some jobs. The market is full of inefficiencies and can optimize for the wrong things in some cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349294466.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>not really. you can disagree with the market, but that doesn't make the market wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349314802.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;not really.

Please feel welcome to elaborate. :)

&amp;gt;you can disagree with the market, but that doesn't make the market wrong.

I did not suggest that it is wrong *in virtue of* my disagreement lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349350270.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>Money is the unit of value measurement. However much you get paid for work is inherently how much your work is valued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349373800.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Money is the unit of value measurement. However much you get paid for work is inherently how much your work is valued.

Yes and people can be mistaken in their appraisal of value, creating market inefficiencies. The value theory that the market operates on, in being profit maximizing, maps poorly onto value forms that are not directly profitable but nevertheless beneficial for society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349405368.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>You think people can be wrong compared to your own valuations. The flaw in your logic is that you're taking your own personal opinion as absolute truth. You can say "oh golly gee, I think cashiers are worth $150,000" all you want but that doesn't mean that's actually what they're worth. Your wishful thinking does not manifest reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349440874.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You think people can be wrong compared to your own valuations.

A market inefficiency is an opportunity that can be capitalized upon. They occur all the time.

&amp;gt;The flaw in your logic is that you're taking your own personal opinion as absolute truth.

How did you arrive at this theory?

&amp;gt;You can say "oh golly gee, I think cashiers are worth $150,000" all you want but that doesn't mean that's actually what they're worth.

Where did I say this?

&amp;gt;Your wishful thinking does not manifest reality.

Which wishful thinking? You seem to be confusing me with someone or something else. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349607337.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>You appear to be arguing that all jobs are equally valuable. Looking at the the real world, they clearly are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349626039.0" user="Slinkusmalinkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You appear to be arguing that all jobs are equally valuable.

How did you arrive at this theory?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349408427.0" user="hsteinbe" delta="False">
    <text>Employment remuneration is irrelevant to value. If I have a child and have to dedicate all of my time to raising that child (24/7), then I will not have any time to do my highly skilled highly paid job (that required a lot of advanced education).  In order to do my job, I must rely on daycare workers to care for said child so I can dedicate time to my job. I need electricity to do my job, without other people putting electrical poles and wires, I cannot do my job. And on and on with millions of other examples. In a society we all rely on each other. All jobs hold equal value to society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349442425.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>You're confusing having value with having equal value. Sure all these things are valuable, but they don't have the same value. How much would you pay for a gallon of milk? Now, how much would you pay for a 3 bedroom, 2 bathroom, 2,000sqt home? A home is more valuable than a gallon of milk, which is why you're more willing to pay more for it. That's not to say milk isn't valuable, but that it's simply much less valuable than a home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349471242.0" user="hsteinbe" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t need milk or a home to do my highly paid, highly skilled job. I do however need other people doing millions of other jobs - that don’t get paid as much and don’t require as much education - in order to do my job. Without them, I cannot do my job. We have the same value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349591300.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>You're missing my point. People do jobs to provide that milk and that home to you. The products of various jobs are valued differently which is in part why the job itself is valued differently. Wanting two different things doesn't mean you want both things equally as much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349639932.0" user="hsteinbe" delta="False">
    <text>I completely understand what you are iterating. My job is useless to society, it completely stops, without all of the other people doing their jobs. Therefore we have equal value to society as a whole. To use the milk house analogy, the oil in the engine of your car is rather inexpensive when compared to the very expensive onboard computer, but without that oil your car is worthless to you. The oil is equal to the very expensive onboard computer in value of the car functioning as a whole. You need them both equally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40349752716.0" user="MobiusCube" delta="False">
    <text>I need them equally, yes, but they aren't equally valuable. Gas is less valuable because it's readily available and easy to acquire, CPUs are more valuable than a gallon of gas because it takes a lot more resources to create and isn't as easily available. Prices are a measure of value, regardless of whether you think they are or not.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
