<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817703021.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>First, I'd like to point out the exact taxes proposed for this, because unlike many politicians when they introduce an idea like this, Bernie has actual detailed exactly how to pay for this.  I see a lot of speculation mentioned in this thread, but no mention of the actual numbers that Bernie has released.  I point these specifics out because of how small they are, and how much they are generating in return.  The idea that something as hugely as expensive as this could be covered with the tiniest of taxes puts a lot of our other problems into perspective.

http://www.sanders.senate.gov/download/051915-highered/?inline=file


&amp;gt; This legislation will establish a partnership with states by developing a matching grant program
&amp;gt; which would provide $2 in federal funding for every dollar that states spend on making tuition free higher
&amp;gt; education in public colleges and universities.

&amp;gt; This legislation would also expand the federal work study program.

&amp;gt; This legislation not only addresses the crisis of college affordability, but it also deals with another
&amp;gt; issue of huge consequence for millions of families in this country. And, that is the incredibly oppressive
&amp;gt; burden of crushing student loan debt.

&amp;gt; This legislation will allow every American with student debt to refinance their loans, so that
&amp;gt; borrowers will always be able to take advantage of favorable interest rates. It makes no sense to me that
&amp;gt; Americans can refinance their homes when interest rates are low, and that somebody can purchase a car at
&amp;gt; two percent interest rates, but millions of college graduates are stuck with interest rates of 5, 6, 7 percent 
&amp;gt; 3
&amp;gt; sometimes for decades. That makes no sense. That is grossly unfair. 
This bill would cut student loan
&amp;gt; interest rates in half and lower the rate to about 2 percent for undergraduates.

&amp;gt; In addition, this legislation would eliminate the obscene profit that the federal government makes
&amp;gt; through the student loan program – some $89 billion over a ten year period. The federal government
&amp;gt; should not be profiting off of student loans provided to low and moderate income families

&amp;gt; My legislation would impose a Wall Street speculation fee of 0.5 percent on stock trades (that’s
&amp;gt; 50 cents for every $100 worth of stock), a 0.1 percent fee on bonds, and a 0.005 percent fee on
&amp;gt; derivatives.

This would generate approximately $300 billion PER YEAR, to pay for this.  The estimated costs are $750 billion over about 10 years.

I don't think that's unreasonable in any way when you consider the returns.

Edit: Point being, you're not going to be affected by this tax unless you trade stocks. So I don't think most of your post even applies like you thought it would.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817857133.0" user="rdaex" delta="False">
    <text>You need all the upvotes for this. 

The more I hear from Sanders, the more I feel he's the hero this country needs. 

Look.. You didn't get free tuition.. You got fucked really hard by student loans... Why would you want that to continue?  Isn't the point of life to leave the world a better place for our kids and those who come after us? 

You pay taxes on shit you don't use every day.. Stop letting the rich tell you (the middle class) what's "fair".. And also, eliminate the word from your vocabulary. Focus on what's RIGHT and you'll have a lot better time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818425039.0" user="cr42" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You didn't get free tuition.. You got fucked really hard by student loans... Why would you want that to continue? 

I honestly hate this mentality – the "I got the shit end of the stick, so I sure as hell don't want other people getting it easy" approach to life – because it totally misses the bigger picture, as you say, of making the world a better place for future generations. 

I don't fault OP for it, because I know other people that think this way, but it is something that I think we ought to change; it's such a selfish worldview that can be toxic to progress in society. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818444081.0" user="CTHABH" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't looked too far into it but his $15/hr minimum wage sounds like a terrible idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818474778.0" user="rdaex" delta="False">
    <text>Ah so let's dismiss him out of hand. 

Or, he has some great ideas and we need those ideas. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818478062.0" user="CTHABH" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, seems like that would serious fuck our economy. So yes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818504114.0" user="rdaex" delta="False">
    <text>It wouldn't.. And it wouldn't pass... So, no, don't. 

People don't understand compromise.. Ask for 15, get 10-12. Life will go on. I promise. Only difference is, people working those jobs won't be on (as much) assistance programs since they'd be (somewhat) able to fend for themselves </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818739954.0" user="GogglesVK" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain why it's a bad idea aside from "idk, sounds bad"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818749520.0" user="CTHABH" delta="False">
    <text>Inflation, what will happen to other people with much better (harder) jobs who get paid by the hour and right now only make $13-14 an hour. I work at burger king, I'm in highschool, I haven't earned 15 an hour yet. I'm busy right now, could explain in more detail. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818803956.0" user="GogglesVK" delta="False">
    <text>So because other jobs should get paid more as well, minimum wage shouldn't also be raised? That "If I can't have it, no one can" attitude is ridiculous. If we expect people to be able to work their way through college, there should be a reasonable way to support themselves and pay bills without being saddle with a mountain of debt.

This is all from what little info I've gleaned from reading, but, many economists agree that minimum wage wouldn't boost inflation by a large amount. In fact, they say it'll have a hugely positive effect on the economy because middle class workers tend to spend their money, and it would be spent buying goods.

Also, when you consider the fact that minimum wage has actually fallen behind the rate of inflation, I don't see much of an excuse for it being where it is right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818817201.0" user="CTHABH" delta="False">
    <text>His proposed minimum wage is over 2x the current minimum wage dude. And what do you mean "if I can't have it no one can" attitude? I don't believe that I should make the same as my brother in law who works his ass off and has been for several years when I just got hired. Like I said I really haven't read into it, and I probably shouldn't be arguing this. Are other hourly jobs gonna get raised proportionally? Or am I gonna be close to as much as my dad who's been with the same place for 20 something years? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818865144.0" user="GogglesVK" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that his proposed minimum wage is 2x higher is relevant how? It's not as if anyone wants to implement it overnight. It would happen over the course of 5 or more years.

And an "if I can't have it no one can" attitude is saying minimum wage workers should not get paid more just because other jobs are "harder". Just because teachers and scientists might deserve more money doesn't mean low-wage workers don't need more money too. I'm not a minimum wage worker, so I'm not just looking out for myself here.

Other wages wouldn't be forced to be raised proportionally, because they wouldn't be at the minimum. Individual companies will need to decide if they'd like to pay more or not.

The fact of the matter is, all of these rich million and billion dollar corporations have somehow convinced Americans that they can't afford to pay low wage workers more. That's completely false. As the wealth gap between the rich and middle class increases, we also see corporations pull in record numbers over and over. They can afford it. Minimum wage has been stunted by corporate greed so that they can slash costs, and I'm tired of making excuses for it. At the very least, minimum wage should be tied to inflation. Maybe your brother-in-law and father deserve more pay for their work too. But just because their issues might not be addressed immediately, doesn't mean we don't look to fix the obvious issue right in front of us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818608228.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it sound like a terrible idea, and why would it seriously fuck our economy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818375721.0" user="jaybestnz" delta="False">
    <text>There are some other concepts to add to this.

Currently the stock market has around 80% of all trades are executed by a computer algorithm. This creates deliberate patterns where the computer program is trying to move very quickly (really fast, like 3 tenths of a second).

This computer volatility makes the market swing erratically and very very quickly. There was a "flash crash" where somehow the market collapsed in on itself and no one can work out why, but they know that the algorithms caused it. 

This extra tax was introduced I. The UK and several other countries and it has reduced the volatility.

So the same tax causes more financial stability. This tax only impacts investors who can more than afford 50c for each $100 trade.

That is the Robin Hood tax.

Next item to be aware of is that on average, a high school grad will earn half what a uni grad will earn.

So for each grad that exists, we all earn 2x more tax on them.

At the moment, the IT sector is crying out for programmers and people who work in IT earn around 2-3x the avg salary. 

Historically we have had free Uni, and the financial rewards that hit the economy were immense.

19 % of all the income we make is spent on defense. We spent more on defenseman than the next 10 countries combined.

3% is spent on education and social services.

---

One community education program is for the unemployed. They have an 80% hire rate after training and that is to jobs like a $60k per year computer job.

This means instead of having poor youth in crap unemployment and with little hope, and many leading into crime and jail (US has one of the highest incarceration rates in the world), they are employed.

That costs $5,000 per student. It takes them from a cost to social services and food stamps to 80% earning in high paying STEM which helps our economy and they pay $12,000 every year, in taxes.

That seems smart to me.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818410037.0" user="mr_indigo" delta="False">
    <text>While I think the program is a good idea generally, part of the reason university graduates make more is because there are  less of them - their earning potential is not independent of the number of people with a degree.

Pushing lots of people through college is not justifiable on the basis that you'll get more tax from them as higher earners, as if you took all people of working age and put them through college the average amount college graduates earn would immediately drop due to the large amount of un(der)employment that would create.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818424594.0" user="jaybestnz" delta="False">
    <text>Not in a global market. If one country has a lot of Solar engineers and programmers then they are going to get higher paying jobs.

In tech you often have examples where a small team (say 20) have created a tool that disrupts millions of classified Ads, and were making $3M profit per employee.

The team salary becomes irrelevant at that level and if we are creating more high value stuff then we keep earning as a country.

Compared to low educated places,they simply can never see more than 10-30k value. Even then they are not delivering as much value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818452634.0" user="mr_indigo" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that increased earning doesn't come about just because you have a bit of paper from a university. There needs to be economic demand for the particular skills learned.

If you gave every single unskilled person in the US a college degree tomorrow, the average salary of degree holders would plummet because the demand for those college graduates would not have increased. 

Salary doesn't magically increase because of the degree paper, it increases because the demand for the graduate's skills outstrips the supply of graduates. If you make every person in the US a graduate you now have a huge supply without an increase in demand, and the average salary for college grads would drop (as the group is now a lot bigger and captures a lot more people earning little or nothing).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818507569.0" user="jaybestnz" delta="False">
    <text>For sure but the salary of all those uneducated would increase dramatically.

Also if you educate towards demand areas then that keeps pace with the market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818504645.0" user="GTFErinyes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not in a global market. If one country has a lot of Solar engineers and programmers then they are going to get higher paying jobs.

&amp;gt; Compared to low educated places,they simply can never see more than 10-30k value. Even then they are not delivering as much value.

Your point about a global market actually proves the opposite of what you are saying: 

Take a look at India. The country is awash with engineers and computer science degree holders.

You know what the result is? They get *lower* paying jobs than the average American - yes, cost of living is lower in India, but the end result is that the higher cost American CS graduate is out of a job whereas 5 Indian CS degree holders are now holding a job.

In fact, the global market is a great example of what happens when you saturate the market with a lot of engineers and programmers - they end up being common and less valuable, and thus can be acquired for less.

In addition, a country with more solar engineers isn't going to get more high paying jobs if there isn't *demand* for said solar engineers. There are upper limits on all of these things - for the same reason a region will only have so many construction contractors, garbagemen, etc. the same applies with engineers. Take a look at nuclear engineers and how regulations/moratoriums on new construction have shrunk their employment opportunities and earning potentials considerably.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818634348.0" user="ykwrgmg" delta="False">
    <text>IT is crying for stem grads with unnarinable job requirements. This is so they can hire more  h1-b workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819217664.0" user="jaybestnz" delta="False">
    <text>Huh? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818540632.0" user="theoracle12" delta="False">
    <text>But what is the opportunity cost of that? You could effectively eliminate serious poverty in America for $300 billion dollars yet you want to give it to students who are mostly middle class and will go on to get good secure jobs. This is why funding via both normal taxation and a graduate tax is probably more realistic even though I symphathise with the principle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818595890.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>You should check your logic before attempting to shift the goalposts.  This discussion is about free college, and the taxes used to do so.  This discussion is not about trading one thing for another.  Bernie has an entire platform that seeks to do FAR more than simply offer free education to people, so don't even attempt to simplify this into a single issue where we sacrifice one thing for another.  That's what has BEEN happening.  For decades.

As I said in my post, the tax being proposed for this is incredibly small and made of several tiny taxes on various related things.  So just imagine what ELSE could be done with similarly sized taxes in other areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819138574.0" user="theoracle12" delta="False">
    <text>A small tax that raises a lot of money is not a small tax. Businesses/banks would react and think about moving so you can't  just keep raising those infinitely. You might as well do something with the leeway you have to actually redistribute wealth to the poor not the middle class. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819155681.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>I could very easily start going on about the rest of Bernie's platform and how this all ties in together.  Free public college is but a small part of Bernie's entire plan.  I think you're being incredibly short sighted if you don't see the bigger picture here.  Maybe I'm being unfair and you just aren't aware of Bernie's platform.  If so, I implore you to do some research on how this one thing ties into the rest of his ideas.

But as for college - Alright, you're making a claim.  You're claiming that this will "mostly" only help middle class people.  How so?  I think your claim is false, but I'd like to see what logic you're using to reach that conclusion.  I've seen this argument several times and I become further and further entrenched in the idea that it is wrong, every time someone explains why.  So, enlighten me and attempt to convince me that the lower class won't benefit from this.  Because I think the lower "poor" class (which is quickly becoming a finer and finer line between poor and middle class) will see an incredible benefit from this.  Both immediately in the job market, BEFORE it becomes saturated, and in the long run, when we're dealing with some very serious problems.

Even if there is no guarantee of jobs, it is better for a population to be over-educated than under-educated.  The more educated a populace, the more likely they are to solve problems.  The more likely we are to accept evidence of problems, and to address them.  The more likely we are to adapt in a society where the job market is ever-shrinking due to automation.  The more likely we are to come up with political solutions, economical solutions, moral solutions.  The more we understand the world around us, and our role in it.  Education is one of the most important things we can invest in.  While that is not my sole reason for supporting it, it is the most obvious.

A simple relocation of wealth from top to bottom isn't going to solve the problem.  Putting money into nothing but job training (which is still good) and welfare is not going to solve the problem.

Education is a long-term solution to an immediate problem that simply can't be fixed immediately.  It's necessary, even if it doesn't give instant gratification to everyone.  To a great many people, it will.  And in the long run, the lower class will shrink because of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27821517125.0" user="theoracle12" delta="False">
    <text>We probably agree more than you think. I fully support Bernie's program overall and the higher education payment system in your country is shocking. There certainly should be a significant level of government funding for university education. However I would probably argue some proportion of that burden must be shared by the rich, successful graduates who go on to make the most from their degree. For example a small graduate tax on the top third of graduate earners for the first 15 years of their graduation would mean more of the income gained from general taxation of the wealthy can be used for socialist polices that genuinely redistribute wealth such as the jobs and healthcare programs you talk about, as well better child benefit, social housing, state nurseries, secondary education, income support for poorer students etc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
