<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817425053.0" user="AW12321" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?

In a way. Sanders proposes adding a small tax to transactions on the stock market, which are currently untaxed. 

&amp;gt;  I don't have the money for that. Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.

Under this plan, the only people who would actually be paying for the tuition is those who use the stock market. The majority of people who use the stock market can afford it. 

&amp;gt;And what happens with private institutions? Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?

The plan is only to fund public colleges and universities. Private colleges would probably still exist, but they'd have to be paid out of your own pocket or through loans and grants. Incidentally, your taxes already go to these grants and subsidized loans, so you are technically already paying for people to go to private colleges.

&amp;gt; Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?

Part of the reason college costs more now then it did in the past is because they aren't receiving as much funding from the government anymore. Colleges used to get more federal money per student to spend then they do now, so colleges have to make up that money through tuition. The only way to make colleges cheaper again will be if we funnel money into the colleges. Either way, somebody has to be taxed for it. 

EDIT: Part of the reason colleges are so expensive now also has in part to do with how colleges spend their money. In order to attract students who pay tuition, they have to keep building better and better facilities as students get pickier. To get good staff and teachers, they have to pay more and more wages to not only keep up with the standard of living but the expectations of their teachers. Consider that for the best teachers, they're going to choose the college that will pay them the most, and you can see how wages can start to spiral out of control. 

Not to mention there's a lot of money getting spent on sports and coaches, but I won't even start going into that, or else I'll go on a tangent that is only remotely related to the topic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817443037.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>You have certainly been most helpful but still a few questions...

Why should people in the stock market have to pay?  I am all for people paying their fair share and I know a lot of people with money don't.  But I am also against the thought that just because they have money means the government should be able to force them into paying for everything.  Just because they have money does not mean the rest of us should feel entitled to it and get mad when they don't want to pave the way for us.

And though I see your point about the cost of colleges, I mean come on, does it really cost $20,00 a year to house me?  That is a bit ridiculous.  And the worst part is that sometimes colleges don't even allow you to find housing off campus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817461963.0" user="AW12321" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am all for people paying their fair share and I know a lot of people with money don't.

That's why. It's so hard to get people to pay their fair share that taxing certain transactions is one of the only way to get extra taxes out of the wealthy without specifically saying you're targeting the wealthy. I mean, anybody can really buy stocks. 

&amp;gt; Just because they have money does not mean the rest of us should feel entitled to it and get mad when they don't want to pave the way for us.

The poor, who make enough to qualify for paying taxes, proportionally pay much more. That's not a fair share. We don't feel entitled to that money, so much as we feel that everybody should have to pay their fair share. If we're expected to pay our taxes to pay for roads and schools that we use, why aren't they? Because the truth is that a lot of really wealthy people don't pay nearly as much, proportionally, as the poor. So while the majority of money already comes from the wealthy, the wealthy pay less proportionally to their income. 

&amp;gt; I mean come on, does it really cost $20,00 a year to house me?

See my edit. Part of your tuition also pays for the wages of teachers and administration and facilities on campus you may never use. It pays for campus police services you may never need to use, and sports stadiums you may never set foot in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817536101.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>Are you then suggesting something like a flat tax rate?

Also, there is no way the colleges need all the money we pay them.  Usually it is broken down to something where you pay x amount for room and board, x amount for tuition, x amount for "fun" things, etc.  More often than not is is ridiculous. 

What if we did something like streamlined colleges?  A friend of mine was a biomedical engineer who had to take a languages of japan class.  Maybe that is not really necessary and if we cut down the time people are at college, we can also cut down the cost?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817580214.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>A very simple example to show the problem with flat taxes that I like is this:

If I give you $100,000 today, I'm sure you could spend that without issue.  I do the same thing tomorrow, that will go to.  Lets just say I keep giving you $100,000 every day from now on.  Some time toward the end of this week, you're going to run out of bills to pay.  You will move on to the things you want but have been holding off on and sometime next week you'll start buying shit you don't have any meaningful use for.  Next month you're just giving it away and it doesn't matter, the numbers in your bank just keep getting bigger and bigger.  You truly stop worrying about money because it has no meaning, you spend and spend and your life really isn't much better than it was on the 3rd day I gave you $100,000.

Now realize that there are people who literally live that life.  Why do you think its fair that both you living with your bills and them buying whatever pops into their brain should pay the same tax rate?

The purpose of progressive rates is to balance out the demands of living.  Not everyone can afford to give away 30% of their income, but there are some who could give away 60% and still not know the pain of not being able to pay an electric bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817597738.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point, I really do. I am just really confused on what to think because I can see both sides of the coin.  

Taxes hurt the poor a lot more than the rich and often contributes to them not being able to get out of poverty.  Obviously that is not a good thing.  But does that make it fair for us to take from the rich more just because they can afford it?  

If I had millions of dollars I would definitely donate money and create charities and programs.  But the minute the government tells me that I have to give more than my fair share "just because I can and should", I would get angry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817619530.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>So stop looking at it like a social issue and start looking at it like a game.

The people are the players and the money is the points.  People are going to cheat the system any way they can to get more points in their pocket.  It should be the governments job to be the league and referee, ensuring the rules are fare for all players and everyone has an equal chance of winning.

Why are we making it ok for the rich people to write the rules where they start with a 200,000 point lead and they get significantly more points for every action they take.  Not to mention if they make a mistake, we give them bonus points to get back into the game.  The poor people on the other hand have refs all over them calling every foul and throwing them out of the game for the slightest infraction.

The game is already jacked, don't buy into the winners telling you how unfair the system is when it clearly favors them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817633271.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>That is like the monopoly experiment they did on that documentary Park Avenue.  And while watching it, I realized how unfair the system is.  That being said, what if we just made the system fair instead of strictly upping their taxes?

Like I said, I do not know a lot about this but in the documentary they mentioned a bunch of loop holes the rich got if they played their cards right.  So why don't we first work on getting rid of the loop holes first?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817651092.0" user="daryk44" delta="False">
    <text>Upping their taxes is the easiest way to make the system fair. There are always going to be more loopholes to find as time goes on. Especially if we constantly make new legislature, which is obviously bound to happen. Every time a new bill is introduced, players in Congress will try to sneak in amendments and bullshit stipulations that are otherwise irrelevant for that particular piece of legislature. Taxes are an easy way to paint with a broad brush, and they're much more difficult to avoid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817756216.0" user="Metabro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Upping their taxes is the easiest way to make the system fair.  

Its makes the game more balanced.  Its like putting the tallest players on opposite teams in basketball.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817710922.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>Because they've already bought the people who write the loopholes into legislation for them.  You should really watch more of Bernie's rhetoric if you haven't.  He addresses exactly this; that we are losing control over the process due to how far money has seeped into politics.  Getting rid of loopholes is only possible if you control Congress and the White House.  Likewise, adding loopholes in is only possible if you control Congress and the White House.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817720543.0" user="FFX01" delta="False">
    <text>The very nature of loopholes is that there are always more of them. Seal one off, and it creates another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818237359.0" user="mathball31" delta="False">
    <text>That's a large part of what Sanders is trying to do to raise money for his programs. [Close loopholes](http://www.sanders.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/sanders-asks-obama-to-close-six-egregious-corporate-tax-loopholes)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818484253.0" user="RandomMandarin" delta="False">
    <text>The earliest version of Monopoly was called [The Landlord's Game](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Landlord%27s_Game),  and it was intended to teach players how the system of rent and ownership inevitably ends with a few rich landlords and a lot of poor people who own nothing. So, if Monopoly seems like a heartless game, it's *supposed* to.

Incidentally, the reason Monopoly games last too long is that most players don't follow all the rules (they just feel TOO vicious!). Follow the rules as written, and Monopoly games typically last something like 45 minutes, because one player quickly gets too strong and rich for anyone else to beat. Hence, monopoly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818577462.0" user="OCedHrt" delta="False">
    <text>Fair is really an objective term. On your earlier question:

&amp;gt;Obviously that is not a good thing. But does that make it fair for us to take from the rich more just because they can afford it?

I think they key is to make sure they're not making less after taxes than someone who makes less before taxes - and that will be true because only the extra income is taxed at a higher rate.

Because the tax is on income and not equity, it's not the same as "[taking] from the rich more just because they can afford it" and rather means "money gets harder to earn as you start earning more of it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819339047.0" user="mylarrito" delta="False">
    <text>Because there is too much influence from those who benefit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818673478.0" user="ohgr4213" delta="False">
    <text>I want to address a few different points that you brought up. 

I think you are actually misleading others and perhaps yourself by arranging your thought experiments the way you did.

Part of this discussion goes back to Jeremy Bentham who made the same decreasing marginal utility of an additional dollar argument that you reference. 

IE - another dollar is worth more to a person that makes $15,000 than it would be to a person that makes 15 million. If you take a dollar (or a million) from the 2nd person and gave it to the first person, theoretically you would have more total utility.

There is a fundamental problem in relying on that reasoning to make a wealth transfer, you don't know by how much each given dollar adds/removes from the persons utility. Further you are implying at some point that we can measure utility between people, which to accomplish what you want to implies cardinal utility. Economics as a discipline has mostly given up cardinal utility as untenable.

see: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cardinal_utility
and http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ordinal_utility

So what you are actually arguing for in practice, is that difference the rich person values an additional dollar less therefore it is okay to take that dollar from him and give it to the poor man, what illustrates that you are being arbitrary is when I ask you to answer, when should you stop taking dollars from the rich and giving them to the poor? There is no good answer to this question.

You also purposefully or not cut the line of cause and effect to make it a distribution problem which doesn't actually reflect economic phenomena. Once you simplified it to a distribution problem you then had an easier time of trying to make it an equity question. As above however, you should acknowledge that whatever methed you used to apply your equitable distribution will have different winners and losers than would otherwise exist and will cause economic distortion which will likely result in the total amount of wealth in society being less than it could have been. Further one could on similar grounds make exactly the same arguments and use a totally different method to determine equity and you couldn't really fault them in any fundamental way. This is where its particularly hard not to acknowledge that you are involving not obvious values propositions which are relatively arbitrary in nature. 

On another level extending further, say it was the grandfather that gave those bonus points to our hero. How did he get that wealth? Provided it wasn't explicit theft or somesuch, that person provided some sort of service that involved people willingly exchanging money for. Do you feel comfortable after the fact punishing said person who earned his money legitimately for not consuming it himself or appropriating those funds for any other potential purpose but instead saving them to take care of his family? Realistically speaking, all else equal, if he had known that you would make such a policy he would have likely made different decisions. Is that fair or equitable?

Let me note, that I don't think this is actually how things work but... The particularly funny part is thinking like "The game is already jacked, don't buy into the winners telling you how unfair the system is when it clearly favors them." is a circular prophecy and exactly that which you find detestable in those that "won" and why that winning is illegitimate. A similar premise from the other direction would be "if its unfair anyway, I might as well win because I deserve it." both variations would be rationalizing to give themselves the most advantage in a predictable way while being incoherent if applied systematically. It's always the other guy that didn't deserve what he has. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818829261.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>I understand what you're saying, but I also don't care to get into a big quoting discussion.

I don't think the winners are detestable.  I play a lot of games and I like using games to describe things like economics.  The average person doesn't understand "playing to win" in life.  We have these assumptions of working hard for your family and living a fulfilling life etc etc etc but when you put things in terms of "points" and "winning team" it removes those assumptions.  It is an analogy yes, but I feel like I am removing more from the situation than I'm adding.  That's why I use it.

I am also a big proponent of competitive play and playing to win and a lot of people will get upset at me for identifying with people who bend the rules in sport and in life.  If that's the best way to get ahead, why should we hate on that person for doing everything possible to win?

All of that said, I have no problem with things like inheritance tax, I am on the other side of that argument.  If you're just hanging on to that money, it should go back to society.  So much of this political stuff comes down to personal values etc anyway so... I don't know.  I'm just saying my personal philosophy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817622244.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>Rich Americans also benefit more from public services than poor ones. A working class person benefits from public schools, public roads, etc for themselves and their family. A business owner with thousands of employees benefits from those services thousands of times over because those services provide for their employees things that they themselves now don't have to pay for directly with their wages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817740241.0" user="Metabro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Taxes hurt the poor a lot more than the rich and often contributes to them not being able to get out of poverty. 

Source?  

&amp;gt;But the minute the government tells me  

Btw its not "the government."  Its us.  We are telling people the amount that they need to share because they aren't sharing right.  

Imagine a small tribe of hunters.  One hunter does well, and rather than dividing what he has caught among the tribe (the women that stayed and tended to the home, the leaders that makes decisions, the warriors that protect him, etc.) he rationalizes that because what he caught was caught by him, that he shouldn't have to share.  He crosses his arms and little frownie *hmmph* and tells the rest of the village that he doesn't wanna share, because it just isn't *fair.*  

How do you think those people that do more than their fair share in other aspects of his life (getting his back on the battle field, making sure his lean to doesn't blow away while he is gone, etc.) are going to react?  At best they'd probably start to resent him.  He'd respond and get it right after a little learning process.  Through discourses with the other villagers he would come to understand the value of the person that spent the better part of an afternoon fixing his shitty tie jobs on his tent, the value of the man that killed the spearman behind him on the battlefield, and the words of his village elders.  If he is wise himself he will see how though diverse in their contributions, it is *fair* to share with his tribe.

But we live in a much larger society that would allow the hunter to miser his hoard facelessly if he wanted.  This creates situations where people do not have that natural learning process of classical conditioning. They are able to go through life with the hunter's original definition of "fair."  

Rather than just not killing the spearman behind him, or letting his tent blow away, we elect officials to bypass this step.  Through those leaders we create a system of sharing so that the hunter stays alive and housed.  This makes the tribe run a little more smoothly.  




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817740249.0" user="kyew" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But does that make it fair for us to take from the rich more just because they can afford it?

Yes. Because that money isn't going to luxuries people don't need, it's going to ensuring people stay alive, healthy, and safe. Making sure Person A can afford a third car doesn't compare to making sure Person B can keep the heat on this winter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817842456.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But does that make it fair for us to take from the rich more just because they can afford it?

It's not just because they can afford it, it's because the rich disproportionately benefit from the things we all pay for in our society and should therefore be paying a much larger chunk.

Ignore for a second the moral and societal impetus for the rich to pay more in taxes to benefit humanity and think about the "rich" in general and what they do versus what you or me or the average working Joe does.

You or me, we drive to work and we drive home from work.  One car, small section of road, not much impact.  The owner of Wal-Mart employs fleets of thousands of trucks, all of them using public roads to transport their goods.

Those trucks are protected from theft by a police system and judicial system.  If a truck crashes, it is responded to by firemen who will put out the blaze and save the life of the driver.  Their stores exist on a public electrical grid, and are accessed by ALL their customers from public roads leading to their parking lots.  They also exist in a country protected from external threats by our military.

Society is all interconnected.  Those who make the most money, utilize the most services.  Is it fair that you pay the same taxes to use that same tiny stretch of road that the Waltons use to put wear and tear on a hundred thousand roads in all 50 states?  They are profiting from using those roads that we all pay for every single day as well as every other service I listed which is afforded to them, free of charge, just for living in our country.

Also note that they are the ones who can afford it without changing their lifestyle in any way to accommodate those taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817945679.0" user="TheGoldilocksZone" delta="False">
    <text>Rich people drive on roads payed by taxpayer money (as do their employees). They use services supplemented by taxpayer money. Their businesses are subsidised by taxpayer money. They benefit from the security funded by taxpayer money (military, police). They live in a healthier environment because of taxpayer funded regulation. And on, and on, and on.

Their wealth and their quality of life would be unsustainable except for taxpayer money.

If you had to value their use of publicly funded goods (including their businesses, employees, and themselves every time they fly around in a private jet), the amount of value they get expressed in money is far higher than someone who's poor.

And yet, although they get all this value out of the tax system, the rich still manage to minimise their tax to the point where you are probably paying more tax per year than a millionaire or billionaire.

Does this sound fair?

Being part of a society means making a contribution to it. As evidenced by tax receipts, the rich try everything they can to minimise that contribution. So I'm not going to cry any tears over a progressive taxation system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818731002.0" user="Brettster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But does that make it fair for us to take from the rich more just because they can afford it?

Yes. There's no reason it's not fair. They live under society's laws, and the only reason they have something called "money" is because of this system they were born into and played along with. There's nothing about our current system that is somehow natural law. The amount of money you take home due to your job is not your natural right, it's simply what the system provides at that moment. We decide what is fair and not fair. A tax rate of 35% instead of 38% is not inherently more fair. These are just arbitrary lines in the sand. What matters more is what WORKS, what rates create a self sustaining, thriving ecosystem that doesn't collapse on itself or leave people dying in the streets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819153117.0" user="Telcontar77" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so here's part of the argument for taxing the rich; they used to pay way more in tax, then they started lobbying and buying politicians and progressively got their taxes reduced. Don't think of it as increasing taxes on the rich so much so as bringing it back to a sensible level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817806237.0" user="THeShinyHObbiest" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument against a flat tax has a kind of strange definition of "Fair." By your logic, almost everybody in the United States really should be donating large swaths of their income to people who can't even find clean water. For them, "the pain of not being able to pay an electric bill" is a daily reality—so much so that they've never paid on in their entire lives. Or any bill, due to severe poverty.

You're not really balancing out demands of living, since the cost of being alive in America is relatively constant (although it does vary based on location). So you're not balancing out the demands of living, you're just balancing out surplus cash. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817829457.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>Philosophically, I would agree, we all should be giving up 90% of our paychecks to help those people throughout the world who are in need.

Say you're strolling down the pathway of a park and you see a kid drowning in a small pool of water.  Hell, you can probably walk in and save him no swimming needed, but that kid is dying.  Would you jump in and save him?

Most people would say yes.  You give no consideration to the clothes you just ruined, the phone in your pocket that is now worthless, and the minor personal risk you take on to save another persons life.  This choice is easy to you because you can see the clear outcome (do something: kid is safe, don't do something: kid is dead).

Very realistically, you personally can save the life of some child in Africa on a DAILY basis for like $.30 a day blablabla.

Why are you willing to throw away all those physical things to save someone in person but you aren't willing to give up 1% of that for a very real life saved on the other side of the planet?  Simple, it's not your problem.

If we really truly seriously wanted to solve world hunger, we would have to enact a world power with the authority to tax rich nations like the US in order to donate to the poor nations.  We have the food, we have the clothing, we have the power, but we lack the will.  I agree with your assertion that we should be doing it, the big part of that statement that is missing though is the "how."  And holy shit is that a hard "how" to answer.

As far as rich and poor people in America though, we already have the authority to tax the rich higher than the poor, THAT IS THE BASIS OF OUR CURRENT TAX SYSTEM.  But once again, we lack the will.  The difference here is the "how" has already been answered for us, we just choose not to press the button.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817954138.0" user="THeShinyHObbiest" delta="False">
    <text>I really, really, really don't think an organization should be able to arbitrarily tax any country. Even if it starts for a good purpose, that's way too much power to put in anybody's hands.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818029131.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, so lets stop trying to solve the problems for the whole world and solve the problems for our country, an area where we, as a nation, have agreed that having one federal government is an acceptable amount of centralized power.

Maybe some day we can get to the rest of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818539650.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>The problem here is that you are arguing that a government or organization is inherently better than the average person at spending their money to solve world problems. I don't see why that would necessarily be the case. All you would be doing is taking money away from people who may or may not need it and give it to some other people who definitely don't but may or may not pass it along to those who do. Often times large projects designed to better the lives of others fail utterly in their primary objective.

I would refer you to [this 2009 study from New York University](http://dri.fas.nyu.edu/docs/IO/12361/WilliamsonRAEAid.pdf) that suggested that foreign aid programs have has essentially no beneficial impact in terms of GDP growth or poverty reduction. Why? Because large, top down centrally planned programs are inherently poorly structured to handle these problems. We've functionally squandered $2.3 trillion over the past 50 years on schemes that have accomplished very little. Giving the UN the power to tax rich countries to do more of the same would just result in more waste and corruption.

We all want to save the drowning kid, but not if at the cost of our own lives or possibly both of our lives. When that scenario plays out there are many people who don't dive into the water and others who do without hesitation, this isn't because some are *good* and the others are *bad* but because some people believe that they can actually pull it off and others come to the internal conclusion that having two drowning people in the pool is worse than one.

Without a better, and thoroughly tested, methodology for actually lifting people out of poverty being called for any suggestion that we should tax people more heavily to provide foreign aid is unambiguously bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818627676.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>I am not assuming the government is better, I am assuming that they make it the law and by not playing along, you are breaking the law.

Going back to the game analogy.  It's hard to say yes when we ask you to donate 30 points to the other team.  Its hard to say no when you are penalized 30 points.

It's not that its better, it can be shown forever and ever that it's worse, none of that matters.  What's important is that it forces people to play along or break the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818726531.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>But why should it be the law?

If no one is winning why should they play along?

It doesn't help the poor person if one powerful person takes money from another. Government taking power or money from Business or the other way around is meaningless and pointless to what really matters.

I don't understand why anyone should be punished for not agreeing with me. Can you explain why I should be punished for not agreeing with you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818868942.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>Government is supposed to use that money on the people.

Business is supposed to use that money on themselves.

By having our government do what a government is supposed to do, we don't need to feel upset about businesses doing what they are supposed to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818939506.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>So, what you're saying is that *any* government spending including the spending on Mass Surveillance, questionable military ventures in the Middle East, and out and out vote buying on the behalf of established politicians for "pork" spending on their districts is a money spent on the people? I would argue that your argument is founded on a dangerous generality.

Remember those [Studies on International Aid](https://williameasterly.files.wordpress.com/2010/08/40_easterly_canforeignaidbuygrowth_prp.pdf) this is money spent on the people. It is money taken from wealthy nations and spend on the poorest people in the world. The idea is that by letting them do what aid is supposed to do then things will get done and we don't have to worry about other problems, no?

Well, the problem is that this idea is fundamentally broken for several reasons. Those giving the aid often have no idea what the needs of the people they are ostensibly helping actually are. They spent millions of dollars trying to teach the people of Lesotho how to ranch cattle and wheat while opening up the local markets to international trade. This ignored that the local markets had been open to international trade before Europeans even showed up in South Africa, and the primary source of household wealth in Lesotho was getting wages from South African mining ventures. No one in Lesotho was interested in ranching, that was how they saved for retirement as cows pay dividends in milk and appreciate in value by calves. The local residents had known that wheat farming was simply noncompetitive. So millions of dollars that *could* have been used by individuals to better their own or other people's lives were instead taken halfway around the world to make people learn things they already knew. The people of Lesotho had a handful of things that they desperately needed, mostly water infrastructure, but they had no way to tell the aid agencies that. The government of Lesotho made out like bandits, however, as they were able to build roads and got free political offices for the ruling party in rural areas that they had little political influence over previous.

There are hundreds of examples of poor information, no oversight, or the political leaders went with their own interests over those of the people and the people either saw no improvement or were *actively harmed* by those programs. Everything from the Great Leap Forward to Tanzania's Ujaama Villages to Reaganomics were programs launched with the best of intentions but either failed entirely or were unmitigated disasters.

Taking money away from places where it does *some* good for *some* people and giving it to places that *should* to good but ultimately *fails* is a net loss for everyone.

We should put money where it does the most good using the most effective methods. The government isn't that most effective method for most things. The interests of the government don't align perfectly with the interests of the people. I would prefer encouraging *direct investment* from people who have to people who need. That would result in better end use, lower loss to overhead, and minimize the loss to those who work for those who have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818961797.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not disagreeing with any of what you're saying, but it is also getting pretty far from where this thread started.  It began as a CMV for whether or not "free" college is a good idea.

I got involved when the discussion moved toward how we would actually pay for it and flat tax was mentioned.

Now we're talking about donating millions of dollars to African nations and corruption eating large portions of the money and what little DID see the ground was ultimately ineffective because the solution was wrong to begin with.

I also don't see how trying to encourage people to donate excess funds has ANYTHING TO DO WITH GOVERNMENT TAXATION.  This is commonly used as an argument by the republican party and they have nothing to do with each other.  The Government quite specifically takes your money and spends it how they best see fit.  Donating is where you take your own money and give it away to people because you see a social benefit.  If people donated sufficiently in the first place, we wouldn't need these government programs.  In this world, that doesn't happen, so the need for these programs is self-evident.

Flat tax is a unfair to poor people, especially when trying to pay for a social program like free college.

I think your concern for government spending at large is detracting from the conversation at this point.  Unless you're somehow trying to say that paying for poor people to go to school in the U.S. is an equally bad use of our tax dollars as this Lesotho situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819003561.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, going back to the original CMV, the point I was trying to make is that spending money on a *good idea* like making tuition nominally free often ends up with governments spending millions, billion, or trillions and ultimately fail to accomplish what could be accomplished through other means.

There is a political elite that can be every bit as pernicious as the economic elite. Steve Jobs did what was best for Steve Jobs. Hilary Clinton does what is best for Hilary Clinton. The difference here, from my perspective at least, is largely academic. Only when Steve Jobs spent my money at least I got an iPod out of it first.

I would argue that a flat tax *in conjunction with a negative income tax* would have all the benefits of food stamps, free college education, and social security in addition to any number of other programs without the overhead and unnecessary political fights that have the potential to ruin lives or create poverty traps.

I'm saying that the government ordering offering free college doesn't help a lot of people, college isn't really necessary for a lot of careers and lifestyles. This is likely to *alter* people's behavior because they *should* want to go to college because *the powerful say so*, rather than *letting people make their own decisions and helping them get where they want to go*.

Does Johnny Isakson or Barbara Boxer know what you should be doing with your life better than you do? Of course not. I don't trust those people any more than I would let Bill Gates or Warren Buffett plan our military response to a potential Russian intervention in Poland.

Letting members of the political 1% or the economic 1% run everything is a bad idea. I need to run my life. We need to run our society together. Defaulting to let large institutions do whatever they want is fundamentally a terrible idea. When we experiment with letting them they fail just about every time. I don't know about you, but I can't accept surrendering ever more of my political and economic power to others for such questionable results. *We can do better*. We need to do better. They deserve better, and I deserve better. I don't trust Wall Street or Washington to do better, because they never have done better. I *might* do better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819545096.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>The sentiment that the government can do nothing but fail at big social programs is wrong though.

The interstate highway system is an obvious project that lasted for multiple decades and has created something that the average american uses on a daily basis.  You can make all kinds of arguments for how business could do it better and cheaper, and I'm sure they have some legitimacy to them, but nobody had the incentive to do anything on that scope except for the federal government.

I am a veteran and the GI bill, specifically the post 9/11 one has been great for myself and many others.  It is literally paying my way through college right now AND paying me to go.  Big win for veterans and the federal government there.

Paying for all citizens college doesn't have to be much different.  Not everyone takes advantage of the GI bill as it is.  Just because the government reduces the cost of going to school that doesn't make it mandatory.  Trades that don't require school can still exist regardless.

You say that making school free doesn't help a lot of people, and I'm sure that's true.  But I say it ALSO helps a lot of people as well.  Why can't the people that need school go for free and the people that don't... don't?

Why is it ok for there to be a financial cost associated with gaining the skills required to be successful in society?  Isn't that what Apprenticeship has long been for?  Giving people the opportunity to learn a craft by working their way through rather than paying their way through.  What makes school so different that we think you should pay AND work?

I personally value education.  I have seen what it does to people.  It is the only thing that lets the average person have any shot at climb their way into the realm of possibly being great.  The fact that the cost of attending a university has risen several hundred percent in the past few decades is alarming to me.  It should not cost significant money to learn, only time and dedication.

If we can get there without government intervention, great, where do I sign?  I don't think we can.  I would happily pay a higher tax rate to ensure others have that opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819765748.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't intend to imply that governments never succeed at anything, that premise is obviously untrue on its face. I'm simply pointing out that *good intentions are not enough*. The program has to be well constructed based on the actual preferences of the beneficiaries of the programs, it can't be primarily ideologically driven (driven by a notion of how things *should* be as opposed to how they actually are), the planning has to be both comprehensive and flexible, those creating and implementing the program need to be accountable for their decisions to the beneficiaries of the program (or their representatives), and the program cannot be bogged down with either excessive overhead or institutional corruption. If even one of these prerequisites are out of line you go from an obvious win to a questionable program that fails to live up to its potential. If several are out of alignment then you can easily end up worse off than you would have been had you not bothered in the first place.

The Interstate Highway System is a social program? It definitely wasn't constructed to make the average person's life better, in fact much of its impact was mostly unanticipated. The premise was to improve interstate commerce and improve the military's ability to reposition assets. The road trip to grandma's was a surprise to the planners. There had been a number of stabs at private toll road and state-funded public highways prior to the Interstate Highway System. Remember the Pennsylvania Turnpike (Now I-76) was completed decades before the Interstate Highway System was a thing, and Private Turnpikes were a part of the American Road System since at least 1791. I'm not saying that anyone else was about to step in and build a private equivalent to the network of Freeways that we have today, just that the gas tax that pays for it tracks well with usage and were reasonably well spent (even if they don't actually invest money into maintaining the roads already built) and were following a very well defined pattern. They basically copied the limited access State Highway and overlaid the existing road network (most Interstates follow older roads designated US Highways by older laws). It was a very simple idea using mature technology and methods designed to benefit the government's policing and military aims, which also happened to pay massive unforeseen dividends for the average person.

The GI bill is another excellent program, and allows many people whose life goals require a college education to get one. But what if someone wants to be a plumber? They don't need to go to college, but it's *free* to them. They are *expected* to go to college whether it actually helps them or not. There are a lot of people going into fields that require expertise and knowledge that colleges simply do not provide, and it costs people a great deal to build classrooms and hire professors to teach people who neither need nor want to be taught. People talk about increased earnings potential and social benefits, but those advantages don't exist for those people. You get a huge social benefit for taking a person from a trailer park and turning that person into a doctor, not so much if you turn a middle class self employed plumber into a middle class self employed plumber with a Medieval Literature degree.

So, we have some choices. We can benefit one group of people at the expense of another, after all we are taxing *everyone* to fund a program that *only benefits people are seeking white collar work*, or we can craft a program that *helps everyone*. How much does the average college education cost? $40,000? $60,000? So, why don't we set it up that we just *give* people the money to cover college and let them decide if they want to use it for that purpose, or to start their own plumbing business, or as a down payment on a house, or to clear debt acquired before they learned how credit cards worked. You get literally all of the benefits of paying colleges directly to teach the person while also allowing people to use the money *the most efficient way possible for their own ends*. Will some people squander the money? Absolutely, but our choice then is between squandered money and squandered money, there's no loss if we are truly committed to helping people pay for their education.

Remember, the choice isn't between *doing nothing* and *what Bernie Sanders wants to do*. There are a near infinite number of possibilities, and there's no reason to tie ourselves to a losing proposition because we don't want to take the five minutes required to critically evaluate it and come up with a program that answers common criticisms.

Also, *you don't need a college degree to be successful in society*. There are a huge number of alternatives, and college degrees really only help you get hired by large corporations. The educational value in a college degree is now offered free over the internet by sites such as [Coursera](https://www.coursera.org/). Most Ivy League schools post their lecture courses online. People can readily learn on their own time for free, the only thing those tens of thousands of dollars buys you is a certificate of completion that allows HR departments check off boxes.

To reiterate my base points in bullet form:

* The information contained in college courses are available for free online.
* Many people do not require a college education to be successful in life.
* A large number of people go to college because they are expected or told to, not because they have a reason to.
* Colleges are unnecessarily expensive because the true cost of education has been removed from the decision making process.
* We can have all the benefits of having free college tuition by giving everyone a guaranteed minimum income or a one shot payment equal to the average cost of a college education.
* The "just give people money" approach would also benefit people who don't need to or want to go to college just as much as those who do.
* Those who don't go to college would still use that money to either cover necessary large purchases (house, car), start businesses (which increases tax revenue), expend frivolously (which increases tax revenue), or invest prudently (which increases tax revenue over the long run and reduces the burden on social welfare programs for the elderly). 

I believe that we get 100% of the benefits of social security, Medicaid, minimum wage laws, Disability, Unemployment, the GI bill, Food Stamps, and many similar government programs for much less cash outlay if we just cut the crap about trying to control the behavior of poor people and just cut them a check. Think about it, SNAP and Food Stamps have had massive headaches and need to pay enforcement costs in order to prevent people from spending that money on things other than food. I think that's a massive waste of time and money. We want to give relatively poor young adults a shot at having a better life then they could manage on their own, so why put a gun to their heads and demand they go to college? You've taken a thing that is intended to help them accomplish their own goals and turned it into something that is trying to control them by imposing foreign dreams and ambitions upon them. Who the hell am I to tell you that you should want to be a doctor, accountant, or lawyer as opposed to a convenience store owner, electrician, or pilot?

College needs to be an *option*, not an *obligation*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819873370.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; College needs to be an option, not an obligation

I get what you're saying.  Your promoting the idea of negative income tax like you mentioned before.  I would get behind a negative income tax 100%.  But nobody is talking about that right now. Democrats get upset because their social programs are all cut.  Republicans get upset because it sounds too much like welfare and socialism.  If we could get past all that, I have seen enough about negative income for me to be supportive of the idea.

But Bernie is talking about free school right now, and I will take that half measure.  Maybe it works out terribly and the social discussion moves to how the solution just isn't right "If I could just spend the money how I need it rather than how the government decides, I would be in a much better position."  Lets see that plastered all over the news for a while and then we can talk about negative income tax.

It's an idea worth exploring, but I don't see a pathway to getting there right now in the current political climate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27820035440.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>You know who's been talking about a negative income tax? Economists. They've been harping on it since the 1980's. They actually managed to get Reagan to put in most of the back end requirements in the IRS back in the day, but it never really got that far in Congress. Instituting a Negative Income Tax would be relatively easy given that between Social Security and the IRS we wouldn't even have to spend extra money to manage it. But, there's only so much the technocrats in Public Finance can do in a bubble.

In the mean time, I'm really questioning the utility of piling up half measures and broken concepts under the premise that *anything* is better than waiting. That only makes it harder and harder to get a comprehensive solution. If we spend all of our time plugging holes and emotionally committing to some stop gaps then we'll end up with a herd of sacred cattle that would make it progressively harder to make the essential changes we've needed to for a generation already.

I understand that people say "don't let perfect be the enemy of good enough", but there are many cases were being impatient and going for a poorly designed and conceived solution just made everything worse and forced us to wait even longer to finally deal with the problem. My worst case scenario isn't that the government does nothing, my worst case scenario is that the government blunders into the fray and smashes the whole thing inadvertently while trying to help.

The government can be a great force for good, or the source of disaster. Faith that the government doing *something* would make things better is often misplaced. Foreign aid, War on Drugs, War on Crime, (arguably) Great Society/War or Poverty, and government sponsored drug studies (like that syphilis study in Alabama) are all examples of the government trying to fix a thing, but just expending large sums for an insufficient, zero, or negative outcome. We need to carefully control those *what* we pursue and *how* we pursue them, so that when we swing we actually connect. We can turn government into an unambiguous force for good, but it's not one now because we're trying to force it to do things that it really can't do or the methodology we are pursuing it have been mangled so badly during the political process that it completely fails to achieve any meaningful result.

I do have to point out that we control the political climate. We aren't at the mercy of external forces beyond our control, we simply aren't expending any meaningful effort in pursuing those goals. The general mood of Americans *IS* the political climate. When it's hard to press for more welfare spending it's because *people don't believe that existing welfare is working*. Recently in Atlanta some 71% of people view traffic as the biggest problem, but a Transportation Special Local Option Sales Tax was voted down *badly*. Why? The "political climate" was unfavorable. That's really just shorthand because people didn't believe that the plan made sense, they didn't trust the people pushing for it, and they simply didn't believe that they would meet the goals they were setting for themselves. People said no. How could they fix it when they try again? Make a plan people agree with, get different people to run the process, and set up better ways to accomplish it. All of a sudden the political climate would be completely different. It turns out that many (most?) people don't want to sign on to plans that don't make sense because "something is better than nothing".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818190790.0" user="likeahorse17" delta="False">
    <text>The difference you fucking idiot is that nobody is giving someone unlimited money. And life isn't fair dipshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818215327.0" user="JermStudDog" delta="False">
    <text>Real civil.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817475565.0" user="thatmorrowguy" delta="False">
    <text>The NYSE and others can only exist and succeed because investors have confidence in them.  They have confidence that the exchange is being run honestly and that if there are disputes they'll be settled in an impartial court of law.  They have confidence that financial disclosures have to be done accurately and according to industry regulations.  For all that Reddit likes to decry 'banksters' (and there are very real problems with Wall Street regulation), the US is still a very very good place to do business.  A transaction tax is simply saying that in order to trade stocks on our exchanges - that the government helps to regulate, maintain, and police - you owe the government a tax in exchange.

As for what the government chooses to do with that income, that's a separate matter entirely - money is fungible.  Sure, you can say the financial transaction tax pays for schools, but once it has been deposited into the US treasury, it is no different from any other tax that has been collected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817672979.0" user="ellipses1" delta="False">
    <text>I think one of the criticisms, though, is that a transaction fee is extremely burdensome. Right now, we tax profits... "New money..." Dividends and capital gains. You only pay taxes when you make money. The transaction tax taxes every exchange... For an "average" person with an investment account or a 401k, that ends up being tens of thousands of dollars over the life of the account. It would be better to figure out the amount you want to collect and increase the long term capital gains rate to achieve that goal by taking profits the way we do now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817908386.0" user="thatmorrowguy" delta="False">
    <text>Then what exactly is a sales tax other than a transaction tax of retail goods rather than a transaction of cash for shares?  How about a use tax?  A property tax?  A tariff?

The proposed transaction tax is $0.50 per $100 transaction.  For an index fund investor or even your general mutual fund investor it's a pretty negligible loss.  Stock brokers already typically charge anywhere from $10 to $50 per transaction - I fail to see how adding an extra .5% is going to ruin anyones' retirement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817932837.0" user="ellipses1" delta="False">
    <text>Why tax a transaction that isn't profitable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817961419.0" user="thatmorrowguy" delta="False">
    <text>Why not tax a transaction that isn't profitable?  It's not like the NYSE and your stock broker don't apply a fee for every transaction.  Shops still charge sales tax even if they're selling goods at a loss (for example clearance items).  Depending on which side you apply the transaction tax on, you're either paying the government for the privilege of buying stock in the US, or you're paying the government for the privilege of selling stock in the US.  Whether you make a profit on the endeavor is a moot point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818012655.0" user="ellipses1" delta="False">
    <text>I am not willing to pay that tax, so I'll trade on a different exchange that doesn't charge it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817676727.0" user="CrimsonSmear" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why should people in the stock market have to pay?

Are you familiar with a concept called the [Tragedy of the Commons](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons)? This may be a false analogy, since I don't know much about economics, but I think of the economy as a large fertile field where anybody is able to plant their crops. 

When a person harvests their crops, they strip some nutrients from the soil. The farmer can then either move to a different portion of the field, or fertilize the section of the field that they just used and use it again. It would be cheaper to just move to a different section, but if everybody did this, you would end up with a lifeless field where nothing can grow. When people work towards their individual benefit, they can unintentionally end up ruining the environment that benefits them to their own detriment, as well as the detriment of everyone else. If you demand that the farmer give up a percentage of their yield to fertilize the soil, it ensures that the field continues to be able to produce for everyone who comes afterwards.

By taxing the stock market in order to fund education, you're basically fertilizing the soil of the economy, which is the workers. They're basically reinvesting in the ecosystem that allowed them to yield their profits in the first place. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817691535.0" user="jasonthe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why should people in the stock market have to pay?

Taxation and government spending is a bit weird, here's [John Oliver's take on it.](https://youtu.be/9PK-netuhHA?t=725) Essentially, you *will* be paying for it partially. However, they'll be paying for more of it, because their contribution to the pool of government money is larger. Looking at it as "stock transaction taxes will pay for this" is too simplistic; you really should look at it as "stock transaction taxes will give the government more money, and the government should use extra money for free education."

&amp;gt; I mean come on, does it really cost $20,00 a year to house me?

Well, the cost of colleges is another issue entirely. Community colleges are still very reasonably priced, and making them completely free probably wouldn't be a large burden to the taxpayers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817904000.0" user="Gymnocalycium" delta="False">
    <text>If colleges know that any tuition increase will be paid for by the government in full, spending will increase dramatically. It makes much more sense to simply provide a fixed stipend which can be used for educational purposes rather than a blank check.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817814419.0" user="Pleb-Tier_Basic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why should people in the stock market have to pay?

Because they benefit from an educated workforce. Most modern businesses, especially those that are highly technical (i.e. Apple) need an educated workforce to function. Those trading stocks are trading shares of said businesses, and as such, they are benefiting directly from having access to an educated workforce. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818377969.0" user="cavemancolton" delta="False">
    <text>Are you aware that several European countries successfully use similar systems in order to provide free college education?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818574055.0" user="Moimoi328" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am all for people paying their fair share and I know a lot of people with money don't.

This is a huge misconception.  The wealthy pay a disproportionate amount of the total income taxes in this country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27821217970.0" user="unkorrupted" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The wealthy pay a disproportionate amount of the total income taxes in this country.

This is the misconception. Income taxes are not even half of the taxes that the government collects, so it is INCREDIBLY misleading to focus on the one progressive tax category among many regressive ones.

With all things considered:

&amp;gt;The top 400 taxpayers in the U.S. paid an average tax rate of 18 percent in 2010 

http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-11-21/top-400-u-s-households-paid-average-of-18-tax-rate-in-2010</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27822564459.0" user="Moimoi328" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The top 400 taxpayers in the U.S. paid an average tax rate of 18 percent in 2010 

I'm actually on the same page as you on this one.  The effective tax burden for everybody should be 18% maximum, and tax rates should be lowered across the board to achieve this outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27823139675.0" user="unkorrupted" delta="False">
    <text>Adam Smith was a commie, huh? 

&amp;gt;"The necessaries of life occasion the great expense of the poor. They find it difficult to get food, and the greater part of their little revenue is spent in getting it. The luxuries and vanities of life occasion the principal expense of the rich, and a magnificent house embellishes and sets off to the best advantage all the other luxuries and vanities which they possess. A tax upon house-rents, therefore, would in general fall heaviest upon the rich; and in this sort of inequality there would not, perhaps, be anything very unreasonable. It is not very unreasonable that the rich should contribute to the public expense, not only in proportion to their revenue, but something more than in that proportion"

Here's a hint: your Randian philosophies have *nothing* to do with American markets or America's economic rise. The Objectivist fantasy is an ancient relic - a dream of royalty long deposed. (And a waking nightmare for the 99.99% of us who work for a living, using our skills, talent, and sweat to make the world a better place)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27823316814.0" user="Moimoi328" delta="False">
    <text>I thought you wanted to improve the lot of the common man.  How does putting more money in their pockets not help achieve that goal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27823554915.0" user="unkorrupted" delta="False">
    <text>Best way to achieve it would be a moderately progressive tax system in a mostly-market-based economy that rewarded success without excessively punishing failure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819353655.0" user="Almostunbelievable" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, because progress should be avoided because you're selfish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817492749.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?

&amp;gt;In a way. Sanders proposes adding a small tax to transactions on the stock market, which are currently untaxed.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; I don't have the money for that. Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.

&amp;gt;Under this plan, the only people who would actually be paying for the tuition is those who use the stock market. The majority of people who use the stock market can afford it.

I think you're underplaying the significance of the tax hike here.  A financial transactions tax has significant consequences for the broader economy, and is decidedly a tax increase.

First, many more people own stocks and bonds than you make out.  401(k)s, IRAs, and pension funds all own securities as a matter of course.  A financial transactions tax would impact ordinary Americans' retirement savings substantially.

Second, most loans end up marketed as bond securities.  A tax on those securities will make them less desirable, and correspondingly increase borrowing costs.  So expect to see mortgage rates and car loan rates spike a good bit.

Third, this will create huge distortive effects, as markets become much thinner and arbitrage becomes less possible.  Especially when you're trying to raise a lot of money with the tax, you're going to push markets in all sorts of unpredictable ways as people try to dodge the tax.  At the most basic level, expect most of the stock market to move to foreign exchanges, but also massive corporate restructuring, an explosion of unlisted private securities, and all sorts of other things.  All of the above will make markets much harder to regulate and observe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817543407.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>This is a lot stronger of a point than I made.  So what is the solution here?  How can we have our cake and eat it too?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817565908.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How can we have our cake and eat it too?

The short version: we can't.  There's no such thing as a free lunch.

The longer version is that there are ways to help out people regarding college, but that it all involves tradeoffs.  A lot of what college is about is signaling that you're above average in intelligence/diligence. As college becomes more common, people move on to different, less common signals, such as grad school, unpaid internships at prestige firms, etc.

One big driver behind soaring college costs though is that student loans are so widely available that colleges can charge more and know their customers/students can afford it.  Making loans bankruptable would help with that, but would also likely lock out many poorer students.

I don't think there's an easy or obvious answer here.  [This piece](http://slatestarcodex.com/2015/06/06/against-tulip-subsidies/) gives a nice summary of some of the issues, even if the proposed solution at the end is more of a cheeky troll than a genuinely implementable policy proposal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817579628.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain exactly what making a loan bankruptable means and why it would lock out poorer students?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817594331.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, when you owe people a lot  more money than you have, you declare bankruptcy and the court will reduce or wipe out your debts (there are of course a ton of details about when and how this can happen).

Student loans are in general not dischargeable in bankruptcy, which means that if you go to bankruptcy court, the court won't wipe them out.  They used to be able to be wiped out, but over the past few decades, the law was changed gradually - first there was a waiting period, now there's only an exception if you can show you'd never be able to pay them back.

If you made it so student loans could be dumped in bankruptcy, you'd see a lot fewer student loans, since lenders would face a much higher risk that they wouldn't get paid back.  Essentially, unless your parents were very wealthy or had assets (like a house) to put up against the loan, it's unlikely you'd be able to get any private student loans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817604538.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>Oh!  That makes a lot of sense thank you for explaining that.  Yes, I see how that would most definitely be a bad thing the poor.  Or even most people in general.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817612361.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>At the same time, the inability of people to discharge crippling debts is also bad for the poor.  Bankruptcy exists for very good reasons; we don't want people saddled by debt forever.  The bankruptcy code is one of the things that has made America relatively innovative and dynamic in its economy - without it, people wouldn't be as willing to take the risks involved in starting a business or buying a house.

This stuff is complicated.  Like I said before, there aren't easy or obvious answers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817626106.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>And that is why I am having a hard time deciding either way if it is a good or bad thing.  On the one hand it seems great, but who knows all of the consequences it could have.  I don't know enough about finances and the economy to begin to know everything that could happen.  I just think that a lot of people are looking at it for its face value as yay free school, better country.  But there has to be a lot more to it than that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818032680.0" user="debatingaccount" delta="False">
    <text>Well yes, but all you are doing is considering trade-offs. It depends on what you are willing to trade off, you can gain free college, but maybe it means a reduced defense budget, higher taxes on capital gains, more taxes on other people, there's no silver bullet, but it seems to me and many others that free college is worth that trade off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818351822.0" user="_Woodrow_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you made it so student loans could be dumped in bankruptcy, you'd see a lot fewer student loans, since lenders would face a much higher risk that they wouldn't get paid back

The only loans that are not dischargeable through bankruptcy are Federal Student loans (Stafford). The only loan provider for these loans is the US Government. There is no credit check for these loans at all. 

While your reasoning is sound, it doesn't hold up to the reality of the situation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818356829.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>IIRC, the 2005 bankruptcy law made private loans nondischargeable, but I'm on a phone and can't check now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818090859.0" user="Gorsum" delta="False">
    <text>Here is a thought.  What if we made student loans bankruptable and backed by the school you are attending.  In addition make them non-transferable so that the university can't sell the risk to some other party.  If the university is doing a good job of educating then they will make the profits from the loans thus reducing the amount they need from tuition.  If the university has too many bankrupted loans then they would get bailed out by the taxpayers just like the big banks.  If the bail out was because of the economy great I would rather bail out education then banks.  If the bail out is because of poor performance of the university then it can be restructured.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818134751.0" user="szczypka" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize the proposed financial transaction tax is aimed at high frequency trading rather than normal traders? From what I remember, it's a minuscule percentage of the share value.

Sure it might 'distort' the market, but unless those pension funds are HFTs then I doubt it will affect them too negatively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818289065.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Who a tax is nominally aimed at, and who ends up actually paying it are separate questions. You may be aiming at HFT, but I think it's quite likely you'll miss. You're talking about sophisticated traders who will figure out any loophole or exception that you intend to help ordinary people and use it for their own advantage. 

I don't know the exact details of Sanders' proposal though, and I'm on a phone at the moment. How many basis points per transaction is he proposing be taxed? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818447696.0" user="szczypka" delta="False">
    <text>~~Something like 0.01% most likely.~~

&amp;gt; 0.25 percent on a stock purchase or sale and 0.02 percent on the sale or purchase of a future, option, or credit default swap. These rates are proportional to the actual transaction costs in the industry.

That's the proposal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818207001.0" user="ATX_native" delta="False">
    <text>It's on derivative trading... This is not mom and pop on Etrade transactions.  These are multi million dollar transactions banks and organizations do on a daily basis to hedge risk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818281760.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>If there's any type of marketable security or any dollar threshold that is exempt from the tax, that will end up being a loophole that you can drive a truck through. What's to stop me selling shares in a company whose only purpose is to hold a specific type of derivatives I market, for instance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818382523.0" user="TexasAntonym" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, It's a tax increase but aren't we gonna have to increase taxes on the wealthy at some point to right this ship? I mean as far as wealth goes we are top heavy as fuck. At the very least this sort of tax would cut back on high frequency trading, which is a bloated leach on the back our economy. 

And yeah, it might cause some discomfort amongst a larger group of people than is intended but that's different that now, how? We're gonna experience some growing pains at some point. Decisions at the national level are almost always trade offs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817769226.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Under this plan, the only people who would actually be paying for the tuition is those who use the stock market. The majority of people who use the stock market can afford it.

Not so much.  Given that pensions are a thing of the past, where do you think people's retirement money is?

By adding an external, artificial cost to stock market transactions, you're inhibiting one of the primary benefits of the stock market, that of stabilization.  Because every transaction adds a *guaranteed* loss, in addition to the speculative loss, you're not going to want to sell, nor buy, until the benefit of buying (expected gain) or the loss of not selling (expected loss) is greater.

If the cost is per share, the concern about selling is going to be greater the more shares you have.  On the other hand, if the penalty is *transaction* based, you're going to get someone dumping large numbers of shares in one go.  Both of these trend towards *increased* volatility in the market.

You like boom and bust markets, with the average person losing half their retirement savings over the course of a few months, like we saw in 2008/2009?  Then by all means, add artificial costs to stock market transactions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817950245.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In a way. Sanders proposes adding a small tax to transactions on the stock market, which are currently untaxed.

That's not "in a way" it's a new tax plain and simple. 

&amp;gt; The majority of people who use the stock market can afford it.

Not exactly.  A working class person with their 401k invested in a mutual fund uses the stock market.  The tax is on pretty much any stock transaction. The mutual fund buys and sells stocks all the time and the added cost of running the fund will be passed on to the customer.   The idea that this tax will only affect the rich is utter and complete nonsense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818025652.0" user="N64Overclocked" delta="False">
    <text>OP also didn't take into consideration that the free tuition bill allows people who currently have student loan debt to refinance their loans to a fixed low rate. That means OP wouldn't pay as much as he or she is currently paying for their student loans. 

OP saves money, future generations get a free education, and the only people who pay more are the people making hundreds of transactions on the stock market (who can probably afford it).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818194557.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>Really, practically none of the extra tuition is going towards teachers.  Most of it is going towards building new facilities and a growing administrative process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818248003.0" user="thrasumachos" delta="False">
    <text>If anything, that's worse than an income tax increase. An income tax increase would have a greater impact on the rich, who can afford it. A tax on stock transactions, however, if it's per transaction, rather than based on income, would have a greater impact on middle class families who depend on their investments for retirement income and other important purchases (like buying a house), while having a much lesser impact on billionaires who can afford to pay it. It would discourage investment, which in turn means fewer entrepreneurs without a family fortune would save up to open businesses, fewer people would buy houses, and people would retire later, increasing unemployment because there would be less room for younger workers in the market.

Additionally, this presents an issue, since it's effectively punishing people for making good financial decisions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818459475.0" user="GameboyPATH" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Part of the reason colleges are so expensive now also has in part to do with how colleges spend their money. In order to attract students who pay tuition, they have to keep building better and better facilities as students get pickier. To get good staff and teachers, they have to pay more and more wages to not only keep up with the standard of living but the expectations of their teachers. Consider that for the best teachers, they're going to choose the college that will pay them the most, and you can see how wages can start to spiral out of control. 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Not to mention there's a lot of money getting spent on sports and coaches, but I won't even start going into that, or else I'll go on a tangent that is only remotely related to the topic. 

I'm really curious about this point. With students able to get into college for free, how much control would colleges have over how much of that transaction tax they're getting? Couldn't they continue to use this money to overfund sports programs and needlessly upgrading facilities to a shiny quality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818481503.0" user="AW12321" delta="False">
    <text>Colleges will still be capable of making money to offset costs of upgrading and funding unnecessary additions. 

Colleges make money from those sports programs. They can make money from the restaurants and other stores that set up shop on campus. They will still receive research grants. 

Assuming that appropriate stipulations were placed on the money received through the tax, and how much public universities could charge for tuition, then colleges would have to use these other sources of revenue for building.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
