<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817744158.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance

By this logic, the government should never be able to do anything, since whenever they implement something, there is a previous generation who didn't receive the benefit, but will have to pay future taxes.

It's like saying the government shouldn't force you to pay taxes to improve the local high school, because you already graduated, and it was crumbling when you went there.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818064385.0" user="peachesgp" delta="False">
    <text>I'd see that differently, and I don't think your analogy is apt. I'm already paying for the school I went to, unless that's going to be forgiven, I'm not very interested in paying more taxes for others to get that free benefit. That's selfish of me, but I'm ok with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818070098.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>If you had medical debt, would you oppose medical reform for everyone else?  It's basically the same idea.

It's like saying "I got screwed, so the only fair solution is for everyone else to get screwed also"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818106574.0" user="peachesgp" delta="False">
    <text>If I'm paying medical debt then no, I don't want to pay more taxes and be screwed financially for the sake of others. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818757718.0" user="Brettster" delta="False">
    <text>then 
&amp;gt; It's like saying "I got screwed, so the only fair solution is for everyone else to get screwed also"

it's also like saying "the government needs to stop everything it's doing and see to MY PERSONAL NEEDS before it can help anyone else."
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819307325.0" user="peachesgp" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what I'm saying. I'm saying I haven't an interest in being fucked over financially and condemning myself to continuing to live in the ghetto for the rest of my life. Sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818442004.0" user="cno3117" delta="False">
    <text>But that's not what the tax would be. It'd only tax a small small amount on wall street transactions. Most of the corporations that push the most money through wall street pay very little, if any income tax as it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818527384.0" user="dontrain1111" delta="False">
    <text>You shouldn't be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818754530.0" user="Brettster" delta="False">
    <text>Being selfish about a PUBLIC policy is just not a valid argument. It's basically like saying "I'm wrong, but here's my opinion..."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818079750.0" user="Gold4Cash" delta="False">
    <text>Thus isn't really a response to what his argument is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818127113.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>As an ancap, what's the issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819831826.0" user="Khaur" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair your extension of that logic doesn't apply to all policies, only policies in favour of the young.

If a majority of the constituent base still has the prospect of benefiting from a policy, according to that logic it makes sense for a populist government to implement it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
