<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818568911.0" user="shouburu" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry but my stance is honestly against your mentality. It makes me passionately rage. You don't want to contribute to a service because you don't get to enjoy the benefits. I have to say its such a self defeating mentality. Great things are done from people working together for a common goal, not by putting themselves first. You help pay for the roads,  for regular education, museums, healthcare for all. 

How do you think America would be if people didn't have to pay taxes? It would be a total crap hole.  Millionaires and richer would take every penny from you through abusive manipulation.  The government we all help pay for prevents these abuses, providing a common good for all the people. Even if you don't think you personally will benefit(you could get more education) wouldn't you still want this for your children? 

Like let's gets rid of the minimum wage too because those simple jobs don't require any education, which you already have. Let's cut healthcare and let homeless die, let's stop funding public scientific research and let's millions die from diseases that might be preventable, but only for the diseases that affect areas not around you. 

I'm a ranting jerk but you are very shortsighted sir. Grrrrrrrr. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
