<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818225491.0" user="FoxRaptix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct? Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does? Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free? That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that. Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.

This is assuming you still have to pay it off.  If they start making University free, odds are they will develop programs for people still stuck with student debt.  Either forgiveness or an extremely generous plan.

Your logic is also to put it bluntly a tad selfish.  "If i had to pay loans and have my life crippled by debt then everyone should have to!"

Don't needlessly punish future generations just because you're upset for how you've had it.  A healthy successful society will make sure each generation does better or has it better than there's in some way

Unless you're trying to say the massive debt you took on was a good thing, it's hardly fair to tell future generations that the only reason why you believe they should take on the same debt is essentially out of spite because your parents did it to you.

Next you have to stop looking at education as a purchased commodity.  It's not supposed to be this way.  It's an economic investment by the state (or at least that's how it should be and the most beneficial way to approach it to everyone)
There will probably be a slight bump in taxes to pay for the initial investment (it's arguable if the average American would actually  feel it)but the ideal is that it will pay for its self with a profit through economic growth and social mobility.


&amp;gt;And what happens with private institutions? Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?

Probably not for free, but even still, students that go to private school can already qualify for financial aid, just like at public universities.

And you have it backwards.  Its not unfair that they would get to go to school for cheap/free.  It's actually unfair that you had to go to school and pay so much.  College used to be extremely cheap to free.  Your resentment if you must hang on to it, is misplaced.  You shouldn't be upset that future generations might be able to go to school for free and you had to pay, you should be upset that your parents got to go to school for near free and then made you pay exorbitant prices.


&amp;gt; And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.

That's what a community is, you're perpetually contributing to other people and they are perpetually contributing to you.  You might have to pay a bit extra now to help them with cheap school and the economic growth generated from that generation not being dragged down by debt will be perpetually contributed back to you.

And honestly that's actually what education is supposed to be.  You go through school, do good, contribute to the economy and help pay for future generations to have the same/better opportunities as you.  That's still the model of k-12 schools when you look at it closely.

Honestly we're going to have to temporarily shoulder a heavier burden just because we had to pay so much for our education.  But we can either be as self centered and short sighted as our parents generation.   We can either be stubborn and perpetuate with same viscous cycle they started or we can be a bit selfless and hope our investment pays off by the time our generation is ready to retire that we've helped contribute to a society that is strong and stable enough that we can retire.

Ideally it will probably be like the old college system.  Community College was free, you just had to pay some various fee's that added up to nothing, and there was a slight cost for university but again the cost would then be completely negligible to the point of being a non-issue for anyone who wants to and can attend</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
