<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818437239.0" user="bradfordmaster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance

So situations can never improve? Because you had it bad, people of the future have to have it bad too? The government should never be able to give anyone something they didn't offer to you?

I think the whole *idea* that people can't go to schools, or go to expensive schools (like you couldn't) is the problem, and that is what this is trying to solve.

Ultimately, taxes should pay for things that improve the country as a whole, and I think you'll get a really good value for your tax dollar by spending it to increase the level of education in the country. Other posters have explained tons of benefits of education for society, so I won't rehash their points.

In today's world, almost all respectable jobs require a college degree, which requires tons of people to accumulate tons of debt. Are you really happy with the status quo, where we pay millions (probably billions) of dollars in interest payments for student loans?

Expensive education, is IMHO, the #1 thing that continues to increase the wealth gap. Poor people often live in bad school districts, so they get a bad education, then even if they could get into college, they can't afford it, so they can't get better jobs, and they develop a hopeless attitude towards education in general. We already have some grants and scholarships to help with this, but I think it should increase.

Last point: lots of other countries are doing this, and the US is loosing its ranks in terms of education and quality, so if we want to remain a world intellectual superpower, we need to be investing in education.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
