<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818444161.0" user="Renegade_Meister" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?

To put it simply, it doesn't have to all come from taxes.

According to [this article](http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/01/heres-exactly-how-much-the-government-would-have-to-spend-to-make-public-college-tuition-free/282803/), $62.6 billion dollars was spent on tuition at public colleges in one year, which is less than the $69 billion spent on non-loan financial aid programs in one year: Pell Grants, tax breaks, and work study funding.

This provides an empirical possibility that **the US federal government could spend less money on making public college tuition free than providing non-loan financial aid**.

&amp;gt;Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?

If all non-loan financial aid programs were instead applied to public university tuition, then this situation would not occur.

&amp;gt;And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.

The growth rate of Federal Financial Aid already exceed public tuition increases, and you are already paying for federal loan subsidies and indirectly paying for the increasingly tougher debt that students have.  Less loans will need to be taken out if public tuition is free, and thus having to "pay for other people" will be decreased.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
