<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817398224.0" user="Phaeson" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to have not done your research. 

&amp;gt; But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct? 

The tax would be on Wall Street speculation, so unless you'll be making most of your money off the stock market, you won't be directly affected. 

&amp;gt; And what happens with private institutions?

Sanders has stated that it will cover only public colleges and universities. 

I don't have links for these facts since I'm on mobile, but I can provide them for you if you insist. There's also a recent interview with Katie Couric you can watch where he outlines his policy positions. 

Does this address your concerns? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817626020.0" user="nocommemt" delta="False">
    <text>You are way off with your expectation that the mega rich Wall Street kings will be paying for most of this. The most common retirement accounts rely on holding stocks and bonds and trading them regularly. (see IRA,  401K) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817857890.0" user="turkeyIBrox" delta="False">
    <text>You're right that many people rely on trading stocks for retirement funds and things like trusts/inheritance, so 'regular' people (non-Wall Street Wolves) will be definitely be affected by the tax. But the tax rate Sanders proposes is 0.5 percent on stock trades, which is just 50 cents for $100 in traded stock [Source: http://www.sanders.senate.gov/download/051915-highered/?inline=file (thanks to HCPwny for that link)]. That means if someone is trading/selling off $10,000 in stock from their retirement fund, they'll only have to pay $50 in taxes on it. Though that's not nothing, it's not a whole lot—an amount that I would be willing to pay, given the benefits reduced cost of education for young people could have for the whole country's prosperity.

But I suppose that's where the issue lies: Is making life easier for the new generation worth a personal monetary sacrifice for us later in life? To me it would be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
