<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817413334.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>Of course nothing comes free. You are right in that sense. "Free" college would indeed ultimately come from taxes. The specific implementation isn't exactly clear. In any case, in economics there is an idea of positive externalities that make free college beneficial to society as a whole. Here are a few bullet points for you to chew over:

* People, regardless of their wealth, would have equal opportunity to accomplish their goals. Those in poverty would not be limited simply because of their inability to afford college. So in the future, your kids will be able to go to a $60,000 school if they qualified in merit.

* In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs. Ultimately, these people would be paying back into the system through their own taxes. The returns on this investment is high since it would only take a few breakthroughs in technology to create many other jobs. Consider how the university system created Gopher, a predecessor to the modern day internet browser. In addition, educated people have greater potential to make more income when they graduate. This makes taxes towards education fundamentally different from something like welfare, where there are no direct returns. You actually benefit from it.

* An educated population will be more knowledgeable and active in society, steering the nation in a good path for the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817464730.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder, how much of a difference would it really make?  Poorer areas tend to have problems starting with high school graduation rates.  If those kids don't even want to graduate high school, what makes us think they will go to college?  So, would the money be better spent at lower levels of education?  Then as they get older more and more would be able to qualify for scholarships and the like.  I know a lot of people who went to state schools for almost free by doing this.  We just have to get kids at a young age to want to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817470345.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>How can you get kids to care about college at a young age if they don't feel they'll be able to afford it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817476460.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>Now I don't know for certain, but I feel like that is not the main reason they don't go to school.  When I took sociology we had to read this book about poor, urban areas.  A lot of times it boiled down to, why should I have to work so hard and at things I don't even care about to end up making like 50k, when I could just do something else like sell drugs and life is a lot easier? 

Obviously that is not the case for everyone.  We just have to get them to care when they are younger and educate them on the fact that it IS affordable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817562939.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I also don't think it is the main reason, I'm just saying that affordable college is one part of the problem.

There are a myriad of issues at play, and there won't be one single fix.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817682750.0" user="jace100" delta="False">
    <text>Growing up in a poor area, there are so many factors to take in to account.  From personal experience I can tell you, I dropped out of high school senior year so I could pick up a 2nd job to help my family pay bills.  If you know early on you won't be going to college because of financial restrictions you just put college out of your mind.  

I did get my GED when I turned 18 and I was finally able to go to college at 28 but it was quite a struggle.    
 
I don't know the stats but, anecdotally, I think very few people in poverty are selling drugs.  I'm sure a lot of them are doing morally ambiguous things, I know my parents intentionally misreported stuff about my sister so we could keep the WIC checks coming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817693292.0" user="drewsy888" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A lot of times it boiled down to, why should I have to work so hard and at things I don't even care about to end up making like 50k, when I could just do something else like sell drugs and life is a lot easier?

Well free college isn't only aimed at kids in gangs selling drugs. College is very expensive and a lot of kids from poorer families either don't go into college to avoid the debt or go into a lot of debt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817795040.0" user="Pink_Mint" delta="False">
    <text>Having grown up poor, you'd be amazed to know that most poor people wish they even had the opportunity to sell drugs. Unless you have incredibly tight connections (few people do), it costs a good amount of money out of pocket to start dealing.  

Most of the dealers I knew were from wealthy families. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818145565.0" user="scribens" delta="False">
    <text>There's plenty of studies on this.

http://www.nber.org/papers/w6592

Basically, anyone below the gang leader most likely is making less than minimum wage. Even for some of the "lieutenants" in gangs making $11 an hour as a street dealer, that is horrendous when you factor in risks and no tangible benefits whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818164351.0" user="Pink_Mint" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I'm aware of that. If you're in a gang, you stay poor and it isn't easy money. So it's only people who can be independent dealers (people who weren't poor to begin with) who get easy cash.   

I'm not sure why people think of barely getting by while risking your life in a gang to be "easy money," but I guess it's easier to pretend poor people have all these imaginary opportunities they supposedly throw away. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817806718.0" user="Adjal" delta="False">
    <text>It's the main reason I didn't care in high school. I never even took the SAT even though my IQ is in the 140's and I rock standardized tests. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817936321.0" user="Treypyro" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be arguing your own point. For the poor, urban areas it would be much easier to convince those kids to go to college if it were free or more affordable. But if it's not, why would they work really hard at a shitty job they don't like to be able to afford college, then be in debt by the time they are out of college, when they can just sell drugs and not have to work nearly as hard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818109573.0" user="bingostud722" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not from a poor area, but I have been trying to start a small business for quite a while now, but my problem is I have literally ZERO capital because all my spare cash at this point goes to my student loans. I have a decent job but I'd love to be able to take some risk with that money instead of shoveling it in to my college loans.

I have to believe there are a lot of people like that - I can't take many risks because I both need my job to keep making my student loan bills (as well as just life), and I don't have much spare income at all to save up and invest in my own business. It's very frustrating, at this point the way I look at it is the only way I could have avoided it was to not go to college and take an even bigger risk (i.e. forego secondary education to attempt to start a business)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818402670.0" user="BlueApple4" delta="False">
    <text>To add to this. How many of us are not getting married, buying homes, or starting families because we are too busy paying off our student loans. Or even save for retirement. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818760325.0" user="bingostud722" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, I decided to buy a home, but I just got a divorce and can barely get by on my own with the combo of house and student loan payments (was much easier with 2 incomes). so basically if you decide to do something like buy a house, one big money issue and you're up shit creek (and currently I have no paddle)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818740220.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>Highschool dropout here: in my case, that absolutely is the reason I did not go to school. I needed to work instead. (I am not everyone, but just offering an alternative view for you.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817888368.0" user="sir_pirriplin" delta="False">
    <text>Serious question: Why would you want them to care?

If people (employers, especially) cared *less* about college, the problem goes away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817995299.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I think a better educated populous is good for society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818021161.0" user="sir_pirriplin" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good point, but I meant to ask why specifically care *about college*. 

There should be other ways to get an education, but because people can always "afford" college (not really, but the availability of student loans makes it *look* affordable) people fixate on that, and decide they have to go to college *at all costs*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818056956.0" user="GTFErinyes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think a better educated populous is good for society.

The flaw with that, IMO, is that an educated population does not need college to be educated.

Social skills can be learned beyond college, for which many places have become high school 2.0.

Trade skills are also an education, and college does not provide that.

I'm for higher education, but I also don't believe that everyone is a good fit for college and vice versa and alternatives should be encouraged as well</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818084382.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not against alternatives and I'm certainly not going to force everyone to go to college. But I see nothing wrong with encouraging college-level educations in addition to making them free (or at least *actually* affordable).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818281156.0" user="TripleEEE1682" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Benincognito said "better educated" and not "college educated"... just sayin'.

I agree with your post in every other respect.  There should be more money invested in vocational programs in high schools.  I saw a fantastic high school in Boston (I think Newton?) which really had great vocational programs, and the students were really engaged and turned on.

Not all students thrive in a traditional academic environment.  There are all kinds of ways of learning which can enhance our society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818347037.0" user="iKnitSweatas" delta="False">
    <text>If they want to improve themselves. People so easily forgive poor people's actions and excuse them because "what else would they do, they're poor" </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817476805.0" user="AW12321" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Poorer areas tend to have problems starting with high school graduation rates. If those kids don't even want to graduate high school, what makes us think they will go to college?

Don't know how much it'll help, but I live in a poorer area. While we don't have nearly as low high school graduation rates as some areas of the country, I knew several students who dropped out. Most of them dropped out to start working, because they knew they would never be able to get a college education. College is soon as a requirement for a good job, and for most of those I saw who dropped out, high school was only a stepping stone for college. They thought it would be a better use of their time to enter the workforce and start earning money and trying to work their way up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817487201.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>On those in poverty:

Well, you should also consider the people who are graduating from college in debt right now. They are poor in the sense that their families could not pay off their tuition and other fees. Because of this debt, they have to make "safer" choices early in life. If they did not have debt, they could open their own businesses which would help the economy more than if they just got an office job.

In lower levels of education, I think the teachers and other students make a larger difference to a child than funding. After a certain point, there are diminishing returns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817528609.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>I am one of those people with a mountain of debt after college.  I have friends that have it as well.  They had to make "safe choices" like renting a smaller apartment or taking a job back home because it was easier to get one there.  Is that necessarily a bad thing?  Besides the fact that also, just because you have a college degree does not mean that your life is going to be instantly better.  There are thousands of people out there who have a degree and yet can't get a job for beans.  A friend of mine who went to be a teacher is now working at a golf course because he was competing with 500 other applicants for one position (that is not an exaggeration either).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817574600.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>* Nothing is wrong with making a safe choice. But you must agree that it is bad if your life limited due to debt. A person without debt has more freedom to pursue what they want to do without compromising.

* A college degree does not necessarily mean your life will be better. Obviously some degrees are more immediately useful than others. Some markets may be more saturated than others. Depending on the person, college may not be the right path. However, looking at some statistics, it becomes clear that there is some correlation between going to college and your salary. The average person benefits from going to college economically, if not intellectually.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Household_income_in_the_United_States </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817581837.0" user="Zeigzalar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Is that necessarily a bad thing? 

When it's not much of a choice; yea, a bit.  Free college increases opportunity and recourse so that people won't have to deal with a mountain of debt leaving college, among other things.  The idea is that having a college degree should make your life better - how much better is debatable, but with all the problems graduates are having these days I'm pretty sure most can agree that it should be better than it is now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817609999.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>I agree debt is ridiculous.  I am having a hard time paying it off and I am from a pretty well off middle class family and have a decent enough job.  But I also think that is my fault a bit.  I mean, maybe I should have stayed at the $20,000 state school with scholarships rather then transferred to the $40,000 private school.  But I accept that as my own mistake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817695793.0" user="CeIidos" delta="False">
    <text>But why does going to a good college have to be a mistake when it benefits you and society as a whole in the log run? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817799439.0" user="Pink_Mint" delta="False">
    <text>Expensive private schools aren't usually super amazing, and state schools can be really good. The University of Texas is a better University than basically every private school in Texas except Rice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817810393.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, unless you're talking about the elite, nationally known (and not just for sports) private universities, all a private university education gets you is the chance to be around fewer working-class people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817812739.0" user="Pink_Mint" delta="False">
    <text>It's a decent gamble if you're trying to marry rich, I guess. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817942706.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; all a private university education gets you is the chance to be around fewer working-class people.

Actually it can be argued that the value to the student is in the contacts they make. Going to a school with the kids of diplomats and rich CEOs and getting decent but not spectacular grades  opens more doors for you than getting a 4.0 at even a good state school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818029967.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>The kind of schools I'm thinking about here aren't where the kids of diplomats and rich CEOs go (Ivies, Stanford, NYU, USC, etc.).  They're the colleges full of kids whose grades aren't good enough to get into a better school, and whose parents have enough money to send them there but not enough clout to get them into somewhere better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817938559.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>Define "good college". Was the quality of the education that they got at the $40k college twice as good as at the $20k school?  Does it benefit society twice as much? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818261690.0" user="TripleEEE1682" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But I accept that as my own mistake

I'm feeling the same way, as I accrue phenomenal debt trying to complete my doctoral program.  I've come to think that I behaved irresponsibly when I decided to pursue the degree.

And the fact that I feel that way (and you do through your proposal that going to the more expensive private school was a mistake), really says a lot about how we view education these days.

There was a time when we were encouraged to rise up through education - when the desire to pursue learning was smiled upon by our society.  Now we consider it financially irresponsible.

I appreciate Sanders trying to reframe it, and to bring us back to a place where we once again see education as a good thing - something that contributes to an enlightened and well-functioning society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819032278.0" user="flimspringfield" delta="False">
    <text>Have you looked at the debt repayment programs such as income sensitive or if possible working for the federal/state government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817886051.0" user="sir_pirriplin" delta="False">
    <text>How about campaigning for the right to being taken seriously *without a college degree*?

College in the US is so overpriced that it leaves some college graduates worse off than before college. Yet they feel they *must* go to college for whatever reason. Fix that, and people won't need to go into so much debt *and* the government won't have to take such a huge cost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817933355.0" user="Zeigzalar" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, so you've brought up an alternative.  Tell people to forgo obtaining a college degree.  How do you suppose we begin?

There's a [tremendous disparity](http://www.brookings.edu/~/media/Research/Files/Papers/2013/05/07-should-everyone-go-to-college-owen-sawhill/07-should-everyone-go-to-college-owen-sawhill-figure-1.jpg?la=en) between the lifetime incomes of college grads and high school grads.  That's your 'for whatever reason', right there.  You're going to have a very hard time telling people to turn down having a statistically better chance of greater financial success in life.

&amp;gt;College in the US is so overpriced

100% correct.  The biggest problem is that tuition rising like crazy, people taking out more in loans than they can afford, which will create more problems in the long run.

&amp;gt;With tuitions rising faster than family incomes, the typical college student is now more dependent than in the past on loans, creating serious risks for the individual student and perhaps for the system as a whole, should widespread defaults occur in the future. [[Source]](http://www.brookings.edu/research/papers/2013/05/08-should-everyone-go-to-college-owen-sawhill)

I think lowering/eliminating college costs is a better idea than telling people not to go to college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817960842.0" user="sir_pirriplin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The biggest problem is that tuition rising like crazy, people taking out more in loans than they can afford...

The loans themselves are one of the reasons college is expensive. Until people start saying "I can't afford this shit, I'll use the money I was going to use to go to college and open a small business instead", colleges will have no reason to drop prices.

&amp;gt; I think lowering/eliminating college costs is a better idea than telling people not to go to college.

I agree with you, but at the same time believe that the only realistic way to lower the cost is to stop going to college. There is only a limited amount of supply for college education and if lots of people *absolutely need them at any cost* then the price is obviously going to increase.

One way to do this is to subsidize people who don't go to college. Maybe free vocational schools?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817978163.0" user="Zeigzalar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the only realistic way to lower the cost is to stop going to college.

That, or stopping those from [profiting off student loan debt](http://www.marketwatch.com/story/every-second-americans-get-buried-under-another-3055-in-student-loan-debt-2015-06-10).  Look at those numbers and tell me we can't educate the entire country with it haha.  And that money is *clearly* not going back into education right now, with all the cuts we've seen across the board.

Though that wouldn't last forever, so I do see the need to encourage people to take alternatives cheaper than attending college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818006816.0" user="sir_pirriplin" delta="False">
    <text>You could educate the whole country with that money... if you were willing to stop treating college like a sacred cow.

College is a very inefficient way of getting an education. It's bureaucratic, unaccountable (how stupid is it that you are being taught and graded by the same people?), encourages wasteful signaling games (people have to do weird shit to be admitted to the good schools, like doing useless extra-curriculars or 'donating' money to the poor poor people at fucking Yale) and it only costs you the best, most healthy, potentially most productive years of your entire life.

That money could be spent on better things. Like, on actual education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817937116.0" user="Elmattador" delta="False">
    <text>What about instead of "free college for all" there was a large increase in government scholarships - then at least people who work hard to get into college would be the ones taking advantage of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818264749.0" user="TripleEEE1682" delta="False">
    <text>That would work for me.  There used to be way more financial support for students, and those supports have been cut over the years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818072950.0" user="Sanfranci" delta="False">
    <text>In the case of those taking safer jobs back home rather than trying to get a job in areas where wages may be higher, that is a socially in-efficient choice. Wages are the price for labor, this means areas with higher wages need more labor than those with lower wages, after adjusted for cost of living differences. So for example New York has very high wages, it needs a lot of workers. If your friends decided to stay in a lower wage area rather than move to New York due to debt restricting their ability to take risks, than that would be nationally inefficient. If thousands of people make the decisions your friends made, than the economy loses out on billions f dollars of potential output. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818253934.0" user="TripleEEE1682" delta="False">
    <text>It's even harder to get a job without a college degree though.  Folks without are called "unskilled", and unskilled labor doesn't command much of an hourly rate.  Certainly there are very limited choices in terms of career.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818346265.0" user="dildope" delta="False">
    <text>FYI Bernie proposed lowering interest rates on student loans to 2% or something like that. It's not going to benefit everyone but it will help those still paying higher rates and if enacted it will help all future students obviously. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818050784.0" user="szczypka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If they did not have debt, they could open their own businesses which would help the economy more than if they just got an office job.

I'm not convinced that this is true - is a failed business still helpful for the economy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818090314.0" user="0100101010110" delta="False">
    <text>no, but if more people can afford to run businesses into the ground then more people can afford to start successful ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818452378.0" user="szczypka" delta="False">
    <text>That still doesn't make your original statement true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819157051.0" user="0100101010110" delta="False">
    <text>What original statement</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819165909.0" user="szczypka" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, the claim was that opening up your own business would help the economy more than getting a job [at a likely already successful business].

Not sure that claim can be made. And it wasn't made by you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819174707.0" user="0100101010110" delta="False">
    <text>No youre right, thats a rather dubious claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818601113.0" user="MadeSomewhereElse" delta="False">
    <text>The issue I have with free college is that like OP says the problems are in high school. Educational performance is related to socioeconomic status. What I am afraid of doing is paying for a kid's college education who's parents could afford to send him anyways. I know that is not a huge percentage since the majority take out loans, but it is still something to consider. Something this reminds me of is Brazilian universities. Federal universities (equivalent of state schools) are essentially free and entrance is very competitive. The people who get into those schools are the ones whose family can afford to pay for expensive, private high school since apparently the public high schools in a lot of Brazil are not so great. So what it comes down to is that the country funds wealthy kids' college education. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817688213.0" user="drewsy888" delta="False">
    <text>I came from a family who paid for my entire college. I cannot tell you how much that helped me. I knew that I just had to try hard and I would have a career at the end of it. A lot of my friends were just counting how many years it would take to pay off their debt. Several friends I knew dropped out of college because they realized they wouldn't be able to pay off their loans.

Free college would be a huge deal to a lot of people. Worrying about how much every class is costing you adds a lot of stress to an already stressful situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817762411.0" user="plexluthor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;how much of a difference would it really make?

Probably not as much as Sanders thinks.

http://slatestarcodex.com/2015/06/06/against-tulip-subsidies/

&amp;gt;I’m afraid that Sanders’ plan ... would subsidize the continuation of a useless tradition that has turned into a speculation bubble, prevent the bubble from ever popping, and disincentivize people from figuring out a way to route around the problem...

[snip]

&amp;gt;If I were Sanders, I’d propose a different strategy. Make “college degree” a protected characteristic, like race and religion and sexuality. If you’re not allowed to ask a job candidate whether they’re gay, you’re not allowed to ask them whether they’re a college graduate or not. You can give them all sorts of examinations, you can ask them their high school grades and SAT scores, you can ask their work history, but if you ask them if they have a degree then that’s illegal class-based discrimination and you’re going to jail. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817766138.0" user="endymion2300" delta="False">
    <text>former poor kid here. one of the biggest hurdles between me and higher education was the lack of examples growing up. 

when you live somewhere middle class (and by "middle class" i mean "not struggling too hard to survive"), you have a good number of older peers already going into college. its something that's commonly discussed, and not only do you get to see people going through that transition, the idea of massive debt isn't unfamiliar to you. 

in other words, the concept that college is a possibility is something you've been raised with. 

when/where i was a kid, we didn't have many peers who went to college. my parents both dropped out to raise me, none of my older cousins were planning to go, and hardly anyone i was friends with talked about it. we were all trying to find ways to make money. i had to get a paper route so my mom could spend more money on my little sisters. some of my other friends dropped out of high school to work and/or help out at home. 

some just turned to crime. shit happens. 

the idea that college was the next logical step wasn't familiar to me. i mean, i saw college kids on tv, but then i saw muppets and spaceships on tv too.

i wanted to go to college, but it felt like too big of a risk to me. i remember thinking that if my parents and older peers couldn't pull it off, what chance did i have? i was much better off just getting a job and trying to support myself. 

things might've been different had i some college graduate peers to inspire me. 

if college was free, more poor kids would be able to go. they wouldn't take advantage of it right away without some pushing from parents and teachers, but eventually some would go. and once the more cautious kids see their peers going, the concept of themselves being in college someday will be more familiar. 

eventually, hopefully, it'll snowball, and the next thing you know, there's a lot of young inner-city adults sporting degrees and raising the standard of living in their 'hoods. 

[don't get me wrong, i really wish something could/would be done to increase the quality of public schools in poorer neighborhoods, but i don't think that would be very effective without easily accessible colleges.] </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817850201.0" user="Mikeytruant850" delta="False">
    <text>Great post, this was my experience growing up as well. College wasn't even really an option, no one I knew was going or had gone and it just seemed like something that wasn't available to people from my social class. I didn't even know what a scholarship was until after I had already dropped out to work a 2nd job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817989430.0" user="driftwoodprose" delta="False">
    <text>If you wish, you can look up some data on the Kalamazoo Promise. Started in 2004, it provides 100% college tuition for graduates of Kalamazoo Public Schools. Roughly 38.8% of the population ranked below the poverty line, good for 5th worst in the nation (outdated, but [source](http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2011/09/27/us/cities-with-the-highest-poverty-rates-in-2010.html?ref=us&amp;amp;_r=0)).

High School Graduation Rates appear to be up vs other cities in the state (69% v Grand Rapids 45% in 2012, [Source](http://www.mlive.com/news/kalamazoo/index.ssf/2013/03/kalamazoo_promise_analysis_1.html)). That number is still bad, however in comparison to other metro areas in Michigan, it's an improvement.

It seems about 90% of graduates from Kalamazoo attend some kind of higher education now ([Source](http://www.mlive.com/news/kalamazoo/index.ssf/2011/11/the_kalamazoo_promise_scholars.html)), the state average is around 71%. There is still a high dropout rate in college (about 50%), but at least they're getting there and a focus on college readiness is the next phase.

Definitely not the fix-all solution, by far, but a decent experiment showing the direction free eduction in the states could have. At the very least, it seems the opportunity for something more can be a motivating factor for some of those from impoverished communities, whereas knowing there are few options after high school seems to lead to the current cycle of poverty.

Additional Reading:

[Education Next](http://educationnext.org/the-kalamazoo-promise-scholarship/)

[WMU Evaluation](http://www.wmich.edu/leadership/kpromise)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818047433.0" user="someawesomeusername" delta="False">
    <text>This is just speculation, but maybe some people don't try in high school because they know they can't afford college.  I know the only reason I tried to get good grades if high school was because I knew I'd be going to college, and needed good grades to get in.  If college wasn't an option because I couldn't afford it, I really wouldn't have even tried to succeed in high school, since the incentive to work hard just isn't that great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818230454.0" user="Shiredragon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Poorer areas tend to have problems starting with high school graduation rates. 

Yes. When kids are not eating, it effects their ability to be good students. When kids are stressed because mom and dad are stressed because they are acting out due to not enough money, it makes kids do worse in school than they otherwise would. When Parents are so concerned with putting any food on the table and keeping a roof over their heads, they are probably not as worried about their kids' education or do not have the energy or time to express that concern. 

Poverty has many overlapping effects. Often times this creates 'inescapable' realities where education is not able to be achieved readily by many in that situation. 

Providing free education (public schools) for these children gives them a possible out. It does not guarantee graduation. Just like someone going to college does not guarantee that they will graduate with a degree. They have to overcome their situation and this gives them an avenue. Just like providing free college will not mean everyone gets to graduate. It means that everyone has the **opportunity** to graduate and will not be denied that opportunity simply because they were born into poverty. 

&amp;gt;what makes us think they will go to college?

In that case we are not spending money on them so I am not sure why this is a bad thing in your view since you are concerned with wasting money. This would be self-selecting out those that are not going to graduate and consequently making the system more efficient. 

I do not know what system would be implemented, but I doubt it would be compulsory. 

&amp;gt; So, would the money be better spent at lower levels of education? 

According to your argument it is already wasted there since they don't want to graduate but are compelled to complete schooling anyways. While I disagree with the premise of your argument in the first place, this really does not help your argument since you previously stated that you want to not waste money, and these kids are a waste of money according to you. 

&amp;gt; We just have to get kids at a young age to want to do it.

Indeed. Now the proof is in the pudding. So we need to make the home environment for the kids better so that they get 3 square meals a day. That means that they need to either have mom and/or dad make more money, or the government has to step in. Guess what, more money. Then we need to make sure that mom and/or dad have more time and less stress so they can focus on the kids more. That means better jobs, less time working three jobs, and more money from the jobs. This will need better education, worker protections and rights, or federal payouts. But all of that is money somewhere. 

That is the issue really. It comes down to money that people see as 'theirs'. We live in a society where we are conditioned towards the self, individualism, and possessiveness. *(I am not saying there are not positive things to those.)* The down side to this is that we see any taxation or redistribution of wealth as stealing from us, or what we aspire to. Look at tax rates 50 years ago. The wealthy were still wealthy, they just paid more. But we now have a system that is leaning more and more towards keeping what you make even though you are part of a society. So it is really taking from society without contributing back. That is really the mindset that is promoted by this view that my money is mine alone. *Take what you can, give nothing back.* Kansas has been doing a great job of following that dream. Taxes are as low as ever there. 

So, to summarize, the issue is not trying to take your money. It is trying to make sure that all people have the **opportunity** to get an education that is repeatedly being more and more required to get a decent job in the USA. Then you have to decide if that is worth paying for as a nation. 

Also, if you really want to live the low tax dream, I am sure Kansas would love to have you. But be prepared to pay for private schooling for your kids. They might not have much of a public education system left soon. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818293497.0" user="toms_face" delta="False">
    <text>If those who do graduate high school in poorer areas have the opportunity to further their education, they are much more equipped to break the cycle of poverty for their family and their community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818357350.0" user="HKBFG" delta="False">
    <text>Do you seriously think poor people just don't want to graduate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818602167.0" user="HCPwny" delta="False">
    <text>Why should they try in grade school when they're not going to be able to go to college anyways?  Their parents aren't going to be able to pay for it, and neither are they on their minimum wage job.  Maybe a few get lucky on sports scholarships or race-quotas, but the vast majority are sunk and have no way out.  Ignorance breeds ignorance.  This is but a tiny stepping stone on the path to a more educated populace.  Education isn't a bad thing, even if it doesn't guarantee jobs.  It still increases your likelihood of getting one, and merely having one tends to give you a better salary than not.  Education changes mindsets and perception of the world around you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818671853.0" user="laioren" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've neglected to realize that the average public school in the United States (from the nature of your post, I'll assume you live there) is primarily funded by [local property taxes](http://www.lincolninst.edu/pubs/1308_The-Property-Tax-School-Funding-Dilemma). Because of people who are primarily concerned with selfish motivations, like yourself, mbeogoa (you mention your own personal unwillingness to help others at least 5 times in the opening of your thread and constantly center the appraisal of all possible conditionals on how "fairly" **you** are treated), this situation has persisted. The argument is, "I don't want to pay for someone else's child to receive a good education."

The weaknesses of this system are [abundantly clear](http://obs.rc.fas.harvard.edu/chetty/proptax_nta.pdf) as it perpetuates poverty.

Making college free for everyone (which, btw, your college loans would probably be expunged if it were left entirely up to Sanders. What he could actually manage to pass through Congress if elected is a different matter) wouldn't instantly fix every issue in the world (which includes the problem of poverty), but it would certainly be better than doing nothing.

If anyone wishes to focus only on themself and the short-term benefits that they can reap by mortgaging everyone else's future, then they are problem.

Let us know if you change your central operating motivator and want to get involved in how to contribute to the betterment of others.

Good luck!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818827633.0" user="PAdogooder" delta="False">
    <text>Why do rich kids do well in high school and poor kids don't? The general trend is true, but the other correlated facts point to a more complete answer. Kids whose parents went to college are more likely to go to college (not just because of income), and kids from wealthier communities go to college more often (apart from income, as well). 

The truth is that most of us go to college because it is *expected* of us. We have social and cultural expectations of us to go, so we form our expectations of self around those ideas. 

Making college free, and the subtext here (from president Obama, I think in the SOTU this year) is that it would be free AND as common and easy as high school to attend, would change those expectations. "What do you mean you aren't going to college? EVERYONE goes to college." is a strong enough social force to improve the outcomes for many kids. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818897512.0" user="FockSmulder" delta="False">
    <text>Lack of a light at the end of the tunnel makes people stay on the other side of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817705488.0" user="Jmsnwbrd" delta="False">
    <text>You left out the part of his plan where Wall Street speculation would be the tax that pays for college. There will be a tax on trading (only a small amount) and he has it so that it would be enough funding. You did add the "trickle UP" bonus of a well educated and wealthier middle class - in that it will only help the U.S. as well as big business by putting more money into our economy. So, to OP's point - it will only help us grow as a nation and the only tax burden would be on the rich to wealthy speculating on Wall Street which they will get back in some form or another when businesses and stocks grow. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818342593.0" user="iKnitSweatas" delta="False">
    <text>So these people who invested their money into American businesses will have their money taxed once when they receive if, and again whenever they want to trade it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818439367.0" user="dubalubdub" delta="False">
    <text>Implying the stock markets primary function these days is to raise funds for companies and not for gambling. It's 2015 dude get with the times. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27860940163.0" user="gfour" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;these days 

It's always been that way hombre </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818534255.0" user="Jmsnwbrd" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. And I would argue that the American worker (working and middle class) should be important enough to these people making coin while speculating on Wall Street to make sure they get their fair share of the dividends of this hard work. Furthermore - that the substantial wealth generated by the working and middle class not just get gobbled up by the Wall Street guru and CEOs but some (an amount that most in this class won't even notice) of it be made available to help keep a robust middle class. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27819730104.0" user="NotPeetaMellark" delta="False">
    <text>Double taxation is a myth. Money should be taxed whenever it changes hands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817774579.0" user="atlantis145" delta="False">
    <text>Would free college not increase the amount of people going to college just for the sake of college, who either don't want to do anything (lifetime student) or don't know what they want to do (so they get a 4 year BA in art history, then decide to go into trades later)? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818130144.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>And this is a problem because...?
Even going to school for a "useless" degree has benefits. Of course most people with liberal arts degrees still won't end up directly using them, they will still have learned generally useful skills like how to apply themselves toward achieving a goal, as well as how to learn new skills they will use as they continue through life. At least in my experience, there is often a huge difference in intellect between those who took higher education - even an apprenticship or other non-academic field - and those who didn't or, even worse, didn't graduate high school. As for professional students, there likely won't be that many. Most students I've  met cannot wait to be free at the end of their program; university is much more stressful than many in the working world seem to think it is. As for those few who remain, it's a small price to pay for a more educated public.
Edit: typos</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817809838.0" user="chaosbutters" delta="False">
    <text>doesn't higher education generally lead to lower crime, fewer abortions, better health, less obesity,...

hence paying for itself eventually?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817817519.0" user="UrbanZenMonk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People, regardless of their wealth, would have equal opportunity to accomplish their goals. Those in poverty would not be limited simply because of their inability to afford college. So in the future, your kids will be able to go to a $60,000 school if they qualified in merit.

So, doesn't this just water down the 60K school while making the much cheaper school a worse idea/something no one wants or respects? Wouldn't that hinder lesser schools, both in value and reputation?

Or, as someone else already replied, doesn't this just make college "the next thing?" Why differentiate it from high school? What makes any different?

&amp;gt;In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs. 

We have unemployment, now, while many are educated. Lots of engineers graduated in Ontario but there aren't many engineer jobs for them. The idea one has a degree can land a job isn't true. If everyone trains to be a doctor, great, but we only need X many doctors.

&amp;gt;Ultimately, these people would be paying back into the system through their own taxes.

I don't believe in economics where we trickle up or down. To me, economics works when I pay for something and see a return, directly, on it. Otherwise, this kind of thing amounts to a lot of theory and a "wishing well." In theory, people pay back. In reality, most fight to get the maximum amount back from their tax return.

I always hear people happy to pay tax into programs but when asked to pay, they always fight not to do it. Seems contradicting (they really want rich people to front the bill).

Anyways, this also assumes them paying taxes will not be misspent. In Ontario, our last/current Government made 1 billion disappear in an Ehealth scandal. When 1 billion disappears, that's just gone. How did that help everyone? We paid our taxes and people wrote a program but...

&amp;gt; In addition, educated people have greater potential to make more income when they graduate

You're still restricted to the amount of jobs actually available. So, in theory, educated people can be paid a lot. In reality, many with degrees work in retail with high school graduates. 

And, when everyone has degrees, the pool of employees grows and business has a huge selection. So, your value now hinges not on your rarity but the fact you are just way better than the others (which is a good thing but for those who like "equality," that'll screw many disadvantaged people).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817900967.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>* There are many factors that go into a school's reputation including its history, faculty, and endowments/funding. I don't think the cost of tuition in the eyes of the student plays as big of a role as you think. Ultimately what makes it different from high school is that individuals still need to apply like they already do and get in. Competitive schools will remain competitive.

* I know that I would rather have an engineering degree than not have one. You are implying that you want to artificially create scarcity in the market. We only need X doctors, so only X people can be doctors. All free college does is create an even playing field. Students will still need to be able to graduate on their own accord. In any case, a more educated population will be able to create jobs through starting their own businesses. The supply of job isn't fixed. Obviously a degree isn't necessary to do this in all cases, but it certainly is helpful.

* People indeed will do what they can to not pay taxes. They will not act out of benevolence in paying back into the system. But the fact is that a practicing engineer or doctor will pay more taxes than someone who works as a waiter. An engineer who makes around 65,000 dollars will pay 25% in income tax on average. In one year, he pays 16,250. In his career (assume 30 years), he pays 487,500. Realize this doesn't take into account his spending, income raises as he progresses in his career, or any other nuisances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817821151.0" user="Justagreewithme" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree.  "More people occupying higher paying jobs". I feel that that is t the problem.  There is a finite amount of jobs, no matter being many qualified candidates.  In fact, there seems to be the issue where too many people have degrees now that need it.  Furthermore, you are quite literally taking from the poor to give to those better off, or at least soon to be better off.  Education is an investment and the poor/stupid will be investing without reaping any of the benefits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817847533.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>* There is definitely an issue of supply and demand, but there is not necessarily a finite amount of jobs. Educated people have the potential to create jobs, maybe even entire industries. The advent of computers created countless jobs, for example.

* Free college does not take anything away from anybody. People still need to apply as they normally do and compete based on their own merits. Free college would only help create a more just society. If a candidate is truly better, he will get through. This sort of system just allows people to attend a school they would have been able to get into anyway.

* When people enter college, they might indeed be stupid (at least as stupid as everyone else, regardless of their family's wealth.) But through the next four to five years, they will either have prove themselves through hard work, or they will fail out.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817899071.0" user="cooningthedog" delta="False">
    <text>It kind of seems to me that by giving free college education sort of devalues the college degree. 

Before free college, if you didn't have a reason to extend your education, you could go into trade jobs and other labor immediately. But now with free college, you don't have a reason not to go. Cause why not have four free years of your life? I think it would expand the amount of people that are going to college without a long-term reason other than "maybe it will help me get some sort of job".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817943207.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point. However, people can still decide to go into trade jobs if they have the drive. Directionless people will be directionless regardless. I hope you will agree that it is more about what you learn and what your goals are than the paper diploma.

The core of it, I think, is that society should be flexible enough that no one is held back based on the conditions they were born in. If they are capable enough, any number of options should be available for them to choose from, whether that be at the university level or through a trade.

In the end, if more people are attending universities, I see that as a good thing. One person might say that it somehow "devalues" the knowledge, but I would say that it "normalizes" it. For example, shouldn't everyone have the opportunity to learn to cook/swim/drive/etc? Is it better if only half the population ever gets the chance to? There will be greater demand for their skill/knowledge, but society benefits as whole more otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818008125.0" user="cooningthedog" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, yeah I see the greater sentiment behind it now. More about equal opportunity than anything right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817901804.0" user="AzazelsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The advent of computers created countless jobs, for example.

An advent lead by college dropouts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817920801.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>I'm assuming your talking about Bill Gates or Steve Jobs?
http://time.com/3908338/bill-gates-college-grads/

In any case, college graduates are the lifeblood of companies like Microsoft and the rest of the big tech companies. Universities themselves are where computers and the internet started and took off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818035750.0" user="Justagreewithme" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about the stupid people that can't get into college.  Those are the people being fucked over.  They are going to be limited on income already, yet have to shell out more for other people to go to school and make more money.  We have an ok system now-anybody that is capable can get loans.  They will reap the benefits of the education, then repay when they are capable with their now higher income.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818530636.0" user="GTFErinyes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is definitely an issue of supply and demand, but there is not necessarily a finite amount of jobs. Educated people have the potential to create jobs, maybe even entire industries. The advent of computers created countless jobs, for example.

The advent of computers also destroyed countless jobs - and it made it easier to outsource a lot of jobs that weren't possible 30 years ago.

The other problem I have is that this is the same issue with "supply side" economics - the idea that if we increase our supply of degree holders, it will generate demand for those same degree holders.

That form of economics is controversial at best.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817839718.0" user="Pillowy_Mounds" delta="False">
    <text>I totally agree but I'm possibly biased, coming from Scotland where we have free higher education.

Doing a rough estimate I find that Scotland's higher education budget for 2015 is £970.3m ($1.5bn) for a population of 5.3m.

Multiplying this value with respect to the American population would yield a value of $90bn per year in funding higher education.

Looking at the [current](http://www.usgovernmentspending.com/year_spending_2015USbn_16bs2n#usgs302) budget, US spending on defense is $630bn. Surely 1/7th of this could be put to better use by granting free higher education to all? I don't see how taxes would necessarily have to be raised.

Happy to have my opinion changed but this is just my thoughts as an outsider looking in.

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818631310.0" user="cgalv" delta="False">
    <text>I'm in favor of lowering US military spending. However, 1/7th of our military budget is a very sizable sum even by U.S. Federal expenditure standard. That would make the amount we spend on secondary education greater than the spending on any other social program except Social Security (our national pension fund) and Medicare/Medicaid (our equivalent of NHS, but only for poor people). I'm skeptical it's worth it.

Also, while I think it's too high, there are advantages to our large military budget. For starters, most of our allies get away with paying very little. Consider NATO, for instance. The U.S. Spends about 5% of GDP on defense, while most of our NATO allies spend 2-3% (UK excepted). As a result, it's pretty fair to say we get our way (and Germany, Italy, and Canada get relatively free rides). That has some value. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817929129.0" user="TexasAntonym" delta="False">
    <text>Really have to get back to seeing Education as a social good as opposed to a personal achievement. On an individual level, congratulations to anyone finishing college but we're trying to create an effective system for roughly 320 million people, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818309071.0" user="jealoussizzle" delta="False">
    <text>Its incredible how many people don't understand this even after attending postsecondary schools. When we are trying to help improve a developing nation what is one of the first tings we build? Schools. Every time schools is one of the first things aid money is directed to after basic living requirements because an educated populace is one with immeasurable potential for success. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817934004.0" user="Elmattador" delta="False">
    <text>What about blue collar jobs?  We need plumbers, mechanics etc and you don't go to college for that.  If college is free, wouldn't everyone go (even if it's not something they should do) and be a waste of money?  Should there be some kind of aptitude test that determines if college is "right" for you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817975223.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; wouldn't everyone go (even if it's not something they should do) and be a waste of money? Should there be some kind of aptitude test that determines if college is "right" for you?

You still need to compete to get accepted into universities. This just removes one arbitrary element-- your family's wealth, something outside your control. 

Blue collar jobs are very important. All free college does is allow for people to choose between learning trade skills or becoming an apprentice somewhere and going to a university. Individuals have more options and their futures aren't restricted based on something out of their control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817934648.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs. 

With more people qualified for those jobs, the wages for said jobs would go down though.  The reason that high paying jobs have high pay is that there is a relative shortage of people able and willing to do the job. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817970166.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>You assume that supply will be fixed. If I study law and go and create a successful firm, I now have actually increased job supply. In addition, I don't think that there should be an artificial cap put in place on the number of students there are at any given university which is based on family income. How is that justifiable? 

In any case, it would only take one breakthrough to potentially create an entirely new industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817994878.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If I study law and go and create a successful firm, I now have actually increased job supply.

That you create a firm doesn't create an additional need for legal services though. Demand is what creates jobs, not employers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818003702.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>Demand for goods and services creates jobs, yes.

But who knew they wanted cars two hundred years ago? How many jobs has that industry created? Employeers don't create jobs, but innovators do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818022324.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>Which is all beside the point which is that creating more people who are qualified for the existing high wage jobs will lower wages for those jobs. 

I'm not sure what innovation has to do with a college education though. Ever hear of a guy named Bill Gates? What's his degree in? 

That's the biggest example but I think it can be pretty easily argued that innovation and the type of thinking required to be truly innovative has little to nothing to do with college education.  Certainly a college education can be helpful in implementing the ideas, but I think it's wrong to think that more college education necessarily leads to more innovation.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818042582.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>Bill Gates claims he was a fluke. He encourages getting a college degree.

College education doesn't automatically mean that individuals will be more innovative. But equipping innovative people with the necessary skills will give them the ability to act, as you say, implement their ideas. If these skills can be gained easier through college, shouldn't the individual have equal access as anyone else, even if they are born into poverty?

http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/04/upshot/bill-gates-college-dropout-dont-be-like-me.html?abt=0002&amp;amp;abg=1
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818063213.0" user="chaz345" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  shouldn't the individual have equal access as anyone else, 

Depends on who pays the cost. My problem with Sander's proposal is that it's packaged as being paid for by a tax that only affects the rich fatcats when that's not the case for two reasons. First is that a transaction tax on stock transactions will affect mutual funds which is where a lot of 401k s are invested. Second is that the transaction tax is estimated to only cover about 2/3s of the total cost with the rest coming from the states. States that will have to raise taxes in some form to pay for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818370491.0" user="skylmingakappi" delta="False">
    <text>Bill gates doesn't have a degree but he went to Harvard studying on the backs of his parents wealth. it was for a lucky string of events that he created Microsoft. Had he not, he would still probably be earning a high wage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817937279.0" user="Vik1ng" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs. 

Actually I think that's where the US system is pretty flawed. You should really not try to get everyone into college. Here in Germany it's free, but still limited by your grades to get in.

I think when you make it government funded then you have to restrict access in some way, because you don't need every highschool graduate to go to college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817962767.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not everyone needs to go to college. Schools do not accept everyone who applies.

What a free public college system does is create an even playing field where individuals can compete based solely on their own merits-- not based on their family's income. This is also better for the universities, which can potentially admit better students.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817941961.0" user="the_friendly_draugr" delta="False">
    <text>Alternatively, breakthroughs could replace jobs with machines, meaning that fewer people could have jobs and pay back into the system.  An example of this is the self-driving car.  A huge number of employees will be replaced because they pated into this system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817957956.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>In history, new technology has replaced old ones taking away old jobs with it. This cannot be prevented. Horses were replaced by trains which were replaced by cars. If the United States avoids breakthroughs, it will be left in the dust by other nations.

New jobs with higher skill requirements come to replace the old ones. I doubt anyone wants to go back to the days of riding horses or carriages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818693727.0" user="the_friendly_draugr" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that we should avoid breakthroughs.  I'm saying that these breakthroughs are more likely to eliminate jobs than to make more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817988593.0" user="saffir" delta="False">
    <text>What if I told you that prestigious schools such as Harvard and MIT provide all this information for free, and all you have to do is go to library for free Internet? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817994918.0" user="StudiousNights" delta="False">
    <text>Admittedly, it's a lot easier when a professor guides you. Good point though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818033461.0" user="saffir" delta="False">
    <text>Community colleges are like $30 a credit. Not everyone needs to attend a UC</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818151454.0" user="whitepalms85" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People, regardless of their wealth, would have equal opportunity to accomplish their goals. Those in poverty would not be limited simply because of their inability to afford college. So in the future, your kids will be able to go to a $60,000 school if they qualified in merit.

That's not wrong but it's not a positive externality. That's just redistribution.

&amp;gt; In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs. Ultimately, these people would be paying back into the system through their own taxes. The returns on this investment is high since it would only take a few breakthroughs in technology to create many other jobs. Consider how the university system created Gopher, a predecessor to the modern day internet browser. In addition, educated people have greater potential to make more income when they graduate. This makes taxes towards education fundamentally different from something like welfare, where there are no direct returns. You actually benefit from it.

That's wrong, sorry. Income is just the price employers pay for your time/skills. And just like every other price it's based on supply and demand. Assuming that supply for high skilled workers is constant or at least not massively increasing, then salaries would fall if everyone becomes high skilled. Actually this is what is happening in the US at the moment. The returns on a university degree are still positive but constantly decreasing. Also the link between university degrees and productivity isn't very clear. Most degrees aren't very applied or relevant for future jobs. E.g. a course in excel at some local training center increases the productivity of office workers more than a semester of history at Harvard. It's also unclear whether sending more average people to uni will lead to a lot more scientific breakthroughs. Ultimately it's a relatively small group of the leading and brightest scientists that drive innovation. Basically if you aren't right at the top you won't really be able to increase the roof.

&amp;gt; An educated population will be more knowledgeable and active in society, steering the nation in a good path for the future.

That would be a positive externality but it's hard to proof. I think it might be correct but the effects are most likely decreasing. E.g. there are a lot of positive externalities from teaching people how to read but how much is society profiting from someone becoming a specialist that isn't already included in the price (the salary) of that person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818192576.0" user="morphotomy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs.

Just because there are more graduates doesn't mean there'll be more jobs. I know plenty of cashiers with bachelors degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818224764.0" user="AFKennedy" delta="False">
    <text>When the government will pay for tuition at any price, a $60,000 tuition doesn't stay $60,000. The price will actually increase even faster than prices have been increasing, because now it's that people will take out loans for even very expensive colleges (ie, people are very price insensitive), but at some point they'll go to a cheaper school or some won't be able to take out loans; the government will pay $120,000/year if it is mandated to just give free college no matter the price.

This is why free private college can never work as currently constructed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818340727.0" user="iKnitSweatas" delta="False">
    <text>Where are these higher paying jobs going to come from? Unless you're going to be a doctor or an engineer, you'll make more money entering a trade such as plumbing or welding</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818341447.0" user="dildope" delta="False">
    <text>I ctrl-fed it and couldn't find any mention of the Robin Hood tax (so forgive me if you've gotten a million replies about this already)... isn't this how Bernie proposed to implement the College For All Act?  Something along the lines of a .5% tax on all Wall Street transactions and an additional .5% on certain other transactions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818350005.0" user="TheRealChimShady" delta="False">
    <text>Feel free to CMV here, but I feel like free college would hurt US college grad's job prospects by diluting the value of a college degree. The more people who go to college then the less of a competitive edge having a degree gives you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818433848.0" user="qxzv" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Those in poverty would not be limited simply because of their inability to afford college.

Devil's advocate: there are already policies in place for those who are *truly* poor.  The problem is that every middle class kid thinks they should be considered poor when it comes to grant money.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818569958.0" user="Moimoi328" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People, regardless of their wealth, would have equal opportunity to accomplish their goals.

Everybody already has equal opportunity to attend college under the current system.

In practice, it will be significantly harder for the poor to accomplish their goals if college is made tuition-free.  By making college tuition-free, you significantly increase the supply of potential college students against a relatively fixed supply of placement slots at universities.  It will make it significantly harder for the average student to even be admitted to the college of their choice.

In addition, tuition free education will also increase the supply of students with economically unviable majors.  This is a huge problem and creates a massive moral hazard.

&amp;gt;In the long term, free college would mean that more people would be educated and be able to occupy higher paying jobs.

By increasing the supply of college educated people that can do these jobs, you will reduce wages for these jobs in aggregate.  If the salaries are indeed high for these types of jobs, then it is economically viable to take out loans for university in order to attain these jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818605497.0" user="AntimatterNuke" delta="False">
    <text>If college is free, won't this turn it into the new high school diploma, even more so than it already is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818734944.0" user="anodognosic" delta="False">
    <text>College is more a sorting mechanism than any kind of preparation for work or civic life. It's a way for employers to know they're hiring the "right kind of people." If everyone goes to college, employers will no longer have that as an easy way to cut unwanted candidates, and something new will be invited to favor the well-off. Except now we're wasting billions upon billions coutrywide and even more people spend four entirely unproductive years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818824094.0" user="spencer4991" delta="False">
    <text>What if, instead of the government paying for college, public schools are required to make tuition a percentage of income earned after graduation for say 15-20 years? The government could subsidize the transition and it would encourage schools to both improve the quality of both education and networking, while also encouraging the ending or at least shrinking of programs that are "worthless". This would have the advantage of letting everyone go to college (potentially) and not permanently burden the taxpayer. Everyone wins.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
