<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818020092.0" user="doppelbach" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't have the money for that. Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.


Here's a few things to consider:


1.  First of all, let's assume no population growth.  That means that, over the course of your life as a taxpayer, you only need to support one college student with your taxes.  Would you rather pay your entire tuition over a span of 4 years or over a span of 40 years?


2.  Most students end up going into debt trying to absorb the entire cost over 4 years, but this is less likely to happen when your costs are spread out.  If society can keep students from going into debt, that means less money being spent on interest, which should decrease costs overall.


3.  Under the current system, students need to pay at a time when they have little to no income.  Adults in the middle of their careers are in a better financial position.


4.  Income tax is progressive.  I'm not sure where the money would come from, but some sort of progressive tax would make sense.  In that case, most adults would likely be paying for only a fraction of one tuition, while the richest would be paying tuition for many students.


Also, you are probably able to claim interest payments on your student loans as a deductible.  If this plan goes through (it won't), this would serve as a sort of 'discount' on paying for others' tuition while you are still paying for your own.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
