<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817945440.0" user="afspdx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; While the cost of college education in the US has reached record highs, Germany has abandoned tuition fees altogether for German and international students alike. An increasing number of Americans are taking advantage and saving tens of thousands of dollars to get their degrees.

&amp;gt; **More than 4,600 US students are fully enrolled at Germany universities, an increase of 20% over three years.** At the same time, the total student debt in the US has reached $1.3 trillion (£850 billion).
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Each semester, Hunter pays a fee of €111 ($120) to the Technical University of Munich (TUM), one of the most highly regarded universities in Europe, to get his degree in physics. ..."
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; "It's not unattractive for us when knowledge and know-how come to us from other countries and result in jobs when these students have a business idea and stay in Berlin to create their start-up," says Steffen Krach, Berlin's Secretary of Science.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; German students do not need to worry either, he says, because the city has increased capacities massively in recent years at its universities and there is enough space for everyone on campus.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-32821678

The rest of the world understands exactly how good an investment in their economy educating citizens is. If wealthy Americans are too  greedy to spend money educating American citizens, countries like Germany, France, Norway &amp;amp; Brazil are going to bring all those smart American kids to Europe and pay for American kids to study in top European universities.  Half the people that leave a country to get in a degree in a foreign country never come back</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
