<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="52" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27819392847.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct? Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?

They'd probably get raised.

&amp;gt; Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?

That's about right.  Kinda sucks, doesn't it?  But you probably won't actually pay extra, or at least, not much extra, because you're probably not going to be in the income brackets most affected.  And if they're federal loans, I'd imagine that this kind of free college program would address that in other ways too.  But to address the basic concern here, you basically just have to get over yourself.  Your taxes always go to other people.  That's how it is.  And in the case of a new program, they're going to other people and giving them benefits you didn't get to have in the past.  Are you going to oppose it out of spite?

&amp;gt; And what happens with private institutions? Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?

Probably not.  In fact, I'd go further and say this is batshit insane.  The government would *never* do anything this crazy (even the Republicans aren't crazy enough for something like this).  Only *some* public institutions would likely be covered anyway.  By the way, Obama has already stated that he would like to see free community colleges.  That's probably the extent of it, though maybe state schools could be free-er as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
