<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817781774.0" user="blackcoffeecyclist" delta="False">
    <text>Hey bud! 

So when Bernie talks about free school he is exclusively talking about public institutions(state schools). Essentially yes, you would be paying more in taxes, but Bernie is not targeting little guys like us, he is targeting billionaires and multinational companies. 


Every year about 1/4 of multinational companies pay literally NOTHING in taxes due to tax loopholes. Further you have billionaires like Warren Buffet who actually come out and say they have an effective tax rate lower than their secretary due to their ability to pay lawyers etc, to reduce how much taxes they pay through the use of loopholes.


We lose at least 100 billion a year in taxes due to companies/people moving their wealth out of country to tax havens like the Cayman islands. 

Bernie wants the rich to start paying their dues by eliminating tax loopholes. 

P.S- Effective tax rate and Real tax rate are different. Real tax rate is the rate of taxes I'm supposed to pay on paper, Effective tax rate is the rate I end up paying. 

Hope this helps. 

Further, the goal Bernie and those like him is not an immediate cure. He is thinking in the long term. If we increase our average intelligence through school, we can increase our average wealth as a nation over a period of time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818109717.0" user="Sectox" delta="False">
    <text>Whats the cutoff though? If I make over 100k a year I don't want to give 70% of my money to the government. Dont I have a right to keep what I earn?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818212062.0" user="blackcoffeecyclist" delta="False">
    <text>Well, considering Bernie's statements on the matter, he is really quite specific about the top 1%, and that's quite a bit from the top 1%.

The emphasis is on Billionaires and multinational companies.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
