<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="50" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818722450.0" user="patricktlo" delta="False">
    <text>Here where I live (Brazil) we have public free universities, I think it would be interesting for you to see how it works here. 

To start off, money for the University comes from taxes, of course. However, universities don't get paid much, so there are "frequent" (maybe once every 3-4 years, it depends) strikes (when professors stop giving classes asking for more money). Even so, the public universities here in Brazil are the best available (I believe 7 out of the 10 best in the country are public, I could look up a source later, I'm on mobile). 

Are there private universities? Yes, quite a lot, and why would someone pay for university when they could go to a free public one that's probably better? Well, there's a test for the public universities and not everyone gets in. Example : for my major (electrical engineerings) when I got in there were about 800 people trying for it and only 80 people could get in, the ones that didn't get in could either try another public University, or try again next year or go to a private one. 

One interesting thing to look at are those test to enter college, there are a lot of people trying to get in, so, in order to get in so that they don't have to pay for college, they pay before for a private high school that's better than a public one (public high schools are not good here) and then try to get accepted in college. 

Now what happens to the initial idea of the project, that was to put the people with less money in college? Well, they didn't have money to pay for a private high school, they're less likely to get accepted in the University that someone wealthier than them that was in a private high school. The obvious solution to that is to get public HS to be better, but the government doesn't want to spend money and yada yada, so the solution they came up with was to reserve some of the openings for the University for student who studies at public high schools. It works to some degree, the problem now is that student from public high school struggles to keep going like the others because they didn't have a solid background on the basics. 

So yeah, it works and it doesn't at the same time, it could probably be fixed by getting public high schools to be better, hopefully someday. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
