<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="48" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818668282.0" user="yogfthagen" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of the government is t improve the society at large.  
People going to college improves the society for a number of reasons.  
Educated people are less likely to commit crimes, abuse drugs, are more likely to have a higher standard of living, be more productive over the course of their lifetimes, be healthier, have children later (and not have children born into poverty), support their schools, are more engaged in their communities, etc, etc, etc.  And, as the government is so very fond of, an educated person is likely to make more than half a million dollars more over the course of their lifetime, and also pay a significantly higher amount of taxes over that period, too.  They ALSO tend to save for retirement, and are less likely to become a burden on society.  
What you're complaining about is that YOU already paid for school yourself, and you don't wanna pay for someone else to go to school, too.  
Here's te thing.  A lot of the benefits that go into having a well-educated population will SAVE you money in the long run.  You will save on paying for social welfare programs, prisons, retirement subsidies, and so on.  A dollar of education funding tends to produce over THREE dollars in increased economic growth.  
Yes, it sucks that you're going to be paying for other people to do what you got by paying for it, but 20 years from now, THEY are going to be paying for YOU.  
Economics is really kind of a pain in the ass.  There is NO economic policy that benefits everyone.  SOMEONE gets the short end of the stick.  The question is, who should pay?  Should someone who has little earning potential pay NOW, or should they be allowed to train themselves to a much higher level so they can earn a LOT MORE on your dime?  
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
