<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817435850.0" user="Bluezephr" delta="False">
    <text>So, yes, it would probably come from taxes, and while you're finished college and have graduated, you also have graduated high school which is also paid for by your taxes. College is now becoming a more essential requirement for anyone trying to exist in the middle class. My question is: why is socializing education a bad thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817477856.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>Currently we have a situation where college graduates have to fight tooth and nail to get jobs that don't *actually* require you to know anything more than a fifth grader. I don't know a good solution, but how will making education even easier to get money for help that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817490407.0" user="Bluezephr" delta="False">
    <text>And they absolutely need those jobs that require little education and pay close to the minimum wage so that they can pay off the student debt they accumulated. These jobs are also disappearing as automation improves. An educated workforce has long term benefits on society, in the same way that high school education has that long term benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817565451.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>I mentioned this in another comment, but why don't we then just streamline college?  There were a bunch of random classes I had to take to make me "well rounded", but really they were just a waste of time.  What if we could get rid of those classes, only take the necessary ones, and cut college from 4 years to 2?  Or at least 3.  That would cut down costs by the thousands. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817711447.0" user="The_Last_Minority" delta="False">
    <text>What you are referring to is a vocational school or program, and they exist, but frankly the US needs more of them. They fulfill a very specific purpose of training your for a job or a career with less of an emphasis on 'higher education' than a collegiate curriculum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817729687.0" user="TheOneFreeEngineer" delta="False">
    <text>Even now you can finish college in the years if you never fall any classes and work super hard even with your nebulous additional "unnecessary classes". This chance increases if you don't need to work a job during college, as you have significantly more time for classes. But it's colleges that set the bar for minimum for finishing degrees, not the government. They pick those classes for reasons they think it's necessary. You may disagree but they aren't doing it for no reason</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817787529.0" user="dopperpod" delta="False">
    <text>You avoided his question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818308710.0" user="eyreickson" delta="False">
    <text>AP and IB classes streamline college, if you make use of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818473322.0" user="agapE_agape" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that those classes are random or a waste of time. All the classes outside your major/specialization (a vast majority are liberal arts courses) serve to create an informed citizenry, crucial to the proper functioning of ideal democracy. With greater social/economic power comes equally greater responsibility imo so not taking these classes seriously is quite problematic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818648529.0" user="shalafi71" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There were a bunch of random classes I had to take to make me "well rounded", but really they were just a waste of time.

I have to argue this and I'll use myself for an example.  I'm an IT guy, sysadmin for my company.  (BTW, I don't have a degree but I did go to college.)

Many of the classes I took look like a waste of time from an IT employee's point of view but they weren't.

Look at your stereotypical, nerdy, socially fucked up sysadmin.  Come over to /r/sysadmin    and you'll see what I mean.  :)  A huge part of my job is communication.  Taking English, journalism, psychology, even French classes, aided in this.  Hell, I got my first tech support job because I spoke French, here in America no less.  Even taking forestry and horticulture has benefited me.  I grow lots of things and can relate on that level to about half my coworkers.  That's a powerful thing in the office, just being able to BS around with people and share interests.  With the benefit of 25 years of hindsight I can't think of a single worthless class I took.

The thing about education is that you can't ever say what's useful.  It's kinda like science.  Maybe some scientist is awarded a $600,000 grant to study the fucking habits of a certain frog.  Useless, yes?  What if that frog's genes hold the key to regenerating limbs?  Now we need a BUNCH of frogs in a hurry.  Well, I know a guy who knows how to get a bunch of frogs in a hurry.

I'd also like to say that, with your thoughtful participation, this is one of the most interesting arguments I've ever read in this sub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818714373.0" user="mbeogoa" delta="False">
    <text>Haha glad you are enjoying it.  Also, I see what you mean and I also took some classes that were not really relevant, but interesting nonetheless.  Maybe the could be offered as extra and not mandatory?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27818861800.0" user="shalafi71" delta="False">
    <text>You're like my best friend.  Very conservative Southern Baptist vs. liberal atheist.  :)

Classes should be mandatory and it actually pains me to say "mandatory".  It's like a dirty word as regards education.

BUT... Who are you (or I) to say what's mandatory?  Where will you be 25 years from now?   Can you answer that with certainty?  Can you say that those classes weren't worth it?  Of course you can't answer that and neither can I.  I still say, none of them were without worth.

It's trite but... Knowledge is power, pen mightier than the sword stuff.  

We should be friends. :)  Your power of argument and lust for knowledge puts us in the same "box".  You're a person I can learn from.  It's really exciting to me to find someone who can argue their point without being an ass or being partisan.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27817811682.0" user="THeShinyHObbiest" delta="False">
    <text>Socializing education isn't necessarily bad, but college is very different from High School. High School aims to give people a baseline of knowledge to accomplish various tasks. College teaches you a field in-depth. As a result, it's always going to be more expensive. Especially since people tend to live at their colleges. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
