<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27818237008.0" user="Cheeseboyardee" delta="False">
    <text>A couple points... 

Are you also opposed to public high schools? 

If we drop back 100 years the basic level of education needed for most jobs was somewhere between sixth and tenth grade. And you could enter almost any field. A high school diploma, and each tier of diploma after that were essentially a shortcut to experience in the field. So a high school dropout could eventually work their way up in almost any field, and this was more or less normal for people to do. If a degree or additional training was needed, employers would often pick up the cost. So let's say at 16 you say "Screw this lurnin' crap, Imma get me a j o b!" You could. You simply walked out of the school, and over to a local factory and swept the hell outta some floors. You rocked the broom and learned how to operate the new-fangled machine. So now you moved into production and got paid a bit more. Then the war started and your factory went into war-production mode and you became a foreman training and supervising others (Until you were drafted, but we're going to go with somebody who wasn't.). Turns out you were good at it, so you end up being factory manager as our boys came back victorious. They were already familiar with machinery and the skill sets translated well. All this time you were saving all the money you could, and finally make the leap to start your own business. So now you're in your mid-40's ish, and own a business. You're technically making less money per hour than you were in the factory, but the factory closes during the depression anyway. You manage to survive the depression and then BAM another War starts moving production forward again. So you get to hire folks, and you hire a lot of 16 year old drop outs to sweep up. One of them shows promise so you train them up to help manage when you expand/semi-retire. Repeat cycle.

That narrative is the quintessential "American dream". You work your ass off, you get rewarded.

But the major change over the last 100 years has been to raise that entry level of education for almost every job. the Drop out became the GED, the High school Diploma became the Associates, the Associates became a Bachelors etc. Certifications for things like "Driving a forklift" became common. Especially in urban areas. In rural areas heavy machinery operation is still almost a given, but in urban areas most people don't have access to machinery outside of a job. While in the past, the duty of training an operator was on the employer, that onus has shifted to the employee. Basically the same issue as "Can't get the job without the car, can't get the car without the job". 

The basic job has also moved from factory/warehouse to medical coding. Which is one of the reasons the associates degree is the new high school diploma. That sweeping job? Now you need to have a basic understanding of chemistry in order to read the MSDS sheets on the chemicals you're using to clean up the floor. 

Certifications are now more important than "being willing to learn/able to do it". Certifications are obtained through colleges or voc tech programs. So really socialized college education is essentially "adjusting for inflation". 

Secondly... 

The economic benefits of allowing access to people from poor economic backgrounds have been proven repeatedly since the introduction of "the GI Bill" along with the Pell grants and other federal assistance programs. HOWEVER, even with these programs the cost of a post secondary education has risen much faster than inflation. In some states it is because state funding has dropped for public institutions. Since this funding no longer exists the economic barriers effectively remain in place, although diminished. 

So your taxes have always gone towards public colleges, it's just a change in which taxes, and how much. 

Third...

For myself the biggest concern would be the use of "Vouchers" or other types of funding for private institutions. That to me is the major stumbling block to any legislation funding public college tuition free. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
