<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817839774.0" user="Thriven" delta="False">
    <text>I can't give a ton of facts but my opinion. 

I worked in Student Loans Collections for 4 months as I was desperate and needed a job. I sat at a desk with a portfolio of 4 million dollars to collect on. I didn't need full repayment. I just needed to get the borrowers to start a repayment plan as low as $5 a month for 12 months to get the loan out of default and eventually handed to a financial institution showing good faith payments who would fund the loan as a federally insured student loan.

I wasn't very good at the job and my co-workers that were constantly violating FDCPA or falling well into the grey areas that would get them fired and us sued regardless.

Student Loan debt destroys people. I garnished so many peoples wages as I was an excellent skip tracer. I got 2 Doctors licenses suspended over the course of that 4 months and 1 Lawyer disbarred. The only person I ever turned around from a garnishment was a woman living with her parents who told me to "F off" twice that month and I finally violated FDCPA to get her to listen by telling her that her Social Security was being garnished and $5 a month would alleviate $125 being garnished each month. That was the day I knew I couldn't do the job.

Student Loan debt kills people. There are literally no verification or checks in place when a student wants to sign a promissory note. Private colleges are the worst and their loan amounts can be astronomical. College tuition's should be regulated by the government in my opinion.

So I was one person with a 4 million dollar portfolio to collect on in a call center with 185 people at a nationwide company with locations in 35 states. There are hundreds of companies like that employer that collect on student loans and only student loans.

If you asked me, we offer free education as it is. When students drop out they still want to collect on the full dollar amount. **edit** I should add that when this happens the school already got paid, the financial institution defaults the loan but the federal government picks up the check. **/edit** Many times when students drop out they also move or completely change their lifestyle (usually this causes a communication failure between lender and borrower and the student doesn't understand they are about to or are in default). When they find out they are being garnished they go underground. This system creates the dregs of our society where they refuse to work a full time job and tend to be full time freelancers at temp agencys, restaurant and anywhere where work can be found fast and dropped fast. This creates a class of people without health care and complete lack of responsibility because the moment they try to get their life together they are punished with garnishment and to get out of default you must work with student loan collection agencies and they are some of the worst people to deal with. Student Loans will loom over you and as much of a lie it is to say ,"Go to college and you'll be financially stable" its also a lie to tell people ,"The government will eventually forgive your loans". They may have some loan forgiveness programs but most people will not ever qualify for them.

If we made community and university colleges free with proper placement tests and provided a roadmap for students to follow to qualify for free schooling. Student's could come and go. Things happen and when that students head is on his/her shoulders in the right way, they could follow the roadmap and get back into their classes and not have to worry about student loans being in default. 

Private colleges (if regulated) would have to abide by the same costs and road maps to get students into the classroom on feds dime (edit: or the student has to pay with a loan that is not federally insured or pay upfront as the wealthy already do).

Either we as a nation continue to rack up billions of dollars in [defaulted] student loan debt that literally destroys peoples lives or we pay billions of dollars to offer the same services free without creating a subclass of society that must live a nomadic lifestyle that leads to individuals paying little taxes and being a burden on society.

Edit: To me its the same thing as Healthcare reform or universal health care. Debt basically destroys people and creates an industry that continues to destroy people who because so, don't pay much or little taxes as all and don't contribute to society.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
