<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197012632.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39anx4/cmv_bernie_sanders_idea_of_free_college_doesnt/">
    <title>CMV: Bernie Sanders idea of free college doesn't seem like a good thing.</title>
    <original_poster>mbeogoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is probably because I am really bad at understanding politics and don't totally know what Sanders wants to do.  

But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct?  Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does?  Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free?  That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that.  Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.  

And what happens with private institutions?  Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?  Maybe that seems selfish, but that does not seem fair.  And the government should not be able to force me to pay so other people can get an easier life when I myself did not get that chance.  By the way, I know I am already being forced to pay for things I don't want, but shouldn't we be trying to lessen those instances instead of adding to them?

I mean, on paper his idea sounds great.  Free college, a better educated America, a more economically even country. YAY.  But that doesn't come for free.  And just because I am finally out of school and making a semi-decent wage doesn't mean I should have to pay for other people.  I guess that means I am anti-socialism?  Is there maybe any other way that this could be accomplished?  Like just lessening the cost of college somehow instead of totally free?


&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27817801184.0" user="awa64" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the money for free college would come from taxes, correct? Does that mean that taxes would get raised or that he would just alter around the spending the government does? Because if taxes are going to get raised that means I have to pay for my own loans that are going to take 10 years plus extra taxes so people can go for free? That is not fair and while it seems nice, I don't have the money for that. Nor, I'm sure, do most Americans.

The specific proposal calls for a 00.5% (one half of one percent) tax on profits from trading stock, which would also be beneficial in stabilizing the economy by discouraging high-frequency trading. HFT is already widely viewed by economists as a form of "rent-seeking behavior," ways of accumulating wealth that do not actually generate additional value in the economy and are noted for driving income inequality.

Frankly, even if we don't use the money on college, we should still implement the tax.

Also, this proposal is coming at the same time as and largely paired with major pushes to lower interest rates on and forgive student loan debt. So your loans, if the proposals around this plan go forward, would become a lot less onerous too.

&amp;gt;And what happens with private institutions? Does that mean through my taxes I am paying for someone to go a $60,000 school when I couldn't go to one myself because I couldn't afford it?

No, the proposal would only cover tuition at public institutions, which already have tuition price limits they meet in exchange for federal funding. Bernie is not suggesting that we should pony up the $60k/quarter for attendance at expensive private universities like Columbia, University of Chicago, or Dartmouth.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
