<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197802628.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39rlhg/cmv_killing_baby_cows_for_food_is_no_more_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Killing baby cows for food is no more immoral than killing adult cows for food.</title>
    <original_poster>Arandur</original_poster>
    <original_post>Cows are neither sentient nor intelligent. They don't anticipate the future, they don't make plans, they're not moved to tears by bringing a new little cow life into the world. Given that killing animals for food is not generally immoral^1 ,  there is not such a great difference between the experience of a baby cow and an adult cow that one will experience death any differently than the other; neither is the life of a cow so rich and fulfilling^2 that it's immoral to deprive a baby cow of it before it dies.

Therefore, I should not feel any worse eating veal than I do eating a hamburger.

^1 If you disagree with this, that's a different argument entirely; I'm glad to hear your opinion on the matter, but you won't change my view unless your argument assumes this point.

^2 Just the opposite, presently; the lives of cows are full of pain and discomfort, because our (American) food-raising process is horrifying. I *do* think that this is unethical, just based on the principle that pain is a bad thing, but it's not a massive priority for me because I think the amount of human suffering is significantly greater at this time than the amount of animal suffering (due to the greater capacity of a human to experience suffering). Again, this isn't the topic of my CMV, but if you want to give your opinion on the matter I'd be glad to hear it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27824197965.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>I thought that the reason people don't eat veal is not because they are young but because the process of raising them to be veal is cruel. They are forced into pens where they are not allowed to move in order to keep the meat tender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824203289.0" user="Arandur" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, I guess, but then you get the problem where adult cows are in basically the same situation. It's not as if we raise our adult cows on plentiful green fields.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824206203.0" user="DHCKris" delta="False">
    <text>Don't we, though? At least, more often. I mean, comparatively, adult cows lead a much better quality of life. I am just explaining the reason I've heard people give for not eating veal. It is not just because they are young, like you assume.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824216000.0" user="Arandur" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose that does make sense, if it's true. The pictures the vegans show me of adult cows look pretty cruel too, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824537268.0" user="stevegcook" delta="False">
    <text>Bad it may be, but calves raised for veal still have it worse.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824568745.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Normal beef cattle move a fair bit. In fact freedom of movement and proper exercise is vital for proper marbling of the meat. It is rare for beef cattle to be crowded into small pens where they are not able to move. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824655055.0" user="Vorpal_Kitten" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but a fair bit of beef comes from dairy cows that are probably the pictures OP is talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27825060631.0" user="are_you_seriously" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, isn't wagyu/Kobe beef made from cows with limited movement and lots of feed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27825076759.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. The opposite. Kobe and Wagyu get a lot of exercise. They also get massages and sake.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27825176415.0" user="aardvarkious" delta="False">
    <text>Cows have a pretty shitty life in the slaughterhouse. But their life up until then is fine: lots of room to roam around in multiple pastures. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824654507.0" user="Vorpal_Kitten" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Don't we, though? At least, more often. I mean, comparatively, adult cows lead a much better quality of life.

Not really, no especially not if you're American. Though you're right in thinking that the reason people think veal is bad is often because they *think* veal calves have it way worse than the rest of the cows, even though in actuality they all have terrible lives</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824750183.0" user="richertai" delta="False">
    <text>Where are these horror farms?  I drive by huge green fields all the time, and the cows are just hanging out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824773384.0" user="WarOfIdeas" delta="False">
    <text>Where's your source on this? Farmers don't treat their cows like shit because it's unhealthy and all around idiotic practice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824861777.0" user="Vorpal_Kitten" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; source

Google? [Literally the first video that was listed for me](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GzS8p727gvM&amp;amp;t=6m45s)

If you're going to say random videos aren't representative, ask yourself why video cameras are banned on farms</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824882793.0" user="WarOfIdeas" delta="False">
    <text>First off, it's not my job to find support for someone else's point. This is just standard etiquette so don't act like I'm being lazy when the burden of proof was on the person making a claim. Besides, google isn't a source. It's what you use to find them, good or bad. You can find "support" for literally any position from google but that doesn't mean anything. This is why I want to discuss the issue with an actual person.
 
Second, those are dairy cows which are distinct from those you'd eat. Is that representative of beef cows? 

Third, I'm looking for statistics, not a video trying to go for emotional appeal. If you want to use the video as a source that's fine but you should extract some talking points from it and we can go from there point by point. For starters, is the footage taken from one location or many under different management? Basically, I'm looking for something to indicate this is a systematic and widespread issue rather than one bad egg. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824995280.0" user="Vorpal_Kitten" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Second, those are dairy cows which are distinct from those you'd eat

No, you eat dairy cows too...

Your other two points are good, but I don't want to look for statistics either, especially because I'm not sure they actually exist.

&amp;gt; For starters, is the footage taken from one location or many under different management? Basically, I'm looking for something to indicate this is a systematic and widespread issue rather than one bad egg. 

Right, exactly what one would want to do - but you can't get footage from any big meat company of actual conditions within their locations. They operate behind a veil of secrecy, which is often backed up by laws making it illegal to show any footage filmed there without consent, even if it's clearly showing violation of animal welfare laws. If the kinds of things you see in these video wasn't commonplace, wouldn't they just prove it by showing actual, commonplace conditions?

Here's a quote from the book eating animals, obviously outdated and somewhat anecdotal but possibly useful? If you don't know her Temple Grandin works with slaughterhouses to make them more humane.

&amp;gt; When Temple Grandin first began to quantify the scale of abuse in slaughterhouses, she reported witnessing “deliberate acts of cruelty occurring on a regular basis” at 32 percent of the plants she surveyed during announced visits in the United States. It’s such a shocking statistic I had to read it three times. Deliberate acts, occurring on a regular basis, witnessed by an auditor — witnessed during announced audits that gave the slaughterhouse time to clean up the worst problems. What about cruelties that weren’t witnessed? And what about accidents, which must have been far more common?
Grandin has emphasized that conditions have improved as more meat retailers demand slaughter audits from their suppliers, but how much? Reviewing the most recent audit of chicken slaughter conducted by the National Chicken Council, Grandin found that 26 percent of slaughterhouses had abuses so severe they should have failed. (The industry itself, disturbingly, found the audit results perfectly acceptable and gave all plants a pass even when live birds were thrown, tossed in the trash, and found scalded alive.) According to Grandin’s most recent survey of beef plants, fully 25 percent of the slaughterhouses had abuses so severe that they automatically failed her audit (“hanging a sensible animal on the rail” is given as a paradigmatic example of the kind of abuse that dictates an automatic failure). In recent surveys, Grandin witnessed a worker dismembering a fully conscious cow, cows waking up on the bleed rail, and workers “poking cows in the anus area with an electric prod.” What went on when she was not looking? And what about the vast majority of plants that don’t open their doors to audits in the first place?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824297882.0" user="HuntingtonPeach" delta="False">
    <text>I think moreso adult pigs are kept in pretty much the same conditions. Cows, at least in the US, are usually grass-fed until the time they are ready to be "finished," at which point they are transferred to feed lots and fattened up on grain and kept more confined for their final days. But I agree with your overall point that there is cruelty seen in raising any animal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824732004.0" user="elongated_smiley" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's not as if we raise our adult cows on plentiful green fields.

Depends on your food source. I only buy organic meat which involves the cows having more space and freedom throughout their lives. It's definitely possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824589699.0" user="Omnislip" delta="False">
    <text>This is actually illegal in EU countries - I don't know about he US but this practice is thankfully disappearing from large parts of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
