<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197802628.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39rlhg/cmv_killing_baby_cows_for_food_is_no_more_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Killing baby cows for food is no more immoral than killing adult cows for food.</title>
    <original_poster>Arandur</original_poster>
    <original_post>Cows are neither sentient nor intelligent. They don't anticipate the future, they don't make plans, they're not moved to tears by bringing a new little cow life into the world. Given that killing animals for food is not generally immoral^1 ,  there is not such a great difference between the experience of a baby cow and an adult cow that one will experience death any differently than the other; neither is the life of a cow so rich and fulfilling^2 that it's immoral to deprive a baby cow of it before it dies.

Therefore, I should not feel any worse eating veal than I do eating a hamburger.

^1 If you disagree with this, that's a different argument entirely; I'm glad to hear your opinion on the matter, but you won't change my view unless your argument assumes this point.

^2 Just the opposite, presently; the lives of cows are full of pain and discomfort, because our (American) food-raising process is horrifying. I *do* think that this is unethical, just based on the principle that pain is a bad thing, but it's not a massive priority for me because I think the amount of human suffering is significantly greater at this time than the amount of animal suffering (due to the greater capacity of a human to experience suffering). Again, this isn't the topic of my CMV, but if you want to give your opinion on the matter I'd be glad to hear it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27824351876.0" user="nosaJ4297" delta="False">
    <text>I actually agree with your statement in the title of this post, however i find your reasoning behind that statement to be quite weak.

You claim that cows cannot anticipate the future and plan for it, but i see no reason to believe this. I have been around enough cows to see that they are very intelligent animals, so i would think that they have at least a basic ability to expect certain things to happen in the future.

EDIT: someone called me out on that last paragraph, saying i'm using the same logic i'm arguing against (OP claimed cows arent intelligent with no evidence, i responded by saying they are solely based on personal experience). So i found a paper about a study on cow intelligence. [Here's] (http://www.appliedanimalbehaviour.com/article/S0168-1591%2803%2900294-6/abstract) the link. TL;DR cows can associate certain actions with food.

You also say that they are not moved to tears when a calf is born. This may be true, but that does not mean that cows do not have an emotional attachment to their calves. In the meat and dairy industry, it is common practice for newborn calves to be taken away from the mother as soon as a day after birth. There are many recordings on youtube of the resulting screams that occur when the calf is taken from its mother. And listening to those recordings, it is very obvious that there is an emotional attachment between a cow and her calf.

Cows are very social animals, and there are many complex relationships involved in a herd of cows. [This article] (http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/016815919090125W) goes over the results of a study on the eating habits of a herd of cows, and how changes to their social groups effected how they eat. Cows are both sentient and intelligent, and because of this, i agree with you. It is equally as horrible to eat a calf as it is to eat a fully grown cow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824514402.0" user="nowonmai" delta="False">
    <text>You realise that after criticising OP's reasoning that you state as fact that cows are sentient and intelligent, based on nothing more than "I have spent time with cows".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824619722.0" user="LewsTherinT" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think he needs to have a source, to state as fact, that cows are sentient and contain a degree of intelligence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824661550.0" user="Vorpal_Kitten" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need strong evidence to support such a non extraordinary claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27825075495.0" user="nosaJ4297" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I agree with you. I am using the same logic I'm trying to disprove. Thanks for calling me out on this one.

So I did a bit of research into it, to find more evidence than just personal experience. [Here's] (http://www.appliedanimalbehaviour.com/article/S0168-1591%2803%2900294-6/abstract) what I found. This article shows the results of a study on the intelligence of cows. A group of 12 cows were trained to press a panel to open a gate, giving them access to food. When these cows opened the gate, another cow in the control group would also gain access to some food. Between the gate and the food, there was a 15 meter path the cows had to walk. The heart rate of the cows were monitored, and it was observed that the cows which had to open the gate had a higher heart rate than the cows which did not need to work for their food, and the cows that had to work for their food also tended to run towards the food quicker than the other cows.

So this study shows us two things about the intelligence of cows. First, cows are able to associate certain actions, such as opening a gate, with a reward like food. They will then learn how to do what is necessary to get the food.

Second, we learn from this that cows are able to make the connection between their actions and the reward. The cows that had to work for the food moved towards it faster than the cows who were given food, which means that the cows may value the food more because of the work required it for it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
