<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="197802628.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/39rlhg/cmv_killing_baby_cows_for_food_is_no_more_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Killing baby cows for food is no more immoral than killing adult cows for food.</title>
    <original_poster>Arandur</original_poster>
    <original_post>Cows are neither sentient nor intelligent. They don't anticipate the future, they don't make plans, they're not moved to tears by bringing a new little cow life into the world. Given that killing animals for food is not generally immoral^1 ,  there is not such a great difference between the experience of a baby cow and an adult cow that one will experience death any differently than the other; neither is the life of a cow so rich and fulfilling^2 that it's immoral to deprive a baby cow of it before it dies.

Therefore, I should not feel any worse eating veal than I do eating a hamburger.

^1 If you disagree with this, that's a different argument entirely; I'm glad to hear your opinion on the matter, but you won't change my view unless your argument assumes this point.

^2 Just the opposite, presently; the lives of cows are full of pain and discomfort, because our (American) food-raising process is horrifying. I *do* think that this is unethical, just based on the principle that pain is a bad thing, but it's not a massive priority for me because I think the amount of human suffering is significantly greater at this time than the amount of animal suffering (due to the greater capacity of a human to experience suffering). Again, this isn't the topic of my CMV, but if you want to give your opinion on the matter I'd be glad to hear it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27824629490.0" user="twinsocks" delta="False">
    <text>Even if we say killing for food isn't generally immoral, do you think that extinguishing more lives is more immoral than extinguishing less lives? For instance, killing a cow for 1 steak is more immoral than killing a cow for 20 steaks?

Baby cows are little, so I suppose you could at least argue that you have a less meat-to-lives-taken ratio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27824726156.0" user="Arandur" delta="False">
    <text>That was in fact the argument that swayed me, yes. To be clear: killing an animal generates disutility, but eating the animal creates far more utility, therefore the system as a whole is not immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27825066420.0" user="deusset" delta="False">
    <text>That depends on how you account for externalities, which many would assert render meat production grossly inefficient. I'm going to leave this here (I'm on mobile now) in the hope that I'll come back with evidence later. 

In the meantime, maybe /u/friendlyelephant has some handy. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
