<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828840264.0" user="Diabolico" delta="False">
    <text>Someone correct me if I'm wrong, but when bitcoin hits the 21 million cap, isn't it going to begin taxing itself to provide incentives to the miners to keep up the distributed network that manages the transactions?

If that's right, then bitcoin will actually be eternally inflationary, bu instead of that inflation taking the form of your units of currency having less purchasing power, it will instead literally be sapping currency passively from everyone's wallet, which is a major disincentive to sitting on your cash forever.

If it doesn't work that way... maybe we should invent one that does?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829212863.0" user="Kingreaper" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't work like that. I believe there is a cryptocoin that does, but I can't remember which one.

Bitcoin is designed to continue paying the miners by having transaction fees, charging people for every transfer of money.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
