<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828353394.0" user="omrakt" delta="False">
    <text>I can't seriously argue that Bitcoin will become the most widely used currency at this point, but I disagree with your argument regarding deflation.

What you say would only hold true if the rate of deflation generated a return greater than alternate investments. If you want a guaranteed return on your investment, you could invest in something like treasury bonds, super safe but super low returns, or you could put it in a start-up where you get the inverse effect. Depending on adversity to risk, people will invest in myriad different areas. Clearly it isn't simply the case that guaranteed return = hoarding.

Additionally, you may have a point if there were only 21 million coins possible, as that would present some obvious issues (less bitcoins than actual people), but here you are mistaken. Because the coins are divisible down to 8 decimal places, the actual theoretical amount of bitcoin 'units' would be around 2 quadrillion. Quite a bit more than what you asserted. The current amount of USD in circulation is, by comparison, only $1.3 trillion. Divided to the smallest amount (a penny), that would mean a total of 130 trillion units of US currency, or 1500 times less than the number of bitcoin units.

The currency is new and highly volatile. Until things stabilize, I don't think we can make any definitive claims one way or the other. That being said, the very fact that volatility exists rebuffs your claim on guaranteed investment. There are a lot of factors that affect the price of bitcoin, and you just can't predict where it will be at any given time in the future, anymore than I can predict what Apple stock will be worth a year from now. 

I hope I've shown why deflation won't necessarily lead to hoarding as you suggest. At the least, I hope I've demonstrated why you aren't justified in your current position.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828366856.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What you say would only hold true if the rate of deflation generated a return greater than alternate investments. If you want a guaranteed return on your investment, you could invest in something like treasury bonds, super safe but super low returns, or you could put it in a start-up where you get the inverse effect. Depending on adversity to risk, people will invest in myriad different areas. Clearly it isn't simply the case that guaranteed return = hoarding.

Some people might still invest, that is true, but a deflationary envoirment still discourages investment and spending.

&amp;gt;Additionally, you may have a point if there were only 21 million coins possible, as that would present some obvious issues (less bitcoins than actual people), but here you are mistaken. Because the coins are divisible down to 8 decimal places, the actual theoretical amount of bitcoin 'units' would be around 2 quadrillion. Quite a bit more than what you asserted. The current amount of USD in circulation is, by comparison, only $1.3 trillion. Divided to the smallest amount (a penny), that would mean a total of 130 trillion units of US currency, or 1500 times less than the number of bitcoin units.

I just claimed that there would be a maximum of (actually slightly less then) 21 million actual Bitcoins. Not units of Bitcoin currency. And I never claimed loss of liquidity from deflation was aproblem, but the deflation itself.

&amp;gt;The currency is new and highly volatile. Until things stabilize, I don't think we can make any definitive claims one way or the other. 

For now, yes. But if one most of the world economy would run on Bitcoin, and there was no way of introducing new currency, then deflation is the logical conclusion.

&amp;gt;That being said, the very fact that volatility exists rebuffs your claim on guaranteed investment. There are a lot of factors that affect the price of bitcoin, and you just can't predict where it will be at any given time in the future, anymore than I can predict what Apple stock will be worth a year from now. 

True, because at the moment it is a speculative investment, not currency. If it were to ever become currency, it would behave more predictably.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
