<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828489773.0" user="skinbearxett" delta="False">
    <text>The deflationary nature is one possible issue in a sense, but it is self regulating. If one person holds on to a bunch of currency everything balances out using the remaining currency. The individual could theoretically payout into external currency after deflation and make a profit, but when they do this someone else will shortly do the exact same thing. This is not a short term strategy, it requires patience and time. 

When you invest money in something you are making a sacrifice of not investing it elsewhere, an idea known as opportunity cost. If deflationary growth could be used it would have to outperform other options to be worthwhile. Would it be more than a few percent per year? In the short term, maybe. When more money runs through bitcoin this will become less and less of an issue as it will be less viable to do this buy and hold strategy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828511801.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When you invest money in something you are making a sacrifice of not investing it elsewhere, an idea known as opportunity cost. If deflationary growth could be used it would have to outperform other options to be worthwhile.

It still disincentivizes not investing over investing. In other words, where do you think people have more pressure to invest? Somewhere with 1% inflation or 1% deflation? Sure, some might still invest in deflationland, but not as many as in inflationland.

&amp;gt; Would it be more than a few percent per year? In the short term, maybe. When more money runs through bitcoin this will become less and less of an issue as it will be less viable to do this buy and hold strategy. 

That's the problem. Once, in 2100 or so basically no new coins will be mined, the supply of Bitcoins will drop through losses, while the number of goods and services (barring some huge disaster) will increase. Result? Inflation, easily a few per cent per year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828553562.0" user="skinbearxett" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I don't know about the rate, assuming that most people have a single wallet they use most of the time, and assuming that backup systems get better over time, I would expect there to be less loss over time. That said, 1% is a shitty gain for a year. 

http://polarisfinancialplanning.com/polaris-blog/

There's some info there about recent market returns. Have a peek and think about whether you think bitcoin deflation will match that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829686612.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There's some info there about recent market returns. Have a peek and think about whether you think bitcoin deflation will match that.

Irrelevant. It doesn't have to be the best possible investment for some people to do it anyway. There are already people sitting on money. The more profitable it becomes, the more people do it. This is not something I just came up with, this basically is happening in germany right now.

http://blogs.wsj.com/moneybeat/2014/08/19/germany-set-to-issue-at-0-as-investors-seek-refuge/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829736039.0" user="skinbearxett" delta="False">
    <text>Its not about whether some people do it, its about whether it will be enough to be influential. To influence a market you have to have significant sway over the market in the form of something like lots of capital, control over supply or demand, or some other mechanism. People who have enough money to be influential don't get that way by making bad choices, they get there by either luck or good choices. If luck, sure, they may make the bad decision here and invest poorly. If good choices, they won't make this bad choice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829741909.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;its about whether it will be enough to be influential.

Well if it is enough to buy all these 0% bonds germany is selling, I would say that is enough to negatively impact the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828620156.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It still disincentivizes not investing over investing.

I do not understanding what exactly makes this worrying. People will still need food, a home, a car, a phone, education, entertainment, etc. So naturally if demand exist there will also be someone to fill that demand. If people prefer holding money over buying something it would mean they don't really need that something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829689618.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I do not understanding what exactly makes this worrying.

Because if you disincenitive something, less people do it. And in an economy, you want as many people as possible to invest and spend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828824299.0" user="ThyReaper2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It still disincentivizes not investing over investing. In other words, where do you think people have more pressure to invest? Somewhere with 1% inflation or 1% deflation? Sure, some might still invest in deflationland, but not as many as in inflationland.

How does it impact investing? If you get a 7% interest rate per year on an investment, it doesn't matter whether you have deflation or inflation, you still get 7% more currency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829719306.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How does it impact investing?

Is it really so hard to understand? The better the investment, the more people make that investment. The better hoarding money becomes as an investment, the less people invest in other things. It doesn't have to beat every investment in the world for that to be true.

&amp;gt;If you get a 7% interest rate per year on an investment, it doesn't matter whether you have deflation or inflation, you still get 7% more currency.

Where in the world can you get a secure 7% annual return nowadays? Cause I want in on that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829752482.0" user="ThyReaper2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The better hoarding money becomes as an investment, the less people invest in other things.

An investment would return more money than you put in (on average). Hoarding money would result in no change in the amount of money. Either way, you have more purchasing power after a successful investment.

&amp;gt; Where in the world can you get a secure 7% annual return nowadays? Cause I want in on that.

Illustrative figures are not intended as an investment guide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829762304.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;An investment would return more money than you put in (on average). Hoarding money would result in no change in the amount of money. Either way, you have more purchasing power after a successful investment.

Yes, but there is some risk involved in that. Now some investors are okay with some risk, some almost seek it out, and some want to avoid it as much as possible.

In a deflationary enviorment, many people of the latter group will haord money.

If you were right, how could germany ever sell 0% interest 2-year bonds?

http://blogs.wsj.com/moneybeat/2014/08/19/germany-set-to-issue-at-0-as-investors-seek-refuge/

&amp;gt;Illustrative figures are not intended as an investment guide.

In that case, I retroactively change my example deflation rate to 10%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829790327.0" user="ThyReaper2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you were right, how could germany ever sell 0% interest 2-year bonds?

I honestly can't figure out why anyone would buy 0% interest bonds. They're paying 1 euro to receive 1 euro 2 years later. I guess they just wanted to donate some money to Germany for a bit in return for risk?

Looks like they may be purchased below the face value?

&amp;gt; In that case, I retroactively change my example deflation rate to 10%.

Which doesn't change the situation. If I have $100 now which can buy a single sofa, but in 7 years it could buy two sofas, I can still invest it in the meantime to end up with $171 capable of buying more than three sofas.

Now, debtors would have some problems. The real cost of their debt will grow with deflation on top of needing to provide competitive returns to be worth investing in. High deflation rates would make it prohibitively expensive to hold debt for any significant length of time. Only negative interest rates would compensate, but retaining money would win out over any such loan. In such a situation, I can only imagine the federal government would need to provide those loans to sustain growth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829793676.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Which doesn't change the situation. If I have $100 now which can buy a single sofa, but in 7 years it could buy two sofas, I can still invest it in the meantime to end up with $171 capable of buying more than three sofas.

Yeah, but you need an investment, that in real terms more than triples your value. Good luck with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829795271.0" user="ThyReaper2" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you completely ignore the content of my posts at this point. Oh well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
