<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828776574.0" user="athanathios" delta="False">
    <text>Don't confuse, fair value with inflationary or deflationary pressure on currencies, which are related to long term interest rates and inflationary rates more precisely. With fixed supply and increasing productivity in the world (i.e. GDP increasing all the time), then the value of Goods in the world are fixed and the currency therefore would gain value and would create inflationary. In the case of Fiat currencies unless the amount of Money Supply growth is greater than the increase in GDP, assuming fair value.

However currencies are seldom fully values and long term misvaluations sometimes persist for years. This is because some currencies are preferred over others (because of what they can buy or what entities need the currencies for), some are held as they are riskier or less riskier than others, while other give a way for investor to get economic benefits from the country issuing the currency.

Fiat currencies are a different creature in that they usually have a floating supply and are guaranteed as legal tender by the issuer. Bitcoins, despite being a currency, lacks a political backing and is subject to political risk. So it's not a fair comparison, per-se to fiat currencies like the USD.

If anything Bitcoins will become inflationary with a fixed float as their scarcity and fixed supply will cause global GDP to increase relative the fixed float growth of zero causing inflationary pressure on the currency, this is why Gold goes up in value because of it's scarcity. People speculating on the currency taking long positions would cause the currency to be subject to more inflationary pressure actually if anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829736082.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I read this three times and still have no clue what you're talking about. Can you dumb it down a little?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829770949.0" user="athanathios" delta="False">
    <text>Basically scarcity drives price grow, so if there is less currency and the value of the asset goes up, which is the value of what it trades or represents, then the pressure is inflationary or expansive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829776012.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>So deflation causes inflation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829778044.0" user="athanathios" delta="False">
    <text>Deflation is when the currency loses value, there is no value, with normal growth patterns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829781986.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Deflation is when the currency loses value

No, deflation is when currency *gains* value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829784899.0" user="athanathios" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking cross currency here, relative value, say compared to USD.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829790394.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>So if the price of Bitcoins in USD goes up, people are going to sell Bitcoins for USD, causing the price of Bitcoins to drop?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
