<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27832700773.0" user="saibog38" delta="False">
    <text>I've commented about the differences (and more importantly, the similarities) between inflationary and deflationary monetary systems before in response to similar questions about the deflationary bitcoin, so I'll just link to them [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/1p5w6o/would_you_ever_take_out_a_loan_denominated_in/ccz4op5) and [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/202x5b/one_concern_ive_never_been_able_to_shake_about/cfzlnpe).

A TL;DR - they're not nearly as different as people think they are; the main differences between a fixed supply currency (like bitcoin) and a managed, inflationary supply currency backed by sovereign debt (like the Dollar) is that in the latter there exists an entity (the central bank) with unilateral influence over interest rates, as well as the ability to "bail out" an unsustainable credit bubble by debasing the base monetary unit.  If you think the central bank knows better than the market, that's a good thing.  If you don't, it's not.  That's honestly the only big difference, and the whole notion that one incentivizes spending and the other does not is a misunderstanding that's pretty easy to clear up if you compare the systems directly *while accounting for the differences between nominal values and real values* (that's where most people slip up).  The main point to understanding this is that in an inflationary monetary system, the role of "saving" (or "hoarding" if you want to make it sound bad) is fulfilled by the debt of the currency issuer - in the case of the Dollar, that's US treasury bills/notes/bonds (i.e. US debt).  A currency issuer doesn't borrow their own currency because they need to (think about that), but rather they "borrow" because people need to be able to save (sit on it, hoard it, whatever you want to call it) the currency in order to give it stability and value.  All that is explained in more detail in my links above.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
