<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828320437.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're forgetting about being able to create Bitcoins. You seem smart enough to know that you can set up your computer to farm and make Bitcoins and there are super computers around the world that are doing this. So yeah some money will disappear due to various things, but deflation isn't a logical thing to worry about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828322418.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>I know that, but if I understood it correctly, there is a hard limit of 21 million Bitcoins that can ever exist. Meaning, if all of them get created, that's it, no more Bitcoins ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828330752.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not that well versed in this, so I can't be relied on too much, but I imagine that if deflation was ever becoming a problem, one of the benefits is how easily Bitcoin can be manipulated, meaning I bet they would find the number of stagnant bitcoins and adjust the limits based on that.

But like I said, I don't know if that's even possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828333457.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>It is technically possible, but unless I'm mistaken it would need the consent of everyone using bitcoin. Which needlessly to say is impossible to achieve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828338394.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's true, the US Govt doesn't need the permission of everyone using their money to manipulate their currency. It may need the consent from a few different national govts. but I'm really not sure. I really just don't know enough about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828353476.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that state-issued currency doesn't rely on people downloading their software. Also Bitcoin is entirely decentrelized, there simply isn't any one person who can decide to change how it works now, even its creators.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828365125.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>Something tells me they won't need a 100% acceptance of the potential rule changes. I also don't think as much of the currency is going to stay stagnant as you think it might. If we were reliant on cryptocurrency, people wouldn't just let $200 sit in an account that wasn't used, and if they do, oh well. The losses would be negligible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828374897.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Something tells me they won't need a 100% acceptance of the potential rule changes.

True, but I don't think you could get even a majority of users to accept effectively lowering the value of their money. Especially among people who seem to think that Inflation is the devil himself.

&amp;gt; I also don't think as much of the currency is going to stay stagnant as you think it might. If we were reliant on cryptocurrency, people wouldn't just let $200 sit in an account that wasn't used, and if they do, oh well. The losses would be negligible.

People lose valuable things all the time. It was the same when gold and silver where the currency, and it will stay the same if its 1s and 0s. If not mining in the ancient world would have inevitably lead to deavaluation of these metals. Instead Rome fell partly because its best silver mines began to dry up.

Even if nobody ever lost anything, the total ammount of goods and services in existence will (hopefully) continue to grow, and you need more currency to accomodate that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828402662.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>Well the difference is people would literally lose or destroy their money. Cryptocurrencies don't get lost.

Maybe there could be an expiration date on bitcoins? Like "use before..."? That seems to me to be the most practical solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828408456.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well the difference is people would literally lose or destroy their money.

Which People have been doing for as long as money existed.

&amp;gt;Cryptocurrencies don't get lost.

Yes. Yes they do. 

http://www.coinbuzz.com/2015/03/31/23-bitcoins-mined-13-may-lost/

&amp;gt;Maybe there could be an expiration date on bitcoins? Like "use before..."? That seems to me to be the most practical solution.

Again, you would be basically asking people to devalue their own currency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828390596.0" user="NablaNabla" delta="False">
    <text>You can rather easily lose access to your bitcoins permanently if you delete/lose your wallet private key or forget a passphrase to it. Then there is literally no way the lost money could ever come back in circulation. Something like this would only happen with hard money if you drop your wallet in a river or something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828421616.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying you think *more* cryptocurrency would get lost than hard cash?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828425391.0" user="NablaNabla" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have any actual numbers, but I wanted to show that it is unwise to presume the opposite without checking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828469317.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>Well now that Bitcoin has proven to hold some value, I just think less people will forget their passwords than more dollar bills falling into a river. Someone posted a link earlier about how I think it said 1/3 of Bitcoin hasn't moved since it's purchase. I think this is due to people buying it 5 years ago that haven't given it another thought (or got locked out of their accounts)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828377156.0" user="NablaNabla" delta="False">
    <text>It is technically impossible to enforce a protocol change like increase of bitcoins without every single user agreeing on it (e.g. by installing a client update). This is an important feature of bitcoin, as it becomes almost impossible for a minority, even with huge political influence, to manipulate the currency.
In practice it would probably be enough to get a large fraction of bitcoin owners to change protocol, a small remaining minority would then be forced to accept the change, too, if they don't want to lose the value of their coins.
If users cannot agree upon a protocol change, then eventually the bitcoin blockchain would split into two, with the one fraction of users using the old chain and the other fraction using the new one. Effectively you then have two different incompatible bitcoin currencies. But it would be unlikely for both to remain stable I guess. Either one of them would ultimately dominate or the both lose their users in the chaos that would follow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828388351.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>This makes Bitcoin sound pretty unusable, no? Sounds like an enormous flaw</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828399980.0" user="NablaNabla" delta="False">
    <text>I think it is intentional, although there probably wasn't enough thought made into the necessity for protocol updates during the initial development of bitcoin.
It makes it possible to use bitcoins without having to trust any single person/entity. A government can neither take your money, nor can it artificially devalue it by increase of money supply.
I don't know details though, just some basics about how the system works in principle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828447444.0" user="pdeluc99" delta="False">
    <text>Well it sounds like Bitcoin was a good place to start, but it either needs to be modified to better suit this economy or get replaced by a more dynamic cryptocurrency</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
