<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828749539.0" user="optroot" delta="False">
    <text>I actually agree with your stance but for other reasons. The number of BTC can change using loans and bonds (essentially using BTC credits, that aren't actual BTC) - this can essentially make the number of BTC boundless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829722433.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;this can essentially make the number of BTC boundless.

Aren't there limits on fractional reserves the banks must actually hold?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829760296.0" user="optroot" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but this doesn't *have* to be the case in a BTC society, we could put the limit where-ever. Repayments can be made with BTC credits essentially adding more BTC to the market.

For example, 10 BTC bond pays 10 BTC + 1BTC', I guarantee anyone who really wants can exchange 1BTC' for 1BTC, and just hope that not everyone decides to do it and accepts they are equivalent (like the gold standard).

EDIT: changed * to ' because italics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829766111.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>What do you do then if for some reason enough people run to the banks to deplete the reserves? 

&amp;gt;I guarantee anyone who really wants can exchange 1BTC for 1BTC, and just hope that not everyone decides to do it and accepts they are equivalent (like the gold standard).

What if they don't? Isn't the entire point of bitcoin that you don't have to trust in some institution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829775682.0" user="optroot" delta="False">
    <text>If everyone runs to the bank to exchange, you're basically fucked. But why would anyone do this? You wouldn't gain anything except anarchy. This is how money was introduced in the first place, allowing money to be redeemed for gold. It worked then.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829780263.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is how money was introduced in the first place, allowing money to be redeemed for gold. It worked then.

Because banks had to keep ceirtain percentages as a reserve. I don't think it would have been successful if every bank has just one small chunk of gold.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
