<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27828447640.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>BitCoin isn't *really* deflationary any more than gold was.  Sure, there's a limited amount out there while the economy expands.  But here's the thing: if everyone expects the price to rise in the future, it rises immediately instead.  If I know there's some potential investment (bitcoin, gold, Matisse, whatever) that is going to be worth 50% more in a decade than this year, I'm interested in buying it (even at a premium) and uninterested in selling it (even at a premium).  So is everyone else.  Which means that item is actually worth 40% more overnight.  It goes up in price to a level where as many people think it's heading down (relative to T-bonds anyway) as think it's heading up.  At that price I can find people to sell it to me, and/or people willing to buy it from me.

So no - people don't all sit on their money just because there's a limited amount.  Instead, the price jumps to such a point that some people think it's a good investment while others think it's a crummy investment.  There's the new pricepoint and the people who think it's a crummy investment buy search engines and hospitals and such instead.

There is a thing called a deflationary spiral, and it requires one of two situations: a bad economy (where the deflation is a symptom rather than a cause) or government policy.  It doesn't just happen purely because there's a limited amount of gold/bitcoins/whatever currency in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828499935.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;BitCoin isn't really deflationary any more than gold was.

Which it was. Very much so, in fact the gold standard led to several periods of deflation, and some economists even think that that caused the great depression. That's why the gold standard was eventually abadnoned.

&amp;gt; Sure, there's a limited amount out there while the economy expands. But here's the thing: if everyone expects the price to rise in the future, it rises immediately instead. If I know there's some potential investment (bitcoin, gold, Matisse, whatever) that is going to be worth 50% more in a decade than this year, I'm interested in buying it (even at a premium) and uninterested in selling it (even at a premium). So is everyone else. Which means that item is actually worth 40% more overnight. It goes up in price to a level where as many people think it's heading down (relative to T-bonds anyway) as think it's heading up. At that price I can find people to sell it to me, and/or people willing to buy it from me.

If that were true, why did the US Dollar go through multiple sustained periods of deflation when it still had the gold standard? In reality, these changes in price don't happen overnight. There are price corrections, recorrections, over- and undercorrections all the time. And that whole time you have the economy suffering the effects of deflation, which are pretty well established.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828626720.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Which it was. Very much so, in fact the gold standard led to several periods of deflation, and some economists even think that that caused the great depression. That's why the gold standard was eventually abadnoned.

I don't agree.  First off, there were certainly a few periods of deflation and depressions under the gold standard - but there have been plenty without it.  *Perhaps* there's a higher proportion with or without it, but if so that's because the government has less control over monetary policy.  Not purely because "everyone knows" gold will become more valuable.

We didn't abandon the gold standard because it was deflationary, we abandoned it so the government could more easily pay its debts.

Consider: right now, I am deciding where to put my money.  I can invest it in Apple, in a new startup, in dollars, in bitcoins, or in physical gold.  For there to be investment, that investment doesn't just have to beat dollars in expected return.  It has to beat commodities as well.  So if gold and bitcoin are inherently deflationary, it literally shouldn't matter whether those are our official currency.  It should only matter whether I can successfully buy/sell it.  Which I can.

&amp;gt;If that were true, why did the US Dollar go through multiple sustained periods of deflation when it still had the gold standard?

Deflation is always possible.  What is impossible is predictable deflation without government intervention.  If everyone knows gold will go up, it goes up immediately.  But if people don't know whether gold will go up/down, it can certainly go up.  It can go up every day for a decade, with some investors thinking it'll go up forever and others wonder when the bubble will pop.  And those will invest in other things.

&amp;gt;And that whole time you have the economy suffering the effects of deflation, which are pretty well established.

Certainly deflation can be a symptom of a depression.  That's different.  If it were really cause/effect, why would it matter whether the object increasing in value were a currency, a commodity, or an equity?  If there's one investment that's magically known to be better than all other investments, it would attract all the investment capital regardless of whether it were the currency of the realm or not.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829710424.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Consider: right now, I am deciding where to put my money. I can invest it in Apple, in a new startup, in dollars, in bitcoins, or in physical gold. For there to be investment, that investment doesn't just have to beat dollars in expected return. It has to beat commodities as well. So if gold and bitcoin are inherently deflationary, it literally shouldn't matter whether those are our official currency. It should only matter whether I can successfully buy/sell it. Which I can.

If everyone in the world were a savvy investor maybe. But the average guy just knows that that car he is looking to buy costs 20000$ now, but that guy on TV said it might cost only 19000$ in a few months, so he will hold off on purchasing it.

And of course deflation can lead to fears of a deflationary spiral, reinforcing itself.

&amp;gt;Certainly deflation can be a symptom of a depression.

Most mainstream economists seem to believe it can be a cause as well. From the wikipedia article on deflation:

&amp;gt;Economists generally believe that deflation is a problem in a modern economy because it increases the real value of debt, and may aggravate recessions and lead to a deflationary spiral.

&amp;gt;If it were really cause/effect, why would it matter whether the object increasing in value were a currency, a commodity, or an equity?

Because people buying stock or goods or gold isn't bad for the economy. In all these cases you are buying things. You don't really buy money, you just exchange it, which does no good for the economy.

&amp;gt;If there's one investment that's magically known to be better than all other investments

I never claimed anything like that. Just that the better the investment, the more people make it. And if that investment is money, that is bad for the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27830281203.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If everyone in the world were a savvy investor maybe. But the average guy just knows that that car he is looking to buy costs 20000$ now, but that guy on TV said it might cost only 19000$ in a few months, so he will hold off on purchasing it.

There are certainly people on AM talk radio telling you gold is deflationary and a great safe investment.  I wouldn't call the people who believe them "savvy investors".  I'd say the savvy investors admit they don't know whether gold is going up or down.

But if your concern is merely denomination/psychology, that's fixable.  All you need to do is put a "wrapper" on the bitcoin currency like the URV ("Real Unit of Value") in Brazil in the 1990s.  Prices were listed in the actual currency (the Cruzeiro) and in URVs that indicated a continually-increasing number of Cruzeiros.  People saw that prices/wages were relatively stable in URVs, and regained confidence.

So if we create a "wrapper" like the URV, backed by bitcoin, then people won't be thinking in terms of decreasing prices.  And Bitcoin (despite providing the nuts and bolts of the currency) would just be one more commodity people can speculate in like gold is today.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27830307696.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But if your concern is merely denomination/psychology, that's fixable.

It's not just psychology, currency is inherently different from other forms of investments because we use it almost exclusively (that is to say except in the case of barter) to exchange and measure value. The dollar going up in value is something different from oil or gas or apples going up in value, because it by definition affects the entire economy.

&amp;gt; All you need to do is put a "wrapper" on the bitcoin currency like the URV ("Real Unit of Value") in Brazil in the 1990s. Prices were listed in the actual currency (the Cruzeiro) and in URVs that indicated a continually-increasing number of Cruzeiros. People saw that prices/wages were relatively stable in URVs, and regained confidence.

&amp;gt;So if we create a "wrapper" like the URV, backed by bitcoin, then people won't be thinking in terms of decreasing prices.

The URV was really only a stopgap measure to deal with the effects of hyperinflation, and it was soon replaced with an entirely new currency, the Real. If you were to make such a wrapper permanent, there would be more problems with that than I can bother writing down.

&amp;gt; And Bitcoin (despite providing the nuts and bolts of the currency) would just be one more commodity people can speculate in like gold is today.

But you if people treat your currency as a speculative investment, it makes for a bad currency, even with a wrapper.

Example:

I have a guitar teacher in my area that only accepts bitcoin. Fair enough, each lesson is 30 $ I think, so I just change 30 of my $ into bitcoin the day before and go there. Except the bitcoins are now worth only 25$ because some investment bubble burst. Even if the URV stays the same, I now don't have enough bitcoin to pay the guy.

If someone who usually uses Bitcoin and has a guitar teacher who does not, you have the same problem if the price suddenly spikes.

If you hold currency, you need some confidence that it won't drasticly change value overnight. You can call it "just psychology", but in the end you could call all of economy that, and this confidence just is something we need for a stable and working economy.

As another example, my father is receiving a pension in €, but living in Australia. Of course he watches the course like a hawk, but all things considered I can be pretty sure that neither will he be out on the street tommorow, nor will someone have to sponsor him living like a King.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27830377199.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's not just psychology, currency is inherently different from other forms of investments because we use it almost exclusively (that is to say except in the case of barter) to exchange and measure value. The dollar going up in value is something different from oil or gas or apples going up in value, because it by definition affects the entire economy.

I can't say I agree here.  Oil affects every bit of the economy that relies on transportation or energy.  Dollars affect every bit of the economy that relies on contracts that have been denominated in dollars.  Those are about equal in size right now, but the trend has been towards more hedging/futures/foreign currency denominated transactions.  If we were just talking apples or gold, I'd agree dollars are more important.  Energy will probably be more important than dollars in the future. 

&amp;gt;The URV was really only a stopgap measure to deal with the effects of hyperinflation, and it was soon replaced with an entirely new currency, the Real.

Agreed.

&amp;gt;If you were to make such a wrapper permanent, there would be more problems with that than I can bother writing down.

Give me the top 3?  As near as I can tell, the big deal would just be that we'd have a backed currency instead of an unbacked one.  That gives the government less power to manage the economy.  Which is a bad thing if your government is doing a good job and a good thing if your government is doing a bad job.  It's easy to imagine the Fed becoming a political instrument like so many other government branches have and as a result doing a worse job than a backed currency.

Or is your worry that we'd have bigger currency fluctuations than we already have?  I think they'd be about the same for the dollar, and less fluctuations than with less stable currencies.

&amp;gt;But you if people treat your currency as a speculative investment, it makes for a bad currency

People speculate on currency all the time.  If your guitar teacher example is a common problem, I'd never take out bitcoins except at the moment of payment.  I'd transfer $30 to him at that point, and who cares if it's "really" $29.90 or $30.10?  (Obviously the larger the size of the currency and the more speculators, the more stability you end up with.  Thus dollars:gold hasn't been more prone to fluctuations than dollars:euro).

&amp;gt;If you hold currency, you need some confidence that it won't drastically change value overnight.

Sure, absolutely.  That's a minor advantage of backed currencies over unbacked.  We hope/assume that there won't be some QE7 that tanks the dollar.  We know that couldn't happen with a backed currency.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828553564.0" user="lawrencekraussquotes" delta="False">
    <text>The thing that I have a hard time wrapping my head is the idea of scarcity to a precious mineral like gold. It's obviously more scarce than printed money, but isn't mined all the time? No one investing considers the fact that one day there may not be any new gold being pulled of the ground. Wouldn't that have significant repercussions on the gold market? I feel like this is analogous to when bitcoin reaches the limit of 21 million coins, that it's going to have strange effects based on the perspective of investors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27828634209.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The thing that I have a hard time wrapping my head is the idea of scarcity to a precious mineral like gold. It's obviously more scarce than printed money, but isn't mined all the time? 

Well, you have to look at the marginal cost of mining an additional ounce.  If the rate at which it is mined cannot be profitably increased without a large jump in valuation, and the increase in demand per year exceeds the increase in supply per year...

I don't think a hard limit has special effects.  I think it's more an issue of the rate of increase of supply vs the rate of increase of demand.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
