<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27830179950.0" user="UnfairAdult" delta="False">
    <text>In a sense, we *already* live in a deflationary economy.

Most of the world's wealth is not held in the form of cash. 

Cash is only a short-term intermediate.

A typical investment decision is not a choice between leaving $1M of cash on your savings account and lending it to company X where you will get a 3% return.

It's usually a choice between selling some stocks/bonds/real estate and buying OTHER stocks/bonds/real estate.

Those things are of fixed supply and increasing value just like bitcoin.

Whether the cash intermediate has positive or negative inflation doesn't really matter if you only hold on to it for a short time. What matters is its liquidity and convenience and Bitcoin could potentially excel in those areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27830237867.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Most of the world's wealth is not held in the form of cash. 

cash =!= currency. I don't have any statistics, but I bet a huge chunk of the worlds wealth is held in some form of currency.

&amp;gt;It's usually a choice between selling some stocks/bonds/real estate and buying OTHER stocks/bonds/real estate.

&amp;gt;Those things are of fixed supply and increasing value just like bitcoin.

Not really. The stocks of one individual company may have limited supply, but new companies get created all the time. New Real estate is built, new bonds are given out etc.

&amp;gt;Whether the cash intermediate has positive or negative inflation doesn't really matter if you only hold on to it for a short time.

From the wikipedia page on deflation, most mainstream economists seem to think deflation is bad for the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
