<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="198230656.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3a0rr4/cmv_bitcoin_will_never_be_the_most_widely_used/">
    <title>CMV: BitCoin will never be the most widely used currency because of its inherently deflationary nature</title>
    <original_poster>Prince_of_Savoy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying all of my economic knowledge comes from some highschool courses and the internet, so I'm bound to get something wrong.

That being said, my actual argument:

Because the ammount of Bitcoins is limited to 21 million, these coins will increase in value as the world economy expands and some are lost.

If the value of a currency increases relative to goods and services, that is called deflation.

That sounds like it's not a big deal. And if you're an investor, it isn't. But if an economy relies on a currency that is undergoing deflation, that economy slows drasticly. 

The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Without investments, the economy grinds to a halt. This is why most economists think that moderate inflation is more desireable than even small deflation, some going so far as to say that some ammount of inflation is healthy.

Most people of course already treat Bitcoin as an investment instead of a currency, as you can see by its wild swings in value.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27829088161.0" user="skatastic57" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The reason: If you can increase the worth of your money just by sitting on it, many people will do so. Why go through the trouble and risk of investing it if you are guaranteed to make profit (in terms of value) by putting it under your mattress?

Two problems with this statement.
Firstly, there is never a guarantee that the value of something will go up so hoarding bitcoins for the future isn't riskless.  Gold has a fixed supply just like bitcoin but its value fluctuates and as much as the people selling gold on the TV would like you to believe there is no guarantee that it will always be more valuable in the future than it is now.

Secondly, the biggest problem with deflation is sticky prices.  Suffice it to say, it is very difficult to cut an employee's nominal pay.  It is much more likely that the employee would be laid off.  As a result unemployment could be higher due to deflation.  This isn't a law but just a phenomenon that has been observed.  As people begin to work for companies for much shorter intervals anyway the linkage between unemployment and deflation should dissipate.

Additionally, it is entirely possible that traditional banks would come in and create a fractional reserve system of bitcoins.  It'd be just like our money system is now where we have M0 and M1 which represents how much physical currency there is.  That'd be how much real bitcoins a bank has on deposits.  Then there'd be M2 and up which would include all the bank issued bitcoins.  It's likely that this system would be small relative to our current banking system and bank reserves, as a percent of deposits, would be significantly higher than they are now.  I say this system would be smaller because with bitcoins the things you can't do without a bank (or company that looks like a bank) would be trivial to do with bitcoins.  For example if I want to loan you money so you can buy a house, I can't just give you that much in paper cash.  With bitcoins I could transfer it to you without any problems at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27829733835.0" user="Prince_of_Savoy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Two problems with this statement. Firstly, there is never a guarantee that the value of something will go up so hoarding bitcoins for the future isn't riskless.

Yes. So? People will still do it.

&amp;gt;Gold has a fixed supply just like bitcoin but its value fluctuates and as much as the people selling gold on the TV would like you to believe there is no guarantee that it will always be more valuable in the future than it is now.

Of course. And yet, most gold is just sat upon as investment, not used in industry.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
