<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1986453802.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/wuolka/cmv_cereals_before_milk/">
    <title>CMV: Cereals before milk</title>
    <original_poster>Big_Committee_3894</original_poster>
    <original_post>It is my opinion that cereals take precedence over milk. I justify this with the fact that in this order, the benefit of correctly measuring the amount of cereal desired is obtained, since otherwise, placing the cereals after the milk, they do not sink and therefore overflow out of the bowl, requiring the help of a spoon to lower the cereals in order to place more on top of them. 
"When you put the cereal first, and you measure the amount of milk wrong, you will have to add more cereal, so you will contradict yourself since you argued to use the cereal first so you don't have to put it more than once" This happens, but only if you measure the quantities wrong 
"But putting the milk on top of the cereals can spill it out making a mess" Only if you are clumsy and you squirt all the milk at once as if it were a torrent. You should be careful to pour it slowly enough so that it doesn't splash out as you pour it over the cereal 
"Yes, but if you add the milk after the cereal, you won't be able to eat all of them crispy yet as the heat of the milk will soften the cereal the longer it is immersed, the cereals on top will be crispy and the ones below will be crunchy more quickly" A valid point, but in this case you must regulate the temperature of the milk. If it boils, it quickly softens the cereal, but if it is lukewarm you can enjoy the pleasure of all the cereal from start to finish being crispy. I personally am not in the habit of drinking hot milk, so all my cereal is crispy and crispy as it should be.
"But I heat the milk in the microwave already in the bowl" What's the problem? Can't it be poured into the cereal bowl? 
"I say Milk with Cereals and not Cereals with Milk, the same way I say Chocolate Milk and Milk of This and Milk of That" Phonetic precedence is not a valid argument? 
"Phonetic precedence makes sense because it means you live in a culture where milk is mostly put first" It's not because something is cultural that it's intrinsically correct.
"Milk has historical precedence over cereal so it must be honored by the primacy of milk in the bowl" And then must the republic also honor the monarchy because it has historical precedence? History is human evolution and evolution implies improvement, so the more in the past we go back worse is the human condition, cereals came like this in the context of historical evolution in improvement of the human condition complemented by milk. 
"Milk is nobler than cereal because it is the first food that we humans, and also mammals animals, take when they are puerile and that makes us grow virile" In fact, milk is fundamental in life almost as much as water, for be the infant's primary source of nutrients, but are you an infant or already a manly man? A man, therefore, why do you treat milk as if you were still a child?

Just my opinion but feel free to change my mind</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40470052396.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;they do not sink

You almost had the right answer in the few couple of sentences. Cereal doesn't sink when added on top of milk but does when you add milk later. Why? Because in latter case cereal will get wet and soggy. And temperature of milk have nothing to do with this. Cold milk (as cereal should be eaten) will still get your flakes soggy.

Milk second gives you heterogeneity in the food. You have different textures that combine in your mouth (not your bowl). You have crunchy cereal, wet milk and viscous honey/jelly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470069244.0" user="Big_Committee_3894" delta="False">
    <text>So milk first gives homogenity?

I have cold milk so the cereals stays more crunchy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470111626.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>More crunchy than what alternative? Hot milk? Who in their sound minds eats cereal with hot milk. But that aside you really need to compere cold milk first and cold milk second.

Milk first (regardless of temperature) will always lead into drier and crunchier cereal. This because cereal floats. The very thing you view as a problem is actually blessing in disguise. There is always distinct difference that becomes more and more apparent longer you eat your cereal. Milk second will always have those soggy pieces in the end. You cannot avoid them. But milk first will never have them (or have significantly less).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470140351.0" user="Big_Committee_3894" delta="False">
    <text>When I was a kid I used to eat cereals with hot milk. But indeed they get very wet very fast. I would also eat with biscuit because they are harder and would take more time to get soggy

Milk will indeed lesd to drier and crunchier cereals, but is that diference that big? I mean, I guess it can depend on the cereal one uses</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470162898.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Milk will indeed lesd to drier and crunchier cereals, but is that diference that big? I mean, I guess it can depend on the cereal one uses

Well you can experiment this with your favorite cereal. Measure (it's important to use exact measurement when doing science) equal amount of milk and cereal into a bowl. First go with your cereal first and eat it and see how much that soggy mush you have in your last few spoons. Then repeat it with milk first and see how much the difference there is.

If you think this you should be logically come to conclusion that floating cereal means dry cereal and sunken (as in cereal first) cereal must be wetter. Now it's just a personal preference if you care about that difference and how much.

Funny think is that you can change milk first cereal into cereal first just by stirring it and getting it wet/submerged. But you cannot do this in reverse. You cannot turn sunken cereal into floating cereal without drying it first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470169355.0" user="PoppersOfCorn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Who in their sound minds eats cereal with hot milk

Anyone who has ever lived in a frigid climate amd has cereal as a common breakfast.. cold porridge is horrid</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470184656.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>I live near arctic circle. Hot milk cereal sounds awful.

But porridge should be hot. And most relative to this CMV. Cereal shouldn't be porridge. Porridge is homogeneous mass of grayish slug. Cereal is crunchy and heterogeneous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470197847.0" user="PoppersOfCorn" delta="False">
    <text>Oats are literally a cereal..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470249565.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Oats are cereal in meaning of word "edible grain" like oat, wheat and corn but not in meaning of word "breakfast cereal" like cornflakes or cheerios.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470273025.0" user="PoppersOfCorn" delta="False">
    <text>Or porridge...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470304355.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Porridge is not breakfast cereal. Porridge is boiled oats. You don't boil your cornflakes (or if you are you are doing it wrong).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470366610.0" user="PoppersOfCorn" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but you could have it like muesli so you don't have to boil it, still a breakfast cereal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470384710.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>If you eat your oats like muesli then it's muesli not porridge. You are eating oats, not porridge. Ingredients are similar but method of cooking are different. Also muesli is often roasted in comparison to raw oats that are then boiled to become porridge.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
