<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1995616287.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/x04zdr/cmvgermany_could_not_win_ww2/">
    <title>CMV:Germany could not win WW2</title>
    <original_poster>Niberus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve often heard that if Germany did something different one way or another then they could have won WW2 however, I'd argue that they had no chance to win no matter what they would have done (a realistic way that is). 

From attacking the French and English in the west, to trying to subjugate various countries in the Balkans to having the brilliant idea of invading the Soviet Union, the Germans just kept making the war harder for themselves whilst making their goals further and further unreachable as the war staggered on and they were eventually chased all the way back to Berlin.

Not exactly sure what was going through Hitler’s brain at the time or when he ended his life in the Fuhrer bunker though I have to imagine that whatever mistakes he might have wanted to avoid at various points of the war it would still have ended terribly for them.

From the Allies having the control of most of the world’s resources, to the Soviet Union being too big of a block to try and knock down, to the unstable and unreliable allies that Germany had on its side, to the ideological zeal that prevented many alliances that could have taken place simply vanishing into the wind, to the massive industrial output being underestimated by the axis, to the poor planning of certain plans, to the various manpower issues that Germany suffered from, to the poor prioritization in subjecting various “””subhuman””” (their words not mine) cultures or deficiencies of human beings rather than building more war material.

Another issue is that time was simply not on Germany’s side due to all the continuing escalations that were occurring from the Japanese and Italians that various other powers were going to be fighting Germany regardless thereby tipping the scales even if the Germans wanted to keep the war on a small scale. While I won’t say that the Americans or Soviets would inevitably join if the Germans decided to draw the war out, it certainly didn’t look positive for them either. Secondly the British simply wouldn’t have fallen or settled for a white peace as they had the industry and manpower to fight on and had a superior air force to begin bombing Germany itself during nighttime. The Soviets had the manpower and industry to fight on and a massive distance between the German army and the relocated industry in the Urals. And the Americans? Well they had so much that they could sustain a war on two front against two major enemies that Germany itself could only have dreamed of either from the First World War or from the Second World War that they ended up losing anyway.

With all of this in mind, I just do not see a (rational and realistic) way in which the Germans could win. Everything was against them from the very beginning in the invasion of the Second Polish Republic to the scorching deserts of North Africa, to the hellscape of Far Eastern Europe to the collapse of the Reich itself. 

Would be welcome to changing my mind…</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40522746658.0" user="limepickle" delta="False">
    <text>It's sort of hard to address your view, because the reality is that they didn't win. What does it mean then to say that they "could not win" WW2? You've pointed out what you feel was poor strategy on their part, but then obviously they could have won if they did things differently? For example, they could've won if they developed the atomic bomb faster IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40522887073.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>Rephrased the beginning paragraph to make it more clear that no matter what Germany did during the Second World War they were doomed from the start. No decisions would have yielded a victory.

As for developing the Atomic bomb that unfortunately was never going to be a reality as the Germans had either killed or kicked out many of their top researchers because, they were Jewish and they subsequently fled to the US to help with their atomic program there.

Second off there wouldn't be a way to successfully deploy an atomic bomb as the Germans required air superiority over major industrial centers of the allied countries, something that they lacked after 1942.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523115681.0" user="ZorgZeFrenchGuy" delta="False">
    <text>So if Germany had managed to keep and woo over those top researchers, it would be feasible for them to have developed the a-bomb first?  

Would not killing or exiling top scientists qualify as a decision that could have helped Germany win the war?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523211440.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>It would have helped them but they wouldn't have kept those scientists unless you fundamentally changed who the Nazis were.

And the Nazis decreed that various other cultures and races were beneath the German race and so keeping those scientists would have gone against their intentions and goals because they were ideologically minded.

Besides, at the time of their expulsion, the Germans didn't prioritise developing the atomic bomb and instead prioritised war production and resources into war materials that would defeat their foes...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523314594.0" user="TheTeaMustFlow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So if Germany had managed to keep and woo over those top researchers, it would be feasible for them to have developed the a-bomb first?

No. They could have had every researcher in the world, and they still couldn't have managed it - because it's not just a matter of knowledge. Germany simply didn't have the resources to conduct a full-scale atomic weapons program *and* fight a total war at the same time. 

(In all likelihood, only the USA did possess that capability. *Maybe* Britain or the USSR if you're being generous.)

The German atomic weapons program literally had 1/1000th of the funding of the American one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40524174031.0" user="ProLifePanda" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The German atomic weapons program literally had 1/1000th of the funding of the American one.

There is a leaked audio of the lead German scientists talking about the atomic bomb bring dropped. They were flabbergasted that the US was so far ahead of them, had solved problems they had no solution to, and speculated their funding had to be significantly more than theirs to make it happen.


https://germanhistorydocs.ghi-dc.org/pdf/eng/English101.pdf

Just adding context. I found reading this fascinating and thought you and others might to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40524491055.0" user="TheTeaMustFlow" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks very much - I had read about their reaction, but actually seeing the direct transcript is very interesting indeed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523563391.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>Not invading the West could’ve helped as it pushed back operation Barbarossa quite a bit and thinned resources the Nazi’s needed. Ergo, it wasn’t something that Germany could do, but if England and France hadn’t declared war after Poland, the Nazi’s would’ve had a good chance defeating the Soviet Union. I mean they nearly did anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523612501.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>And why would Britain and France not declare war to protect Poland? Hitler made it clear after Austria and Czechoslovakia that he was going to be driving east and so the allies knew they had to stop him otherwise Germany would grow far too dominant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523638212.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not saying they would. I’m saying that in this particular case this wasn’t something in Germany’s control. But it would’ve made a huge impact. 

If you want to guess at a reason anyway, they didn’t declare war after Austria or Czechoslovakia either. Or after any of the other transgressions that Hitler committed regarding the Versailles treaty. Also, a war against the USSR would’ve been welcomed by western powers. But the fact that Hitler had signed the Molotov-von Ribbentrop pact made that an insecure prospect. 


The irony is that Hitler probably wouldn’t have invaded the west without that war declaration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523649743.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>An interesting scenario but not a realistic one that I was looking for...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523325343.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that the Nazis could not have developped the atomic bomb, because of a combination of nazi pseudoscience rejecting the basic science behind it as "jewish physics, institutional mismanagement, lack of funding, lack of prioritization, lack of resources, and so on...

So, when one says "they could not win WW2", what people mean is that even if the Nazis had acted differently, they would still have lost. The only way for them not to lose, was not be nazis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40525177769.0" user="Straight-faced_solo" delta="False">
    <text>The nazis had already halted most nuclear experimentation before the war started. They viewed nuclear physics and "Jewish" and therefor wrong. Ideologically the Nazis could never have developed the atomic bomb because they where opposed to it. Sure if we imagine a world where the Nazis weren't the nazis maybe, but to what end.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
