<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1995616287.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/x04zdr/cmvgermany_could_not_win_ww2/">
    <title>CMV:Germany could not win WW2</title>
    <original_poster>Niberus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve often heard that if Germany did something different one way or another then they could have won WW2 however, I'd argue that they had no chance to win no matter what they would have done (a realistic way that is). 

From attacking the French and English in the west, to trying to subjugate various countries in the Balkans to having the brilliant idea of invading the Soviet Union, the Germans just kept making the war harder for themselves whilst making their goals further and further unreachable as the war staggered on and they were eventually chased all the way back to Berlin.

Not exactly sure what was going through Hitler’s brain at the time or when he ended his life in the Fuhrer bunker though I have to imagine that whatever mistakes he might have wanted to avoid at various points of the war it would still have ended terribly for them.

From the Allies having the control of most of the world’s resources, to the Soviet Union being too big of a block to try and knock down, to the unstable and unreliable allies that Germany had on its side, to the ideological zeal that prevented many alliances that could have taken place simply vanishing into the wind, to the massive industrial output being underestimated by the axis, to the poor planning of certain plans, to the various manpower issues that Germany suffered from, to the poor prioritization in subjecting various “””subhuman””” (their words not mine) cultures or deficiencies of human beings rather than building more war material.

Another issue is that time was simply not on Germany’s side due to all the continuing escalations that were occurring from the Japanese and Italians that various other powers were going to be fighting Germany regardless thereby tipping the scales even if the Germans wanted to keep the war on a small scale. While I won’t say that the Americans or Soviets would inevitably join if the Germans decided to draw the war out, it certainly didn’t look positive for them either. Secondly the British simply wouldn’t have fallen or settled for a white peace as they had the industry and manpower to fight on and had a superior air force to begin bombing Germany itself during nighttime. The Soviets had the manpower and industry to fight on and a massive distance between the German army and the relocated industry in the Urals. And the Americans? Well they had so much that they could sustain a war on two front against two major enemies that Germany itself could only have dreamed of either from the First World War or from the Second World War that they ended up losing anyway.

With all of this in mind, I just do not see a (rational and realistic) way in which the Germans could win. Everything was against them from the very beginning in the invasion of the Second Polish Republic to the scorching deserts of North Africa, to the hellscape of Far Eastern Europe to the collapse of the Reich itself. 

Would be welcome to changing my mind…</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40523254221.0" user="shooketh_not_stireth" delta="False">
    <text>Could Germany have won if they did x or y and were *still* trying to conquer all of Europe, the Mediterranean, *and Russia* at the same time? Most likely not. While there are a couple pivotal movements which would have a made a substantial impact upon how the war progressed (e.g. Dunkirk or Moscow), so long as their ambitions were as expansive as they were, and their resources as constrained as they were, loss was inevitable.

However, if they had chosen several offramps, they could have simply stopped with a massive increase in territory. Offer England peace, and wrap up the Western theater before the US ever joins, then focus primarily on the Eastern front and force access to badly needed fuel sources.

There were several points where if they had simply stopped, they could have kept everything that had up to that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523319454.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While there are a couple pivotal movements which would have a made a substantial impact upon how the war progressed (e.g. Dunkirk or Moscow)

How would Dunkirk have changed the outcome? Also they never took Moscow so I'm not sure how that factors in

&amp;gt;There were several points where if they had simply stopped, they could have kept everything that had up to that point.

Hitler and the ideas and goals that he clearly wrote out in Mein Kampf meant that he was going to go to war with the Soviet Union eventually and that offering peace was never an option as he wanted to see Bolshevism destroyed and the East ripe for German settlement</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523465536.0" user="shooketh_not_stireth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How would Dunkirk have changed the outcome? Also they never took Moscow so I'm not sure how that factors in

As other's have already pointed out, Britain losing their entire expeditionary force, as well as the remnants of the French military who were also able to escape, would have been a significant moral and military blow to Britain. Even though they had suffered a loss and left a significant amount of material on French soil, that they were able to escape at all was an important victory that kept them in the war.

Otherwise they might have sued for peace, or accepted a truce. 

Regarding Moscow, Germany came close enough that its clear that a cascade of smaller decisions leading up to that moment *could* have culminated in them reaching and maybe even taking the city. 

&amp;gt; Hitler and the ideas and goals that he clearly wrote out in Mein Kampf meant that he was going to go to war with the Soviet Union eventually and that offering peace was never an option as he wanted to see Bolshevism destroyed and the East ripe for German settlement

Sure, and *when* and *how* Germany set about accomplishing that would significantly alter the outcome. Prosecuting a war on three fronts was far too much to take on. 

Had they been able to settle the matter with Britain first, that would have knocked out an important set of ports and staging areas for US European action, as well as kept the remainder of the UK out of the European theatre.

Whether or not this actually would have happened I can't say, as the UK's conflict with Germany's ally, Japan is a major issue that could keep them in the war regardless.

If Germany could have isolated Russia, either by focusing its submarines on preventing Lend-Lease shipping to Russia or keeping the US out of the war altogether, and bring its military fully to bear on Russia, we would have seen a pretty different outcome. 

But we'd still have to account for Russia also having several more years to prepare for the conflict, so who knows how it would have gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523592799.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As other's have already pointed out, Britain losing their entire expeditionary force, as well as the remnants of the French military who were also able to escape, would have been a significant moral and military blow to Britain

Sorry but again, Britain isn't the only country at war with Germany, its entire empire is. The scales were more balanced than some believe as Germany had trouble bombing and starving the British into surrendering. More than a million troops would be dedicated by the Indian army alone which helped to fill in the army that had escaped from France.

And again a peace treaty was never going to happen as Germany showed that it would keep breaking treaties to satisfy its own end when it broke the Versailes and Munich treaties on the basis of advancing their goals and that was clear as day for the British.

&amp;gt;Sure, and when and how Germany set about accomplishing that would significantly alter the outcome. Prosecuting a war on three fronts was far too much to take on.

Ok Germany takes Moscow and the Soviets say no.

Remember that Joseph Stalin was an authoritarian dictator and the last thing he would have said was "Oh well game over guys". The Soviets were never going to surrender to Germany just as Germany never surrendered until the entire country was taken. Taking the entirety of the Soviet Union? Yea good luck with that</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
