<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1995616287.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/x04zdr/cmvgermany_could_not_win_ww2/">
    <title>CMV:Germany could not win WW2</title>
    <original_poster>Niberus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve often heard that if Germany did something different one way or another then they could have won WW2 however, I'd argue that they had no chance to win no matter what they would have done (a realistic way that is). 

From attacking the French and English in the west, to trying to subjugate various countries in the Balkans to having the brilliant idea of invading the Soviet Union, the Germans just kept making the war harder for themselves whilst making their goals further and further unreachable as the war staggered on and they were eventually chased all the way back to Berlin.

Not exactly sure what was going through Hitler’s brain at the time or when he ended his life in the Fuhrer bunker though I have to imagine that whatever mistakes he might have wanted to avoid at various points of the war it would still have ended terribly for them.

From the Allies having the control of most of the world’s resources, to the Soviet Union being too big of a block to try and knock down, to the unstable and unreliable allies that Germany had on its side, to the ideological zeal that prevented many alliances that could have taken place simply vanishing into the wind, to the massive industrial output being underestimated by the axis, to the poor planning of certain plans, to the various manpower issues that Germany suffered from, to the poor prioritization in subjecting various “””subhuman””” (their words not mine) cultures or deficiencies of human beings rather than building more war material.

Another issue is that time was simply not on Germany’s side due to all the continuing escalations that were occurring from the Japanese and Italians that various other powers were going to be fighting Germany regardless thereby tipping the scales even if the Germans wanted to keep the war on a small scale. While I won’t say that the Americans or Soviets would inevitably join if the Germans decided to draw the war out, it certainly didn’t look positive for them either. Secondly the British simply wouldn’t have fallen or settled for a white peace as they had the industry and manpower to fight on and had a superior air force to begin bombing Germany itself during nighttime. The Soviets had the manpower and industry to fight on and a massive distance between the German army and the relocated industry in the Urals. And the Americans? Well they had so much that they could sustain a war on two front against two major enemies that Germany itself could only have dreamed of either from the First World War or from the Second World War that they ended up losing anyway.

With all of this in mind, I just do not see a (rational and realistic) way in which the Germans could win. Everything was against them from the very beginning in the invasion of the Second Polish Republic to the scorching deserts of North Africa, to the hellscape of Far Eastern Europe to the collapse of the Reich itself. 

Would be welcome to changing my mind…</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40522760681.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Could Germany have won?  Probably, if you are willing to consider some smarter moves on the German side.

For example, if Germany delayed their invasion of the Soviet Union until after Britain had been knocked out of the war, things might have turned out differently.

Similarly, Germany could have delayed declaring war on America after Pearl Harbor, which may have led to the US throwing more of their power into the Pacific.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40522938323.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if Germany delayed their invasion of the Soviet Union until after Britain had been knocked out of the war

Operation Barbarossa (the Nazi invasion of the USSR) didn't start until 6 months *after* the Battle of Britain was over. The time for knocking Britain out of the war had come and gone, and there is no evidence that an armistice was ever seriously entertained as notion by the British government even at the worst of it. So, this part is just flat wrong.

&amp;gt; Germany could have delayed declaring war on America after Pearl Harbor, which may have led to the US throwing more of their power into the Pacific.

By Sept of 1941, we were already in a warm war with the Nazis (e.g. US ships/planes were already shooting at German subs). Hitler not declaring war may have delayed things in the Atlantic *slightly,* but ultimately wouldn't have changed anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523036710.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>As I said elsewhere, I think that taking the British at Dunkirk and suing for peace was a possible outcome of the war.

Had Dunkirk gone the other way, Britain suing for peace was a real possibility.

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_cabinet_crisis,_May_1940</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523189124.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>I'm well aware of those meetings, and there's still no indication that Britain seriously thought about an armistice. Even if they had lost the entire 200k at Dunkirk, they still had a considerable force already called up, potentially a million more that could be called up, and reinforcements from the Commonwealth that would come in. Unless you can show me something more concrete than Halifax really, really wanting to... your position doesn't really stand up to any scrutiny.

Moreover, Dunkirk was a year before the Germans invaded Russia, so it  had absolutely nothing to do with the Germans "waiting to attack Russia until Britain left."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40522970466.0" user="TheTeaMustFlow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if Germany delayed their invasion of the Soviet Union until after Britain had been knocked out of the war

Essentially impossible. ‘Knocking Britain out’ requires a successful invasion. Germany does not have anywhere *near* the naval capability to invade, and cannot develop it without a) critically weakening the land capabilities it needs to win in on the continent and b) triggering British rearmament several years early.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523003204.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily.  Had the Germans wiped out the British at Dunkirk, I think it’s likely that Britain sues for some sort of peace terms.

The Germans didn’t need to conquer Britain to win the war.

See here

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_cabinet_crisis,_May_1940</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523276711.0" user="TheTeaMustFlow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Had the Germans wiped out the British at Dunkirk, I think it’s likely that Britain sues for some sort of peace terms.

Not so. If Halifax had got in he might have put out feelers, but we now know the gulf between the terms he was willing to accept and the terms the Hitler was willing to offer were so vast that he would have quickly balked. 

More to the point, even had their been a premiership willing to completely throw in the towel, it is irrelevant, because they couldn't have done so even if they wanted to - a majority of the public and the House were solidly in favour of fighting on, even at the direst point when the BEF had been written off for lost, and a pro-surrender administration would have been quickly thrown out. This is *why* Churchill became Prime Minister in the first place, despite otherwise not being particularly popular either with Labour or the Tories - and if it hadn't been him, it would have been another pro-war figure in his place (Eden, perhaps).

The belief that Britain was close to capitulation in 1940 owes more to Churchill hagiography and outdated Great Man obsessions than it does to the facts of the matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40522978927.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>Defeat the British how exactly?

First they tried to bomb them into dust that didn't work and then tried to starve them through convoy raiding that also failed. And they couldn't have invaded the mainland as the British Fleet that was far superior to the Kriegsmarine</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523016418.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>I think the most likely scenario is capturing the majority of the British forces at Dunkirk, and then Britain sues for peace.

No invasion necessary.

See here:

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_cabinet_crisis,_May_1940</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523046105.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>The escape at Dunkirk while more successful than others had ever calculated, led to the army losing alot of their equipment back in France and was in no way ready to fight Germany. 

However, that still doesn't solve the problem as Britain had reserve troops on the mainland and plenty overseas and in colonies that it could call up. India itself would come to contribute alot of that and that still leaves the Germans with having to deal with the Royal Air Force and Royal Navy

Edit: In regards to the Cabinet crisis that is also something that Germany didn't have any control over and it is something that Churchill had great influence in winning as he had been warning the British public and government for months and years that Germany would come to challenge the world order.

So when the idea of surrendering was passed around it was clear that even if they signed for a white peace with Germany, that would leave the Germans in total control of Europe which is something that was unacceptable to the cabinet when proposed by Lord Halifax</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523053746.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>So you think that there was no possibility of the War Cabinet Crisis of 1940 ever going the other way?

What if Churchill could simply not get the support he needed ?

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_cabinet_crisis,_May_1940</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523055744.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[War cabinet crisis, May 1940](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_cabinet_crisis,_May_1940)** 
 
 &amp;gt;In May 1940, during the Second World War, the British war cabinet was split on the question of whether to make terms with Nazi Germany or to continue hostilities. The main protagonists were the prime minister, Winston Churchill, and the foreign secretary, Viscount Halifax. The dispute escalated to crisis point and threatened the continuity of the Churchill government. With the British Expeditionary Force in retreat to Dunkirk and the fall of France seemingly imminent, Halifax believed that the government should explore the possibility of a negotiated peace settlement.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523113644.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>And he wouldn't get that support how exactly?

Neville Chamberlain's plan of peace in their time had failed so he was gone and Halifax's idea of surrendering to the Germans or trying to white peace was seen as a lie after the Munich Agreement had been broken.

Every point that Halifax brought up was shot down by Churchill as he had been espousing the same rhetoric ever since he saw the German facade of trying to take over Europe because, hey if they signed the peace treaty now then the Germans would simply break it, just like Versaille when they occupied the Rhineland, unified with Austria and took over Czechoslovakia.

There was no competition and the cabinet saw that...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523138047.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Historians call it the “War Cabinet Crisis” for a reason, not the “War Cabinet Foregone Conclusion”

As the article I linked points out, it was a turning point in the war.  It’s hard to imagine, but it absolutely could have gone a different way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523170469.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>It could have happened sure but, you're going to have to give some pretty good reasons as to why the cabinet and the ministers would have agreed with Halifax and not Churchill as the table was already heavily slanted towards Churchill's side from all of his years of warnings and hysteria that was casually brushed off for all those years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523204184.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;table was already heavily slanted towards Churchill

It really wasn't.   If Chamberlain decides to support Halifax over Churchill, then Churchill is out, and you very likely see Britain suing for peace.

That's just one example of a turning point in the war.   There are others, like the Battle of Midway, El Alamein, the Battle of Stalingrad, Hitler rerouting troops to Greece to help the Italians, and the escape from Dunkirk.

There is also the possibility that various inventions that were critical to the war fail to be invented or delivered as they were in history.  Britain without radar is a very different Battle of Britain.

One or more of the world leaders could have been assassinated or simply dropped dead of a heart attack, too.

Do you think all these events are foregone conclusions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523287737.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>As I noted in my original post, I'm looking for realistic ways that the Germans could have won. 

Not "what if" scenarios that just happen to have occurred out of the blue, without reason or extreme luck to help the Germans along.

&amp;gt;There is also the possibility that various inventions that were critical to the war fail to be invented or delivered as they were in history. Britain without radar is a very different Battle of Britain.

If we were to play by those rules then why stop there?

There is also the possibility that Stalin could have had a heart attack weakening the leadership of USSR

There is also the possibility that Germans simply invented various wunderwaffen to help them along

There is also the possibility that Italy just stops being incompetent and revives the Roman empire.

If there is no basis to what you are talking about, then what's the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523445006.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it depends on how you view history.

Was the Brits having radar during the Battle of Britain a foregone conclusion or the result of some luck and some skill?

Was Midway a certain victory for the US or was the combination of a few bad decisions and lucky breaks the deciding factor?

Was Normandy guaranteed to succeed or was there a chance it could fail?

I tend to see it more in probabilities.  Maybe Normandy had a 70% success rate.  But that still leaves a 30% chance of failure

Allied failure at Normandy wouldn’t be “unrealistic or out of the blue”.  We knew going in there was a chance for failure, even a catastrophic one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523520461.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Was the Brits having radar during the Battle of Britain a foregone conclusion or the result of some luck and some skill?

Unless you find some way for the entire research team to simply drop dead, the funding to disappear into thin air and allies being unwilling to help along for no reason then that is an extremely far fetched situation.

Besides Britain wasn't the only country with Radar, the United States and the Soviet Union also had facilities that the British could (and did somewhat) copy from.

&amp;gt;Was Midway a certain victory for the US or was the combination of a few bad decisions and lucky breaks the deciding factor?

Even if Midway was lost the US was churning out ships at a tidal wave speed and would have defeated the Japanese regardless. I would really recommend reading about the post-war fleets that were eventually scrapped it's really interesting.

&amp;gt;Was Normandy guaranteed to succeed or was there a chance it could fail?

Even if Normandy failed the Soviet hordes were charging in from the East and the Allied invasion failing wouldn't have stopped that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523996491.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>I think that we assume history was inevitable because we lived with it, so how could it possibly turn out any other way?

Or the idea that even if one major factor changes, all the other factors would keep going exactly as they had, and  the difference in outcome would have been in the noise.

I’m much more of a believer in the ideas that many, many paths were possible, and we simply are living in one of those paths.

With all the possible arcs of history, do you really think there was never one where the Allies lost ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40526530183.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>In the war that the Germans found themselves in, they were doomed from the start particularly the war they started in September 1939.

There are many events that could have gone differently however, they are either insignificant to change the course of the war, have absolutely no basis meaning that the people behind the decisions wouldn't have taken them in the first place or require extreme luck that it's the equivalent of playing the lottery and winning several times in a row.

As I said in the beginning, I don't see a realistic way in which the situation might have changed to favour the Germans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40527203002.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Something like Stalin, FDR, Churchill or Hitler dying in the early days of the war isn’t “extreme luck” it’s just life, those things happen.  

That’s not a lottery ticket.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523296322.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of which I really want to know how you think those various Battles changed the War (somehow) that would be more fun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523574788.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, it was Hitler’s strategy change that cost him the battle of britain. The Nazi’s were very effective at the start, bombing infrastructure and airfields. But because Hitler was impatient he wanted another Rotterdam, which didn’t work and gave the British the possibility to rebuild their airforce.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523632391.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but you still have the Royal Navy to deal with, and that wasn't going to be collapsing anytime soon. You try and switch to destroying the Royal Navy with the german air fleet and the Royal Air Force rebuilds and so you're back to square one. And even then you still have reserve troops back on the Aisles awaiting a possible German invasion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523724442.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not how you proceed tho. After you defeat and completely destroy the RAF and its infrastructure you are free to carry out bombing raids on whatever targets you deem fit, perhaps making additional runs at airfields intermittently to ensure they stay destroyed. In this way you can force a total collapse of Britains infrastructure so rebuilding things is out of the question. This could force Britain into an armistice. The Royal Navy wouldn’t be able to defend against this strategy. Nor would it have a good time defending against an invasion with airsupport without airsupport of their own. This is why historians find the Battle of Britain to be pivotal to how the war progressed. Germany’s loss was a major turning point and completely preventable without changing any major parameters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40526481337.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>I think you really underestimate just how much ordinance is required to flatten cities and their industrial capacity, something that the German bomber fleet was incapable of achieving due to design restrictions that were implemented in Versailles to mask bomber planes as civilian planes.

Secondly, Britain wasn't the only country to be fighting the Germans which together with lend lease, had the industry and capacity to simply outproduce the Germans and make sure the Battle of Britain in the end  was going to be a win no matter which way they sliced it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40527168986.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>Britain *was* alone during the Battle of Britain. And the lend-lease act didn’t come into effect until march 1941. That is why this battle was so pivotal. 

The Germans didn’t need to flatten the entirety of Britain. They needed to put Britain into a position where it would be more likely to either A) accept an armistice (which the foreign secretary Halifax was very much in favor of doing, following the isolationist policy that was typical for Britain) or B) give Britain such a blow that the invasion of the USSR could be done with more resources. This could be achieved by bombing ports, major roadways, etc. The nazi’s didn’t need to completely destroy Britain. Nor was that their intent. An actual invasion would have been incredibly difficult, if not impossible. But even that wasn’t a prerequisite for what I outlined above. The major factor here is whether it would make an invasion of the USSR more likely to succeed. 

Even with losing the Battle of Britain the nazi’s came very close to taking Moscow because Stalin was woefully unprepared. 

I’m not saying it would be easy, or a done deal. But it is plausible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40530316724.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>And that's if Halifax was able to gain power instead of Churchill which didn't happen because, Halifax subscribed to Chamberlain's thoughts of suing for peace in hopes of a better day (Czechoslovakia) which is something that had run it's course by the time the Germans came knocking on Poland's door and Churchill was having none of it and affirmed that Britain would fight until the end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40530426525.0" user="Uddha40k" delta="False">
    <text>A ‘what if’ scenario is very difficult to play out, hence why it hardly has track among historians (Niall Fergusson being a notable exception). If used, it’s mainly to point out the importance of events. But if we do want to entertain ‘what if’ scenario’s we can’t keep faling back on what actually happened because what actually happened is that Germany lost WWII. If you want a plausible scenario you have to accept changes. 

My point with Halifax is that there were obviously more proponents of peace within the cabinet and parliament. Churchill’s position as prime minister was, until his heroic defence of Britain, quite tenuous. A loss in the Battle of Britain could have swayed opinion toward peace or an armistice. The fact that Churchills position wasn’t that strong is also evidenced by him losing the elections after the war despite his succes during the war. 

This scenario becomes even more plausible (but not a surety) if we take into account that the lend-lease act wasn’t signed into law yet for another half year and Britain was actually for a while on it’s own. The cash and carry act didn’t have enough impact to save Britain. A victory over the RAF, destruction of ports and infrastructure, industry etc on a large enough scale with Britain having no immediate hope to come back from could certainly have resulted in an armistice. Which in turn would have made a succesful operation barbarossa more likely. If only because Germany wouldn’t have to keep carrying on with the Blitz and most certainly not with those heavy losses. Had Germany been able to use that airforce against the USSR their chances would have increased significantly. Capturing Moscow and Stalin would have sealed the deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523370512.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>While others have pointed out the fact that Nazi germany was nowhere near ready to force Britain to surrender, I will counter the other point. 

&amp;gt;For example, if Germany delayed their invasion of the Soviet Union until after Britain had been knocked out of the war, things might have turned out differently.

A delay of the invasion of the Soviet Union might not have gone better for the Nazis.

The initial success of the Operation Barbossa relied on suprise and the Soviet Union being utterly unprepared. A significant delay would have allowed Soviet forces to organize themselves better, and recover further from the great purge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523394033.0" user="GoblinRaiders" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but it would also allow the Germans to focus their full attention on the Eastern front.

With Britain out of the war, there is no need to worry about a future invasion in the channel, and more forces could have been brought to bear on the Eastern front.   It also frees up your armies in Africa to move towards the Middle East</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
