<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1995616287.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/x04zdr/cmvgermany_could_not_win_ww2/">
    <title>CMV:Germany could not win WW2</title>
    <original_poster>Niberus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve often heard that if Germany did something different one way or another then they could have won WW2 however, I'd argue that they had no chance to win no matter what they would have done (a realistic way that is). 

From attacking the French and English in the west, to trying to subjugate various countries in the Balkans to having the brilliant idea of invading the Soviet Union, the Germans just kept making the war harder for themselves whilst making their goals further and further unreachable as the war staggered on and they were eventually chased all the way back to Berlin.

Not exactly sure what was going through Hitler’s brain at the time or when he ended his life in the Fuhrer bunker though I have to imagine that whatever mistakes he might have wanted to avoid at various points of the war it would still have ended terribly for them.

From the Allies having the control of most of the world’s resources, to the Soviet Union being too big of a block to try and knock down, to the unstable and unreliable allies that Germany had on its side, to the ideological zeal that prevented many alliances that could have taken place simply vanishing into the wind, to the massive industrial output being underestimated by the axis, to the poor planning of certain plans, to the various manpower issues that Germany suffered from, to the poor prioritization in subjecting various “””subhuman””” (their words not mine) cultures or deficiencies of human beings rather than building more war material.

Another issue is that time was simply not on Germany’s side due to all the continuing escalations that were occurring from the Japanese and Italians that various other powers were going to be fighting Germany regardless thereby tipping the scales even if the Germans wanted to keep the war on a small scale. While I won’t say that the Americans or Soviets would inevitably join if the Germans decided to draw the war out, it certainly didn’t look positive for them either. Secondly the British simply wouldn’t have fallen or settled for a white peace as they had the industry and manpower to fight on and had a superior air force to begin bombing Germany itself during nighttime. The Soviets had the manpower and industry to fight on and a massive distance between the German army and the relocated industry in the Urals. And the Americans? Well they had so much that they could sustain a war on two front against two major enemies that Germany itself could only have dreamed of either from the First World War or from the Second World War that they ended up losing anyway.

With all of this in mind, I just do not see a (rational and realistic) way in which the Germans could win. Everything was against them from the very beginning in the invasion of the Second Polish Republic to the scorching deserts of North Africa, to the hellscape of Far Eastern Europe to the collapse of the Reich itself. 

Would be welcome to changing my mind…</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40523274014.0" user="TheMikeyMac13" delta="False">
    <text>Germany was not doomed from the start. The benefitted from the weakness of Neville Chamberlain, England and France early, who could have stopped them before it got started, but didn’t.

Then the reality exists that nobody in the world was as advanced militarily as Germany was. Tank to tank, plane to plane, Germany tended to stand out from everyone. Where the rest of the world prepared for WW1 again, Germany innovated and it hurt the allies for a while.

But here are some examples of what could have been done differently, and taken together there could have been a different result:

Germany let England off in the battle of the Atlantic, they were sinking British boats and starving the UK, and pulled the uboats back.

Germany trusted their technology too much, believing nobody could break the enigma. Plans should have been in place that assumed the enigma was broken, changing ciphers at very least more often.

Germany should not have declared war on the USA, at least not yet. It gave FDR all he needed to enter the war. The USA was firmly isolationist, better to leave them as close to that as possible.

When Germany took France, they were close to encircling and taking the entire British army, and Hitler slowed down the tanks, it was moving too fast for his limited military mind. Letting them escape at Dunkirk was a massive error, that army captured could have ended the war. Times were very hard for England just then.

Not listening to Rommel about where to place the reinforcements in France was stupid, you plan for the possibility you are wrong, and Hitler didn’t. So the reinforcements that could have pushed the allies into the see were too far away.

Attacking Russia when he did. Germany had time, and waited to invade when they diverted troops to another nation. At that point you wait, you don’t go into Russia in the winter.

And a moronic military command structure, where only Hitler could move reinforcements? That is terrible.

All together, those poor military choices doomed them, but that war wasn’t a sure thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523436079.0" user="Niberus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Plans should have been in place that assumed the enigma was broken, changing ciphers at very least more often

How does an enigma help the Germans from trying to take on 3 superpowers at once? While the enigma was effective it would not stop vast Soviet Armies, British Ships or American Bomber Fleets from destroying Germany to pieces.

&amp;gt;Germany let England off in the battle of the Atlantic, they were sinking British boats and starving the UK, and pulled the uboats back.

While the convoy raiding fleet was impressive the British Navy and Air Force was superior to the German Kriegsmarine and Luftwaffe which prevented a decisive move needed to defeat Britain

&amp;gt;Germany should not have declared war on the USA, at least not yet. It gave FDR all he needed to enter the war. The USA was firmly isolationist, better to leave them as close to that as possible.

Even with the US not directly involved the USSR would still have rolled across the Germans in the war of attrition

&amp;gt;When Germany took France, they were close to encircling and taking the entire British army, and Hitler slowed down the tanks, it was moving too fast for his limited military mind. Letting them escape at Dunkirk was a massive error, that army captured could have ended the war. Times were very hard for England just then.

I mentioned this elsewhere but, to repeat the British aren't the only ones fighting in the war. And not all of their armed forces were in France as they had reserves on the mainland, on other fronts and could still call up more from colonies

&amp;gt;Not listening to Rommel about where to place the reinforcements in France was stupid, you plan for the possibility you are wrong, and Hitler didn’t. So the reinforcements that could have pushed the allies into the see were too far away.

Again, even if D-Day failed, the Soviets were rushing in from the East and would have still rolled over the Germans

&amp;gt;Attacking Russia when he did. Germany had time, and waited to invade when they diverted troops to another nation. At that point you wait, you don’t go into Russia in the winter.

Germany was low on oil and needed to invade the USSR otherwise later on their tanks couldn't move as they needed to beat the USSR. Also Hitler invaded during the Summer, and planned to finish the campaign in 3-4 months, i.e. when he thought he would make the USSR collapse in on itself

&amp;gt;And a moronic military command structure, where only Hitler could move reinforcements? That is terrible.

Reinforcements were things that army field Marshalls could move not just Hitler. Hitler simply overruled any decisions that he wanted. Something that he rarely did in the early years but abused to his heart content in later years when the war was already decided</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523479786.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While the convoy raiding fleet was impressive the British Navy and Air Force was superior to the German Kriegsmarine and Luftwaffe which prevented a decisive move needed to defeat Britain

Also, the nazis didn't let Britain off.
They did a surge effort and sunk a lot of cargo early in the war , but then British anti-submarine tactics adapted, and the pace of operations was unsustainable.
They didn't chose to give britain a break, they couldn't afford to keep up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40523445879.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then the reality exists that nobody in the world was as advanced militarily as Germany was. Tank to tank, plane to plane, Germany tended to stand out from everyone. Where the rest of the world prepared for WW1 again, Germany innovated and it hurt the allies for a while.

This is quite simply not true.
While the Nazis had some innovations, in many other areas they were strictly, and often dramatically inferior.

Take tanks for example.
During the battle of France, most Nazi units had to rely on Panzer II and Panzer I tanks. The latter was a training vehicle, armed only with machine guns, and yet made up a significant portion of nazi armor during the early war simply because they had nothing better.

In comparison, French tanks were far more numerous, possessed better armor and had larger guns.

Their failure was not the result of technology, but of doctrine, which saw the French tanks dispersed and unable to concentrate force and meaningfully challenge the Nazi advance.

-----------

The same story repeated during Operation Barbossa, where the nazis found that they had no mechanized answer for the Soviet T-34 tank, and had to convert anti-air guns to anti tank operation as a stopgap solution.

-----------
The same thing repeats in other fields. The nazi army by and large lacked mechanization, being utterly reliant on horse drawn transportation. 

Allied forces meanwhile had far better mechanization. 

----------

Nazi forces never developped a proper strategic bomber, unlike the allies

---------

Nazi technological innovations focussed on ineffective wunderwaffe such as the V-2.

Allied technological innovations included such essential systems such as the radar proximity fuse, which dramatically improved the performance of anti-air and ordinary artillery.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
