<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1995616287.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/x04zdr/cmvgermany_could_not_win_ww2/">
    <title>CMV:Germany could not win WW2</title>
    <original_poster>Niberus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve often heard that if Germany did something different one way or another then they could have won WW2 however, I'd argue that they had no chance to win no matter what they would have done (a realistic way that is). 

From attacking the French and English in the west, to trying to subjugate various countries in the Balkans to having the brilliant idea of invading the Soviet Union, the Germans just kept making the war harder for themselves whilst making their goals further and further unreachable as the war staggered on and they were eventually chased all the way back to Berlin.

Not exactly sure what was going through Hitler’s brain at the time or when he ended his life in the Fuhrer bunker though I have to imagine that whatever mistakes he might have wanted to avoid at various points of the war it would still have ended terribly for them.

From the Allies having the control of most of the world’s resources, to the Soviet Union being too big of a block to try and knock down, to the unstable and unreliable allies that Germany had on its side, to the ideological zeal that prevented many alliances that could have taken place simply vanishing into the wind, to the massive industrial output being underestimated by the axis, to the poor planning of certain plans, to the various manpower issues that Germany suffered from, to the poor prioritization in subjecting various “””subhuman””” (their words not mine) cultures or deficiencies of human beings rather than building more war material.

Another issue is that time was simply not on Germany’s side due to all the continuing escalations that were occurring from the Japanese and Italians that various other powers were going to be fighting Germany regardless thereby tipping the scales even if the Germans wanted to keep the war on a small scale. While I won’t say that the Americans or Soviets would inevitably join if the Germans decided to draw the war out, it certainly didn’t look positive for them either. Secondly the British simply wouldn’t have fallen or settled for a white peace as they had the industry and manpower to fight on and had a superior air force to begin bombing Germany itself during nighttime. The Soviets had the manpower and industry to fight on and a massive distance between the German army and the relocated industry in the Urals. And the Americans? Well they had so much that they could sustain a war on two front against two major enemies that Germany itself could only have dreamed of either from the First World War or from the Second World War that they ended up losing anyway.

With all of this in mind, I just do not see a (rational and realistic) way in which the Germans could win. Everything was against them from the very beginning in the invasion of the Second Polish Republic to the scorching deserts of North Africa, to the hellscape of Far Eastern Europe to the collapse of the Reich itself. 

Would be welcome to changing my mind…</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40530614335.0" user="AdditionalPrice7336" delta="False">
    <text>Well if Chruchill wasn't chucked by you know who
Yeah 
I mean, shit wrong meeting.
Uh, what I mean to say is, if the British Empire wasn't so devoted to bankrupting itself by getting involved with saving Europe then sure the Germans might have had a chance.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
