<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27843014213.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Dogs aren't a real animal. They were invented by mankind. 

If there were no humans, there would be no dogs. A dog is, of course, a grey wolf that has been tamed and domesticated. 

There was purpose to that domestication. We, humans, created dogs to be our companions. We invented dogs to be our friends. To help us heard put sheep, to help us keep panthers at bay. 

But above all else, we invented dogs to give us love. And to love them in return. 

When we entered into a compact with the grey wolf 20,000 years ago, we told them, "you are now our companion and friend. You will work beside us and you will protect us. And we will be friends forever" 

By eating them, we violate 20,000 years of that compact. We violate the friendship of humanities first friend. 

Yea, humans domesticated other animals. the cow, the pig, but we did that for the sole purpose of food. We tamed wild bores and bovines to eat. Not to be our friends. And yes, we domesticated other animals to work as well as dogs: the horse. But the difference between the horse and the dog is that the dog is our companion and friend and then a work animal, were as a horse is a tool first. 

It is wrong to eat dogs because we invented dogs to be our friends. The only reason there are dogs is because humans wanted a companion. We did not create dogs to eat them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843092856.0" user="looeee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Dogs aren't a real animal. They were invented by mankind.

Ignoring for a second your strange idea of what constitutes a "real animal", the exact same argument applies to goats, pigs, cows, sheep, chickens and even pretty much all fruit and vegetables that we eat. None of them are in their wild form (for dogs this would be wolves), they have all been selectively bred for centuries to better suit our needs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843169284.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Did you not see the part where I said how we created dog to be our companions and horses to be our tools and pigs to be our food? 

I did address your point. Unless you would like some more clarification? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843774290.0" user="roderigo" delta="False">
    <text>your argument is extremely stupid.

cows aren't real animals since they were bred for a specific human need; same with pigs and chicken, then?

people have domesticated dog for food, same with horses. so the idea that animals are domesticated for a sole reason is historically wrong.

and the whole "compact" thing is laughable, since both parties have to agree to such thing, which animals in general can't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
