<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842769708.0" user="seiyonoryuu" delta="False">
    <text>While I generally agree with the sentiment, you also have to consider how they're being raised.  I'm going to give this to ya chiefly from an American standpoint.

The meat industry in the US is terrible.  But different animals feel pain differently, both emotional and physical.  For example, find a video of a cow getting castrated, then look up one for a horse.  A cow, you can just cut those suckers out, but a horse needs to be put under first.  Dogs take even longer to recover.  That's why we don't want animals like horses and dogs in the meat industry, not just because we're more attached.  The industry is horrific, but it would be so much more so if we put dogs and horses and the like in it, they'd go even crazier and suffer even more.

There's also the question of intelligence and whether the value of a life is affected by how intelligent the animal is. I suppose we could ask as well if other creatures are going to be affected by its dying.  Dogs are intelligent enough to have legitimate friends sometimes, ya know?  Cows, less so.  Humans, much, much more so.  (There's also the flavor-to-brains *ratio* to consider, hence why it's okay to eat delicious, delicious pigs despite their brainy nature.)

All things equal, I figure if you have a dog or a cow in front of you and you're just gonna kill one of them, then hey, it's not worth fussing over.  But that's not how it would really work in the real world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842841264.0" user="Pienix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The meat industry in the US is terrible. But different animals feel pain differently, both emotional and physical. For example, find a video of a cow getting castrated, then look up one for a horse. A cow, you can just cut those suckers out, but a horse needs to be put under first. Dogs take even longer to recover. That's why we don't want animals like horses and dogs in the meat industry, not just because we're more attached. The industry is horrific, but it would be so much more so if we put dogs and horses and the like in it, they'd go even crazier and suffer even more.

Except that in Western Europe (which is culturally not so far away from the US) it's pretty common to eat horse meat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843400142.0" user="seiyonoryuu" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I know.  And if they treat their horses the way we treat our cows, that's disgusting and awful and they should be ashamed.  (Not that we shouldn't be, too)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
