<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842734953.0" user="complete_misanthrope" delta="False">
    <text>I have two problems with dog meat.  i enjoy guinea pig and rabbit.  who cares if its cute or not, its the taste and how you use it.  cows, rabbits, lamb pig etc.  you kill them quickly, cleanly and then eat them.  even guinea pig you minimize pain.  my second problem is dog meat doesn't taste good, though that's personal taste.  

most places that eat dog meat i have a problem iwth because they intentionally torture the animals to make the meat "taste better"  which is both cruel and unusual punishment and affects the taste of the meat very badly.  fear makes meat taste like shit.  if they kill and cook dogs like any other meat im fine with it.  i've eaten lamma, veal, etc. and have no problem.  and yeah i'm white american.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843901217.0" user="twiifm" delta="False">
    <text>Dog tastes like duck.  What do you mean it doesn't taste good?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844105343.0" user="complete_misanthrope" delta="False">
    <text>depends how its made i guess.  also for me taste isn't as big as texture.  i don't like tough or gamey, though how it's cooked could probably fix that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844406603.0" user="twiifm" delta="False">
    <text>I've had it in Vietnam texture is like duck or deer.  They roast it w five spice so its similar to Chinese roast duck

A bit gamey like duck or mutton but not as bad as goat.

Definitely better than rabbit or turkey which I find too dry.

I saw a documentary where this dog meat seller also have dogs as pets.  The seller can differentiate between livestock and pets.

Just like some people could keep a miniature pot belly pig as pet and raise pigs for farming.

In Asia a lot of people keep dogs only outdoors for house guarding and there's dirty wild dogs roaming the streets.  Not all dogs are same.  Seems like in the West people only know one type of dog as a pet</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
