<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842652252.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>**Note:** Your thread has **not** been removed.
Your post's topic seems to be about a "double standard". These kinds of views are often difficult to argue here. Please see our [wiki page](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_double_standards) about this kind of view and make sure that your submission follows these guidelines.

Regards, the mods of /r/changemyview.  


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842683064.0" user="moshed" delta="False">
    <text>How the hell does this bot know that... impressive</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842686845.0" user="simobk" delta="False">
    <text>I thought exactly the same when I saw this!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842887601.0" user="TheNosferatu" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the word "hypocritical" usually has something to do with "double standards"

That would be my guess, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842914990.0" user="sophistry13" delta="False">
    <text>I'm convinced that the "bots" on reddit are just people with too much time on their hands. I've even made this post in reply to one of them and it came up with a witty retort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843062665.0" user="xahhfink6" delta="False">
    <text>You should make a bot that finds other bits and poses questions to see if they are actually just a person with too much free time.

And by make a bot I obviously mean just to do it yourself ;-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843071210.0" user="sophistry13" delta="False">
    <text>Turing Bot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842693430.0" user="Vonauda" delta="False">
    <text>Probably programmed to give this comment whenever the word "hypocritical" appears in the title</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842709239.0" user="moshed" delta="False">
    <text>yeah that makes sense. thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843134959.0" user="DownOnTheUpside" delta="False">
    <text>The singularity's arrived, looks like we're doomed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843140241.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>It's just looking for "hypocrit" and "double standard" (and maybe one or two other things, I don't remember what I chose to have it look for off the top of my head, and I'm too lazy to go look, even though it would have taken less effort than typing this sentence :-). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
