<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842721628.0" user="feelix" delta="False">
    <text>1. The practices are often extremely inhumane, doing things like beating the dogs to death and boiling them alive. [Link.](https://www.google.com/search?q=yulin+dog+meat+festival&amp;amp;num=100&amp;amp;biw=1920&amp;amp;bih=981&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=_FaKVZ_pAYOr-QHyuZC4CA&amp;amp;ved=0CAkQ_AUoAw&amp;amp;dpr=2)

2. There have not been any large scale dog farms found anywhere. And if you look at the dogs in photos and videos, you can see that they are former pets of people or are at the very least socialized. Most of the dogs are (usually pets) found on the street, and just snagged at any given opportunity.

3. Dogs have been domesticated to be friends with humans for so long that they [actually love us](http://www.foxnews.com/health/2013/10/08/neuroscientist-uses-mri-scans-to-show-that-dogs-have-emotions-similar-to-humans/.)

It is true that if you [take intensive pig farming](https://www.google.com/search?site=&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=1920&amp;amp;bih=981&amp;amp;q=intensive+pig+farming&amp;amp;oq=intensive+pig+farming&amp;amp;gs_l=img.3..0l2j0i5i30j0i24l7.1542.3946.0.4233.21.11.0.0.0.0.495.1383.2-4j0j1.5.0....0...1ac.1.64.img..16.5.1381.grn0A6wW3j0), for example, and consider the fact that pigs are as smart as or smarter than dogs, you can argue that it is close to being equally as wrong. I would say it is, but we have to start somewhere. Personally I don't eat intensively farmed animals and I do condemn intensive farming and eating dog meat alike. Any attention we can draw to these issues is good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842749710.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>OP explicitly framed this as a hypothetical question not related to actual differences in cruelty within any particular existing supply chain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842753665.0" user="shivishivi1997" delta="False">
    <text>The last thing you touched on with pigs makes complete sense! But you personally disagree with farming of animals, hence no hypocrisy. I think OP was going for the kind of people who eat mass farmed pigs, and then argue about dogs anyway.

The way I see it is that a country such as the UK or America have no right to tell China to stop mistreating animals until we stop in our own countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842758957.0" user="Lansan1ty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The practices are often extremely inhumane, doing things like beating the dogs to death and boiling them alive

That is true for almost all animals. There are pigs and cows who are abused an insane amount. We boil lobsters alive too, and cut off crab heads to kill them. Fishermen take fish out of the water in troves and let them suffocate basically until they die, or throw them into spaces more confined than anything you could think of. Might as well not eat any meat if you're worried about treating food "inhumanely".

&amp;gt;There have not been any large scale dog farms found anywhere. And if you look at the dogs in photos and videos, you can see that they are former pets of people or are at the very least socialized. Most of the dogs are (usually pets) found on the street, and just snagged at any given opportunity.

You're looking at cherry picked confirmation bias photos of people who are "outraged" that another culture eats something you see as a pet. OP pointed out there are dogs which are actually bred as livestock: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nureongi.

&amp;gt;Dogs have been domesticated to be friends with humans for so long that they actually love us

So they have emotions? So do pigs. 

http://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/pigs-exhibit-complex-emotions-claims-study-2037318.html

https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/animal-emotions/201307/are-pigs-smart-dogs-and-does-it-really-matter

It's really a form of thinking your culture is better than another and nothing more, OP is 100% correct in saying its hypocritical. I was never raised in a country which eats dogs or cats, but I don't think it's inhumane that there are people in the world who eat dogs or cats. There's nothing "humane" about a dog or a cat, they aren't humans. 

There are pet pigs in the USA, its not as common as dogs. Yet most Americans have zero problem eating pig. Tell them that Koreans eat dog meat though and they cry about how inhumane it is. Think about what pets are if you care about how humane something is. You raise an animal from captivity, generally leave it in your home or apartment all of its life, maybe with a few walks if it's a dog. Then it dies, in your home. Sure it thinks it loves you, you're the benevolent god who feeds it. If dogs are as intelligent as you might think, perhaps they can also suffer from Stockholm Syndrome. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842879756.0" user="wee_woo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That is true for almost all animals. There are pigs and cows who are abused an insane amount. We boil lobsters alive too, and cut off crab heads to kill them. Fishermen take fish out of the water in troves and let them suffocate basically until they die, or throw them into spaces more confined than anything you could think of. Might as well not eat any meat if you're worried about treating food "inhumanely".

[When can I come over to your house and watch you beat the shit out of stray dogs and then flay them alive?](http://www.dailymotion.com/video/x2uv1ew_cats-and-canines-crammed-into-cages-ahead-of-yulin-meat-festival_news)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843015438.0" user="bxk21" delta="False">
    <text>The next time we go hunting. What would you like? Deer? Turkey? As for the torture, Pre-tenderizing is a thing.

Again, as OP stated, the HOW is not what we're debating about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843477296.0" user="Lansan1ty" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, clearly this is exclusive to Cats and Dogs!! /s

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tKaCFyGdazo

I understand you find cats and dogs "Cute" so you think it's harsh that they do it, but as OP said in the topic, we're not here to discuss anything more than the consumption of their meat. Like I said and you seemed to take in some weird "we do it at home way" ANIMALS ARE MISTREATED GLOBALLY. I never said "at my house" read the paragraph you quoted. I'm talking about animals in farms in the USA, the people who supply your your hamburger meat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842787327.0" user="Regalian" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't the boiling/skinning the dog alive get debunked in the original thread where they're used to raise reaction from the readers? The skinning was from car crash, where people fed the dog to keep it clam. While boiling alive is scalding water to remove fur from a dead dog (much like what you do with chicken). Given strengths of dog even if you tie them up, having them knock over the pot or getting yourself burnt is quite likely if you boil them alive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
