<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27843322558.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>After taking a class on dog psychology and evolution it has been understood that dogs evolved solely to be our companions. The idea that this was the human's idea to breed wolves to dogs has been dismissed. The way dogs evolved is to rely heavily on human cues, movement and facial expression, which makes them a very special animal. No other animal has the empathy for humans that dogs do, his happiness is completely reliant on your hapiness. No other animal will look you in the eye, and no other animal (save humans and some highly developed apes and sea mammals) really gives a shit wether or not you are happy or sad. It has been speculated that dogs truly do love humans, in the same way that you love another human. So this book brings up the moral dilemma: is it right to kill a being who is so capable of love for you, just so that you can eat something that your diet doesn't depend on? The depth of their human-like emotion, being so like us, is it ridding the earth of one of it's "souls"? Or is it just another mound of food covered in fur on four legs? My heart says dogs are special understanding creatures, science says dogs are special understanding creatures, and when your dog looks you I. The eye, his face turning grey from the years you have spent bonding, and comforting each other, and he sees you smile at him, and he smiles back in his own way. Can you really say that this is not a creature with a soul, without empathy, without love? His kind is a good kind to our kind. Who has spent millennia in our direct service, does he truly deserve to be treated as a sack of meat? If you have as much empathy and compassion as a dog, but the foresight and knowledge of a human, you would answer no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844081642.0" user="FailClaw" delta="False">
    <text>That was a very compelling argument. It's especially great since you appealed mainly to the emotional side of things, which I usually don't think is a good way to make a point, but yours was fantastic. Both scientifically and emotionally dogs are our companions, have been for centuries, and we do not NEED to consume them in lieu of other, more purpose-bred animals. Thank you for your points. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845421596.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! I believe there is science behind our emotions. Usually when something *feels* wrong, there is a scientific reason why you feel that way. Anyhow thanks for reading.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844212062.0" user="thomasbomb45" delta="False">
    <text>This is what I was going to say, and you put it way better than I would have! Although it would be easier to read if split into paragraphs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845400551.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! Maybe you can tell me why, even though it's in paragraphs on my iPhone 5, as I write it, after I submit it, 
      it turns into one big block? I need some technical help, as you aren't the first person distracted by this phenomenon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845402634.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I just wrote that with paragraphs four spaces in and it reverted to block. It's very frustrating. And doesn't happen on my computer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845411748.0" user="thomasbomb45" delta="False">
    <text>Reddit formatting requires two line breaks to separate text into paragraphs. Between paragraphs, press enter twice.

Also, if you want to make a new line without a space between, use four spaces at the end of the line before you press enter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845445722.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks

How    

Is this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845447691.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Hurray!! You have just improved my reddit writing career so much thank you, thank you! I'm going to go upvote all of your posts now!

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845605175.0" user="thomasbomb45" delta="False">
    <text>No problem! Also I think that counts as vote manipulation so I wouldn't advise it lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27847290777.0" user="jackster_" delta="False">
    <text>Oh... Shoot. Well I didn't upvote ALL of them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
