<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842903830.0" user="flintlock_biro" delta="False">
    <text>It's kind of a controversial topic when it comes to ethics.

When we talk about eating meat, most people agree we don't eat other humans. Why? Health reasons, sure, but before we knew about that. I can't think of a human society that would deliberately breed other humans to eat. Because we like humans. They're smart. We feel guilt when we, eh, murder them.

What about chimps? Same problem. They're intelligent. We feel uncomfortable with the idea of farming them.

What about pigs? Very smart animals. We do eat them, but, historically many cultures have forbade their consumption.

Cows? Most people are pretty comfortable with eating cows. Vegetarians are still against it, but they're in a minority. Edit: /u/goldsnake pointed out that the cow is sacred in India, I actually did think of that but I supposed that it wasn't as significant as pigs being banned elsewhere. That was a pretty stupid thing to think in hindsight, hence this edit.

Fish? Even amongst the people who say they are vegetarians, some will eat fish. Why? We intrinsically understand a moral distinction between killing an orangutan and killing a clam. Why?

Plants? Very few people care if we hurt plants.

So if we can (loosely) agree that the degree of complexity to which a being can experience life has to be factored in when we talk about moral equivalency, even though it's kind of a cold way of looking at things, I believe that it *is* worse from a moral perspective to farm and eat a dog than it is to do the same to a cow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843019137.0" user="goldsnake" delta="False">
    <text>Just as a quick edit, you might also wanna mention the "minority" of ~ 1 billion people on the Indian subcontinent that don't eat cows</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843068873.0" user="Gejakiat" delta="False">
    <text>This naturally brings the question: where should we draw the line? At what degree of intelligence does this treatment become acceptable? Surely there are particularly intelligent cows and particularly stupid dogs. Is it more acceptable to feast on certain species of dog over others? Discuss (25 marks :p)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843092313.0" user="flintlock_biro" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah, like I said it's a controversial subject and there's no right answer. My understanding is that they actually do breed specific kinds of dogs for meat. I don't know but I imagine they're slower, less muscular, heavier etc. It's not like they're eating prize sheepdogs or family Labradors.

Things get even more complicated when we extend it to humans. We like to say that every human has inexorable human rights, but I think intuitively somebody would be more okay with pulling the plug on somebody after an accident leaves them in a vegetative state with the mental capacity of an &amp;lt;1 year old, versus an ordinary healthy human, however cruel and uncomfortable that makes us feel.

At the end of the day it is morality we're talking about, so personally I don't think we're ever going to be able to scientifically measure this stuff. Not like "a gorbluxian alien measures 12.5 intelligence units so legally we can kill and consume them." But as long as we *can* agree that there has to be a ethical distinction between eating a chimp and a lobster, I think it's fair to say that the relative intelligence of the creature *should* factor in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843085990.0" user="looeee" delta="False">
    <text>There is a good reason for forbidding the eating of pork in hot countries in times before refrigeration though: disease. 

Pork meat when it goes bad, goes very bad. See the first answer [here](https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080101201254AAfPd0x) for an in depth explanation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843099021.0" user="flintlock_biro" delta="False">
    <text>I've heard dozens of potential reasons why pork is banned in many religions and the short answer is *we don't exactly know why.*

I'm not a big fan of Christopher Hitchens but I do think this video on the subject is really good: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4LoWVkSyC0o</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843117619.0" user="Allen-H" delta="False">
    <text>Chimps are sometimes eaten in Africa, and eating chimpanzees also comes with health risks because they are closely related to humans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843460533.0" user="Quarter_Twenty" delta="False">
    <text>FWIW, clams are not fish. For that matter octopi seem to be extremely intelligent, and they're invertebrates. I don't think there's an intrinsically moral distinction. One is just more like us than the other. That's not a moral statement. Moral statements are "it's wrong (or right) to X because of Y reasons."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843505819.0" user="flintlock_biro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;FWIW, clams are not fish

Sure, but that's kind of missing the point.

&amp;gt;For that matter octopi seem to be extremely intelligent

Intelligent compared to what? Look I'm not saying it's a completely black and white delineation but as a general rule the more intelligent something is the less willing we are to abuse it. Dolphins are amongst the most intelligent species on the planet and we consider dolphin hunting to have major ethical ramifications, outside of them being endangered.

&amp;gt;That's not a moral statement. Moral statements are "it's wrong (or right) to X because of Y reasons."

Well, I just think that's false. Is "it's more wrong to X compared to Y because of Z reasons" or "X is usually unacceptable but in Y situations it may be a preferable option" not moral statements? Splitting things into black and white dichotomies are only ever going to bring you so far when we're dealing with morality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843545296.0" user="Quarter_Twenty" delta="False">
    <text>Native intelligence is clearly *not* a uniform standard by which we choose to abuse or not abuse animals. If it were, we would never harm a pig or goat--or a cow. The intelligence argument arises merely out of correlation, not causation, and isn't tied to moral underpinnings. CMV, if you think otherwise.

I believe what people choose to see as friend vs. food is strictly cultural and is taught to children from a young age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843938191.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What about pigs? Very smart animals. We do eat them, but, historically many cultures have forbade their consumption.

So how can someone who eats pork justify judging other people for eating dog?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844561416.0" user="awesomeoctopus98" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes but what about a dog and a pig? Pigs are smarter than dogs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844566125.0" user="awesomeoctopus98" delta="False">
    <text>I almost agree with you. I would actually syay that we think of this in terms of relateability rather than intelligence. For example pigs are much more intelligent than dogs but dogs are much more similar to humans in terms of their lifestyle. At least we percieve that they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844941674.0" user="Kiltmanenator" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder how many cultural proscriptions against pork consumption are actually based on their intelligence, and not sanitary reasons. I look at the Old Testament and the food rules on things like cloven hooves, cud chewing, dairy-meat combos, and shellfish don't seem to have anything to do with the intelligence of the animal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
