<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842686889.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Dogs have been bred for most of human history to be companions and working animals.  They've been selectively bred to be able to respond to human emotion, and to a lesser extent to express (or simulate expressing) it.  They've also been selected for the ability to evoke an emotional response in humans.

By comparison cows and pigs have been selectively breed to be food.  

That makes a huge difference. Killing and eating creatures that have evolved to have or mimic human emotion, to respond to human emotion, and to be companions is very different from killing and eating creatures than have evolved to be good to kill and eat.  

Not all meat is ethically the same, the animal it is taken from matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842693829.0" user="simobk" delta="False">
    <text>Again, what you're saying applies to the western civilization, not all civilizations.

In some regions of India, cows are sacred and aren't bread for food.

In Korea, the [Nureongi](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nureongi) dog is bred as live stock...

Finally, what about all the animals we eat but that we never bred to be food (ie hunting game)

Which brings me back to my initial question. We see dogs as special because **WE** see them as pets. Other cultures have different views...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842700247.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>I live in Korea. It is illegal to eat dogs here, though some people still choose to do it. The dogs that are bred as live stock still have the same emotional depth of other dogs, as shown by the many owners who rescue the dogs from breeding farms. 

/u/law-talkin-guy is 100% on point with his/her response. Eating an animal that has been bred for 40,000 years to love and trust humans is very different from eating animals which have been bred as food. If you can't see it, watch what happens to the cows when the farmer walks away versus what happens to the dogs when their owners leave the house. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842714162.0" user="WattsTolleDass" delta="False">
    <text>Partially true. In Korea, it's not illegal to bred, raise, or slaughter dogs for dog meat. It is illegal to process dogs like livestock and use dog meat as any kind of food product. 

http://animalrightskorea.org/dog-meat-issue/current-situation-of-koreas-dog-meat-industry.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842721376.0" user="Vegandalf_the_Grey" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you can't see it, watch what happens to the cows when the farmer walks away versus what happens to the dogs when their owners leave the house.

Farm cows are not raised as pets, so I'm doubtful about the utility of this comparison.

Watch what happens to humans when someone they don't know/like walks away vs. what happens to humans when someone they have a deep personal relationship with walks away.   Clearly the first humans are emotionless biological automata and suitable for slaughter and consumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842759404.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>A good farmer feeds and cares for his animals like they are family. Many times they name them. The animals still show no signs of attachment when they walk away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842815565.0" user="TripleOGeg" delta="False">
    <text>Says someone who has never worked on a farm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843020134.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Farm cows weren't created to be pets either. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842725368.0" user="Rwinterhalter" delta="False">
    <text>There's three restaurants where I can eat dog within 10 minutes from my apartment. Downtown in my city there's a dog stew restaurant with a giant fucking dog on the placard. Eating dog is totally legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842725570.0" user="ResoIve" delta="False">
    <text>Fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842763259.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't make it legal. There are dozens of brothels within 10 minutes from my house, many with scantily-dressed ladies in the windows, but prostitution isn't legal.

However, I *did* overstate my point. I guess currently it's a grey area. Dog meat is not technically illegal. However, it's also not legally considered to be a food as are beef and pork. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842753656.0" user="hwangerbanger" delta="False">
    <text>But although pigs weren't bred that way, they show as much emotion and are smarter than dogs. Does the fact that we bred them differently change the fact that in the present they should objectively receive the same positive treatment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842772796.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>That's a fantastic question. I haven't had any personal experience with pigs and have never read anything that would make me believe they have the emotional depth of dogs. I've seen the way my mom's dogs greet me after years of being away. I've read about dogs who stayed by their owners' graves until their own death. I know literature isn't exactly proof of anything, but here's a poem that captures the essence of dogs:

&amp;gt;Dès que le chien fut crée, il lécha la main du Bon Dieu et le Bon Dieu le flatta sur la tête : Que veux-tu, chien ?
 
&amp;gt;Seigneur Bon Dieu, je voudrais loger chez toi, au ciel, sur le paillasson devant la porte.
 
&amp;gt;Bien sûr que non, dit le Bon Dieu, je n’ai pas besoin de chiens, puisque je n’ai pas encore crée de voleurs.
 
&amp;gt;Quand les créeras-tu Seigneur ?
 
&amp;gt;Jamais, je suis fatigué, voilà cinq jours que je travaille. Il est temps que je me repose. Te voilà fait, toi, chien, ma meilleure créature, mon chef d’oeuvre, mieux vaut m’en tenir là. Il n’est pas bon qu’un artiste se surmène au déjà de son inspiration ; si je continuais à créer, je serais capable de rater mon affaire. Va chien, va vite t’installer sur Terre et sois heureux.
 
&amp;gt;Le chien poussa un profond soupir :
 
&amp;gt;Que ferai-je sur Terre, Seigneur ?
 
&amp;gt;Tu mangeras, tu boiras, tu croiras et tu multiplieras.
 
&amp;gt;Le chien soupira plus tristement encore.
 
&amp;gt;Que te faut-il de plus ? ….
 
&amp;gt;Toi, mon seigneur, Maître. Ne pourrais-tu pas, toi aussi t’installer sur Terre ?
 
&amp;gt;Non, dit le Bon Dieu, non chien, je t’assure, je ne peux pas m’installer sur Terre pour te tenir compagnie. J’ai bien d’autres chats à fouetter….Ce ciel, ces anges, ces étoiles, je t’assure c’est tout un tracas.
 
&amp;gt;Alors le chien baissa la tête et commença à s’en aller. Mais il revient :
 
&amp;gt;Ah, si seulement, Seigneur Bon Dieu, si seulement il y avait là-bas un espèce de maître de ton genre ?
 
&amp;gt;Non, dit le Bon Dieu, il n’y en a pas….
 
&amp;gt;Le chien se fit tout petit, tout bas et supplia plus près encore :
 
&amp;gt;Si tu voulais Seigneur Bon Dieu, tu pourrais toujours essayer…
 
&amp;gt;Impossible, dit le Bon Dieu, j’ai fait ce que j’ai fait, mon œuvre est achevée, jamais je ne créerai un être meilleur que toi…Si j’en créais un autre aujourd’hui, je le sens dans ma main droite, celui là serait raté…
 
&amp;gt;Seigneur Bon Dieu, dit le chien, ça ne fait rien qu’il soit raté, pourvu que je puisse le suivre partout où il va et me coucher devant lui quand il s’arrête.
 
&amp;gt;Alors le Bon Dieu fut émerveillé d’avoir crée une créature aussi bonne et il dit au chien :
 
&amp;gt;Va, qu’il en soit fait selon ton cœur. Et, rentrant dans son atelier, il créa l’homme….
 
&amp;gt;L’ homme est raté naturellement, le Bon Dieu l’avait bien dit….
Mais le chien est joliment content...

(L’œuvre du Sixième Jour de Marie Noël)

I can't imagine a culture anywhere writing such a thing about pigs, cows, or chickens. I've never thought pigs had such strong need for humans or have shown remorse at our absence or death. I'd be willing to read sources if you have evidence for it, though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842800077.0" user="hwangerbanger" delta="False">
    <text>From other sources as well, it's been shown that mice, chickens, and pigs all display empathy. Cows have been known to cry when losing their "best friends".

https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/animal-emotions/201307/are-pigs-smart-dogs-and-does-it-really-matter


But I suppose you mean that level of emotional depth. Which is answered here.

https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/animal-emotions/200910/grief-in-animals-its-arrogant-think-were-the-only-animals-who-mourn

The first article basically states that many animals are capable of deep emotional connection and the second confirms it. The reason it's okay to eat other animals is because we are conscientious beings and they are not. When we eat any animal capable of deep emotion, we shouldn't discriminate. We should discriminate based on conscientiousness, not emotion. 

P.S. I can't read that  poem</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844173789.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>First, I thought you might try google translate or even googling for a translation if you couldn't read French. [It wasn't very difficult](http://www.mmdigest.com/Archives/Digests/200912/2009.12.23.01.html). Still, as with all things, it's more beautiful in its original language.

I want to reiterate my criterion for dismissing pigs and cows. It wasn't that they're not emotional. It was that they're not emotionally connected to humans. That's a big difference. Is it bad when a stranger lies to you or cheats you? Yes. Is it a whole other trespass if the liar/cheater is not a stranger but your family or a close friend? Someone you've sacrificed for and loved? Absolutely. Therein lies the difference. It's a break in trust.

I'll be honest, on a moral ground, I have trouble deciding why I think it's OK to eat animals in general. I tell myself that it's a slippery slope. Do we stop eating just the mammals since they seem to be intelligent and emotional towards each other? Well, chickens may be dumb, but gosh aren't they cute? Besides, what would happen to chickens if we stopped raising them for food? Should we just cut out all farm animals? What would happen to those species if we did? They have been bred to be docile. They wouldn't survive long in nature - especially having to find their own food in limited space. Predators would quickly gobble them up, causing the predatory animal populations to swell. Then where do they go once their prey have all been eaten and they are starving? Into the town to scavenge for leftovers?

What about animals not kept on farms, like the octopus and squid, which are very smart for invertebrates. They problem-solve and have good memories. Heck, they seem downright playful at times! Shouldn't they get to live, too? Eventually, we're left with plants. But plants have been shown to have a system similar to our nervous system. Can they feel pain, too? I know people who swear plants grow better when you sing or talk to them. It's not truly emotional, but who are we to decide whose pain is important. What, then, can we still eat without guilt?

But I also second-guess myself. Do I have these thoughts because they make it easier for me to live the way I want to? Am I just fooling myself? It would be very difficult for me to cut animal products out of my every day life. I can't imagine how I would get all the nutrients I need without meat, eggs, dairy, etc. unless I dedicated every spare moment of my life (of which I have few) to my diet. I've done that in the past when I was trying to maintain a smaller waist. Not only was it exhausting and expensive - I developed an eating disorder.

In the end, I come back to why I feel the dog is different. We built a trust with them. We've bonded over tens of thousands of years. We promised to feed and protect them so long as they help and protect us. There is no other animal on the planet that has this sort of relationship with humans. To turn around and eat them seems, deep down in my bones, to be a betrayal. So.... yes. The purpose we bred into animals does make a difference to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844218112.0" user="hwangerbanger" delta="False">
    <text>Well duh, I didn't see the value in translating a poem when I could use one meant to be in english. 

Ok with that, the idea is that we should eat animals that don't have the capacity to understand the pain they're in. That's why we can eat fish or insects and no one cares. I do think octopi shouldn't be eaten though. 

As far as plants go, they can't even think, so that isn't valid. That's like saying if you grew a pain receptor in the lab and hit it a bunch of times, it would be inhumane. 

Dairy and eggs are also a different argument here.

We haven't bonded with a single dog for thousands of years, we've just had them evolve next to us. If that's the case, then pet birds and guinea pigs should be treated the same. Yet we have no problem with other cultures eating them. 

So what if pigs didn't grow next to us. They grew up in their own communities. They socialized, developed emotions, and became somewhat more intelligent. Other animals haven't had that long of a relationship, but pigs, dolphins, primates, etc. are able to have bonds just as strong as a dog, if not more. To take preference for dogs just because we have an evolutionary connection with them is unfair. It's an irrational emotional bond connected to guilt, that alienates other species. That's not loyalty and trust, that's nepotism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842821974.0" user="TripleOGeg" delta="False">
    <text>You're mistaking dependency for love.

Pigs are proven to be more intelligent than dogs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842805446.0" user="minqj" delta="False">
    <text>Contrary to popular belief, cows aren't mindless automatons. They have lots of emotional depth too! http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2011/jul/07/cows-best-friend

Also I'm not sure if I agree with your example; cats have been bred to "love and trust humans" but they're still real dicks and couldn't care less if their owner has left the house or not. Why should that be the criteria for whether it is ethical for certain animals to be killed and eaten?

I don't think it follows that if an animal has been bred for food, they are inherently less capable of emotional depth than other animals. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843158691.0" user="sindeloke" delta="False">
    <text>You've clearly not had much experience with cats. An animal that will shit in your laundry to punish you for going on vacation is not an animal that doesn't care that you're gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842812896.0" user="TripleOGeg" delta="False">
    <text>That's bullshit and you've clearly never been on a dairy farm.

Cows are gentle and friendly, they follow you around like a dog, they lick your face and love attention like scratching or petting, they're intelligent enough to remember specific people and what those people are like and they bring themselves in to pasture every morning/evening because they're intelligent enough to know it's milking time.

They get just as sad when you leave them, it's just we're more receptive to dogs responses and dogs tend to panic because they can't imagine life without you. I don't think 'sad because you're leaving' and 'sad because they're totally dependant on you' are the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843036086.0" user="kimchi_station" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It is illegal to eat dogs here, though some people still choose to do it

I feel that is a little misleading considering [(korean language link warning)it is the 5th most common meat consumed, 55.3% of all adults have tried it, and over 2 million dogs are slaughtered for food every year](http://www.pressian.com/news/article.html?no=10793). It would be more accurate to say "It is really only illegal on paper". The cities have dozens if not hundreds of dog meat restaurants that clearly say 개장국 or 보신탕 in big letters on the signs. In fact if you are ever in Daegu just go to Bukbu Bus Terminal and you can find about 10 restaurants there or better yet go to Chilsong Market and you can pick a dog already skinned and hanging or pick a live one out of a cage and they will butcher it for you right there. I ride my motorcycle all around Korea and have seen countless farms with dozens of dogs in tiny cages in plain view of the road, and they make no effort to hide the sight or ungodly smell.


The **only** time I heard about the police doing **anything** about dog meat is when those pictures surfaced of [that dog getting hanged by a metal wire and burned with a blow torch](http://www.koreaobserver.com/undocumented-indonesian-arrested-for-killing-dog-in-korea-26612/)(semi-nsfw), and the ones they arrested were all South Asian migrant workers. I have never in the years I have lived here ever heard of a Korean being punished for dog meat.

Dog meat is illegal just like [prostitution is illegal](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prostitution_in_South_Korea), and just like no one with two eyes and a hard cock has to walk more than 25 minutes to find a hooker here, anyone with an empty stomach can easily find meat that came from some dog that was beaten to death by a middle aged man and a shovel. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844181015.0" user="energirl" delta="False">
    <text>Illegal on paper means illegal. I responded to another poster with exactly the argument you gave: that just because I can find prostitutes all over the place doesn't mean prostitution is legal. 

I have friends who eat dog and still celebrate the festival. I don't try to talk them out of it or lecture them on it.... but that doesn't mean I like it, and that doesn't mean it's legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842702534.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying applies to the history of the species - dogs, cows, pigs, etc. - not to any particular civilization.

Dogs are special because they were sleceted in prehistory to be workign companion animals - that there are breeds (is a breed) in recent times created to be livestock, doesn't change this fact any more than the fact that we now have toy poodles changes the fact that poodles were historicaly breed as hunting dogs.  Unless the breeding of this livestock dog has selected against the traits that make dogs good companions, a fact the article you link to doesn't suggest is true, then the core argument remains.  Dogs, even those now raised as livestock, are the result of selective breeding designed to make them companions.  

The reverse is true of cattle.  Even in India.  The modern cow is a result of selective breeding to create a good livestock creature.  To breed food without any history of breeding for human emotion or behaviors.  Cattle have never been selectively breed to show or respond to human emotion.  They've been breed to be docile, produce lots of meat, and produce lots of milk.

This is not about how a particular culture sees a particular species today.  it is about what the nature of a species is and the human responsibility for the nature of that species.

It's one thing to breed a creature to be good food and then use it as food.  It's entirely another to breed it to be a companion and then use it as food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842726366.0" user="PrototypeNM1" delta="False">
    <text>Does this argument also hold for a animal testing? If it holds to dogs then why not for other primates which have similar traits as a result of having a common ancestor to humans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842734091.0" user="Lord_Jeebus" delta="False">
    <text>I think this gets into the whole 'do the means justify the ends' argument. Primates are used to produce medicines and such that work on humans, because as you said, humans and primates are extremely similar genetically. I'm personally not sure if the means justify the ends, it's largely a matter of opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843060609.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know enough about the behavioral traits of primates in general to make a blanket statement one way or another.  But my sense is yes it would also hold in such a situation.  Though that's just my gut instinct and I could be totally wrong about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842737990.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is still culturally subjective and biased. Why must the people living in China today be beholden to the breeding decisions of long dead people from other cultures? Regardless of how the dogs were bred, these people may not view or value them as companions, only food. So far as we can tell, dogs don't have complex emotions the way humans do - mimicry is as close as they get and is insufficient to afford them special protection. Until an animal is endangered or found to be sentient they're free game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842982235.0" user="callthezoo" delta="False">
    <text>Not even remotely subjective or biased. OP asked said it is "hypocritical" to shun other cultures for eating dogs if your culture eats other animals. But this is a scientific, evolutionary argument as to why dogs are genetically different from any other species in terms of their relationship with humans. Chinese people might not agree with it, but by no means is it "hypocritical".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844055033.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>Why does them being bred for companionship in any way alter their fitness for consumption once they are dead? A dead dog is not anybody's companion - it's just meat at that point. It would actually be far better to at least make use of said meat by consuming it rather than letting it rot in the ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843018302.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>That is not how it works. 

Dogs were invented to be friends from the get go. Just because some people 8,000 years later decided to go against the previous 12,000 years of evolution does not mean what they are doing is right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844049211.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't mean what they are doing is wrong either. All moral choices are inherently subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843078040.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why must the people living in China today be beholden to the breeding decisions of long dead people from other cultures?

Becasue the impacts of those choices are true.  they exist in the world, reguardless of what your culture says.

If your religion or culture teaches that there are enough natural resources for everyone to have as much as they want, you are entitled to believe that.  But no matter how much you believe it, no matter how deeply held the belief, the amount of natural resources in the world are not changed.  

&amp;gt;Until an animal is endangered or found to be sentient they're free game.

So you agree with me that the position of the OP which is all meat is morally equivalent is false.  You just disagree on where to draw the line.  

I think you are drawing the line in the wrong place (If the goal is to protect species from extinction, why draw the line at endangered?  why not at threatened?  why care about extinction at all?  If the goal is to protect sentient species why require proof?  Why not suspicion?  And what about non-sentient members of the species?  Is it okay to eat the meat of an aborted fetus?)

It think it makes more sense to draw the moral line at what the behavior says about the person than the impact on the physical world - and I'd argue that killing dogs, which so closely mimic human emotions that it's hard not to respond as if they had them (or which actually have them) says very bad things about the person doing or ordering the killing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844047584.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between this and your hypothetical culture is that it can be empirically determined whether there are enough resources or not. A moral decision such as what should or should not be eaten cannot be similarly tested.

As for my comment on endangered and sentient species: I should have made myself clearer. It is only the act of killing of such creatures which I would oppose; the former because I personally respect the idea of biodiversity and would thus wish to minimize the number of species which go extinct due to human intervention, and the latter because I would consider such killing to be murder. Once they're dead then absolutely, meat is meat, regardless of its source. Even in the case of a fetus, if somebody wanted to eat one for some odd reason and it wasn't to be used for some better purpose such as potentially life-saving research. It's already dead, and thus has no more right to moral consideration than a stone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844059536.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The difference between this and your hypothetical culture is that it can be empirically determined whether there are enough resources or not. A moral decision such as what should or should not be eaten cannot be similarly tested.

The religion/culture I describe is far from hypothetical - pleanty of Christians believe this as an easy example.  

Why can't moral decisions, in your view, be tested the same way that the abundence of resources be tested?

&amp;gt;As for my comment on endangered and sentient species: I should have made myself clearer. It is only the act of killing of such creatures which I would oppose; the former because I personally respect the idea of biodiversity and would thus wish to minimize the number of species which go extinct due to human intervention, and the latter because I would consider such killing to be murder.

But that makes the view subjective - it's about what you view as moral, not an objective standard.  And my point was you can't advance this subjective standard while at the same time objecting to my position on the grounds that it is subjective.  If being subjective is grounds for objecting to a moral view, then it must apply to your view as well and if not, then what is the objection to my view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844096579.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>What empirical data could be used? All moral decisions are inherently subjective. To be otherwise would require them to be the same regardless of interpreter or agent. The question of whether it's ok for humans to eat dogs matters only to humans, and can therefore never be purely objective. One would have to say that it is wrong for dogs to be eaten at all and provide objective evidence in support of that stance. Is it morally wrong for a wolf or lion to eat a dog? What about if a chimpanzee ate a dog? No? Then why is it wrong for a human to do so? We are, after all, only intelligent apes. Yes? On what grounds? 
I never said your opinions are wrong based on their subjectivity, only that they are subjective. I do not claim objectivity for my moral views nor do I claim they are inherently superior or inferior to any others. They may only be judged on their own merits and the merits of the arguments used to justify them, which are themselves subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843215832.0" user="SomeKindWords" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's false. I have seen my dog show compassion at a young age that there is no chance I taught it to him. I was floored and inspired by the way he reacted to a situation with my cat in which my cat was mean to him, I put the cat outside, the cat hated that so he begged me to open the door, and then he celebrated that the cat was allowed back in with a victory lap around the couch.

He views the cat as part of the pack and is upset when anyone in the pack is in trouble. My dog is one of the more emotional and empathetic breads, so maybe that explains it.

Then the cat noticed what he did for her, and started being a tad kinder. She stopped being so scared and will approach him now and allow him to be near her without freaking out. I was floored by the emotional spectrum I witnessed from my animals that day, and humbled by it. I had previously thought that they were too primitive to feel anything so complex as compassion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844022050.0" user="Grahammophone" delta="False">
    <text>Personal anecdotes prove nothing. Even if they did, your dog would never have had to learn compassion-like behaviour if it had been bred into him as instinct. Same goes for the cat. Instinct =! Compassion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845095176.0" user="SomeKindWords" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you can say that anything is bred into them, but it isn't. Especially not for cats, as they were never even domesticated and that's why they ignore you despite scientific evidence that they can understand human speech better than dogs. I know lots and lots of people that say animals' emotions are largely underestimated, and more and more studies are being published to say the same. I don't have any bookmarked on this computer, but I'm sure if would not be hard to find some of these with a Google search.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842747494.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's one thing to breed a creature to be good food and then use it as food. It's entirely another to breed it to be a companion and then use it as food.

So in your view, what makes it wrong to kill dogs as food?  Because that's not the best way to use them?  I'm having a hard time seeing how the way human beings have bred the animal makes it better or worse to kill it and eat it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843089761.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Largely the ablity of dogs to express human emotion (or mimic it so closely as to induce humans to believe they are expressing human emotion).  A dog in pain or suffering or happy or nervous and so on is able to communicate that to you as efficiently (if not more so) than a pre-verbal child.  Ignoring those cues and the responses they engender in you is in and of itself wrong.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843168142.0" user="JustAManFromThePast" delta="False">
    <text>What about a retardate unable to communicate?  We can fry and batter him?  What about pigs, which have been proved SMARTER than dogs, and more emotionally intelligent.  I eat pork too, because I'm weak, and don't go through mental gymnastics to make me a good person.  It isn't about intelligence, otherwise we'd eat retardates, instead, it is about pain and pleasure, and even fish demonstrate a feeling of pain, noxious taxia.  What if aliens came and wanted to hunt and eat men, you'd have a problem with it, but all your arguments could be turned to theirs.  Eating meat is bad, even if natural, slavery and racism are more natural than eating meat, while their are societies and cultures throughout time and the world none have ever lacked racism or slavery, until very recently.  Hopefully, the same thing will happen with the giving of pain to things which can feel pain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843206874.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Your making a leap from this is the relevant distinction between dogs and pigs and cows, to this is the only relevant distinction.  I'm not saying it's the only morally relevant factor.  I'm saying it is one morally relevant factor.  

&amp;gt;What if aliens came and wanted to hunt and eat men, you'd have a problem with it, but all your arguments could be turned to theirs.

Unless it is your contention that aliens have been selectively breeding humans for the past 10,000 years or so to be livestock, I don't think that my argument would support that conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843214790.0" user="JustAManFromThePast" delta="False">
    <text>If little green men came down with shrink rays, a innate knowledge of quantum mechanics at 2 the way we begin to count, you could argue, be it the truth or not, that we were not selectively bred?  And why would it make it better, wouldn't add to their crime, consider if aliens had said, "Don't worry, as we screeched and ran, your whole existence has been building up to this, we ordained it!", we'd stop, and take comfort in it?  Again, start trying to kill a cow, they clearly don't like it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843241374.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If little green men came down with shrink rays, a innate knowledge of quantum mechanics at 2 the way we begin to count, you could argue, be it the truth or not, that we were not selectively bred?

No you couldn't.  If it isn't true, then it isn't true.  Have little green men been directing human evolution to make us livestock?  If yes, then in that regard we are like cows (though there are other morally relevant distinctions).  If no, then we are not like cows.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843169323.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the ablity of dogs to express human emotion (or mimic it...

Well, by this way of determining whether a living being's suffering is morally relevant, it would be more ethical to slaughter and eat a person who's been paralyzed than it would be slaughter a healthy dog. :/

Your emotional expression / mimicry based ethic has serious flaws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843199436.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>No.  I'm not suggesting that's the only ethical criteria.  I'm saying it is one of the relevant distinctions between dogs and cows and pigs.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843204303.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that it is ethically relevant.  To me, what makes something good or bad is what effect it has on some sentient being, and whether that sentient being suffers more or suffers less because of it.  Whether I can understand it or not doesn't matter one bit - it might lead to me making ethical mistakes, but it does nothing to change *what is right or wrong*.  It's wrong to torture dogs, because it hurts the dogs.  It's wrong to torture cows, because it hurts the cows.  I don't see any distinction at all.

If I also used your criteria, it could only lead to errors.  I might think it was less wrong to torture a developmentally disabled child than it was to torture a healthy child, because I can't relate to the developmentally disabled child's emotions as easily.  Or I might think that torturing a dolphin isn't as bad as torturing a cat, when in truth, it's probably worse to torture the dolphin (as dolphins are more intelligent and aware, and will therefore suffer more).  What good is an ethical criteria that produces errors like that?  It only complicates and confuses the issues.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843233718.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I also used your criteria, it could only lead to errors. I might think it was less wrong to torture a developmentally disabled child than it was to torture a healthy child, because I can't relate to the developmentally disabled child's emotions as easily.

 I'm not suggesting that's the **only** ethical criteria.  You could only reach that conclusion if it were the only ethical critera.  

&amp;gt;It's wrong to torture dogs, because it hurts the dogs. It's wrong to torture cows, because it hurts the cows. I don't see any distinction at all.

Torture is not the same as killing for food.  It's wrong to torture.  Full stop.  It's wrong no matter what.

It is not wrong to kill for food in all cases.  The question is in which cases is it moral to kill for food and in which cases is it not.  I've sugested one way of deciding when it is not okay to kill for food (and agian, because you seem confused on this point, it is one of many ways and not the only way).  On that criteria it would be ethical to kill cows and pigs for food but not dogs.  On other criteria (sentience, for example) it is not okay to kill dolphins for food and okay to kill cows and pigs.  On other criteria (humanity, for example) it is not okay to kill developmentally disabled humans and is okay to kill cows and pigs.  

But the exact lines for all meat eating don't mater here - and I'm not sure I could draw them with precision if they were needed.  We can clearly distinguish dos from pigs and cows in a morally relevant way, which is enough to show that it isn't hypocritical to object to eating dogs while still eating cows and pigs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843276598.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not suggesting that's the only ethical criteria. You could only reach that conclusion if it were the only ethical critera. 

No, no.  I could only reach the conclusion that one is perfectly ok and the other is wrong if that were my only criteria.  But using both a sane criteria (actions are wrong if they cause suffering and there is an alternative that causes less) and your criteria could lead me to think that two things that cause equal suffering are not equivalent, only because one of them isn't as emotionally salient *to me, the observer*.  That would be a mistake.  My example isn't black and white, good vs evil - it's a case that would be clear-cut that's made fuzzy if you judge with fuzzy logic.

My point is this:  your suggested way is a poor way of deciding ethical questions, and should be disregarded in favor of superior means.  Human emotional salience is simply not a good ethical criterion.  It produces all kinds of errors.  It awards ethical status to robots and television screens, if they look cute enough; it reduces the ethical status of retards and animals that don't resemble us visually.  It makes no sense to use, even as *one factor*, because that factor simply introduces error into what could have been a pure and rational judgement based on a superior ethical criterion (such as the suffering caused by a proposed course of action).

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843293828.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But using both a sane criteria (actions are wrong if they cause suffering and there is an alternative that causes less) and your criteria could lead me to think that two things that cause equal suffering are not equivalent, only because one of them isn't as emotionally salient to me, the observer. That would be a mistake.

I agree that would be a mistake.  I also think that would require misunderstanding the criteria I suggested.  I also also think you could make the same mistake with just your "sane criteria" - I could easily assume that suffering is only occurring when I observe it and fall into the same error.

&amp;gt;It makes no sense to use, even as one factor, because that factor simply introduces error into what could have been a pure and rational judgement based on a superior ethical criterion (such as the suffering caused by a proposed course of action).

How do you measure suffering?  How is it quantified?  How do you determine in advance which course of action will minimize it?

Suffering isn't subject to "pure and rational judgment" because it is inherently subjective.  Does dropping a hammer on my toe cause more or less suffering than being turned down for a date?  Does killing a cow quickly and painlessly cause more or less suffering than not being able to afford steak?  Does committing suicide cause more or less suffering than living a full life?  You can't measure it, you can't compare it, it isn't subject to an objective analysis.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843359084.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I could easily assume that suffering is only occurring when I observe it and fall into the same error.

This would be an error in your ability to determine the facts of the situation, though - not an error produced by the ethical criterion itself.

&amp;gt;How do you measure suffering? How is it quantified? 

This is an important question, and one which has been written on and debated extensively by ethicists and other philosophers.  It is not an insurmountable problem for any ethical theory.  It's also equally a problem for just about any ethical theory, though.  How do you measure and quantify whatever it is that you use to determine how good or bad an action is?  Every ethical theory has this same problem.

&amp;gt;Suffering isn't subject to "pure and rational judgment" because it is inherently subjective. Does dropping a hammer on my toe cause more or less suffering than being turned down for a date? Does killing a cow quickly and painlessly cause more or less suffering than not being able to afford steak? Does committing suicide cause more or less suffering than living a full life? You can't measure it, you can't compare it, it isn't subject to an objective analysis.

Hmm...

The way I see it, the only comparisons that are relevant are those between two possible outcomes in a single moral dilemma - so let's consider cow slaughter vs steak, since it depends the least on worldviews about life after death, what makes a good life, and so on.

What causes more suffering - instantly, painlessly killing a cow, or denying some people the experience of eating that cow?  It seems that by definition, the cow's death causes no suffering at all, so we'd better slaughter it and feed it so as not to disappoint anybody.  This is a problem for an ethical theory where actions are only wrong if they cause suffering, and there is nothing wrong with depriving goodness - the potential for this cow to go on living a good life is irrelevant, so as long as it causes *any suffering at all* to deny people the opportunity to eat its body, we have to say it's better to kill the cow.

We could invoke an ethical theory that takes good experiences and bad both into account, and seek the best balance of the two.  In that case, it might be wrong to kill the cow painlessly unless greater goodness could be derived by eating its body than would be loss by depriving it of its remaining years of life.  So it'd probably be good to kill it if some people would otherwise starve, or if the cow was going to die soon anyway (which seems about right).

This is probably better than invoking a theory based on human perception of cow emotions, which would probably not have anything to say anyway - this cow is not going to express any emotions during its instantaneous, painless death.  So your idea would imply that it was ok to kill the cow - or any being at all - any time, so long as it's instant and painless.

Incidentally, there is no existent system of meat commerce that involves painless slaughter, nor that slaughters animals that weren't raised to be slaughtered - usually raised in terrible conditions that cause immense suffering.  So the hypothetical is irrelevant to the realities of any actual case of mass meat production.  Even a strictly suffering-based ethic would find almost all modern meat production to be clearly, unequivocally unethical.

&amp;gt;You can't measure it, you can't compare it, it isn't subject to an objective analysis.

I disagree.  You can't measure it, sure.  But we can certainly compare.  It's rough, but it's better than nothing.  Just because our ability to judge these things is limited by subjectivity, does not mean it'd be better to make no judgements at all and declare all ethical propositions to be equivalent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843464576.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  How do you measure and quantify whatever it is that you use to determine how good or bad an action is? Every ethical theory has this same problem

No.  Every consequentialist ethical theory that claims to be purely objective has this problem.  That's a small subset of all ethical theories.  

&amp;gt;Incidentally, there is no existent system of meat commerce that involves painless slaughter, nor that slaughters animals that weren't raised to be slaughtered - usually raised in terrible conditions that cause immense suffering. So the hypothetical is irrelevant to the realities of any actual case of mass meat production. Even a strictly suffering-based ethic would find almost all modern meat production to be clearly, unequivocally unethical.

I disagree with you on the facts here, but assume for the moment that it is true.  Why?  If I can't eat steak I will suffer some amount and if McDonalds can't sell hamburgers a bunch of people will suffer some amount and if we raise cows they will suffer some amount.  We all agree on that, but if minimizing suffering is what we are after, how do we decide which path achieves that goal?  

Suffering as a metric is useless because it isn't capable of being measured.  I have no way of knowing or measuring how much a cow suffers.  I can't do it.  I can guess at it, I can try to intuit it, but I can't measure or know it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844233352.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you ignored most of what I said...I'm having a hard time taking this as a serious attempt at conversation.  But ok...

&amp;gt;No. Every consequentialist ethical theory that claims to be purely objective has this problem. That's a small subset of all ethical theories. 

This is too narrow, I believe.

(Incidentally, you've misunderstood me to be supporting a purely objective theory, which I am not)

If quantified measurement is a requirement for a consequentialist theory, then it seems it would be a problem for any theory that bases ethical status on any non-binary variable.  It's equally a problem if you base your system on whether emotions are being communicated to human beings or not - how much are they communicated?  A lot?  42%?  How do you decide?

You can't, of course.  So you must accept this as a limitation of any theory that depends on a non-binary variable.  Binaries don't have this problem: if you base ethics on a system of laws, you can determine well enough whether this or that legal condition was met or not, and limitation of measurement is of a different kind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844310950.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well, you ignored most of what I said...I'm having a hard time taking this as a serious attempt at conversation. But ok...

I didn't respond to your analysis comparing the suffering caused by killing a cow quickly and painlessly to the suffering of not eating a steak, because the question was rhetorical and you dodged the thrust of the question.  it didn't seem worth getting into.

I didn't respond to your last point because I missed it, and that was my mistake - especially as I think it's the heart of the issue.

&amp;gt; You can't measure it, sure. But we can certainly compare. It's rough, but it's better than nothing. Just because our ability to judge these things is limited by subjectivity, does not mean it'd be better to make no judgements at all and declare all ethical propositions to be equivalent.

But, no one is saying that we should declare all ethical propositions to be equivalent.  That's a straw-man.  And moving away from suffering as a metric because it can't be measured doesn't leave you with nothing.  There are plenty of other ethical systems that don't rest on measuring the unmeasurable.  Sure it's better than nothing, but so are all the other real alternatives.  by framing the discussion as so e sort of consequentialism or nothing you've cut out most of the field for no reason at all.

&amp;gt;(Incidentally, you've misunderstood me to be supporting a purely objective theory, which I am not)

When you talk about "a pure and rational judgement based on a superior ethical criterion (such as the suffering caused by a proposed course of action)" you certantly seem to be saying that your prefred system is objective.  I'm open to arguments for how a subjective system can include a pure and rational judgment - but from where I'm sitting rationality demands objectivity.

&amp;gt;If quantified measurement is a requirement for a consequentialist theory, then it seems it would be a problem for any theory that bases ethical status on any non-binary variable. 

I have no idea what you mean by "bases ethical status on any non-binary variable".  That said, quantified measurement is only a problem when you demand a quantifiable metric.  "Cause the least suffering" requires being able to quantify suffering.  "Don't eat companions"  simply requires being able to recognize companions there is nothing to measure there.  

 &amp;gt;  It's equally a problem if you base your system on whether emotions are being communicated to human beings or not - how much are they communicated? A lot? 42%? How do you decide?

But that's not my view, my view is that the ability to communicate emotions to humans is one way we identify companion animals.  I don't need to know what percent is begin communicated just that some are.

&amp;gt;You can't, of course. So you must accept this as a limitation of any theory that depends on a non-binary variable. Binaries don't have this problem: if you base ethics on a system of laws, you can determine well enough whether this or that legal condition was met or not, and limitation of measurement is of a different kind.

I'm not sure exactly what you are saying here, but it seems you're over simplifying the matter some.  Rules based ethical systems may or may not have the same problem as the system I understand you to be advocating.  But I'm not sure what you mean by "limitation of measurement is of a different kind."  In a rules based and non-consequentialist system there is no need to measure anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844341376.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; from where I'm sitting rationality demands objectivity

I don't believe that it does.  Rational thought is a subjective experience in exactly the same way that emotions are.  Rationality can be used to convey inter-subjective or perhaps objective statements very easily, and emotionality cannot.  But rationality *is a subjective experience*, and can be applied to subjective experience just as well as it can be to supposedly objective reality.

For example, I could count how many times I felt happy today.  Tomorrow, I could tell you: I was happy 37 times yesterday.  It's a perfectly rational (in this case, mathematical) judgement based on observation of totally irrational, purely subjective emotional phenomena.  It isn't objective - only I can make the observation.  But it is rational.

&amp;gt;But that's not my view, my view is that the ability to communicate emotions to humans is one way we identify companion animals. I don't need to know what percent is begin communicated just that some are.

Ah - so you're actually promoting a rule-based ethic....something like "companion animals should not be eaten."

This is what I'm getting at about binaries.  A binary is a variable that can either be true, or false (or 1 or 0 - it has two possible values).  Rule-based ethics, such as "things in category X should not be killed for food", are essentially a series of rules based on binary variables.  You're either a companion animal, or you're not.  This is why they don't have the same measurement problem as systems dependent on continuous variables (e.g. suffering, which can be great or small or anything in between).

They have plenty of other problems, though.

In a rule-based system, you still need to determine whether a rule has been satisfied, whether condition X is met or not met in each specific case.  Is this animal a companion, or isn't it?  That isn't a trivial question.  It also isn't as big a problem as the measurement of continuous things like suffering, which could be anywhere on a broad scale of values.

But more importantly - *why should anybody care if an animal is a companion to human beings*?  What relevance does this have to whether it's wrong to kill that animal for food?  I get that this would be convenient if you wanted to go around believing it was ok to slaughter pigs, and not ok to slaughter dogs, but *convenience doesn't motivate an ethical claim.*  What's so great about being a human companion, that it demands ethical status?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844431551.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't believe that it does. Rational thought is a subjective experience in exactly the same way that emotions are. Rationality can be used to convey inter-subjective or perhaps objective statements very easily, and emotionality cannot. But rationality is a subjective experience, and can be applied to subjective experience just as well as it can be to supposedly objective reality.

On that account there is no such thing as objectivity.  All thought is a subjective experience in that way.  You've defined objectivity out of existence.  Yet, objectivity exists.  So there is a problem with your definition.

&amp;gt;For example, I could count how many times I felt happy today. Tomorrow, I could tell you: I was happy 37 times yesterday. It's a perfectly rational (in this case, mathematical) judgement based on observation of totally irrational, purely subjective emotional phenomena. It isn't objective - only I can make the observation. But it is rational.

That only I can make an observation doesn't mean it isn't objective.  I can objectively observe my own subjective states.  When I feel happy that's a subjective experience, when I observe "I am feeling happy right now" that is an objective experience.  That I am the only one who can observe my subjective states does not impact the objectivity of those observations.

&amp;gt;This is what I'm getting at about binaries. A binary is a variable that can either be true, or false (or 1 or 0 - it has two possible values). Rule-based ethics, such as "things in category X should not be killed for food", are essentially a series of rules based on binary variables. You're either a companion animal, or you're not. This is why they don't have the same measurement problem as systems dependent on continuous variables (e.g. suffering, which can be great or small or anything in between).

I can see that now.

&amp;gt;They have plenty of other problems, though.

Yes, yes they do.

&amp;gt;In a rule-based system, you still need to determine whether a rule has been satisfied, whether condition X is met or not met in each specific case. Is this animal a companion, or isn't it? That isn't a trivial question. 

You are right it isn't a trivial question.  But I don't see that as a problem for my postion.  It's an unfortunate fact, that following ethical rules is hard, in part because we don't always know when the rules apply.  But, it's a fact of reality, and I don't see that much can be done on that front.

&amp;gt;But more importantly - why should anybody care if an animal is a companion to human beings? What relevance does this have to whether it's wrong to kill that animal for food? I get that this would be convenient if you wanted to go around believing it was ok to slaughter pigs, and not ok to slaughter dogs, but convenience doesn't motivate an ethical claim. What's so great about being a human companion, that it demands ethical status?

I don't think there is always a clear why for an ethical rule - at some point it is a brute fact.  "X is the rule" because "X is the rule".  And the answer to why is simply because it is.  (Much like the answer to why the speed of light is whatever it is is because that is what the speed of light is).  

In this case though the answer to why is because companion animals are not just objects but also subjects.  Humans can enter into an "I/thou" relationship with companion animals (in Martin Buber's sense).  While livestock are objects and not subjects.  We can only enter into "I/it" relationships with cows.  Confronted with the other we are indebted to the other and owe it certain obligations - including to refrain from killing the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844517557.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;On that account there is no such thing as objectivity. All thought is a subjective experience in that way. You've defined objectivity out of existence. Yet, objectivity exists. So there is a problem with your definition.

I don't think so.  I was quite careful to include the possibility of objectivity (although that is pretty much an untenable position for other reasons), and the clear allowance of inter-subjectivity.

My point is that rationality can operate on and communicate about both subjective and not purely subjective phenomena.  I'm being very careful with my language so as not to claim that objectivity is possible, but only that *if it is possible, rationality can work with it*.  I guess we disagree about that - probably because we hold very different views on what objectivity and subjectivity are.  A discussion of such views seems beyond the scope of this conversation, to me.

&amp;gt;I don't think there is always a clear why for an ethical rule - at some point it is a brute fact. "X is the rule" because "X is the rule". And the answer to why is simply because it is. 

If this is the sense in which you're writing, then...well, that's a lot to swallow.  You really believe that an ethical rule that affords heightened moral status to animals on the basis of their being companions to human beings is as fundamental as the speed of light?  And you take the speed of light to be established by a tautology...when in fact, it is established by a far more complex justification that took long decades of observation, debate, and mathematical modelling to come about.  This makes no sense to me; it's really quite astounding.  Either I misunderstand you, or you've confused yourself.

&amp;gt; In this case though the answer to why is because companion animals are not just objects but also subjects. Humans can enter into an "I/thou" relationship with companion animals (in Martin Buber's sense). While livestock are objects and not subjects. We can only enter into "I/it" relationships with cows. Confronted with the other we are indebted to the other and owe it certain obligations - including to refrain from killing the other.

Interesting...

I disagree that there is any necessary difference between dogs and cows in this regard.  I guess you view cows as objects, and don't believe that they have subjective experiences?  Or their subjective experiences only matter if it's something that humans can relate to?

It seems quite plain to me that the *kind* of relationship I can enter with a dog is the same as the kind of relationship I can enter with a cow, or a human being for that matter.  It's a limited relationship based on communication through these evolved perceptual and social systems that I have as a human, and that the animal has as whatever animal it is.  The relationship varies in scope and ability between individuals; my relationship with my spouse is deeper and more powerful than my relationship with my cat.  My relationship with an uneducated fool is not as profound as my relationship with a trusted colleague.  But to me, all of those entities are conscious beings that suffer, and it would be equally wrong for me to hurt any of them unless I had very strong justification.

So I don't see the nature of any particular human relationship as a basis for establishing ethical status for any particular entity; to me, its relevance to ethics is only in its utility for humans as a means of investigating which phenomena indicate the presence of another entity with subjective experiences that are good and bad (from that entity's perspective).

edit:  Interestingly, Martin Buber's view was that the "I / Thou" and "I / It" faculties of relation were both equally operable on animate and inanimate objects.  So cows are in!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845216101.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think so. I was quite careful to include the possibility of objectivity (although that is pretty much an untenable position for other reasons), and the clear allowance of inter-subjectivity.
&amp;gt;My point is that rationality can operate on and communicate about both subjective and not purely subjective phenomena. I'm being very careful with my language so as not to claim that objectivity is possible, but only that if it is possible, rationality can work with it. I guess we disagree about that - probably because we hold very different views on what objectivity and subjectivity are. A discussion of such views seems beyond the scope of this conversation, to me.

And my point is that if your understanding of the objectivity/subjectivity distintion is that it's all subjectivity and there is no such thing as objectivity, then you've made a mistake.  

But you are right it's probably beyond the scope.

&amp;gt;If this is the sense in which you're writing, then...well, that's a lot to swallow. You really believe that an ethical rule that affords heightened moral status to animals on the basis of their being companions to human beings is as fundamental as the speed of light? And you take the speed of light to be established by a tautology...when in fact, it is established by a far more complex justification that took long decades of observation, debate, and mathematical modelling to come about. This makes no sense to me; it's really quite astounding. Either I misunderstand you, or you've confused yourself.

I think the ethical rule about compaion animals is not that fundamental.  I think that eventualy - once you dig deep enough - ethical rules are simply facts of the universe.  

&amp;gt;So I don't see the nature of any particular human relationship as a basis for establishing ethical status for any particular entity; to me, its relevance to ethics is only in its utility for humans as a means of investigating which phenomena indicate the presence of another entity with subjective experiences that are good and bad (from that entity's perspective).

I think this is where the main difference is between us.  I think that relationships matter.  We owe more to our children than the children of others (a parent who saves a stranger's child at the expense of his/her own has acted immorally).  We owe more to friends than strangers.  And so on.

I think this is true even when the utility weighs against the act.  Imagine a father sees two children drowning in the pool - he has time to save one - either his own child who has terminal cancer and will die in the next two years or the child of a stranger.  Such a father would be acting immorally if he chose to save the stranger's child rather than his own. 

&amp;gt;edit: Interestingly, Martin Buber's view was that the "I / Thou" and "I / It" faculties of relation were both equally operable on animate and inanimate objects. So cows are in!

Apparently I need to reread my Buber...

I'm either misremembering what I read or conflating him with someone else...
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845243995.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>Ahh...ok, so you assign moral status on the basis of inborn human biases that cause us to value another being's life on the basis of how close it is to *us*.

Yes, we have a fundamental disagreement about where morality comes from.  I acknowledge the *experience* of loved ones being more important than strangers, of those with close genetic similarity to oneself seeming more important than those who lack it, but deny that this has any direct relevance to the question of whether any particular entity's wellbeing is ethically relevant.  It seems to me that to do otherwise would serve as justification for racism, speciesism, and a whole host of other really awful ethical positions.

Anyway, cheers. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845267397.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Anyway, cheers. :)

Cheers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843439555.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Whether it's right or wrong is entirely irrelevant to whether it's *hypocritical*. If that's someone's ethical standard, then right or wrong if they follow that ethical standard, they aren't hypocritical. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844236268.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't matter to you whether the ethical standard itself is flawed?

In this case, I could just hold an ethical standard that what most people think is ok in my culture is what's ethical...and you would apparently say that isn't hypocritical.

Somehow, I don't think this is going to change OP's view. :P  "It's right *for them...*"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844587035.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that hypocrisy has a meaning, and it has absolutely nothing to do with whether someone's ethical standard is *correct*. 

It is defined as claiming to have what you claim to be a virtue that you do not, in fact, possess. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844701105.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>...

.......

Huh.

Hypocrisy is essentially pretending to hold some belief, standard, virtue, feeling, etc., that you don't actually hold.

Yet you see nothing hypocritical about someone claiming to hold an untenable ethical standard, that conveniently allows the slaughter for food of *only those animals that that person's culture happens to slaughter for food*.

The way I see it, if I can show that an ethical standard produces ethical claims that are plainly false, then I've shown that it is hypocritical for any rational person to claim that they hold that standard.  This is because a rational person can't be expected to hold an obviously false belief; any person doing so must be a hypocrit.

So whether the standard is wrong, alone, may not be relevant - but if the standard is grossly, obviously flawed, that alone is enough to demonstrate hypocrisy on the part of any reasonable person claiming to hold it, and so it is a poor candidate for changing OP's view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845214555.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is, that's simply not what the word "hypocritical" means. You can make up a definition that does what you want if you really want, but you're better of using words that people will actually understand.

No, being irrational in your ethical standards is not "hypocritical". Even having inconsistent ethical standards is not hypocritical. Only having an ethical standard that you claim to follow, but which you do not follow, is "hypocritical". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845247915.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand me.  Being irrational isn't hypocritical, no.  But a rational person *claiming to hold a plainly false view* is **absolutely hypocritical**, because it is not possible for a rational person to *actually* hold a plainly false view.

Or, if you want to use a very narrow definition of hypocrisy that only operates on ethical views, just stick "ethic" in there instead of view.  My arguments still run just fine that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845255983.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Fine, so the person isn't rational, then. If they hold irrational views, they pretty much can't be, by definition.

Irrational != hypocritical. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845358656.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Hmmm... Perhaps I'm misunderstanding what you're saying. If a person *claims* to be rational in all things, but is irrational about something, then that indeed would be hypocritical... About the claim of being rational in all things.

They would not be hypocritical about that irrational thing, though, just about their absolute rationality.

However, very few generally rational people claim to be rational about all things, and those who do are incorrect. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27846064236.0" user="lodro" delta="False">
    <text>You must be either very attached to me be wrong, or not very smart, or not really paying attention.

&amp;gt; If a person claims to be rational in all things, but is irrational about something, then that indeed would be hypocritical

I suppose it would be, but it's not what I was saying at all.  My "rational person" does not have to be completely, perfectly rational in all things; they only need to be rational enough that they can't hold plainly false views on the subject at hand.

Anyway, who cares.  This isn't an interesting point; you aren't engaging in a genuine attempt at debate.  Just trying to show yourself that I was wrong about *something* - doesn't seem to matter what, as ever post you make a new false characterization of what I've said. :P
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27846351079.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Hypocrisy *always* includes an element of lying. It is a subset of the set of all lies. If you are honest about everything you believe and say that you do/are, it's fundamentally impossible for that to be hypocrisy.

So, yes, if you *claim* to be rational, and are actually irrational (either totally or specifically about the topic at hand), then you may be hypocritical (or you might just be wrong... it has to be knowing in order to count as hypocrisy). 

If you make no such claims of rationality (either in general or about the topic at hand), you simply can't be hypocritical about it being irrational.

Hypocrisy requires a *claim* about having a virtue that you don't possess. No claim, no hypocrisy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843171255.0" user="voteforthisguy" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with /u/lodro in that I still don't see why this makes it okay to eat cows but not dogs. It seems that you're saying its wrong to eat dogs because we can see their emotions more clearly than we can in a farm animal. But this doesn't mean that farm animals don't have the same or similar emotions.

Furthermore I'm not sure that I agree with the fact that a dogs emotions are that much clearer to see than a cow's. Surely someone who has grow up around cows or someone who works with them is able to tell when they are happy and when they are in distress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843211355.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Furthermore I'm not sure that I agree with the fact that a dogs emotions are that much clearer to see than a cow's. Surely someone who has grow up around cows or someone who works with them is able to tell when they are happy and when they are in distress.

If it requires special experience to tell then it is less clear.  Infant humans can tell what emotions a dog is experiencing.  We've bred them (and ourselves) to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843235897.0" user="voteforthisguy" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so granted dogs' emotions maybe easier for us to read. Now this would provide a reasonable explanation as to why eating a dog intuitively feels wrong for so many people. However I still don't see why it makes it wrong to eat a dog over a cow. Why does their ability to show their emotion to humans make it wrong to eat them over an animal that still feels the same emotions but can't show them off to humans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843258907.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>First, because showing those emotions is part of what makes them companions and it is wrong to kill and eat companions.  Second, because by showing the emotions they prove they have them.  Third, because by acting contrary to the apparent emotional needs of another creature you deaden your own emotional response making it easier to do future harm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842762622.0" user="ellevt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's one thing to breed a creature to be good food and then use it as food. It's entirely another to breed it to be a companion and then use it as food.

Huh. I never thought about it that way. Not OP but I award you a ∆
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843170202.0" user="JustAManFromThePast" delta="False">
    <text>How is it different, except to us?  Why should our feeling matter, shouldn't it be the thing in pain?  Go hit a cow, see if it doesn't bellow, try to flee or fight.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843627557.0" user="ellevt" delta="False">
    <text>I'm guessing you haven't spent much time around cattle</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843638298.0" user="JustAManFromThePast" delta="False">
    <text>Wrong, knife a bull, see if he just takes it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843416566.0" user="boobbbers" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Dogs are special because they were sleceted in prehistory to be workign companion animals - that there are breeds (is a breed) in recent times created to be livestock, doesn't change this fact any more than the fact that we now have toy poodles changes the fact that poodles were historicaly breed as hunting dogs.

You have to show proof of this. It could very well be the the case that dogs were initially bred as livestock prior to companion animals. And for a lot longer too thus effecting the historicity of dogs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843480136.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>[Here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Origin_of_the_domestic_dog) is the wikipedia article on the issue.  What we know is dogs were domesticated as companions for hunting and protection.  They were the first domesticated animal, livestock came later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842712001.0" user="anggu" delta="False">
    <text>This is a discussion about what is morally right and wrong. You're basically saying that we're in the right because of how we did things 40,000 years ago. That just explains our biases but doesn't justify them. It's circular logic. There is a huge hypocrisy in the way we view the animals we feed on, and we should be re-evaluating ourselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842752544.0" user="CompromisedBullshit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is a discussion about what is morally right and wrong. You're basically saying that we're in the right because of how we did things 40,000 years ago.

Which is exactly what /u/law-talkin-guy was doing, so OP was responding to that specifically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842974461.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  and we should be re-evaluating ourselves.

Which is OPs point. We do the same thing.

We can't give them shit for eating dogs if we are also eating other animals</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843111848.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You're basically saying that we're in the right because of how we did things 40,000 years ago. That just explains our biases but doesn't justify them. It's circular logic.

That's not the postion at all (and it's not circular at all either).

The position is that history effects the present day. The truth of history has an impact on what is and is not true in the world right now.  (The truth that the North won the American Civil War is part of why it is true that South Carolina is part of the United States - it is one historical fact that explains a present day truth.)

"Eating dogs is immoral" is, I am arguing, a present day truth.  "Eating cows and pigs is not immoral" is, I am arguing, another present day truth.  

The reason the former today is because of the historical truth that dogs were breed to be companions and express (or mimic) and respond to human emotion.  This makes it immoral to eat them because they have been selected to be companions and friends (and we don't eat our companions and friends if we are moral) and because they are empathetic and capable of expressing emotion (which is another class of animals we don't eat if we are moral).  The reason for the latter is that cows and pigs were breed to be livestock.  It is moral to eat animals that have been bred to be food and lack empathy or emotional expressiveness.  (NB in the case of cows and pigs who have, in fact, been raised as pets it becomes immoral to eat those individual animals for the same reason it is immoral to eat dogs as a species.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843683232.0" user="sfurbo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This makes it immoral to eat them because they have been selected to be companions and friends (and we don't eat our companions and friends if we are moral) 

We don't eat our companions and friends because they are humans, and it is ethically wrong to eat humans. Anyway, most dogs are not my companions and friends(I don't even knoe them), so that would only make it immoral for me to eat a few dogs.

&amp;gt;and because they are empathetic and capable of expressing emotion (which is another class of animals we don't eat if we are moral).

That class of animals would include at least pigs, and probably cows, sheep and hens as well (at least for the emotion, I don't know about the state of research into animal empathy), so that can not be used to argue for differing between dogs and other animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843778863.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We don't eat our companions and friends because they are humans, and it is ethically wrong to eat humans. Anyway, most dogs are not my companions and friends(I don't even knoe them), so that would only make it immoral for me to eat a few dogs.

I don't know most humans, but I still cant eat them.  

You say it's wrong to eat humans, but why?  What distinguishes humans from dogs in a morally relevant way?

&amp;gt;That class of animals would include at least pigs, and probably cows, sheep and hens as well (at least for the emotion, I don't know about the state of research into animal empathy), so that can not be used to argue for differing between dogs and other animals.

I disagree, obviously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844708924.0" user="sfurbo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You say it's wrong to eat humans, but why? What distinguishes humans from dogs in a morally relevant way?

For one thing, it could be me being eaten tomorrow, and I would prefer for that not to happen. For another thing, humans can understand that they are to be eaten, which makes it much more cruel to slaughter them for food than it is for other animals. Animals might understand the concept of death, but what is about to happen can be hidden from them much easier than it can for humans.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;[...]pigs, and probably cows, sheep and hens [also show emotions] [...] I don't know about the state of research into animal empathy[...]

&amp;gt;I disagree, obviously.

It is abundantly clear from what we know about cows, sheep and hens that they show emotions. It is not really something it makes sense to disagree with, any more than it makes sense to disagree with whether dogs show emotion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845187818.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; For another thing, humans can understand that they are to be eaten, which makes it much more cruel to slaughter them for food than it is for other animals. Animals might understand the concept of death, but what is about to happen can be hidden from them much easier than it can for humans.

And given the empathy dogs have for humans, this is true for dogs as well.  Especially in comparison to livestock.  I'd suggest that if this is your moral argument against cannibalism (and, I don't want it to happen to me is pragmatic, but not moral) then it should lead you to treat dogs as you would humans, but not cows or pigs or otehr livestock.

&amp;gt;It is abundantly clear from what we know about cows, sheep and hens that they show emotions. 

I've spent minimal time with cows and sheep - my experience with them says that's false but I'm open to the possibility I'm wrong.  But hens?  I've raised hens.  I've spent plenty of time with them, and I can assure you they don't show emotions. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843685659.0" user="ashketchem" delta="False">
    <text>People are capable of becoming companions with many types of animals, even ones we eat in the western world. Does the history we have with dogs really impact how close of a bond people can make with an animal, or is a bond with a dog just more likely to exist due to the history we have of having dogs as companions?

Are dogs the only animals protected by this special companionship bond you're referring to?

There are other animals that were not bred to be deep companions that we typically find immoral to eat (cats, horses). 

Essentially you seem to be saying that because we found dogs especially useful to keep around (living), we didn't eat them. We shouldn't eat them because in the past we found them useful to keep around, while other animals are ok to eat because in the past we got the most use from eating their plentiful meat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843792636.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People are capable of becoming companions with many types of animals, even ones we eat in the western world. 

Yes.  And it's wrong to eat individual animals that are companions no matter what the species.  It is also wrong to eat companion species like dogs.  

&amp;gt;Does the history we have with dogs really impact how close of a bond people can make with an animal, or is a bond with a dog just more likely to exist due to the history we have of having dogs as companions?

I'm not sure of the asnwer to that and I'm not sure the answer matters.

&amp;gt;Are dogs the only animals protected by this special companionship bond you're referring to?

I don't know.  Cats almost certantly, and probably horses (I lack enough experience with/knowledge of either to be 100% sure).  Maybe other species.

&amp;gt;Essentially you seem to be saying that because we found dogs especially useful to keep around (living), we didn't eat them. We shouldn't eat them because in the past we found them useful to keep around, while other animals are ok to eat because in the past we got the most use from eating their plentiful meat. 

I can see where you are coming from, but that's not the argument I am trying to make.  

My point isn't about how we treated the species in the past, but about the traits we selected for in the past (which we see in the species today).  it's not that we didn't eat dogs in the past that matters, it's that in the past we bred them to have traits that make it immoral to eat them today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842780433.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Dogs only exist as pets. You could, perhaps, make that argument for wolves, but it does not work for dogs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842883911.0" user="dabo0sh" delta="False">
    <text>They don't exist only as pets universally, and that's the argument OP is making.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843474908.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>Only because some people in some places have stopped treating them as pets. That does not change the 40,000 years of selective breeding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844513467.0" user="dabo0sh" delta="False">
    <text>Is there empirical evidence suggesting such? Furthermore, OP's argument is not contextually based on our eating habits by way of historical merit, rather his scope is based on dietary habits of the present.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842833826.0" user="callthezoo" delta="False">
    <text>Dogs were selectively bread for the purpose of being human companions. I don't see why it has to be any more complicated than that. No matter what country you live in or how you "breed" them now, that's how they evolved. That's been the case since the hunter-gatherers 20,000+ years ago. Its not how you "see" them, its a scientific fact. On the other hand, another culture finds cows "sacred", which is fine for them, but it has no basis in anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843756410.0" user="ckaili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; On the other hand, another culture finds cows "sacred", which is fine for them, but it has no basis in anything.

You make it sound like it's some completely random superstition.  Cows are revered in certain cultures/religions because they provide milk, fuel (dung), and help till the fields. They are seen as care-taker animals in those societies and therefore it is considered immoral to kill and eat cows in those societies.  How is that any less a valid moral conclusion than not eating dogs due to their companionship?  

As far as breeding is concerned, cats were not bred to be companions, and yet I would argue that there is just as much stigma for eating cats.

I think we have personal and societal relationships with certain animals that make them special to us.  We don't need a 40,000 year history of breeding to justify a societal decision that dogs are companion animals.  They just *are* companion animals.  The *only* reason to bring that up is to somehow claim that our relationship with dogs transcends our personal and our society's experiences and therefore exists as a moral absolute.  And that is the part that doesn't hold, because ultimately, it is not, I feel, the basis for our moral decision. 

I personally did not develop more empathy for a cat than a cow because of some complicated prehistoric occurrence.  It's solely based on my personal experiences (or lack thereof) with the animals themselves and as being part of a society which believes the same.  People don't seem to like this argument because it implies that someone without such personal experiences could eat dog and have it be a completely amoral occurrence rather than an absolute immoral one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843835080.0" user="callthezoo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Cows are revered in certain cultures/religions because they provide milk, fuel (dung), and help till the fields…How is that any less a valid moral conclusion than not eating dogs due to their companionship?

As you suggest, the artificial selection of cattle by humans was motivated by their ability to a) provide sustenance and b) perform inexpensive slave type labor. Nowhere in the world that I know of, now or any point in history, have cows been bred to just to be friends to human beings. It doesn’t matter if you personally don’t care or think about the evolutionary history when you pet a dog, but you can’t pretend it’s irrelevant. You’re claim “They just *are* companion animals” is too simplistic because the western point of view literally traces back to the origins of the species. I don’t have a problem with anyone choosing not to eat cows, but it just isn’t analogous to say that those societies could look down on us for eating cow the way we might look down on China for eating dog.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844007303.0" user="ckaili" delta="False">
    <text>I think your suggestion that dogs were bred for friendship is very modern and first-world.  I don't doubt that dogs have been long seen as providing companionship, but their utility of protecting, herding, hunting, and retrieving earned their keep.  After all, unlike human friends, we maintain ownership and responsibility of dogs.  In addition, dogs, as a species, don't know to respect some sort of historical alliance with humanity.  Therefore it is the society which has such a relationship with dogs that places higher value on their life and dignity.  A society that does not have such an established relationship will not place that same value, not necessarily for an intentional negligence to a morality bound to them by tens of thousands of years of other human history.  The point is, we either decide there is some sort of absolute moral ideal (and argue why revering cows is stupid while revering dogs is logical), or we recognize that our personal experience and social upbringing define our moral compasses and that they are by their nature ethnocentric.  It doesn't mean we have to respect it, rather realize that when people are doing what we think is wrong, they are not necessarily acting against their moral compass.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842913771.0" user="npinguy" delta="False">
    <text>No, we see dogs as special because we spent 40,000 years working to make them trust us, and trusting them. Western, Korean, and Indian cultures are all relatively new compared to the timeline of historical human-dog relations.  And while I'm sure humans always ate any animals they could in time of need, the vast majority of human history we spent knowing that this animal can be more beneficial as a companion (hunting, protecting, whatever) than as a meal.

Now, of course, you could argue that "just because we did something 40,000 years ago doesn't mean we should do it now", but you and I both know that if anything culture is moving away from eating ANY animals, not just dogs, rather than treating them equally.

So while you can make a moral argument for NOT eating animals, you can't make an equitable cultural or historical one for continuing to eat dogs, nor could you have made one for STARTING to eat dogs whenever the cultures that split off decided to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844466346.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>Except the Chinese have been domesticating dogs for a significant amount of time as well and portions of China are just fine with eating dogs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842963159.0" user="bhujiyasev" delta="False">
    <text>  You used the example of cows in India, so I'll use that to illustrate something. 

  Eating dogs is seen as disgusting in the west because of the emotional attachment to the animals as friends. Cows, on the other hand, are held sacred in Hindus culture. In Islam, pigs are seen as too disgusting to eat. 

&amp;gt;However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

  It is, but not for the same reasons. You criticize people for eating animals which you view as too *intelligent* to be mercilessly slaughtered for food. Most other cultures prohibitions on meats are due to *superstition*. 

  While defending dogs for their intelligence compared to other animals (as intelligence should be no measure of value of life) is admittedly myopic, considering the host of superstitious reasons other cultures employ, it is not *as* hypocritical as the reasons used by most others. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843023682.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Islam has been around for what? 1,400 years? May is less than 5% of human history. 

We probably should not compare such a new ideology to the breadth of humanity that spans 40,000. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843096167.0" user="bhujiyasev" delta="False">
    <text>How is the time relevant? The resultant superstition is just as effective as, say, a pagan religion from hunter-gatherer times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843170871.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that humans created pigs to be our food source far before Islam was around. And we will continue to use pigs as our food source far after Islam fades away. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844462118.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>Judaism prohibits pork consumption, and many places in the Ancient world also prohibited pork consumption. 

It's something that humans grew "out of" rather than grew into. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844504561.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Judaism is only slightly older than islam on the continuum on humanity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844511041.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>Syria prohibited pork and was founded around 10,000 BCE. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844513651.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>Once again, a blip on the timeline of humanity. 

I am curious, however, of how we know Syria (a country that was created in 1920) banned pork 4,000 years before any recorded history. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844518063.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>..... 

Ancient Syria. 

We know this because religions in the area (Not Judaism) banned pork consumption and it was recorded by travelers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844534108.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text>It was not recorded by travelers because nothing was recorded before 6000 BC. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844545491.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>The Syrian God Atargatis forbid the consumption of pork. Her worship in Syria predates 6000 BC. Travelers after 6000 BC recorded the prohibition of pork. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845009231.0" user="nmhunate" delta="False">
    <text> Oh okay. 

Regardless. Most of humanity lived before this. It is a relatively recent development. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842993552.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;not all civilizations.

MANY of them, including the Chinese. In fact, only the Americas seem to stand apart here. Dogs have been bred, both intentionally and by evolutionary accident, to be companions to humans *in China*. Think of all the cute toy dog breeds. Consider the names. Shih tzu? Pekingese?

Did you know that humans look to the right side of the face when meeting another human? This is because an asymmetry in the human brain results in that side of the face being slightly more expressive. Thus, humans look to that side first to better gauge human emotion. Fun fact: Dogs do the same thing when encountering a human, but they do NOT do the same thing when encountering another dog. Think about that. Dogs are *programmed* to be human companions. 

Perhaps I don't need to belabor the point, but this sets them aside from pigs and cows. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843068716.0" user="xahhfink6" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that the Chinese only eat specific breeds of dogs which are selectively bred as meat rather than to be companions. In their mind, the difference between a meat dog and a pet dog is as different as a pig and a pet dog.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843075386.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>Their minds are wrong. The dogs they eat are behaviorally similar to the ones they see as companions. Even breeds that have not been purposely bred for 'love and snuggles' have been subjected to what, 130 000 years of human (homo) coevolution?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843106962.0" user="raptor6c" delta="False">
    <text>While you have established you recognize a readily observable behavioral difference between generic dog and generic pig/cow what's your overarching philosophical basis for why that behavioral difference should translate into a behavioral difference in humans consumption patterns?

Your argument seems to be dogs have been bred towards the purpose of companionship rather than consumption, therefore dogs should not be consumed as food.  But why should the conclusion follow from the premise?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843129219.0" user="Kmouse2" delta="False">
    <text>Some animals are already considered non-human persons because of their outstanding intelligence and social abilities.

Taking into account those differences with other animals and the pain and suffering caused to them is usually enough for society to grant them rights and protection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843137084.0" user="sindeloke" delta="False">
    <text>Generally humans hold the concepts of "trust" and "betrayal" to be ethically very weighty. It's not unreasonable to distinguish between killing a creature that just sort of is out there in the world doing its own thing and killing a creature that is genetically programmed to constantly turn to and trust you for guidance, help and protection. Particularly when your species is directly responsible for instilling that trust and devotion. You can see this even with human crimes - the idea of a parent hurting a child is much more viscerally affecting to most people than a stranger hurting a child, and the only difference is in the relationship,  not the act itself.

There's also possibly a sense of gratitude toward work animals that isn't given to livestock; you don't hear stories about cows heroically rescuing humans from attacking intruders or even see chickens helping people with chores and making them happy on a daily basis. Humans are more likely to treat a creature well if they feel obligated to it or believe it regularly gives them something worthwhile. Notice the number two animal in the world that weirds people out when they hear about other people eating it is horse, the other domestic work animal that we owe our civilization to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843652829.0" user="dealbreakerjones" delta="False">
    <text>*bravo*

I seriously wish I could award you a delta for that. Thanks for the clarity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27926768933.0" user="lecterrkr" delta="False">
    <text>you can give him a delta even if you are not the OP of the thread.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27927020015.0" user="dealbreakerjones" delta="False">
    <text>How?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27927044637.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>You edit your comment to insert the delta symbol in (but not in quotes)

&amp;gt;∆

You can also use the following text (also not in quotes)

&amp;gt;!delta</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843269572.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry but I do not understand at all what you just wrote.

&amp;gt;But why should the conclusion follow from the premise?

This I understood better. The answer is simple. Humans, as a species, have benefited from our species' interaction with dogs. It's been symbiotic, no doubt. This relationship is rather unique because it has been based upon an emotional and sentimental attachment. Dogs were bred by us with not just the intention of physical protection but also with the intention of companionship. They are they way they are (that is to say, extremely emotionally competent animals with respect to humans) *because* of this. As a species, we are responsible for them. To turn around and then cruelly slaughter them for food is a violation of that relationship. 

Basically, we benefited enormously by making them emotionally competent sentimental animals. To then treat them with a total lack of emotional sentimentality is a betrayal and violation of our previous intentions. 

You can go ahead and adopt the stance that nothing is moral, blah blah blah, postmodernism bs, but if you're not going to do that, then you need to apply some other more solid form of philosophy to this question. I'm unaware of such a system that is not compatible with what I am saying here. Perhaps you have a suggestion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843474940.0" user="raptor6c" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have a suggestion for any universal framework that should convince any well adjusted human that eating dogs is wrong but that eating cows is not.  I was hoping you or someone else did.  

I'm looking for something more general because while I personally wouldn't eat dog meat except at the extreme necessity for survival I recognize that this is simply because of my biased perception that the idea of eating dog makes me feel creeped out and I know there are plenty of other things to eat that don't make me feel creeped out in most cases.

But what I'm looking for is a framework whereby I wouldn't just not eat dog myself but would also view other people 'negatively' because they would eat dog in the absence of the anti-squick motivations that stop me without any need for an intellectual argument.

I don't feel moved by the breeding/collective human responsibility argument argument because they seem too disconnected to the act of a person today eating a dog today.  It feels like it's saying every human alive today is responsible for the acts of any given subset of humans who ever lived and I don't agree with that sort of reasoning.  I think that it places unacceptable burden on individual humans who might live at any given time under conditions for which they had no hand in bringing about.

My most obviously recognizable bias here is that I feel that if I were to accept the argument of collective responsibility of humans towards dogs as a justification for all individual humans to treat all individual dogs in any particular way I would have a hard time resisting the argument of collective responsibility of tribe A towards tribe B being used as justification for all members of tribe A being obligated to treat members of tribe B a certain way.  And once that argument is settled in you're getting close to justification for some pretty awful inter-tribal relations.  Thus I hold that involuntary membership in any sort of collective or group can not be sufficient on its own to justify restrictions or obligations on the part of any individual who a member of that group towards someone/something who/that is not.

In simple terms, I don't accept that 'being human' is enough justification on its own to restrict a human from engaging in any particular behavior towards a non-human entity regardless of what 'humans' have done in the past.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843517226.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;this is simply because of my biased perception that the idea of eating dog makes me feel creeped out

If you explore the origins of that feeling more, you may find something more concrete. 

It would feel like a betrayal, would it not? 

OK, here is an argument you may accept: 

We have an aversion to eating humans? Why is that? When humans die, we don't eat them, even if it would be perfectly safe to do so. The reason for this is simple:

Morality is often based upon a concept of justice as in - how do we separate things like family, job, sex, etc. Ask yourself why we don't ask for the bill when we eat at a friends house. Or how about why we would find it repugnant to sell a child. This all has to do with keeping those circles of our lives separate. You don't fuck coworkers and you don't eat family members. It's hard to put your finger down exactly on the why of that, but it's there. Steven Pinker writes about this a lot but it's been a while since I've reviewed the exact reasoning. 

Dogs are surrogate humans. Some people even replace human babies with the fur-having variety. If you accept all that, then seeing why the morality of not eating humans extends to not eating dogs.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843580810.0" user="raptor6c" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely see the morality for it on the individual level, where I can't seem to follow you is in applying it to the species/universe level.  I accept that for you and I eating dogs is the same as/similar to eating babies, but I don't agree that for the man in China eating dogs should be considered the same as eating babies.  I would agree that he should be willing to have the same conversation we are having and examine his own beliefs, but I have no particular confidence that he should, after examining his beliefs thoroughly, change his position and swear off dog meat forever any more than he should have confidence that after hearing his reasons we should change our positions and stop being opposed to dog meat consumption ourselves.

I'm trying not to go into any post modernist bs as you called it, but I can't help the fact that I do feel that if there is such a thing as an absolute morality, which I doubt, it's highly unlikely that my personal feelings are so directly in touch with it that I can be confident that I should view my own feelings as sufficient justification to reject the feelings of others when there is a dispute.  I'll challenge and probe other people's beliefs all day long, but I try to stop short of prescribing my beliefs to be superior to someone else's simply because they're mine and work for me.

I know I can examine how I feel and draw insights from them which I can present to others in a discourse, but after expressing my own opinion and sharing my own insights if another person tells me they don't feel the same way I do I generally don't usually indulge in the thought that the person is supposed to feel the way I feel and that there is something wrong with them if they refuse to do so. The biggest exception here is when I'm invested in the person for other reasons, then I will get caught in the trap of wanting them to see things my way to facilitate having a smooth relationship with them.  But usually I'll just think that the person doesn't feel the same as me about an issue, then I'll wonder what is going on in their head, and then I'll ask them, hopefully in an inoffensive way, so they'll tell me rather than feel attacked and withdraw.   Once I have an idea of what's going on in the other person's head if I find we don't share some belief that I feel is a core principle of my perception of humanity I will probably back away slowly and try to avoid getting too close to that person, but that's the extent of my conviction to advancing my personal sense morality on other people's behavior, at least if I'm not being directly harmed by the behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843193449.0" user="Cartosys" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Did you know that humans look to the right side of the face when meeting another human? 

Never heard this before.  I wonder if left-handed people look at the left side of the face by default?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843302020.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>The notion that dogs have been artificially selected to be human companions has nothing to do with eating them. If the Chinese are extra prone to having more responsive dogs then it is curious why the are one of few civilizations that eats mean. 

People always complain about the suffering of the animals, and pigs are known to be as smart as dogs. So the logic is that they suffer and are higher up on the chain of intelligence. No one has the intuition that "oh this animal likes people so we shouldn't eat it." Birds land on people, and we kill them for food. Any animal can like a person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843414154.0" user="arah91" delta="False">
    <text>The same people who won't eat dog also bulk at the idea of eating something like deer or goat, and all the arguments fall flat. They try to make up arguments, but I find more often than not the root issue is its just foreign. However, for some reason that's not good enough so they try and find more compelling arguments. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843482408.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Balk? Yeah, I agree that most people are just not used to the idea and they might have had a pet dog at some point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843432138.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The notion that dogs have been artificially selected to be human companions has nothing to do with eating them.

I disagree for the reasons stated. This will be a very short conversation it seems. 

&amp;gt;and pigs are known to be as smart as dogs.

No arguments there. But we are not responsible for the intelligence of pigs. They are smart despite our efforts towards domestication. Dogs are emotionally competent with respect to humans *thanks to* our efforts. There is a key difference. 

As an aside, I fully support the dumbing down of pigs, even by genetic manipulation if necessary.

Beyond that, pigs may be smart, but they do not share the unique social relationship to humans as dogs. The emotional sensibilities of humans and dogs evolved in lockstep. This is different and separate from intelligence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843453887.0" user="ChamplooFool" delta="False">
    <text>dogs only started to follow us and help us hunt when they realised if they hung out they could get food scraps easier and be better protected from other predators

So the dogs owe us at least a little bit ie munching them at a cultural festival</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843508437.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>We encouraged them to do so. There's a reason why humans did not simply kill the dogs following them around for meat. They were more valuable to us as not meat. Just like today. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843598934.0" user="ChamplooFool" delta="False">
    <text>yea exactly, I should have mentioned it was mutually beneficial </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843484111.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>You think people have made dogs smarter over time? Not bred them as companions but made them noticeably smarter? I'd love to see a cite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843506794.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>You'll notice that I said nothing about being smart. I am talking about emotional comparability. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843533419.0" user="thefeint" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Dogs are smart thanks to our efforts.

Is that the case? Wolves are plenty smart, and organize themselves into social groups that self-police, but I'd be interested to see if you've found articles that indicate that we've "smartened" dogs as we've domesticated them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843564169.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>I meant emotionally competent with respect to humans, sorry for the confusion. Wolves no doubt are close, but this is likely why dogs made the match with humans that they did. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843592402.0" user="Yawehg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Perhaps I don't need to belabor the point, but this sets them aside from pigs and cows.

I definitely buy what your selling, but I don’t know if that makes eating dogs worse than eating than pigs. Dogs respond to human emotions, but that doesn’t mean they suffer more if you kill/eat them. It seems like your argument against eating dogs is that consumption is a betrayal of their purpose or our shared legacy, which strikes me as a weirdly highbrow angle to take. Is the issue the sanctity of legacy in general? If so, the idea doesn't really hold up. Consider the reverse: Pigs and hogs have been domesticated as livestock, is it morally wrong to keep a pig as a pet and then *not* eat it when it dies?  If it's just about this particular legacy, why is it important? You seem to be putting a high price on our shared history with dogs, I question that valuation.

Of course, your point might be that a dog’s quality of suffering is greater than a livestock animal’s. I don’t think apparent emotional intelligence can really prove that. It can certainly make us feel worse about viewing that suffering, but “it makes me more uncomfortable” isn’t really a compelling moral argument. It also has more to do with treatment of the animal than it does with actual eating. People still kill companion dogs, either when they get sick or suffer grievous injury, is there something wrong with eating them after that?

In the end, thinking about killing a companion dog for food makes me feel sad, but I can’t find a compelling reason for why it’s not okay to eat dogs but **is** okay to eat other stuff.

Pigs are similarly intelligent, live in complicated social arrangements, and display empathy at an equal or higher level than dogs, but we eat them without questioning their suffering. For me, all of this becomes an argument better suited for advancing vegetarianism, not eating one animal over another.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843739498.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  It seems like your argument against eating dogs is that consumption is a betrayal of their purpose or our shared legacy, which strikes me as a weirdly highbrow angle to take. 

Sorry that I can't respond in more detail but I am at work. i wrote here before about eating humans, selling children, and asking for a check when at a friends house for dinner. These social taboos exist because a large part of morality has to do with keeping these things separate. Not eating dogs is morally unacceptable to many for the same reason that it is morally unacceptable to eat our dead, even if it were perfectly safe to do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843917432.0" user="Yawehg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sorry that I can't respond in more detail but I am at work. 

No worries, I am too. Would love to keep talking about this when we get off though. My short response:

&amp;gt; Not eating dogs is morally unacceptable to many for the same reason that it is morally unacceptable to eat our dead, even if it were perfectly safe to do so.

I agree that many people would say that, but I also don't think eating dead people is a moral issue if it's in the context of funeral traditions. 

I went back to read your Steven Pinker post, and I think I see what you're getting at. It actually gives me pause when considering the question of "should we look down on dog-eating in western society?" But I don't think it's a strong argument against OPs point, which is that you shouldn't be critical of other culture's dog eating habits. The societies that eat dog as a regular thing obvious *don't* regard them as surrogate humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843927736.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>Is that true of all breeds of dogs? What of the dogs that are specifically bred to be livestock?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844859889.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>That would have been recent. The ancestors of those dogs would have certainly been evolved for companionship and human interaction. That's how dogs became a distinct species. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845249826.0" user="r314t" delta="False">
    <text>How do we know that some dogs weren't always used more for food? Cows, pigs and chickens also became distinct species, and yet we use them for food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845268070.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>Because we know from anthropology that the species of 'dog' (C. l. familiaris) was domesticated by the process of joining groups of humans in symbiotic relationships. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843978698.0" user="UltimaGabe" delta="False">
    <text>Do we know for a fact that pigs and cows don't do something equally as distinct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844859384.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>Can't prove a negative. But they were never bred for companionship, so probably not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844265719.0" user="xraymango" delta="False">
    <text>Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844865737.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>2 second google search?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844972336.0" user="xraymango" delta="False">
    <text>Are you asking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844457199.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>[Dogs were bred as meat sources in China though](http://www.nytimes.com/2009/09/08/science/08dogs.html), and in general, dogs that are eaten in China were never considered "pets." 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844857419.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>Irrelevant. Those dogs were evolved first for not meat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845113408.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>Pigs were evolved first as foragers, not meat for humans. 

Doesn't stop us from eating them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845130556.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>That's not my argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845136363.0" user="Siantlark" delta="False">
    <text>Then what is your argument? That dogs were evolved first as partners and therefore shouldn't be eaten? 


I just showed evidence that the Chinese started domesticating dogs for meat before using them as pets or partners. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845023202.0" user="kosmic_kolossos" delta="False">
    <text>The only variable changing in your equation is the animal's relationship with humans. What does that have to do with anything?
Cows and pigs are intelligent beings, who have the capacity for fear, pain, and loneliness- -and we put them through immeasurable amounts of suffering. Right from the birth of it's existence, 'til it's anguished last breath.

Cows have best friends! Pigs are supposedly smarter than dogs, and can be manipulative to get their way!

&amp;gt;[The claim that it's okay to slaughter pigs, for example, rather than dogs, because dogs would suffer more, is misleading and vacuous and there are no data to support that conclusion. All of these mammals, and all other mammals, are sentient beings who share the same neural architecture underlying their emotional lives and who experience a wide spectrum of emotions including the capacity to feel pain and to suffer.](http://www.livescience.com/39717-are-pigs-as-smart-as-dogs.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845138575.0" user="MyPenisIsaWMD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What does that have to do with anything? Cows and pigs are intelligent beings, who have the capacity for fear, pain, and loneliness

Certainly. I maintain that it is different. There's a taboo against eating humans. Dogs are perhaps the most human like animal in emotions. Thus, the taboo extends to them. I wish pigs were less smart, but eating dogs treads too closely on the cannibalism taboo, which exists for a number of reasons. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845157603.0" user="kosmic_kolossos" delta="False">
    <text>Taboo is a human construct, nothing to to do with the animals</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843154325.0" user="zabethflores" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if this has been brought up in other comments, but all the fuss about the chinese dog eating festival got me thinking about the mexican Xoloitzcuintle (hairless dog) which was bred for ritual reasons (it was considered sacred and ritually sacrificed for burials), companion reasons (according to the Codex Floresiensis the Mexicas made special blankets to cover them at night, to help them stay warm) AND food reasons (they even overfed them to make them fat and nice for eating).

The Mexicas ate everything, there is a modern mexican saying about that: "todo lo que corre, nada y vuela va directo a la cazuela" (anything that runs, flies or swims, goes to the pot). I don't think they saw any contradiction between having pets and eating them. Then again, they ate other people... so, there's that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843390328.0" user="skullpizza" delta="False">
    <text>Cows are ***bred*** for food in india.  Indians eat dairy products.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843493804.0" user="Differently" delta="False">
    <text>Bred. Past tense of breed is bred.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844130182.0" user="bezjones" delta="False">
    <text>What about those of us who are from "dog = friend &amp;amp; cow = meat" cultures aren't being hypocritical just as anyone from a "dog = meat &amp;amp; cow = friend/sacred/not meat/whatever" culture aren't being hypocritical if they criticize our culture?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844268065.0" user="Amadacius" delta="False">
    <text>That just isn't true. Even the nureongi was breed as a companion long before it was breed as food, look at how it resembles modern dog species rather than wild species of dogs. 


Also, most species that are consumed are still domesticated for the home.

As for Indian cows, they were not breed as companions, they were just not breed to be eeten</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842714777.0" user="workreddit565" delta="False">
    <text>Even if your stance on the controlled breeding of dogs into companions is accurate in the United States (I don't think it is) that change wouldn't be reflected across the entire world. The practice of some Asian countries consuming dog meat is nothing new so they wouldn't have selectively bred their dogs for companionship but for food. Which means by what you stated they shouldn't be judged for treating or eating dogs any differently then we (assuming also American) judge ourselves when consuming pork, cow, chicken, etc </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843054866.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>The controlled breeding of dogs as companions is true for all dogs.  It's been true since before there was a United States.  Hell, it's been true since before there was a United Kingdom.

That's what dogs are - wolves that joined with humans bred selectively for thousands of generations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842903848.0" user="ibrake4monsterbooty" delta="False">
    <text>This is a great response that I wholeheartedly agree with. I hate to be *that* guy but I'm pretty sure we say "have been bred". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843091465.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Yes we do say that.  Redditing late at night is my official excuse for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842953884.0" user="protestor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That makes a huge difference.

Pigs and cows can be very emphatic creatures though. You can grow them as pet animals.

The past generations of each animal does not justify how they are treated today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843136341.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Pigs and cows can be very emphatic creatures though. You can grow them as pet animals.

And it would be wrong to eat your pet pig or cow. Because it is wrong to kill and eat companions.

&amp;gt;The past generations of each animal does not justify how they are treated today.

How they are treated today encompasses much more than whether it is ethical to eat them, and I agree with you as it applies to the much more. But as it applies to the morality of using them as food, I think it does.  Because those past generations, how they were selectively bred, determines the traits of the species today.  

Dogs are, as a species, companions and it's wrong to eat companions.  This is true because of their past generations.  Cows are, as a species, livestock and it's not wrong to eat livestock.  And so on.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843416810.0" user="dietbroccoli" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's wrong to eat companions. This is true because of their past generations. Cows are, as a species, livestock and it's not wrong to eat livestock.

Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843492004.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on your theory of ethics.  

On the theory I ascribe to it's because you can have an "I/thou" interaction with companion animals that you can't have with livestock.  (See Martin Buber's *I and Thou*).  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843591811.0" user="dietbroccoli" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think that?  What about homesteaders who raise their animals, treat them well, and butcher them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843599148.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>The mere fact that they can butcher them shows they haven't entered into an I/thou relationship with them.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843610091.0" user="dietbroccoli" delta="False">
    <text>That sounds exceptionally narrow-minded, honestly.  You're ascribing concrete rules to something as ridiculously flexible as ethics and human relationships.

What it boils down to is "*I* have a personal issue with eating certain animals because I was taught to."  There's nothing wrong with that, but surely you're aware that it's not meaningful enough to adjust other people's behavior.  I'm not gonna make a Jew eat pork or tell someone that they shouldn't eat dogs.  Objectively speaking, the only ethical statements I can make about consuming other things without being a thoughtless hypocrite are "don't make your prey suffer" and "don't consume other humans unless you really, really have to."

Now, I would consider eating dogs an absolutely last-resort kinda deal, but I acknowledge that those feelings are just an emotional/cultural bias.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843631529.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Objectively speaking, the only ethical statements I can make about consuming other things without being a thoughtless hypocrite are "don't make your prey suffer" and "don't consume other humans unless you really, really have to."

Why do you say that?  How are those claims objective?  

Don't they suffer from the same flaws that you claim my view does?

&amp;gt;That sounds exceptionally narrow-minded, honestly.

When we enter into an I/thou relationship we are forced to recognize the other as a subject rather than an object (in the I/it relationship).  To borrow from Heidegger we are "always already guilty" before the other subject which demands of us on a fundamental level to treat it as a subject.  Having entered into such a relationship we can't back out, the knowledge that the other is also an I imposes itself on us at all times and forces us to try to treat it as one.  To retreat from that and so thoroughly objectify the other as to make it possible to kill for food is ... lets say unlikely rather than impossible.  That is the expreintal nature of such a relationship.  What grounds do you have for thinking otherwise? 

&amp;gt;What it boils down to is "I have a personal issue with eating certain animals because I was taught to." There's nothing wrong with that, but surely you're aware that it's not meaningful enough to adjust other people's behavior. 

That's not at all what it boils down to, eitehr you've never read Buber or you've grosely misunderstood the point.  It bolis down to that the other forces us to treat it as a subject rather than an object.  it's got nothing to do with me, but the nature of the being standing before the potential butcher.  I don't have to impose myself - the other imposes itself in that moment, so long as the butcher is not closed off from such encounters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843005264.0" user="no-mad" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Not all meat is ethically the same, the animal it is taken from matters.


This is a cop out. Unless you raised, slaughtered it yourself. You are separated from the animal till it is on your plate and you stuff it in to your face.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843096861.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>It's hardly a cop out.  It's, in fact, true.

Is it ethical to eat humans if you don't raise and slaughter them yourself?  If your answer to that is "no" then we agree that not all meat is ethically the same, the animal it is taken from matters.  The disagreement is not about that, but where we draw the line. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843109352.0" user="no-mad" delta="False">
    <text>I am a lifelong vegetarian. I find the whole process repugnant and unethical on many levels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843118152.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>That's very different that what you were arguing above.

If it's okay to eat meat you've slaughtered and raised yourself then it's okay to eat some meat.  If the whole process is unethical then it's not okay to eat any meat.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843493126.0" user="Differently" delta="False">
    <text>Bred. Past tense of breed is bred. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843503468.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>This is true.  I left it up to not make people wonder what the first guy who commented on it was saying, but I've fixed it now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843570390.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Killing and eating creatures that have evolved to have or mimic human emotion, to respond to human emotion, and to be companions is very different from killing and eating creatures than have evolved to be good to kill and eat.

Just to play devil's advocate, why? I feel like you haven't qualified the argument enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843586981.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>It depends on your moral theory.  I can give you an argument for why this is the case under a number of different moral theories (and if you tell me what your theory of morality is I'll tell you why I think this is true under that theory, if I think it is), but honestly I think that once you have your attention drawn to the difference the fact that this difference is morally relevant is self-apparent.  (Moral facts are like other facts of nature, once you observe them you know them even if you can't say why.  If I told you, "The fire is hot" and you stuck your hand in the fire, it would be apparent this was true even if I couldn't explain to you why exactly this was the case.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843659893.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it wrong in your opinion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843673329.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Short version is that we can enter into an I/thou relationship (in Martin Buber's sense of the term) with the former, but only an I/it relationship with the latter.

Once we recognize that the other is a subject and not just an object (a thou and not an it) we are morally obligated to treat it as a subject and not an object.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843714702.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>In my opinion, we should (and can) have an I/thou relationship to all animals, whether they're particularly similar to us or not. I think that in the west, since very little of our food looks like it was once an animal, we have generally grown up without ever having to confront the fact that death is necessary for life.

Primitive mythology and religion around the world was, at its earliest stage, the worship/reverence of animals, because early people needed a way to reconcile the fact that they had to kill in order to survive. They had more reverence for the animals they ate than they did for other humans, because the sacrifice of those animals allowed them to survive (obviously this varied from culture to culture but it was generally a very pervasive theme). In modern times, we find it hard to eat animals which we revere, and easy to eat animals we see as, like you put it, "it"s. This is a complete reversal.

We're one of the most spiritually immature cultures to ever have existed, and I believe that contriving a system where we see certain animals as "objects" just so that we feel justified in eating them is just us further procrastinating the development of our spirituality. I also feel that using "how much does it remind me of me" is a poor measure for whether something is worthy of ethical treatment. Ideally, we should see that there's beauty in all things. Instead, we pretend that some things aren't beautiful so we don't feel so bad destroying them; the spiritual/intellectual equivalent of sticking our fingers in our ears. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843822731.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In my opinion, we should (and can) have an I/thou relationship to all animals, whether they're particularly similar to us or not.

Great, except you can't.  You can't have that kind of relationship with things that are, in fact just things.  Some animals are, in fact, just things - they aren't subjects.  

&amp;gt;Primitive mythology and religion around the world was, at its earliest stage, the worship/reverence of animals, because early people needed a way to reconcile the fact that they had to kill in order to survive. 

It was the worship/reverence of animals and other phenomena and objects (and I doubt that we have near enough information to give a because for that behavior).  Fire, which was also worshiped, obviously lacks the kind of subjective existance to be a thou, so the fact of worship tells us nothing.

&amp;gt;We're one of the most spiritually immature cultures to ever have existed,

What is your metric for measuring spiritual maturity?

&amp;gt;Ideally, we should see that there's beauty in all things.

Some things aren't beautiful.  Famine, war, dysentery, genocide, HIV/AIDS, malaria, and on and on.  the world is full of ugly ugly things.  Things we would do well to eradicate if we could.

&amp;gt;Instead, we pretend that some things aren't beautiful so we don't feel so bad destroying them; the spiritual/intellectual equivalent of sticking our fingers in our ears. 

Pretending all things are beautiful and good is no better.  It's a willful blindness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845284503.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Great, except you can't. You can't have that kind of relationship with things that are, in fact just things. Some animals are, in fact, just things - they aren't subjects.

Is there any way you can qualify this outside of it simply being your opinion? The framework of deciding which particular animals are worthy of being "thou"s is invented, as far as I can see. To suggest that it's impossible to view certain animals as more than objects is an *enormous* claim and I don't know that there's any evidence available to support it. The same goes for your points about fire and the beauty/ugliness of certain concepts. As far as I can see, all you can realistically offer on those subjects is your personal opinion on how you feel about a given thing on a case-by-case basis. To say that nobody can ever find X beautiful or nobody can ever see X as a subject seems axiomatically untrue. 

To be clear, I'm not saying you can't disagree with me, I'm just saying that all I can see in your argument is that you do disagree with my opinion on whether certain things are beautiful/worthy of being considered a subject. I don't see any reason at this point that your opinion on those matters should preclude others from having different opinions.

&amp;gt;What is your metric for measuring spiritual maturity?

The most fundamental/simple way I can define spirituality off the top of my dome is that it's a recognition of the connectedness of all things, or of the "oneness" of the universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845485050.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The most fundamental/simple way I can define spirituality off the top of my dome is that it's a recognition of the connectedness of all things, or of the "oneness" of the universe.

There are many things wrong with this view. 

Consider the following:  It is moraly acceptable to sexualy stimulate myself (masturbate).  If you and I are "one", then you are me.  Therefore it is morally acceptable to sexualy stimulate you.  Only it isn't morally acceptable to sexualy stimulate you without your permission.  Therefore either mastubation isn't moraly acceptabel or you and I are not "one".

You can do this with all sorts of things.  Suicide is moraly acceptable, but I'm not allowed to kill you.  Picking my nose is moraly acceptable, but I can't pick your nose.  And so on.  

At it's root the belife that we are all one falls apart over issues of autonomy. 

&amp;gt;Is there any way you can qualify this outside of it simply being your opinion? 

Not really, you get to a point were there are things whihc are.  ZYou observe the world, and if others fail to observe the world properly you can't do much more than point and say "look at it, you are wrong."  I can tell you the sky is blue and if you tell me it is red, I can't do much more than point.  If you tell me murder is morally good I can't do much more than point either.  Facts about the world are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845503931.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Consider the following: It is moraly acceptable to sexualy stimulate myself (masturbate). If you and I are "one", then you are me. Therefore it is morally acceptable to sexualy stimulate you. Only it isn't morally acceptable to sexualy stimulate you without your permission. Therefore either mastubation isn't moraly acceptabel or you and I are not "one".

I'm sure you don't really think that's what I meant? To say that the universe is one isn't to say that it's not made up of lots of different things. You and I are different but we are "of" the same ineffable something, in the same sense that two leaves on a branch are different but of the same tree.

&amp;gt;Not really, you get to a point were there are things whihc are. ZYou observe the world, and if others fail to observe the world properly you can't do much more than point and say "look at it, you are wrong." I can tell you the sky is blue and if you tell me it is red, I can't do much more than point. If you tell me murder is morally good I can't do much more than point either. Facts about the world are.

"The sky is blue" is a factual statement because there is nobody in the world who sees it as anything other than blue. On the other hand, "nobody can possibly find war beautiful", for example, is not a factual statement by virtue of the fact that there *are* people who find it beautiful (consider The Art of War, one of the world's most best-selling books, which treats war as beautiful).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845534902.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm sure you don't really think that's what I meant? To say that the universe is one isn't to say that it's not made up of lots of different things. You and I are different but we are "of" the same ineffable something, in the same sense that two leaves on a branch are different but of the same tree.

I think it's exactly what your claim entails.  I assume by we are "one" you have in mind some sort of Hindu or Buddhist understanding of the world - that the apparent differences between us are illusion.

If you and I are leaves of the same tree then me touching you in any way I see fit is really just the tree touching itself and it has the right to touch itself as it sees fit.  If you and I are just different parts of the universal consciousness, then any contact I have with you is just the universal consciousness playing with itself.  And one may do with oneself what one pleases.

&amp;gt;"The sky is blue" is a factual statement because there is nobody in the world who sees it as anything other than blue. 

That's actually not true, some people have different perceptions.  A person with faulty eyes might see the sky as some other color or not be able to see it at all.

&amp;gt;On the other hand, "nobody can possibly find war beautiful", for example, is not a factual statement by virtue of the fact that there are people who find it beautiful (consider The Art of War, one of the world's most best-selling books, which treats war as beautiful).

That's not my claim.  My claim is war is ugly.  Some people may see it as beautiful, but jsut like people who have faulty visual senses the people who see war as beautiful have faulty moral senses.

NB - most people don't buy The Art of War because they think war is beautiful, they buy it because they think it's important to know how to win (or that it's an important book worth reading).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845775258.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think it's exactly what your claim entails. I assume by we are "one" you have in mind some sort of Hindu or Buddhist understanding of the world - that the apparent differences between us are illusion.

Actually, Buddhism/Hinduism entails a much more nuanced idea of the universe than that, it's really interesting! It varies a bit because these are massive religions, but the gist as I know it is that in Hindu cosmology, the universe is conceived as being (fundamentally) two basic elements: the self and the universe which the self experiences/ exists within (atman and brahman, respectively). The ultimate realisation is to see, through the abandonment of concepts and ideas, that these two elements are part of the same whole, as opposed to two independent entities that have nothing to do with one another. 

This can be visualised by imagining a triangle with an infinitely diminishing tip/point and an infinitely expanding base (the point being the self, the atman, and the base being the universe which the self sees, the brahman). Although the point and the base are totally and completely different in every possible way, you can see that they are part of the same thing.

Another good visualisation, with the big bang theory/inflation in mind, is this: imagine you shoot a blue paintball at a wall, and it creates a huge sprawling splatter of paint. If you isolate two splatters and compare them, you might find absolutely no similarities in size or shape, but what colour will they be? 

Abstract concepts aside, I'll ask you this: if we aren't part of the same whole, why is it that humans all look fairly similar? Isn't it because we grew out of the same proverbial tree/seed? The same question can be asked of planets, stars, solar systems, and galaxies. If we aren't a single whole, those are some tremendous coincidences. How many big bangs were there?

&amp;gt;That's actually not true, some people have different perceptions. A person with faulty eyes might see the sky as some other color or not be able to see it at all.

Fair, but isn't that a point in my favour? The sky's blueness being fundamentally true was your point, it wasn't mine. If you can see the relativity of such "true" things as the sky's blueness, can't you see it in seemingly more subjective things like whether a cow warrants higher-than-object status?

&amp;gt;That's not my claim. My claim is war is ugly. Some people may see it as beautiful, but jsut like people who have faulty visual senses the people who see war as beautiful have faulty moral senses.

I do completely understand your point, but I still can't get past the notion that somebody who disagrees with you has "faulty" senses. Doesn't that mean that you yourself are the benchmark by which all of humanity should judge their moral behaviour?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845807887.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The ultimate realisation is to see, through the abandonment of concepts and ideas, that these two elements are part of the same whole, as opposed to two independent entities that have nothing to do with one another. 

Which is exactly what I said only in more flowery language.  If we are both part of the same whole and not two independent entities, then you and I are actually one.  And if we are one, then this part of us (me) can do as he sees fit to that part of us (you) because in reality we are one and an entity may do with itself as it pleases.

No amount of visualization or refraiming gets past that single problem.  If we are a part of the same whole I may do to you as I please because really I am only doing to myself.

&amp;gt;Fair, but isn't that a point in my favour? The sky's blueness being fundamentally true was your point, it wasn't mine. If you can see the relativity of such "true" things as the sky's blueness, can't you see it in seemingly more subjective things like whether a cow warrants higher-than-object status?

It isn't relative.  the sky is blue.  Some people see it some don't.  The perception is retaliative, the truth is not.

&amp;gt;I do completely understand your point, but I still can't get past the notion that somebody who disagrees with you has "faulty" senses. Doesn't that mean that you yourself are the benchmark by which all of humanity should judge their moral behaviour?

No, my sense may well be faulty too.  Historically most people had faulty moral senses (failing to recognize the true humanity of large numbers of people for example).  I think it's likelier than not that my moral sense is also faulty.  Sucks to be me.  But I also think it's the only moral sense I have access to, so I have to use it to the best of my ability, hone it where I can, apply corrective measures where I can, and keep chugging along.  it may be faulty (it probably is) but I can do my best to make it as faultless as possible.  (And based on my experiences with others I think its less faulty than most, but I could be wrong about that).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845831128.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Which is exactly what I said only in more flowery language. If we are both part of the same whole and not two independent entities, then you and I are actually one. And if we are one, then this part of us (me) can do as he sees fit to that part of us (you) because in reality we are one and an entity may do with itself as it pleases.

&amp;gt;No amount of visualization or refraiming gets past that single problem. If we are a part of the same whole I may do to you as I please because really I am only doing to myself.

Why does the universe being a single whole preclude multiple experiences? I'm not saying that there is only one single conscious being in the universe, I'm saying that all of the conscious beings in the universe are part of the same whole. There's no law that says a single whole must be harmonious. In fact all of the classic illustrations of this whole generally imply some sort of conflict: yin/yang, the ouroboros, the wheel of fortune, etc.

&amp;gt;It isn't relative. the sky is blue. Some people see it some don't. The perception is retaliative, the truth is not.

There's no such thing as a truth that isn't relative to perception; there's no such thing as an objective universe. I appreciate that that sounds wacky, because it's contrary to our entire worldview, but the idea of an objective universe is a uniquely western idea, and there isn't a single scrap of evidence for it. It's entirely ideological. Think of this: every conceivable experience has consciousness as a part of it, right? So an experience without consciousness is, quite literally, inconceivable, and there's no evidence whatsoever that the universe can exist without consciousness (other than it just "feels like it should", which is just what it feels like to be ideologically offended).

&amp;gt;No, my sense may well be faulty too. Historically most people had faulty moral senses (failing to recognize the true humanity of large numbers of people for example). I think it's likelier than not that my moral sense is also faulty. Sucks to be me. But I also think it's the only moral sense I have access to, so I have to use it to the best of my ability, hone it where I can, apply corrective measures where I can, and keep chugging along. it may be faulty (it probably is) but I can do my best to make it as faultless as possible. (And based on my experiences with others I think its less faulty than most, but I could be wrong about that).

Fair enough, so I wonder if there can be said to be any central "benchmark" for morality at all. I think it's more the case that it's different from person to person. In this case, arguing the idea that eating a dog is more objectionable than eating a cow from personal feelings can only really be used to tell yourself what to do, not to tell other people what they should do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845911507.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why does the universe being a single whole preclude multiple experiences? I'm not saying that there is only one single conscious being in the universe, I'm saying that all of the conscious beings in the universe are part of the same whole. There's no law that says a single whole must be harmonious. In fact all of the classic illustrations of this whole generally imply some sort of conflict: yin/yang, the ouroboros, the wheel of fortune, etc.

I'm not saying the exprence has to be harmonious.  I'm saying that I have the right to do with my body as I please, and if you and I are part of the same unified thing simply having diffrent exprences, your body is as much me as my body is.  

Let me ask you this.  If a person suffering from Multiple Personality Disorder starts to masturbate and part way through the dominant personality shifts, have they assaulted themselves?  I'd say no.  How is that any different than me jerking you off?  We are a unified whole, just having different perceptual experiences.

&amp;gt;There's no such thing as a truth that isn't relative to perception; there's no such thing as an objective universe. I appreciate that that sounds wacky, because it's contrary to our entire worldview, but the idea of an objective universe is a uniquely western idea, and there isn't a single scrap of evidence for it. It's entirely ideological. Think of this: every conceivable experience has consciousness as a part of it, right? So an experience without consciousness is, quite literally, inconceivable, and there's no evidence whatsoever that the universe can exist without consciousness (other than it just "feels like it should", which is just what it feels like to be ideologically offended).

I'm familiar with this view.  It's wrong.  

It's not only wrong it's self-contradictory.  You say there is no evidence for objective reality, but if there is no objective reality what is the value of evidence?  If reality is purely subjective, then why is your experience of reality being subjective privileged over my experience that there is an objective reality.  I have "perceiving the existence of objective reality" experiences on a daily basis.  If reality is purely subjective, why is it that when I read the same book as 100 other people we all agree on the broad outlines of the text?  I'd argue that it's becasue teh words on the page are the same (they are the same objective reality) even if each of us has a slightly different reaction to that reality.  

I may as a human being see all the world through my own subjective filters, but there is an objective world I am seeing.

&amp;gt;so I wonder if there can be said to be any central "benchmark" for morality at all.

Sure there can.  Most people agree on the broad outlines of morality.  Rape is immoral.  Murder is immoral.  etc.  ALmost everyone has that same perception of the moral truth, which strongly sugests that it is the moral truth (The same way that almost everyone having the perception the sky is blue strongly sugests the sky is blue).  We could all be wrong, but it seems deeply unlikely.  And we are moving to increasing consensus.  Almost everyone now agrees women are human too - that was not the case.  The moral truth is the moral truth, we just are getting better at seeing it.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27847586972.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not saying the exprence has to be harmonious. I'm saying that I have the right to do with my body as I please, and if you and I are part of the same unified thing simply having diffrent exprences, your body is as much me as my body is.
Let me ask you this. If a person suffering from Multiple Personality Disorder starts to masturbate and part way through the dominant personality shifts, have they assaulted themselves? I'd say no. How is that any different than me jerking you off? We are a unified whole, just having different perceptual experiences.

I have to admit, I don't get the point you're making so I can't really respond. Sorry, long day!

&amp;gt;If reality is purely subjective, then why is your experience of reality being subjective privileged over my experience that there is an objective reality.

You don't experience that there is an objective reality, you only *believe* that there is an objective reality. You have never perceived a reality without consciousness, because you have always been present in everything you've ever perceived. Therefore, you can't provide any evidence for a universe that exists without consciousness.

&amp;gt;If reality is purely subjective, why is it that when I read the same book as 100 other people we all agree on the broad outlines of the text? I'd argue that it's becasue teh words on the page are the same (they are the same objective reality) even if each of us has a slightly different reaction to that reality.

You misunderstand me - I agree that we all experience the same reality, I just don't agree that it exists independently of our experience.

&amp;gt;Sure there can. Most people agree on the broad outlines of morality. Rape is immoral. Murder is immoral. etc. ALmost everyone has that same perception of the moral truth, which strongly sugests that it is the moral truth (The same way that almost everyone having the perception the sky is blue strongly sugests the sky is blue). We could all be wrong, but it seems deeply unlikely. And we are moving to increasing consensus. Almost everyone now agrees women are human too - that was not the case. The moral truth is the moral truth, we just are getting better at seeing it.

I've thought about this before. I believe that our perception that we are at the absolute cutting edge/height of moral superiority is an illusion. This is because we are using our own values to judge ourselves. We look to the past, and we see that they didn't share our values, and so we say that they were less moral than we are. But they would have said the same thing about us! And we'd say the same thing about people from the distant future. If you take a sample of people from 1,000 years ago and ask them to judge their own morality, the morality of people who lives 1,000 years before them, and our morality, they would rank themselves #1. The height of that bell curve is always going to be the present day because it's a tautological judgement (that is, one's values are being judged against one's values).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27847601312.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You don't experience that there is an objective reality, you only believe that there is an objective reality. 

Let me focus in on this.  How can you say that?   By what criteria can you judge the true nature of my exprence?  If there is no objective realtiy, then my exprence is what it is.  Whithout refrence to some objective truth how can you say that my exprence is false?

If I tell you I have objective experiences all the time.  how can you maintain that is false without reference to some objective truth.  ("There is no objective truth" is, after all, a claim of objective truth in and of itself.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27847619404.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Let me focus in on this. How can you say that? By what criteria can you judge the true nature of my exprence? If there is no objective realtiy, then my exprence is what it is. Whithout refrence to some objective truth how can you say that my exprence is false?

Does your experience have the quality of experience? If so, then it isn't objective, it's relative to you. Do faraway things appear smaller than closeup things? If so, they're relative to their distance to your eyes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27847671630.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Does your experience have the quality of experience? If so, then it isn't objective, it's relative to you.

How can you say that?  Are you making an objective claim about the nature of objective and subjective experiences?

If I tell you I have objective experiences which are both objective and have the quality of experience how can you say that's wrong without an appeal to an objective reality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27848673337.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>How do you define the word "objective"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27848871447.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't matter.   Because you can't tell me my definition is wrong without an appeal to some objective truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27848905322.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>But I'm arguing that objective truth doesn't exist, so I don't understand how your logic follows. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27848951963.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>"objective truth doesn't exist" is, in and of itself, an objective truth claim.   

If you say "objective truth doesn't exist" you are asserting an objective fact.  

When you say "objective truth doesn't exist" you contradict yourself as you are asserting an objective truth.

You can say "I experience no objective truth" - that's a subjective truth claim (and mores the pity for you).  But when you start to tell me what I experience you are now asserting you have access to knowledge which is not limited by your own subjectivity - access to some objective knowledge about what the nature of humanity is and how that limits my ability to perceive things objectively.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27848956365.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I need to know what your definition of objective is to understand your argument</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849411213.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>My point is you don't.

If you are right and there is nothing but our own subjective experiences, you **can't** know my definition of anything.  The fact that you think you **can** know my definition proves that you don't believe that we are limited to subjective knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850193683.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure, but I suspect your argument hinges on a different definition of subjective/objective, so we aren't talking about the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850264296.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Okay.  On your definition of subjective/objective.  How can you know that I can't have objective experiences?  And how is the claim that no one can have objective experiences **not** a claim for objective truth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850281164.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>You can't have objective experiences because all of your experiences are relative to you. You have never had an experience that you weren't present for. All experiences are relative to an experiencer, and without an experiencer, there are no experiences. To suggest that an "objective" universe (that is, one that exists without an experiencer) exists is an unfounded claim which, as far as I can see, isn't logically possible. 

As for the second part, I suppose what I'm saying seems like an objective truth claim in a sense, although ultimately it's technically subjective because I'm saying it, and everything I say is "tainted" with my point of view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850282292.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  You have never had an experience that you weren't present for.

How do you know that?  

&amp;gt;All experiences are relative to an experiencer, and without an experiencer, there are no experiences. 

And how do you know that?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850284433.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>Because those are necessary implications of what it is to have an experience. In other words, it's implied in the sentence itself.

If I say "I'm having an experience but I'm not experiencing it" then it's the same as saying "I'm not having an experience", which is the same as saying "there is no experience". We're talking about properties of this word's definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850391335.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because those are necessary implications of what it is to have an experience. 

Why do you think that?  How can you make a claim about what it is for me to have an experience?  On what grounds can yo comment on the universal nature of experiencing when there is no objective truth?  Why are you not limited to telling me what your experience of experiencing is?  How can you universalize that?

&amp;gt; In other words, it's implied in the sentence itself.

And why should the implications of the word matter?  Is there objective truth about definitions that somehow matters?

&amp;gt;If I say "I'm having an experience but I'm not experiencing it" then it's the same as saying "I'm not having an experience", which is the same as saying "there is no experience". 

Why should accidents of language matter?  Why do you think that the fact that the English language is bad at expressing the nature of objective experience means I can't have one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850402903.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you're understanding me. If you *are* having an experience, then you necessarily *are* experiencing, simply because those two sentences mean the same thing. What argument can you put forward that challenges this? It's axiomatic. 

Just to be clear, your argument is as follows: it's possible to have an experience without an experiencer. Correct? Or have I misunderstood?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850416230.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>I understood you perfictly.

What I don't understand is how *you* can make a claim about the nature of *my* experience.  

Unless there is some objective reality some truth which is true for all people no mater the nature of their experience.

&amp;gt;Just to be clear, your argument is as follows: it's possible to have an experience without an experiencer. Correct? Or have I misunderstood?

You've misunderstood.  My argument is that your claim that "You can't have an experience without an experience" is a claim about objective reality.  It is a claim about some truth that is true no matter what the person experiencing it says.  It's a place where if I tell you I'm having an experience without an experiencer, you can and will tell me I am wrong or mistaken.  It's a place where your understanding of reality trumps my on subjective experience of it.

And there are certantly people who report having experiences without being an experience - see most of the writing on "ego death" or a good chunk of Buddhist writing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850431202.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You've misunderstood. My argument is that your claim that "You can't have an experience without an experience" is a claim about objective reality. It is a claim about some truth that is true no matter what the person experiencing it says. It's a place where if I tell you I'm having an experience without an experiencer, you can and will tell me I am wrong or mistaken. It's a place where your understanding of reality trumps my on subjective experience of it.

My claim is something that is true for all people. How does that necessitate a reality divorced from experience? That seems like a leap in logic to me.

&amp;gt;And there are certantly people who report having experiences without being an experience - see most of the writing on "ego death" or a good chunk of Buddhist writing.

These aren't experiences without an experiencer, they're experiences without ego. In other words, the "becoming" of the brahman, like I talked about before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850436691.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My claim is something that is true for all people. 

A thing that is true for all people is an objective truth.  

If you can tell me something about the nature of my experiences, without ever having experienced them (and since you've never been in my head you've never experienced my experiences) then you are making a claim about what is true independent of your own experiences, a claim of objective truth.

&amp;gt;These aren't experiences without an experiencer, they're experiences without ego.

Again, you are making a claim about the truth of someone else's experience.  That is a claim about what is true independent of your experience of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850475706.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;then you are making a claim about what is true independent of your own experiences, a claim of objective truth.

It isn't a claim of objective truth, because its truth depends on experience. A claim of objective truth would be suggesting that something exists or is true whether it is experienced or not, and I'm talking about experience itself; I can't talk objectively about subjectivity. I would say that *technically*, objectivity doesn't exist (although that's very pedantic and I wouldn't generally say that sort of thing outside of this discussion). 

&amp;gt;Again, you are making a claim about the truth of someone else's experience. That is a claim about what is true independent of your experience of it.

"Objective" doesn't mean independent of *my* experience, it meants independent of experience. But for the record, experiences of ego death are not about experiences which don't involve experience (which, as I've said, is impossible by definition, in the same way you can't have uncheesy cheese or dry water). Ego death is the realisation that the universe is one continuous process, and that far from being separate from the universe, we are the universe. It's a perfect example of what we were talking about before, with regards to the universe being "one". The identification with the ego (atman) is said to be the final barrier to realising the truth (that brahman is the self).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850488402.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It isn't a claim of objective truth, because its truth depends on experience.

No it doesn't.  You have no experience of my experiences.  You are making a claim about them absent any experience of them. You know the nature of experiencing for you, and are attempting to expand that to experience for everyone absent any experience of it.  You've made a claim about m mental and cognitive states without any experience of it.  You've made a claim about what is true absent any experience.  

&amp;gt;objectivity doesn't exist

That's another objective truth claim.  You have no experience of the non-existence of objectivity (or anything else for that matter) and yet you assert that in all of the world it doesn't exist?  how can you do so, whith deference to some truth that is true independent of experience?

&amp;gt;"Objective" doesn't mean independent of my experience, it meants independent of experience.

That's another objective truth claim.  You only experience the definition for you, how can you speak to the meaning of a word for me and everyone else if there is no objective truth?

&amp;gt;ego death are not about experiences which don't involve experience 

Another objective truth claim.  Having never been Dr. Leary experiencing ego death how can you say what his experience is?

&amp;gt;The identification with the ego (atman) is said to be the final barrier to realising the truth (that brahman is the self).

And one more objective truth claim.


Any time you make a claim about what is true for others you are making an objective truth claim.  You are speaking about what is true for them, independent of what their experience is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850491561.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>Let me ask you this: is it possible to have a block of wood that isn't made out of wood? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850499135.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>No.  But I believe in objective truth.

If I see a block of wood, touch it, taste it, smell it, and then, due to the oddities of my own cognitive system proclaim "This block of wood is made of metal."  How can you say I am wrong without appealing to an objective truth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850534764.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that to say "here is an experience without experience" is a sentence which cancels itself out. There's no logic to the argument by virtue of the fact that no argument is being made.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850540469.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>And my point is, you can't make that claim without an appeal to some truth that is true independent of experience.  Like logic.

Logic is true whether or not I experience it at all or experience it to be true.   An appeal to logic is an appeal to an objective truth.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850641215.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>You can't say that logic, or anything else at all, is "there" when you're not "looking", so to speak. How would you know? (And I don't literally mean you when I say "you're", by the way, I'm just finding it difficult to convey the point)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850642914.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>And yet you are fine applying it to the internal states of others.  Demanding that they apply it. 

Why do you think that logic as you experience it should or does apply to the internal states of others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850653386.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by the internal states of others? I'm not talking about internal states. I still don't think I'm expressing my point clearly and I'm finding it difficult to do so, so why don't you tell me my argument as far as you understand it. That way I'll know if I actually have failed to explain it properly or if you have a legitimate point that I'm not getting, because I think we're misunderstanding one another on some level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850666434.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>By internal states I mean the subjective experience.

Your argument is that there is no objective reality, that only through experience does the world exist and that things are only true subjectively (through the lenses of experience).

My point is that is a claim about objective reality.  That independent of the subjective observer you claim that we must experience the world subjectively.  You argue that logic dictates that out come, but my experience of logic may well not be the same as yours my logic (if there is no reality to it other than the experienced reality) may not force that conclusion.  Yet you feel fine applying logic to all experiences, which suggests that even if you don't recognize it you believe there are things which are true independent of the observer - things which are true whether my subjective experience is they are true or not.

Go back to your block of wood.  I could very well have a subjective experience that a block of wood is made of metal.  But you want to say that a block of wood has to be wood, no mater what my (or your) experience of it is - that means there is some truth which is true no matter what the experience is, some objective truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850690529.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>This is a crucial point I tried to highlight earlier: my argument is *not* that there can be no universally-true things. On the contrary, I would argue that subjectivity is universal.

My argument is that nothing can exist without an experiencer. In other words, my argument is that "this exists" is the same thing as saying "this is being experienced". 

You're conflating "universally true" with "objectively extant".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850724331.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You're conflating "universally true" with "objectively extant".

It's not a conflation they are the same thing.  If a thing is universally true - true for people whether or not the experience it - then it is objectively extant.  (And if it is objectively extant it is universally true.)

If a thing is true for me, independent of whether or not I experience it (If it is universally true) then it must be objectively true.  

How can a thing be true for me, when I don't experience it, unless there is an objective truth.  If I have a "This block of wood is made of metal" experience, if that is my true subjective experience, then how can you say that a block of wood must be made of wood without an appeal to an extant objective truth?

If I don't have a subjective experience of logic (and as someone who taught logic I can say that many people don't) how can you say logic is true for me without an appeal to an objectively extant truth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850728140.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If a thing is universally true - true for people whether or not the experience it - then it is objectively extant. (And if it is objectively extant it is universally true.)

That's not what universally true means, universally true means "true in all cases". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850738937.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>If it is true in all cases, then it must exist.  And if it is true in all cases, then it is true whether or not I have the relevant subjective experience.  And it is is true whether or not I have the relevant subjective experience, then it's truth must be objective.

Things which are universally true are objectively true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850746298.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And if it is true in all cases, then it is true whether or not I have the relevant subjective experience.

*That* is the central claim I'm arguing against. That is exactly the leap in logic which we all make, and the expression of an unfounded ideological belief. 

If I ask you to prove that something exists whether or not you have the relevant subjective experience, how would you go about doing so? Even if you come up with a genius elaborate experiment, the moment you start experiencing your own experiment you'll have contaminated it with experience, the very thing you were trying to demonstrate isn't essential. 

Even putting aside the fact that it would be impossible to prove, it's also impossible even to imagine. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27850776608.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Is it true in all cases that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal?

Is it true that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal even when exprenced by a peson who has the exprence that the block of wood is not made of wood, but is made of metal?

If I take a block of wood, and consume sufficient mind altering drugs that I experience the block of wood as a block of metal, is it now a block of metal?

&amp;gt;Even putting aside the fact that it would be impossible to prove, it's also impossible even to imagine. 

Interestingly those are both objective truth claims too.  

The latter is actually false, as I'm doing a very good job of imagining the existence of objective truth right now.  

And while I can't prove that objective truth exists, I can compile enough evidence that it makes me think it more likely than not does.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27851036419.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The latter is actually false, as I'm doing a very good job of imagining the existence of objective truth right now.  

You don't understand what I mean by objective and subjective. Whatever you're imagining, you're there. You're present for whatever it is you're imagining right now. You can't imagine a completely empty room, because you'll always be there in the room, looking out from one particular corner. 

&amp;gt;And while I can't prove that objective truth exists, I can compile enough evidence that it makes me think it more likely than not does.  

What possible evidence can you put forward that the world exists when you're not looking at it?

 This is a matter of axiomatic fact. It is *axiomatically* true that you can't provide evidence for the existence of a world without experience, because you'll experience whatever evidence you provide, invalidating it. This isn't something you can argue, it's necessarily true. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27851068817.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>You've ignored my key questions, so I'll ask again:  

Is it true in all cases that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal?

Is it true that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal even when exprenced by a peson who has the exprence that the block of wood is not made of wood, but is made of metal?

If I take a block of wood, and consume sufficient mind altering drugs that I experience the block of wood as a block of metal, is it now a block of metal?

&amp;gt; Whatever you're imagining, you're there. 

No I'm not. I'm imagining the existence of objective reality...right now... and I'm not in that imagining.  I've checked a couple of times and I'm still not there.  

How can you say my subjective experience is false?  Surely you are not in my immaginig, or in my mind.  So you have no subjective access to my imagining.  If you have no subjective access to it, how can you possibly claim to know anything about it?  Unless there are objective truths, things you can know with no subjective experience of them.

&amp;gt;This isn't something you can argue, it's necessarily true. 

Why is it necessarily true?  What kind of experiences have I had that lead me to believe this? Right now, or just a few minutes ago, I was imagining the existence of objective truth, so I can surely comprehend such a thing.  So why can't I have experiences which suggest it is true?  How are you in a position to tell me what kind of experiences I can and can't have?  Have you ever had any experience of my experiences?  If not why do you even think they exist?  If not how can you make claims about the nature of them, if all truth is subjective and you have no subjective experience of them?

&amp;gt; It is axiomatically true that you can't provide evidence for the existence of a world without experience, because you'll experience whatever evidence you provide, invalidating it.

I don't experience that as axiomatically true.  So it isn't true for me.  I thought about it just now, and it doesn't ring true.  My experience of it is that it is false.  How can you say it is true for me, without appealing to some objective truth?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27852435194.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You've ignored my key questions, so I'll ask again:
Is it true in all cases that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal?
Is it true that a block of wood is made of wood and not metal even when exprenced by a peson who has the exprence that the block of wood is not made of wood, but is made of metal?
If I take a block of wood, and consume sufficient mind altering drugs that I experience the block of wood as a block of metal, is it now a block of metal?

No, those would just be that one individual's subjective experience. But the crucial point is this: that's not because the individual's experience disagrees with "objective truth" (in the sense of a truth that exists independent of experience), it's because the individual's experience is idiosyncratic; it isn't corroborated, in other words, by the experiences of anybody else.

Consider this: if you then go on to say that there's a block of wood which *everybody* experiences as a block of metal, and ask whether that's really a block of metal or a block of wood, by what basis could you call it a block of wood? You would have to step in, as the narrator, and say "I say it's a block of wood because I know something which these fictitious people don't know", essentially inserting your experience into the experiment. There's no way it can ever be thought of as a block of wood without somebody experiencing it that way, because again, by what basis could it be thought of as such?

&amp;gt;No I'm not. I'm imagining the existence of objective reality...right now... and I'm not in that imagining. I've checked a couple of times and I'm still not there.

Imagine a completely empty corridor that is infinite in length. Nobody is in this corridor. Not you, not anybody else. No "experience" whatsoever. Now answer this: do the "lines", where the walls connect to the floors, appear to converge and get smaller and smaller the further away they are? If there are doors on the walls, do the further away ones seem smaller, and the closer ones seem bigger? If so, then what is it they're further away from? This should be a helpful illustration in realising the truth of relativity. *Everything* is relative to an experiencer. An experiencer is implied in every experience, because, as Timothy Leary or any "enlightened" person or advanced Buddhist or whatever will attest to: the experience and experiencer are *not different things*. You *are* the world. You can't be extracted from it, and it can't be extracted from you.

&amp;gt;I don't experience that as axiomatically true. So it isn't true for me. I thought about it just now, and it doesn't ring true. My experience of it is that it is false. How can you say it is true for me, without appealing to some objective truth?

I do understand what you're saying, but really consider what I've written above. The problem is that we fail to recognise that experience and experiencer are one and the same, because it's not possible to divorce the two.

Again, I'm not appealing to a "technically objective" truth, in the sense that this is a truth which exists outside of exprience, I'm appealing to an "objective" truth in the sense that it's universally true; true for all (or most) experiences. 

I get what you're saying, you're saying that if everything is subjective then there's no reason for everyone to be experiencing the same reality, and you're saying, rightly so, that there must be something tying together or "grounding" our experiences. The only resistance I have to conceding this point is that it's not *evidence of* objective reality, it's just something which the model of subjective reality can't solve. It's like saying that if one team misses a goal, the other should gain a point. It's not a point in anyone's favour, it's just something we don't know the answer to.

In fact, that very "ineffable thing", the "constant" which, for whatever reason, runs through all of experience, is what is meant in many religions by God. It's certainly what is meant by Brahman, which is the Hindu analogue for God. In Hinduism, (Vedanta, at least), this mystery isn't answered by the model of objective reality, it's answered by the idea that we are all the same being at different stages, places, and times (i.e. with different karma). That's sufficient proof that there is more than one model that can answer this mystery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27852790227.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's because the individual's experience is idiosyncratic; it isn't corroborated, in other words, by the experiences of anybody else.

Why does that matter?  If there is no objective truth, how and why is corroboration important.  It's a block of wood mate out of metal for me and a block of wood made out of wood for you.  If there is no objective reality to compare against aren't we equally right?  If the truth is all subjective, isn't my truth equal in value to yours?

&amp;gt;

Consider this: if you then go on to say that there's a block of wood which everybody experiences as a block of metal, and ask whether that's really a block of metal or a block of wood, by what basis could you call it a block of wood? You would have to step in, as the narrator, and say "I say it's a block of wood because I know something which these fictitious people don't know", essentially inserting your experience into the experiment. There's no way it can ever be thought of as a block of wood without somebody experiencing it that way, because again, by what basis could it be thought of as such?

Why does it have to be thought of as wood to be wood?  You are begging the question here, assuming the conclusion to prove it.

&amp;gt;You are the world.  You can't be extracted from it, and it can't be extracted from you.

How can you know that?  This is something which you are claiming is true without any experience of it.  How can that be if there are no objective truths?  There are people in the world you've never met, talked to, thought of, is this true for them?

&amp;gt;Again, I'm not appealing to a "technically objective" truth, in the sense that this is a truth which exists outside of exprience, I'm appealing to an "objective" truth in the sense that it's universally true; true for all (or most) experiences. 

But you have no experience of my experiences.  None.  Zero. So how can you say what they are.  In fact you have experience of your own experiences only.  You have knowledge of one and only one set of experiences.   So how can you speak to what my exprences are or anyone other than your own?  

How can you tell me the nature of my experiences without an appeal to a thing which you believe to be true, despite no experience of it?

&amp;gt; The only resistance I have to conceding this point is that it's not evidence of objective reality, it's just something which the model of subjective reality can't solve.

If there is a fact, which you concede is true, which can't be accounted for in your theory, you have to change your theory.  It may not prove objective reality (I think it does, but set that aside), but what it does prove is that the theory lacks sufficient explanatory power.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27852893718.0" user="Fealiks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How can you know that? 

I've explained exactly how. Imagine an empty corridor, and now try to imagine it without being present for it. You can't. If the further away doors appear smaller, it's because they're further away from you, therefore you are part of the scene. You can't imagine a scene without being part of it.

Another example: imagine an empty room. On each wall is a window. Through one window is a vase with red flowers, through one is a vase with blue flowers, through one is a vase with green flowers, and through the last window, a vase with yellow flowers. Now imagine this room without yourself in it. Imagine it empty of any "experiencer" or "conscious being" of any sort. Again, you will find it impossible, and you will know that it is impossible because there will always be one vase which you can't see. This is because it's behind your head. You are a part of the scene, *because* there is a scene.

Another example: imagine a completely empty space. Complete blackness, absolutely no experience happening, and no experiencer to see it happen. You notice that there is a ball, floating, and you see it move. How do you know that it's moving? You can only know that it's moving because you see it move relative to your position in space. It gets smaller and larger as it goes forwards and backwards, for example. Therefore, as soon as we introduce an "experience" (the ball), we have necessarily introduced an "experiencer".

These examples show us that the experiencer and the experience are fundamentally inextricable.

&amp;gt;But you have no experience of my experiences. None. Zero.

Are they experiences, yes or no? 

The definition of axiomatic is "self evident". If you are having an experience, it's axiomatic (self evident) that *you* are *having* an experience. There is no activity without an actor. Your argument is like saying "you can never know that every cup of water has water in it". I can know that, simply because a cup of water being a cup of water is axiomatic. I don't have to have direct knowledge of every single cup of water to verify that every cup of water is a cup of water. 

&amp;gt;If there is a fact, which you concede is true, which can't be accounted for in your theory, you have to change your theory.

This isn't true. If I say "gravity is the force which binds objects", I haven't explained why some objects have colour. That doesn't invalidate the theory of gravity, it just means that the theory of gravity isn't sufficient to explain colour. Again, if I say "evolution is a process by which creatures change", I haven't explained how sound propagates through the air, or how electric current works, but that doesn't mean that evolution is a bad theory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27853172345.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I've explained exactly how. Imagine an empty corridor, and now try to imagine it without being present for it. You can't. If the further away doors appear smaller, it's because they're further away from you, therefore you are part of the scene. You can't imagine a scene without being part of it.

But how do **you** know that **I** can't.  You can know that **you** can't.  But you have no access to my experiences.  How can you make a claim about what I can or cannot experience?

You have no subjective knowledge of my experiences, right?  You've never been inside my head, felt what I've felt, been me, right?   If you can make a claim about my experiences, that means there are things you can know without ever having experienced them.  That means there are objective truths.

&amp;gt;imagine an empty room. On each wall is a window. Through one window is a vase with red flowers, through one is a vase with blue flowers, through one is a vase with green flowers, and through the last window, a vase with yellow flowers. Now imagine this room without yourself in it. Imagine it empty of any "experiencer" or "conscious being" of any sort. Again, you will find it impossible, and you will know that it is impossible because there will always be one vase which you can't see. This is because it's behind your head. You are a part of the scene, because there is a scene.

I actually can imagine being able to see all four at once.  I don't find it that difficult to do so.  I don't know that proves anything one way or another, but it's true.

&amp;gt;Complete blackness, absolutely no experience happening, and no experiencer to see it happen. You notice that there is a ball, floating, and you see it move. How do you know that it's moving? You can only know that it's moving because you see it move relative to your position in space. It gets smaller and larger as it goes forwards and backwards, for example. Therefore, as soon as we introduce an "experience" (the ball), we have necessarily introduced an "experiencer".

It seems to me in this example, the experiencer exists before the experience - or are you saying it's possible to experience the utter void without there being an expreiencer?

&amp;gt;The definition of axiomatic is "self evident". If you are having an experience, it's axiomatic (self evident) that you are having an experience. There is no activity without an actor. 

Yes but that requires an appeal to an objective reality.  A thing you know is true without ever having experienced it.

&amp;gt;I can know that, simply because a cup of water being a cup of water is axiomatic. I don't have to have direct knowledge of every single cup of water to verify that every cup of water is a cup of water.

I agree, but I believe in objective reality.

You say it's self-evident, but that's an appeal to an objective reality.  First because without any experince you are making claims about lots of cups of water.  Second, because you are appealing to some principle that is true across the board (A is A, is an objective truth claim).  I can say, based on my experience that "this A is an A", but when I say "all As are As" I'm making a claim about objective reality.

Every cup of water is a cup of water is an objective truth claim.  It is a statement about the nature of reality independent of your experience of it - and independent of any expreince of it.

&amp;gt;This isn't true.

Fair enough I should say, if there is a fact, which you concede is true, which can't be accounted for in your theory, and which the theory should account for, then you have to change your theory.

The existence of perceptual phenomena that can't be accounted for by your theory of perception is a problem for the theory.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843760135.0" user="KoruMatau" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is 100% based on the fallacy that human wishes/emotions are objectively valuable. 

A solid moral foundation should function with as little human-centrism as possible. That is the only way to make something that is objectively rational. 

Your argument boils down to "people think of dogs as being their friends so eating them is worse than eating another animal that is *just as sentient* and feels *just as much pain.* 


That's ridiculous. Cows, pigs, chickens etc. all expeirence pain in a similar way to dogs and humans as far as we can tell. Killing and eating them shares exactly equal status morally with eating dogs. Almost any argument to the contrary is purely emotional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843805153.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Your argument is 100% based on the fallacy that human wishes/emotions are objectively valuable. 

That's not at all what I'm saying.  I don't see any objective value in human wishes or emotions.  I do see value in humans responding to human emotions in others, but that's not because the emotions are valuable, but the act of recognising that others are not objects is valuable.

&amp;gt;Your argument boils down to "people think of dogs as being their friends so eating them is worse than eating another animal that is just as sentient and feels just as much pain.

That's at best a substantial mischaracterization of my position.

&amp;gt;Cows, pigs, chickens etc. all expeirence pain in a similar way to dogs and humans as far as we can tell. 

Even with that substantial mischaracterization you have to change the argument to get here.  Notice you've dropped sentience as a criteria, now you are talking about pain only rather than sentience and pain. (Because the idea that chickens are as sentient as dogs is laughable.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843899248.0" user="KoruMatau" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's not at all what I'm saying. I don't see any objective value in human wishes or emotions. I do see value in humans responding to human emotions in others, but that's not because the emotions are valuable, but the act of recognising that others are not objects is valuable.


Why is it valuable though? The core of your belief is based on human-centrism.


&amp;gt;That's at best a substantial mischaracterization of my position.


Not really. You said dogs have value because humans have bred them as companions. Their value to you came from humans, not their own attributes.


&amp;gt;Even with that substantial mischaracterization you have to change the argument to get here. Notice you've dropped sentience as a criteria, now you are talking about pain only rather than sentience and pain. (Because the idea that chickens are as sentient as dogs is laughable.)


I'm not changing the argument, you don't understand sentience. Part of sentience is the ability to experience pain. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843921678.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text> &amp;gt; Why is it valuable though? The core of your belief is based on human-centrism.

It's valuable becasue that is the ethical demand when confronted with an other.  It ahs nothing to do with being human or not.  It has to do with being a moral actor (by which i mean an actor capable of chosing right or wrong) confronted with an other (by wich I mean a being that is capable of being both a subject and an object).   It's only if you assume that only humans are moral actors or only humans are others that this becomes human-centric.  (Though if either of those things is true, then there is nothing wrong with a human-centric ethics.)

&amp;gt;Not really. You said dogs have value because humans have bred them as companions. Their value to you came from humans, not their own attributes.

No I said that they have the attributes they have because humans bread them for those attributes (which is true).  Their moral import is a result of their attributes.  

&amp;gt;I'm not changing the argument, you don't understand sentience. Part of sentience is the ability to experience pain

"is just as sentient **and** feels just as much pain."  (emphasis added).  "And" is conjunctive, it means both sides of the statement are true.  You moved from an "and" to an "or" where you can focus on one side or the other of your claim.  Now maybe you meant to write "is just as sentient **or** feels just as much pain.", but that's not what you did write.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844024592.0" user="megablast" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That makes a huge difference.

Does it? Not from my point of view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844369444.0" user="qwe340" delta="False">
    <text>Now, there seem to be some evidence that the first domestication of dogs [happened in southern china](http://www.nytimes.com/2009/09/08/science/08dogs.html) , the exact place the recent dog eating scandal happened so there is a possibility that they were actually using dogs for the precise reason it was initially bred for (food) and the rest of the world just diverged from the initial purpose and used it differently. 



In particular, China is probably one of the earliest agrarian societies where farming overtook hunting/herding as the major food source so they have little use for the companion side of dogs. In fact, from what i know, some farmers from the south of china do see cows more in the light of how we see dogs (there are chinese fairytales involving guardian cows) because they are useful for plowing the field.  



Now, I doubt southern chinese people have much of a tradition of eating dogs (apparently the government of that town drummed up the dog festival and tried to back it up with cultural significance to boost tourism). It's probably more of a take it or leave it occasional thing because there isn't much of a meat eating tradition. (agrarian society, meat is historically more for festivals/ special occasions). 




I think a possible timeline to the dog thing is that traditional han chinese people domesticated the dog for meat and because they value agriculture more, did not really bred or value the companion characteristics and dogs were kept in small populations for occasional feasting. Then, the mongols or huns or manchus (all to the north of historical han chinese, all herding communities. They underlie the anti-dog eating attitude of modern day northern china. I.E. if you want to eat dog in northern china, you have to go to an ethnically korean village) probably discovered the domesticated dog in one of the raids (remember, the wall is built to keep them out) and found it much more valuable due to their herding life style. Thus, the dogs probably exploded in population and spread across the world. 



Now, most if not all modern dogs are probably descendants of the northern bred companion dogs because the chinese meat bred probably wasn't kept in large enough numbers (inefficient meat animal for special occasions). However, because there is no history of companionship or emotional attachement. Some southern farmers (there's a huge difference in the attitude of urban ppl who have internet and live like the first world and the farmers who are like 50 years behind). might somewhat rightfully be like, "the fuck, we invented this shit and it's definitely for eating" not realizing that it wasn't the same thing their ancestors ate like 10000 years ago. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27844381957.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Only [more recent evidence](http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/14/health/dogs-domesticated-europe/) contradicts that finding.  Suggesting domestication happened earlier in Europe and not for food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845018300.0" user="kosmic_kolossos" delta="False">
    <text>The only variable changing in your equation is the animal's relationship with humans. What does that have to do with anything?

Cows and pigs are intelligent beings, who have the capacity for fear, pain, and loneliness-
-and we put them through immeasurable amounts of suffering. Right from the birth of it's existence, 'til it's anguished last breath.

Imagine if we did that sort of shit to humans...

&amp;gt;[The claim that it's okay to slaughter pigs, for example, rather than dogs, because dogs would suffer more, is misleading and vacuous and there are no data to support that conclusion. All of these mammals, and all other mammals, are sentient beings who share the same neural architecture underlying their emotional lives and who experience a wide spectrum of emotions including the capacity to feel pain and to suffer.](http://www.livescience.com/39717-are-pigs-as-smart-as-dogs.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27845178070.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The only variable changing in your equation is the animal's relationship with humans. What does that have to do with anything?

I wouldn't say that's the only difference (it's not even the difference I've been pointing to), but relationships matter to moral equations.  If a mother sees two drowning children, one her child and one not, and is only able to save one we'd all (I think) agree that it would be immoral to save the child that is not her own over her own child.  

As for the rest, you are arguing with a position I'm not advancing and don't feel the need to defend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27846710266.0" user="kosmic_kolossos" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so there is where our beliefs must diverge. I don't think it necessarily is more ethical for a mother to choose her child over a stranger, but it is more understandable. 

For example, if a mother were forced to choose between her child, and 10 strangers, then what is the most ethical option there? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
