<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842732808.0" user="DeceptiveFallacy" delta="False">
    <text>It's hypocritical only if you value your own culture as much, and as little, as other cultures. Meaning your stereotypical liberal hipster for sure is hypocritical when he stereotypically complains about eating dogs while at the same time devaluing his own cultures accomplishments in the name of equality and diversity.  

Personally I follow the views and values that I find supreme, how can it be hypocritical for me to criticize the consumption of dogs?  
I don't really have much critique of the consumption of dogs in third world countries per see though. It's an understandable practice in a shitty society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842754678.0" user="shivishivi1997" delta="False">
    <text>That was a very complicated way of saying a very simple thing!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842829933.0" user="DeceptiveFallacy" delta="False">
    <text>What OP is questioning is moral superiority in the context of cultural relativism. Plenty of people have dedicated their lives to such questions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843801854.0" user="roderigo" delta="False">
    <text>so much ignorance in such a small space. i'm not really sure what you're trying to say, either. to say that china is a shitty society is to ignore present and past reality. also, it's not a well thought out argument.

and it's per se, not "per see".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843849543.0" user="DeceptiveFallacy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;so much ignorance in such a small space. i'm not really sure what you're trying to say, either. to say that china is a shitty society is to ignore present and past reality. also, it's not a well thought out argument.

I am not a cultural relativist* and China is a shitty society according to my standards and values. Also, the fact that I see Chinese values as lesser than my own is not included as an argument but an explanation of my personal beliefs. It's context.

The argument against OPs reasoning is as I boiled it down to in the comment below: Only with a cultural relativist preface does moral superiority over another culture become hypocritical. Do you understand this argument and how it is about exactly the thing OP expresses his view?

&amp;gt;and it's per se, not "per see".

Yeah, shit happens with spellcheckers. BTW, the start of a sentence, countries, as well as "I" are spelled with a capital letter... Stop being a jerk about stuff not relevant to the discussion. Are you at all interested in listening?

Edit to clarify even further: * I am not a normative cultural relativist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
