<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842852077.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>It's important to note that dogs aren't farmed. They are captured.

There are dogs that are simply strays on the street, that you might consider similar to *hunting*, others are stolen from those who own them. They are also frequently used as pets in the places that they are used as food. Dogs are often stolen from the yards and surroundings of homes, and served up as food. Many dogs don't wear a collar, so it's impossible to distinguish between a stray and an owned dog (and many dog hunters don't even care, to them it's like a $50 bill is walking around, some have a nametag on it, and some don't. Honest dog hunters are hard to find) However dogs, many with their collar still on, are put out on display at markets.

While you can be near-sure that a chicken or cow was raised legitimately in a coop or pasture that had a lock kept on it, and was killed by the person that owned it, you can not be so sure that a dog on the market was raised the same way. The dog that people in that culture are eating may have been someone's best friend that was kidnapped away from them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842936467.0" user="Ozy-dead" delta="False">
    <text>Source on that? I grew up in Asia, dog meat served in legitimate places is from a special dog breed that is grown in farms like any other cattle or meat source. 

If you buy your dog meat at a shady black market - you won't be able to tell. Everything else comes from dog farms. Besides, regular dogs are pretty bad in terms of meat quality, you kind of have to go for the specific meat breeds to even enjoy the meal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843011581.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Just saw it on a Reddit comment tbh.

I think everyone can agree that farmed-food is more humane than stolen-pet-food. I don't know where to start to look for how much dog meat is farmed and how much is hunted. I've seen protests from other countries about how cruel and unsanitarily dogs are treated in comparison to other meat. I'd like to think they're founded on more than just the Western idea of dog as man's best friend.

I wouldn't necessarily trust non-black market meat. For instance, 1/3 of all diamonds fund warlords in Africa, and 3/3 of diamonds are sold my legitimate multi-billion dollar companies. Just because the seller is legit doesn't mean the source is legitimate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
