<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842692312.0" user="MrFidel" delta="False">
    <text>If you are going to advocate eating dog meat for the purpose of having sustainance itself then you should advocate for the eating of bugs as a primary food source for people. They can be consumed entirely as well as have a much higher rate of reproduction. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842696637.0" user="simobk" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really the argument. The argument is simply that eating dog meat is not better or worse than eating beef meat, whether it's for sustenance or luxury or religious reasons...

EDIT: FWIW, I have nothing against eating bugs!  :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842702232.0" user="ormus_cama" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see why that should be a bad idea. People eat insects in many cultures, so humans can obviously like them. Also 1 kg of insect-meat takes a lot less resources and time to produce then 1 kg of meat from a mammal. It is also rich in protein. Maybe we should all start eating insects to help the enviroment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842731694.0" user="Vegandalf_the_Grey" delta="False">
    <text>[You](http://amzn.com/B005HBTWL0) [go](http://amzn.com/B005HBTNH8) [first.](http://amzn.com/B00K5E9Q7E)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842734315.0" user="ormus_cama" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see the big deal. We eat schrimp, they are in the same family as insects, so basically huge insects. Are they less disgusting because they live under water? No, it's probably just that we're used to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842863672.0" user="NFossil" delta="False">
    <text>Been there done it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27843279559.0" user="Bman409" delta="False">
    <text>Would it make sense to say its ok to eat ants, but not beetles?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
