<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="200394744.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3bb5ko/cmv_there_cant_be_hatred_without_fear/">
    <title>CMV: There can't be hatred without fear.</title>
    <original_poster>Alpy94</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be precise, I meant hatred of group or people. 

My argument is that hatred of a group is a direct result of fear of the group. An example would be with anti-Semitism. Nazis and modern anti-Semitic groups talked/talk about Jews controlling the world and money and the power, and how they are evil and make them suffer with their power. This is a clear cut example of fear. People felt threatened by the Jews. That fear lead to hatred.[ /* Cue in Yoda */](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFnFr-DOPf8) 

I thought of any form of hatred and bigotry I could think of, and I couldn't find any where fear doesn't play an important role. 

So CMV
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27849247880.0" user="mushybees" delta="False">
    <text>you're putting the cart before the horse here. fear is not a necessary condition for hate, neither is ignorance (though both can play a part).

usually what we tend to see happen is that a group will *use* hatred that already exists, then inspire fear of that group so as to arouse political support among the 'oppressed' or 'marginalised' group. 

you can have a complete understanding of a thing, and despise it (eg. Nazism) or you can lack complete understanding of a thing, and adore it (eg. the opposite sex)

perhaps a better phrasing would be, 'there cannot be fear without a lack of knowledge' or even 'there can't be love, without mystery'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849265132.0" user="Alpy94" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 'there cannot be fear without a lack of knowledge'

Hmm. That also depends on the level of knowledge, doesn't it? You could have only the right amount to have all the wrong opinions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849283851.0" user="mushybees" delta="False">
    <text>i think i was trying to say, that there cannot be fear of a thing, when one has a complete understanding of said thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849290131.0" user="mushybees" delta="False">
    <text>i don't think that was well worded either. put it this way: if you fully understand a thing, you can't fear it, but you can hate it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849324408.0" user="Alpy94" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't say that. If you are capable of forming total empathy with a group however uncomfortable that maybe, you could see the reasoning behind, see the emotions etc. You can still see it as bad, but not bring yourself to hate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27849391114.0" user="mushybees" delta="False">
    <text>An example might be prophylactic here. You could, for example, live with a group of Nazis, and experience their notions of public policy and humanitarianism and conclude that you hated everything about their philosophy. You might not necessarily fear them, but in understanding them you might hate them</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
