<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2019733331.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xehw7n/cmv_customer_service_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Customer service sucks</title>
    <original_poster>comeandgetsome30</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a broad generalization, but holy hell, I remember a time when I'd walk up to a counter and not be met with someone who would just stare at me until I initiated interaction. I know life sucks, but geeze, try just a smidge to be kind to those who aren't actively f*cking you. The problem seems to be ubiquitous, whether on the phone or in person. People seem disenfranchised, and with good reason, however this negative attitude just spreads like a contagious bug. 

I know this is subjective. For those who are old enough to compare times, I wonder if there isn't anyone who doesn't share this opinion. For those who aren't, I feel pity if this is your normal.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40661593559.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have this problem.  Is it possible you're an annoying customer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661600311.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661641988.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>I said it in a glib way, but it's an honest question.  Like that old cliche, if you look around and can't find the asshole it's probably you.

I don't typically have a problem with my customer service interactions.  And I haven't noticed any particular change in the culture of customer service representatives over the course of the last 20 years that I've been shopping for myself.  So can you say for certain the problem is definitely entire workforces over multiple industries and not you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661658021.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Explain to me how I can change my behavior based on the one example I gave, and I will change my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661702960.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>You could say hello?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661728185.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>I do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661712466.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>What do you suggest I do differently?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661692360.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/comeandgetsome30 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20comeandgetsome30&amp;amp;message=comeandgetsome30%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/xehw7n/-/iogv7lj/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
