<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2019733331.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xehw7n/cmv_customer_service_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Customer service sucks</title>
    <original_poster>comeandgetsome30</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a broad generalization, but holy hell, I remember a time when I'd walk up to a counter and not be met with someone who would just stare at me until I initiated interaction. I know life sucks, but geeze, try just a smidge to be kind to those who aren't actively f*cking you. The problem seems to be ubiquitous, whether on the phone or in person. People seem disenfranchised, and with good reason, however this negative attitude just spreads like a contagious bug. 

I know this is subjective. For those who are old enough to compare times, I wonder if there isn't anyone who doesn't share this opinion. For those who aren't, I feel pity if this is your normal.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40665530755.0" user="sportzthrowaway" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like you’re the problem. You seem to have a sense of entitlement and lack of empathy. You think your only obligation is to not actively screw them over while they’re obligated to be enthusiastic and kind. It’s so weird that you just walk up to counters and stare at the person working expecting them to say something. You’re the one that needs something. When I walk up to someone I greet them and ask them how they’re doing. I say please and thank you. If you treat people with kindness and respect, they’ll be more likely to do the same. Maybe if you stop treating customer service workers like they owe you something and start treating them like they’re people, you’ll have better experiences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40667222086.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>It appears you are not an employer, or a successful one. As an employer, it would be foolish to not require kindness from your employees offering service. Personally, as a customer I am kind to the person across the counter. I always say please and thank - that hasn't changed. What has changed is the behavior across the counter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
