<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2019733331.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xehw7n/cmv_customer_service_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Customer service sucks</title>
    <original_poster>comeandgetsome30</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a broad generalization, but holy hell, I remember a time when I'd walk up to a counter and not be met with someone who would just stare at me until I initiated interaction. I know life sucks, but geeze, try just a smidge to be kind to those who aren't actively f*cking you. The problem seems to be ubiquitous, whether on the phone or in person. People seem disenfranchised, and with good reason, however this negative attitude just spreads like a contagious bug. 

I know this is subjective. For those who are old enough to compare times, I wonder if there isn't anyone who doesn't share this opinion. For those who aren't, I feel pity if this is your normal.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40661572135.0" user="gerundhome" delta="False">
    <text>Customer service sucks because those workers have been abused by management and bad customers so much that they can't afford to care anymore. I blame the system, not the workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661596585.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>I could understand management to some degree, but could you elaborate on abuse by customers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661614247.0" user="Throwaway_12821" delta="False">
    <text>Think of what a Karen is</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661624912.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that a bit judgemental to assume every next customer is a Karen, so you treat them as such?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661648340.0" user="Throwaway_12821" delta="False">
    <text>No one assumes they're all like that but it only takes 1 to ruin your week. Get beat down by enough of them and you become jaded and stop caring. Plus the rewards for doing right are a joke compared to the punishments for doing wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661699143.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've confirmed my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661803607.0" user="Throwaway_12821" delta="False">
    <text>Your welcome lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661657512.0" user="Giant_Gary" delta="False">
    <text>Some people learn from experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661683882.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Racists do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661617486.0" user="gerundhome" delta="False">
    <text>Have you heard the saying "the customer is always right"? That sentence leads a lot of people to think they can get anything they want, and allows them to verbally abuse staff who refuse outlandish request or do not pander to their every whim. There are also a class of people who consider customer service workers to be inferior, stupid and lazy people who cant be bothered to work in real jobs, and as such are targets for abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661670834.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>It's always been a shitty job. It will always be a shitty job. Until it is automated. 

It hardly requires any skill. Will always have a ton of applicants. Often the application pool is filled with criminals and lowlifes. Who if you are unfortunate enough to be working alongside you're going to have to deal with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
