<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2019733331.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xehw7n/cmv_customer_service_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Customer service sucks</title>
    <original_poster>comeandgetsome30</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know this is a broad generalization, but holy hell, I remember a time when I'd walk up to a counter and not be met with someone who would just stare at me until I initiated interaction. I know life sucks, but geeze, try just a smidge to be kind to those who aren't actively f*cking you. The problem seems to be ubiquitous, whether on the phone or in person. People seem disenfranchised, and with good reason, however this negative attitude just spreads like a contagious bug. 

I know this is subjective. For those who are old enough to compare times, I wonder if there isn't anyone who doesn't share this opinion. For those who aren't, I feel pity if this is your normal.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40661566079.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>During the time you’re talking about, these customer service people were paid minimum wage. 

Now, they are paid the same minimum wage. 

Quality of work and drive to perform well gets lower and lower if you continue paying people the same wage but everything else increases in price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661580321.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Minimum wage has gone up, though, I would admit, not necessarily with the cost of living. Then again, was minimum wage ever sufficient for the cost of living, or have expectations gone up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661604532.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.dol.gov/agencies/whd/minimum-wage/history/chart

Last time the federal minimum wage increased was in 2009 when it went from 6.55 to 7.25 or a ~10% increase. That was 13 years ago.

Over that same time, assuming inflation was the targeted 2%, prices have increased 29%. 

It’s not close to being comparable and saying “well it HAS gone up” is a delusional response. 


If I increased your wages by 10% and workload by 30%, how hard would you work?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661610616.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Where did you get the workload number from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661653289.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>It’s an analogy. The same point can be made asking you if your wages increased 10% but you could only buy 70% of the food you could at your original wage, how would you feel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661680877.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>So you agree with my view, and are providing justification for my observation, correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661709462.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>No I disagree with your view that they shouldn’t have a negative attitude. I think their work and attitude are completely justified given the situation they are faced. 

I don’t think you as a customer deserves kindness, generically, from all customer service reps given a vast majority are underpaid and overworked.

I don’t believe they should be required to put in more than the absolute minimum effort of literally waiting for you to engage before they do anything. 

I don’t believe it’s an issue with the workers, I think it’s an issue with the companies, situation, and increasingly competitive and demanding work environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661723422.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>Whether or not you are an employer, you may or may not know that it is the job of a customer service representative to be kind and receptive to customers. That is literally their job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661755536.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>Clearly not or else they would be fired for not performing their jobs and you wouldn’t experience this. 

Their job is to keep you, as a customer, just happy enough to continue spending your money at that company.

I can tell you your job is whatever the hell I want to tell you but at the end of the day, the job is simply what keeps the employee employed. In this case, it’s to provide you the literal bare minimum, as long as you continue to support the employers bottom line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661767627.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>In times where there wasn't a work shortage, that would be the course of action. However, considering that a warm body is all that is required these days, that is all they offer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661818212.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>Your original view was that customer service employees perform subpar customer service for you and in your opinion, they should be performing better.

I have explain to you why they should not be performing any better than the absolute minimum. Regardless of a work shortage or not, the point still stands that the bare minimum service is completely justified and they should not be expected to provide you with better service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661823760.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>The absolute minimum is being kind and receptive to customers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661838207.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>It is not. If it was, they would be fired for not providing you with such.

Again, regardless of a work shortage or not, the absolute minimum is whatever keeps these employees employed. Which is clearly not being kind and receptive to you, no matter how much you wish it was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661862319.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>You are suggesting that people always get fired for not doing their job. That is the strong assumption, one that doesn't hold up here. Read the job description of customer service representative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661903118.0" user="azian0713" delta="False">
    <text>No, I am suggesting the definition of a job is performing a task or service for compensation. 

https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/job

If you get paid to do it, it’s a job, denotatively. 

I can tell you your job description is to like your own ass but if I continue to pay you for standing around and picking your nose, your job is technically picking your nose. You get paid (renumeration) regularly, for the position of nose picker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40661956855.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't address my previous post. Are you suggesting that all people who don't do their job are fired?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40667158867.0" user="naimmminhg" delta="False">
    <text>Rents have gone up and up. That's the actual problem. People can go without fags and booze, they can maybe buy fewer things, they can act more responsible with their money. But if they're handing it over to landlords, they're fucked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40667511730.0" user="comeandgetsome30" delta="False">
    <text>This is all true, but shouldn't be justification for treating others poorly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40667529419.0" user="naimmminhg" delta="False">
    <text>You're over-generalising. I can still go into the vast majority of shops and find someone who is polite and respectful and even friendly at the tills. But having been there, I can also kind of gauge the level of stress, fatigue, and outright shite that people are putting up with.

In places where that's a little lower, people tend to be much nicer much politer, and much friendlier. Because when you're not worried about yourself, you just can afford that. When you're not having to do 2 jobs at once, you've got time to actually be of assistance. When you're not working to a deadline, you've got time to go find the beans. When people are nice to you, you can afford to be nice back. When management don't treat you like subhuman scum, you tend to have a better respect for your job. When problems are amended quickly, people generally try to be on it a bit, and not let anything bad happen to their nice shop.

Also, where things have gotten really tight, people just don't have time to do anything, and their attention is being divided between too much, and even in moments when they don't have to do anything, they're not in a resting state. It's a very different business having to respond to one person's shop than having to man both self-checkouts and tills. And also, they're less and less happy being treated worse and worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40667151528.0" user="naimmminhg" delta="False">
    <text>And the jobs have disappeared.  And having been there during a process of continuous job losses and belts ever tightening, the truth is that the person serving you just doesn't have time or energy to really process your shit.

It went from basically managing, and summers being busy, but overall it being an easy-going job where you would want to talk to people just to pass time to dreading summer time because basically we were always understaffed and you just never stopped, and never got anything much for it only to be dropped to minimum hours in winter, to dreading going to work at all, because even on a quiet Sunday, you're working 2 jobs at once and that's just impossible to manage. It was just a death by 1000 cuts, and the same process happened over and over. Something would get announced. The management would pretend to care about people for a few days, and then they'd start snapping at people. 

And all of that happened while corporate profits went up and up. I'm one of the people who actually read the annual reports, and they were bragging about how they were laying people off and making record turnover and record profits the whole time that we were being sold that times were hard and that we needed to buckle down.

I'm out of that shit now, and honestly my mental health has improved immensely. I'm sleeping well. I'm eating well. I've maybe lost a few pounds.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
