<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40699457427.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten.

Why do you believe this to be the case? 

&amp;gt;And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment

Races? What are you talking about? 

&amp;gt;I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims).

I hope your methodology will demonstrate more rigor then. 

&amp;gt; Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Oh look, infinitely less rigor. 

&amp;gt;Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute.

Why objectively superior? Do you not know what the word objectively means? 

&amp;gt;The poor envy, that is universal truth.

Do they? There are a lot of Buddhist monks that don't envy but aren't rich. 

&amp;gt;Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed.

Or might it lead to the poor trying to become rich instead?

&amp;gt;slave revolts

Ya, that wasn't because of envy. That was to no longer be enslaved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699560828.0" user="AssMercenary" delta="False">
    <text>If nothing else, OP perfectly encapsulates a rich person's mindset. They view the people they are exploiting with contempt and as their natural enemies for not wanting to be exploited. They don't care what socioeconomic research shows about the dynamic, or what's best for society as a whole. They want to be rich, and they don't care what they have to do to justify what they want as the "right" thing to do.

Reminds me a lot of how religious zealots tend to say that God tells them to do what they were already planning on doing. Starting at a conclusion and working backwards to justify it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699597278.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If nothing else, OP perfectly encapsulates a rich person's mindset.

No, he doesn't. Rich people are, for the most part, rich because they created value for others. This is a difficult thing to do if you view the people you're trying to create value for as your enemy. OP's an edgy boi nothing else. 

&amp;gt;They view the people they are exploiting with contempt and as their natural enemies for not wanting to be exploited. They don't care what socioeconomic research shows about the dynamic, or what's best for society as a whole. They want to be rich, and they don't care what they have to do to justify what they want as the "right" thing to do.

Are you rich? How would you know what the view of rich people is? Why do you think they have one singular view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700785582.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you Ayn Rand, very cool. 

Got anything based in reality?

&amp;gt;Every machine has had the same history — a long record of sleepless nights and of poverty, of disillusions and of joys, of partial improvements discovered by several generations of nameless workers, who have added to the original invention these little nothings, without which the most fertile idea would remain fruitless. More than that: every new invention is a synthesis, the resultant of innumerable inventions which have preceded it in the vast field of mechanics and industry.

&amp;gt;Science and industry, knowledge and application, discovery and practical realization leading to new discoveries, cunning of brain and of hand, toil of mind and muscle — all work together. Each discovery, each advance, each increase in the sum of human riches, owes its being to the physical and mental travail of the past and the present.

&amp;gt;By what right then can any one whatever appropriate the least morsel of this immense whole and say — This is mine, not yours?

- Peter Kropotkin</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700857767.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A quote I'm not going to read that probably justifies your edgy hatred of the rich. 

&amp;gt;Peter Kropotkin

"I'm going to write a book all about how animals help eachother in a state of nature despite the fact that I'm not a biologist, have no idea what I'm talking about, and will admit in the first chapter that I'm going to ignore every example that doesn't fit with my conclusion." -Peter Kropotkin, *Mutual Aid*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700888842.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any relevant information to contribute?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700916265.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>More relevant than that Mutual Aid is a shitty book and you shouldn't read it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700924173.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty irrelevant since it ain't the book I quoted, nevermind that the quote stands on its own so the book it originates from is not particularly relevant either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700978323.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>It was about as relevant as your quote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40701112346.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>U literally are daft enough to think that Elon Musk is personally designing and building cars. 

How about you sit down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40701162745.0" user="PmMeYourDaddy-Issues" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;U literally are daft enough to think that Elon Musk is personally designing and building cars.

When did I say that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699735254.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Not true, didn’t mention desire to exploit. Although it probably does exist in some instances. But I think the real issue is the immoral and selfish behavior of the poor.

They envy and hate, and only identify the rich person only by their wealth. Why is it that recent lottery winners have to watch out for scrubs that will immediately come after them asking for money? It’s not other rich people that beg to freeload of someone else’s fortunes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700367421.0" user="AssMercenary" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't have to. You view poor people as rich people's natural enemy, it's an easy inference that you want to exploit the poor (though you might not see it as you exploiting them).

The way people handle enemies is typically totalitarian: killing them, imprisoning them, etc. You view their wants as fundamentally opposed to yours, and thus you have to coerce/control them or eliminate them. I.e., someone wants to stab you, you either kill them back or restrain them so they can't stab you.

Let's take a look at things such as company towns. These give rich owner class the maximum control over their workers. They control their housing, food, health care, etc. (And the price is set so the employee is always in debt)The employees are in debt to the rich people, whom are profiting off their labor. The employees can't leave, cause then their debt comes due. Employees can't strike, cause then they lose their homes, health care, etc, and are also now in debt. Conditions can be the absolute worst, and there is little people can do about it. Company towns aren't a thing of the past either, check out Amazon.

This is the result of rich people treating poor people as an "enemy". Rich people then can exploit poor people without any recourse. Poor people want a decent wage, roof over their heads, enough food on the table. If that's enough to make them a rich person's enemy, says a lot more about the rich person.

You want to compare that to people asking their family or friends for money who just won the lottery? Don't waste my time.

(Oh, and rich people absolutely beg for handouts, see the bank crash in the 00's. The rich people in charge that caused the problem could have paid their own money to fix the problem, they used our money, the taxpayer's. Greatest scam ever, make your company integral to the functioning of society, purposely fuck it up to make money, then get paid by the people whose lives you wrecked to make a quick buck. Cause you're "too big to fail". Or just look at Trump, the "billionaire" who is constantly whining for people to donate to him while also bragging about how rich he is).

Then remember that during the pandemic, people could make more off welfare than jobs. Welfare has never given a lot of money, but it's enough to survive usually. Rich people, instead of saying that maybe jobs should pay more, said they should cut welfare so people were forced to work for jobs that didn't pay enough to live. So if anything, the inverse of your claim is true. Rich owners are always the enemies of poor people (or all other people in general). people having the things they need to survive makes it so that the people whose only contribution is ownership (of the things people need) can't use their ownership of those things to coerce.

Edit for some grammar and run on sentences</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700381368.0" user="Djdunger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But I think the real issue is the immoral and selfish behavior of the poor

You've got to be trolling, right?

There is no way any well adjusted human being is saying that the people who have been exploited by an unjust system and unjust working environments. Performing back breaking labor, working 2 jobs to make ends meet, being a bit upset that someone who sits in a desk all day playing office mini golf making phone calls to other guys sitting at desks playing office mini-golf is making hundreds of millions of dollars more than them. 

You don't think its immoral to sit on a mountain of cash that you couldn't spend all of even if you tried while people starve on the side of the road, or spend their nth year in a homeless shelter? 

I am sorry that you are living such an apathetic life. I don't know if you believe in a higher power, but I don't think they're going to be nice to you when you show up at the pearly gates</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
