<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40699472287.0" user="tomveiltomveil" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;*I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.*

Dude.  You're dismissing 300 years of sociology out of hand, and replacing it with your own anecdotes?  This isn't the CNN audition, this is CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699649019.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>I mean you are more than welcome to try and provide such countering examples. I just think research or academic results  would be impractical for a number reasons. Mainly that  they may take too long to review and establish whether they do indeed defeat my claims or not. 

My academic background is in math and statistics up to the masters grad level. So if I decided to attack the evidence of that research it would be in regards to those disciplines. But that could severally limit the audience interested in this discussion, so again it’s just stuff I’d rather avoid if possible</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699939823.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure you see the irony with the paragraph quoted above though. Any issues of rigor with academic research apply tenfold for personal anecdote. Even if it's not your intention, you have to admit that's exactly the kind of thing a person would write if they were satirically taking the piss.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700176085.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Sort of, but anecdotes are great in context of my claim. My contention is that of a near universal claim that will transcend most geographical and timeframe factors. 

The more data-driven evidence you think of is harder to justify in making such inferences since they are usually based on their research setting/parameters. In other words, we would to show that the conclusions of said research would hold even against a back drop of different factors spanning civilizations and time periods. This is not impossible but I would argue again it would be quite the in-depth discussion which would hurt the “accessibility” of our discussion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700430778.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not so sure about the transcending time and geography part. If you look at most of history, when we talk about the rich, we're not talking about people who just happened to be rich. We're talking about people who actively ruled over the poor as a legally distinct caste of people. Most rebellions against "the rich" were against feudal lords or conquerers, not business owners or people in high-paying professions.


I'm reminded of a different CMV from a while back where the OP claimed that Robin Hood was an attack on capitalism. And I had to explain it was actually an attack on feudalism, and rich he stole from were cronies of a corrupt king, not just regular people with money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700616341.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Δ

What were kings besides estate owners? Words like feudal and warmongering are nothing than just ethnocentric applications. When western kings expanded they were just landlords, when foreigners invaded (I.e. mongols, Turks, etc..) suddenly they are warlords. 

I applaud you for making distinction between ruling elite and rich, they may not need to be synonymous. Although it’s sad the nonetheless all the rich lose regardless. Given that the rich are naturally the more “crucial” population to the state…when the state collapses, the remaining high professionals tend to follow. 

Still you made a nice point</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
