<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40706377315.0" user="tihotap21" delta="False">
    <text>So you claim this:

&amp;gt;I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling

And then you say you will use personal anecdotes, which is already a contradiction to above. But that's not all, your personal anecdote is actually you claiming that once you grew up you understood this unviersal truth, without even explaining how you got to that (not that that would be a good argument, but it would at least be a start). Like, are you serious?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40706475005.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Did you forget to read the fine print, specifically said in the context of these macro level generalizations of my contention. Wish people would actually read.

I got to that truth by simple observation of behavior of the poor. So it first hand how being rich meant they hated us with their envy, despite them trying to hide it at first</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
