<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40700723424.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>Bro this is literally the communist manifesto except youre taking the side of the rich</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700813883.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t know that! I mean I’ve heard of it but don’t know much details</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40700883620.0" user="StrangleDoot" delta="False">
    <text>I will lay out the absolute basics: 

Generally there are 2 classes, the bourgeoisie who own businesses and land and factories, and Proletariat: workers who don't own those things and have to sell their labor to survive. 

The Bourgeoisie generates profit by having  workers use the Bourgeoisie's property to create value, and then paying the workers a wage that is less than the value they created. 

This causes an inherent tension between proletariat and Bourgeoisie. The proletariat wants their wage to be as close to the value they generate as possible while also having to work as few hours as possible to survive. The bourgeoisie wants to keep as much of the created value as possible and to get workers to work as many hours as possible to create more value. 

Marx thought this tension would reach inevitable boiling points in which a revolution to overthrow the bourgeoisie is possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40701160876.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Very well explained thanks. Yes that is sort of the same concept, except I focus more on the human aspect of the distinction between the classes (envy and greed). Marx seems to have tried to workout the economic details. 

But definitely the general theme of revolt is always a concern. Although to me it’s not just one final climatic event but rather dynamic changes that shift the wealth away from rich (sometimes violently).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
