<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2026542997.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xijul1/cmv_the_poor_are_the_enemy_of_the_rich/">
    <title>CMV: The poor are the enemy of the rich</title>
    <original_poster>The_Saracen_Slayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>My contention is simple:  the poor are fundamentally the enemy of the rich and for the prosperity of the later, this maxim must never be forgotten. And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races are simply temporal practical concessions for creating a preferred balanced environment…but this does not solve the ultimate underlying conflict between the two.

I won’t base this claim much on socio-economic research since I find such disciplines to lack the sufficient rigor I value from applied math and statistics modeling (at least for these macro level claims). Instead I will simply use personal anecdotes and maybe some generalized historical events to support my claim.

Being rich is of course an objectively superior attribute. Even as a child I immediately knew the luxuries of the new rich inheritance  were vastly preferable to the environment of being poor. Only an imbecile would think otherwise. But it wasn’t until I lost my innocence did I understand the dichotomy that being rich caused between family and friends. The poor envy, that is universal truth. The poor will always envy the rich, and this alone will always be a destabilizing force between the two classes (for humility is unfortunately a lacking virtue in the vast majority of humans).

Because of this, the poor will inevitably always end up hating the rich and this will lead to violence if left untamed. We’ve seen it in historical events: slave revolts, seizure of property and of course good old revolutionary distribution of wealth movements. Furthermore, ideologies like egalitarianism or communist type theories are indeed weapons that can, and have, be used to seize the assets of the rich. 

The ultimate goal of the rich is to maintain their prosperity, and this requires looking at the reality of the situation. No matter the current system, the rich must always be vigilant for any populist movements…because they will all inevitably be used to take money away from us and give it to the poor.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40699425955.0" user="Jedi4Hire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And whatever “compromises” are established between the two races

The what now? I thought you were talking about the rich/poor?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699444375.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>Just being flexible with linguistics. In this context just take races to be synonymous with groups, classes, etc…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699493910.0" user="smokeyphil" delta="False">
    <text>Or you just Freudian slipped your real argument onto the floor maybe?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40701290911.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>He said the quiet part out loud</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699496614.0" user="HolyPhlebotinum" delta="False">
    <text>I find that your linguistic flexibility lacks the sufficient rigor that I value in my arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699532176.0" user="The_Saracen_Slayer" delta="False">
    <text>You mean explanatory wording? But these are just descriptions of accessibility, but don’t have any real association to the strength of an argument. Any lack of information can simply solved asking for further clarification. Simple</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40699546952.0" user="Jedi4Hire" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't ask if you were racist but thanks for letting me know.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
