<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2029604189.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkdgm5/cmv_sustainability_from_a_philosophical/">
    <title>CMV: Sustainability, from a philosophical perspective, is misguided</title>
    <original_poster>Pyropeace</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been an advocate of sustainability for a while. However, I've recently begun to question the underlying assumptions behind the sustainability movement. 

Nothing is truly, infinitely sustainable. The sun will eventually go nova, killing everyone on earth (if humans haven't already gone extinct by then). If humanity manages to escape Earth, then the universe will likely perish as well, depending on what model you accept. The universe is in a constant state of change, and nothing lasts forever. Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time? When talking about entire societies, I tend towards the latter, though on an individual basis I tend towards the former. 

Essentially, my question is this; what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40716815219.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>when we talk about sustainability we're usually concerned with timeframes that are very long from human's perspective.

we'll have solar power for about a billion years.  Fossil fuels will at least 50 years but not more then 1000 years.   

So neither resources is infinitely sustainable, but solar is sustainable for all intents and purposes.

&amp;gt; Essentially, my question is this; what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?

there is implicit value in temporary things.  If you got to take a shower and there is no hot water left, would you say oh well the shower will end if 3 minutes anyways, do the fact that I am unpleasantly cold doesn't matter.   Of course not.  Temporary things still matter to humans.  Whether our existence as a specifies is temporary or infinite, you still have 1 life to live.  If you have kids they have 1 life to live.  probably you want you great great great great grandkids to have a reasonable comfortable life.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
