<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2029604189.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkdgm5/cmv_sustainability_from_a_philosophical/">
    <title>CMV: Sustainability, from a philosophical perspective, is misguided</title>
    <original_poster>Pyropeace</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been an advocate of sustainability for a while. However, I've recently begun to question the underlying assumptions behind the sustainability movement. 

Nothing is truly, infinitely sustainable. The sun will eventually go nova, killing everyone on earth (if humans haven't already gone extinct by then). If humanity manages to escape Earth, then the universe will likely perish as well, depending on what model you accept. The universe is in a constant state of change, and nothing lasts forever. Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time? When talking about entire societies, I tend towards the latter, though on an individual basis I tend towards the former. 

Essentially, my question is this; what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40716293601.0" user="shooketh_not_stireth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time?

You are applying what should be a personal valuation of cost and benefit to entire generations.

This is a question that two different generations will answer differently. It was better for the boomer generation to live extravagantly and be happy for the duration of their lives in material excess. On the human scale their brief but highly destructive policies is short, but for them, the experience was long.

However for the newest generations, they will experience an ever declining quality of life as the world destabilizes economically, environmentally and politically, and despite having enjoyed some of that excess themselves, I believe that they will weigh the burden of knowing that their future is ever worsening as being more important than their past experiences of western consumerism.

Hope is important. Believing in a better future than the present is important. Knowing that you are doomed because humanity is consuming well past the sustainable margin robs a person of their ability to enjoy the present.

Future generations will condemn our behavior as they will have to live with the damning consequences of our cheap thrills. For them the costs will be incalculable and the benefit have gone completely to a bunch of dead people who wasted the world for momentary pleasures.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
