<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2029604189.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkdgm5/cmv_sustainability_from_a_philosophical/">
    <title>CMV: Sustainability, from a philosophical perspective, is misguided</title>
    <original_poster>Pyropeace</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been an advocate of sustainability for a while. However, I've recently begun to question the underlying assumptions behind the sustainability movement. 

Nothing is truly, infinitely sustainable. The sun will eventually go nova, killing everyone on earth (if humans haven't already gone extinct by then). If humanity manages to escape Earth, then the universe will likely perish as well, depending on what model you accept. The universe is in a constant state of change, and nothing lasts forever. Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time? When talking about entire societies, I tend towards the latter, though on an individual basis I tend towards the former. 

Essentially, my question is this; what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40718446280.0" user="IAmOldAndIKnowIt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time?

I think you are falsely assuming that "unsustainability" will increase happiness.

Let's take an example - Eating to the extreme, weighing 300 kg and dying at 40 vs eating moderately, living a moderately healthy lifestyle and dying at 80. The unsustainable lifestyle is half as short but it's not necessarily twice as happy.

Coming back to your original example, too much consumerism, wastage of natural resources, hunting, all these activities are unsustainable for the nature. But there's no guarantee that these activities make one happy. Personally, I think it's just a trend to always have the latest phone, latest clothes, shoes etc. Most people do it because others are doing it, but that doesn't necessarily make them happy. Even people who do not have access to the latest things aren't less happy in comparison to those who have access to these things. If it were not a trendy thing to always own the latest phone, most people would probably not even bother replacing their phones. Here again, an unsustainable lifestyle is not necessarily the happier one.

&amp;gt;what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?

I think philosophically, you are correct - there isn't value in extending something for as long as possible. The value is in quality rather than quantity.

However, if one has created something of good quality (a good life, a good society), then there is no reason to not wish to extend it for as long as possible - in order to learn and experience more.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
