<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2029604189.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkdgm5/cmv_sustainability_from_a_philosophical/">
    <title>CMV: Sustainability, from a philosophical perspective, is misguided</title>
    <original_poster>Pyropeace</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been an advocate of sustainability for a while. However, I've recently begun to question the underlying assumptions behind the sustainability movement. 

Nothing is truly, infinitely sustainable. The sun will eventually go nova, killing everyone on earth (if humans haven't already gone extinct by then). If humanity manages to escape Earth, then the universe will likely perish as well, depending on what model you accept. The universe is in a constant state of change, and nothing lasts forever. Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time? When talking about entire societies, I tend towards the latter, though on an individual basis I tend towards the former. 

Essentially, my question is this; what is the value in things that last a long time in a universe where nothing is eternal?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40716325515.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, the sun won't go nova. It's not big enough.   
The sun will eventually switch from hydrogen fusion to helium fusion. It will become a red giant, and earth is likely doomed at that point.    But that's 5 billion years from now.  Billion. With a B.  
  
Human civilization has been around for maybe 10,000 years.   
You could argue that some form of "humans" have been around for around a million years, with modern humans emerging somewhere around 300,000 years.   
  
From an anthropological standpoint, anything longer than a million years might as well be forever.  5 billion years from now is longer than the current age of the earth. For all intents and purposes, 5 billion years from now is all of eternity.    
  
If we put zero effort into sustainability, how long do we have left on earth? Maybe centuries. With sustainability, who knows? Maybe we'll make it thousands or millions or billions of years.  That's a HUGE difference.   
  
  
&amp;gt;   Is it better to be moderately happy for a long period of time or extremely happy for a short period of time?    
  
Go jump off a cliff.  You'll have an exciting thrill for a few seconds, but cut your life short by potentially several decades.  That's about the same timescale ratio we're talking about</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
