<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40725197494.0" user="ConfedCringe_1865" delta="False">
    <text>1) Depends what animal we are talking about here, and what qualities we are talking about, but yeah animals are inferior. An organized society able to use something as advanced as a computer or phone in everyday life is probably more advanced than the ones who have the same instincts after a few thousand years. Your comparison is invalid. Jews are proven to not be inferior with something called science.

2) No, we put animals in farms and grow them until they are plump enough to die. I, of course, am not one for animal cruelty by big corporations, so I ussually hunt my food or buy it from local/small time farms. Nazis put people in concentration camps and torture them for no reason other than the fact that they think they are inferior.

3) WTF is this argument. Firstly, it depends on the animal, and if an animal is about to get slaughtered of course they would escape. What, you think a pig is just going to stand there and let the axe come down? 

4) Do you know what normalized means? Jews have endured a long and hard history, but have managed to come out on top in todays day and age. They were discriminated and killed due to their culture and ethnicity, it really is sad and it didn't contribute to the human race. Animals were not, we killed them for food. Simple. If you really want to argue against this, then you could say its bad for a lion to kill a deer. Humans need food, it really is that simple, and thats why we kill them. Its not like us meat lovers like watching an animal get slaughtered, rather than anti-semites.

5) Both are unnecessary? Anti semetic?

6) What the hell does this reason mean? Most animals were born on the farm first of all. Secondly, when they killed Jewish people, they did put them in trucks and transport them, because they wanted to murder as much as possible, and this is really sad. But you comparing this to animals is straight up dog shit. A farm needs to farm meat, and needs cattle to be shipped. A farm exists for a reason, and its not to just randomly kill cattle and let them rot (like a concentration camp). Buying from small, local farms is the best option, as there is much less brutality and the food is more nutritious.

7) The psychology of an animal and a human are incomparable. As I said, it depends on the animal, and a human is smarter and more emotionally active than an animal. 

8) Yes, animals are sentient, but again, they are incomparable to a human, and therefore have less sentience than your average human. Additionally, local farms are more humane. Of course they kill them in the end, however most farms euthanasia and then kill the cattle or pig or whatever.

Discrimination and consumption are entirely different things. You comparing a Jewish person to an animal truly is insulting.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
