<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40719625007.0" user="Efficient_Monk_1491" delta="False">
    <text>I'll start by saying I'm vegetarian and sympathetic to vegetarianism/veganism as an emotional matter. (I'm aware of the "vegetarians think we are friends but we aren't trope" but hear me out). But I think there are kinda three things I'll raise here. 

First, I'm always wary of just lists of similarities. Even if just for yourself, do you think there are differences? If so, what are they and why don't they matter? Which of the similarities are are minimally sufficient for the analogy to be fair and work for you?

Second, and I probably won't convince you of this here, but I think what "unnecessary" means, which is often a very important concept in these arguments but not really discussed thoroughly, is more complicated than it might seem at the outset. Are vegans, because they are not freegans who avoid actively increasing the demand for crops whose agriculture kills animals like nazis? Or, if not nazis since the rounding up is not apparent, imperialists? (I think all but #2 probably apply to this situation, and depending on your subjective view, #5 might not apply). 

Third, I know it was an aside, but would you accept a young looking 88 year old meat eater because they attributed it to the meat?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
