<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40719939909.0" user="Far-Village-4783" delta="False">
    <text>As a vegan non-jew, all I really want to say is that we should not be equating atrocities in my opinion. Each atrocity is horrible for two very different reasons. Hitler's hatred of jews do not translate to what we do to animals. Most people are simply brainwashed into thinking that they need to eat animals for sustenance. 90% or more of food-related commercials have animal products in them. Governments are pushing this, large animal ag lobbies are pushing this, schools are pushing this, hence parents also are pushing this misconception.  


That's why I can say with certainty that anyone who supported the Sho'ah against the Jews were horrible, evil people, but not every carnist is evil. They may simply, like I did for most of my life, believe that we needed to do it to survive and be healthy.

There are obviously comparisons to be made, but that can be said for any two atrocities. Like, you can draw a comparison between oppression of women and the Holocaust too. However, what we will sooner than later come to realize is that these issues are very different as well, have different causes and different solutions.

For instance, I don't think we should be storming factory farms to free animals like the Allies did the concentration camps. That will only do more harm than good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
