<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40719423923.0" user="nevbirks" delta="False">
    <text>Humans have been hunting animals for thousands of years. We need food to sustain ourselves. The same can't be said about people who suffered at the hands of Nazis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719449908.0" user="Arkenhiem651" delta="False">
    <text>We also treated woman as inferior for hundreds of years. Just because it does happen doesn't means it right. We need food to sustain our seeds, not the flesh of animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719996035.0" user="Amisarth" delta="False">
    <text>It is decaying organic matter that sustains all life that grows. Thus goes the life cycle of all living things. Including bacteria. There is nuance here you don’t seem to see. We don’t compare treatment of women to bacteria for the same reason we don’t compare them to dogs. There is a scale to how we designate importance to living things - we are more inclined to crush a roach or spider than we are a cat or dog and we are more inclined to euthanize a dog than a human. 

I give these examples very deliberately because the moral justification for both comparisons are not as clear as we might like them to be. Which brings me to how I agree with you - just because it happened before doesn’t mean we should continue to do it. 

It is morally desired to reduce suffering as much as possible but not when you trade one suffering for another. For instance, *have you considered what it would take to transition to an all plant diet?* Are you aware of the effect it would have on our economy? Our ability to sustain enough resources to go around? Our ability to feasibly feed ourselves given a society that is built around meat products?

Are you aware of what kind of burden your moralizations will put on people? Don’t get me wrong, *we should definitely make that transition.* but we can’t make judgement calls based on ideas in a vacuum. It is a mistake to ignore the logistics that such a transition would involve. 

Let’s talk realism: meat is cheaper than fresh fruits and vegetables. I can buy a frozen meal with processed meat for the same price as a single serving of vegetables. The average person living under the poverty line in the United States has a poor diet that primarily lacks fruits and vegetables. And there are *millions* of people in those circumstances. 

I literally can’t afford to make the switch. ***And I want to.*** Am I still a terrible person because I eat meat? Am I really so disgusting to you that the nuance of there being a bigger problem with poverty and food scarcity is just totally lost on you?  I find this notion hard to swallow. I trust that you are capable of empathy because I know that your current belief very likely stems from that very same empathy. But it’s the nuance you need to temper it. Because my wellbeing is more important than a cows. Even if the world *should* see that difference in importance as closer than they do now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40735934749.0" user="Acerbatus14" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of people are vegan BECAUSE they understand the importance and the consequences of switching to a vegan diet

Do you know something like 70% of crop farmed is fed to livestock? Meat is cheaper because it's subsidised to be, not because it's easier or cheaper by itself


In many ways the factory farms are more devastating to the economy of using land to feed mouths right now than whatever consequences there would be if we shut down all factory farms</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719465016.0" user="wasd12la12" delta="False">
    <text>I eat meat too, but your argument is pretty flawed. It's extremely inefficient to raise crops to feed to animals just to eat the animals. There's a ton of wasted energy and water in the process.

If the main argument is that we need food to sustain ourselves, we would just cut out the middle man(animals) and eat the crops directly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719507236.0" user="nevbirks" delta="False">
    <text>Meat is more nutrient and calorie dense than plants are. For example, chickens can produce 250 eggs a year. They need don't need a lot of food as they can graze for insects and you can supplement it with fruits and veggies.

I'd much rather have chickens in a drought as they can graze for insects and you don't need to give them a lot of fruits and veggies.

Let's say you hunt a deer, that's 50 lbs of meat. That's bone where you can make broth out of. That clothing for your family. Tell me a veggie substitute. Cotton? That produces much more waste than hunting. Or are you only against animal husbandry and not hunting?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719970407.0" user="wasd12la12" delta="False">
    <text>I'd be a hypocrite if I said I was against anything, honestly. 

The eggs are a fair point and I agree that should stay. I'm speaking more of raising cows to kill them for meat. 

Definitely not against hunting, it's the most humane type of meat eating we do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719988093.0" user="nevbirks" delta="False">
    <text>The reason humanity has been able to evolve past hunter gatherer is bacause of farming and animal husbandry. Now you didn't have to follow a herd of animals across the plains. You can raise them, get nutrients such as eggs and dairy which you can tend to your vegetables.

I will agree that our over consumption of meat is a problem. However I'd rather have too much meat than none. With veganism, you're only fed if a farm succeeds in their crop yield. It's always better to be to have multiple sources of food rather than just one. If one stops producing you have another to fall back on.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
