<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40719404397.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>Animals aren't sentient. People are. And I would be leery about comparing jewish people to *animals.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719421881.0" user="SirFatDab" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t disagree with you but animals by definition are sentient</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719429041.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>Okay - conscious, self-aware, sapient *and* sentient, you're right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719436782.0" user="Arkenhiem651" delta="False">
    <text>"Evidence from multiple scientific studies has helped us to understand that a wide range of animals are sentient beings. This means they have the capacity to experience positive and negative feelings such as pleasure, joy, pain and distress that matter to the individual."
https://science.rspca.org.uk/sciencegroup/sentience#:~:text=Evidence%20from%20multiple%20scientific%20studies,that%20matter%20to%20the%20individual. 

I updated my post to include other victims of nazis besides jews.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719447359.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>Right, sapient, self-aware, conscious *and* sentient. That's people, only. My point is our intelligence is qualitatively different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719456265.0" user="Arkenhiem651" delta="False">
    <text>We may be smarter, but animals are still conscious, sentient, sapient and selfaware. The article I cited shows that to be true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719466190.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>There is a difference between sapience, self-awareness, and sentience. Animals can have qualities of some, but the only animal that has all of those altogether is humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40720058087.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't show that to be true:

&amp;gt; The RSPCA and many others believe that there is sufficient scientific evidence to indicate that these animals should be considered to be sentient

They *believe* the evidence is strong enough. The problem being that we don't have a great understanding of either sentience or sapience, nor do we have tests that conclusively prove either.

We have indications that many animals have sentience, and some sapience, but not strong proof of it.

I too, believe (and view it as obvious that) some animals have sapience, and many have sentience, but that doesn't make it true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40720209945.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree with OP, but I never understood this sentiment. 

Like your Dog can learn and make choices for it's self, other Dogs actively communicate with them, they show you love and affection and show people they don't know or like hostility.

That's Sentience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40720659809.0" user="dylbr01" delta="False">
    <text>Animals aren't sentient? Insects aren't sentient because they don't have brains. Animals do have brains, so the basic assumption would be that they are sentient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40721970153.0" user="No-Produce-334" delta="False">
    <text>Insects are animals dude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40813238410.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it so offensive to compare humans to other animals? Humans are animals too, after all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40813242874.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's something the nazis did specifically to justify butchering jewish people.

Context matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40814674614.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah,  but don't we often use holocaust for other analogies? And moreover, several famous Jewish Holocaust survivors have compared the Holocaust to animal agriculture in the present day. You going to say that they're being offensive now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40814961649.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>...are jewish holocaust survivors using the animal comparison to justify murdering jewish people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40815419452.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40815488096.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>This should be good. Example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40817714416.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>Alex Hershaft, Isaac Bashevis Singer. There might be more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40818591052.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>...neither of these used animals as a comparison to people to justify murdering jewish people, what are you talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40818709808.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>They do compare treatment of modern day farm animals to the Holocaust.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40818768188.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>But, critically here, not *jewish people* to *animals* for the *purpose of dehumanizing them* to *murder them*.

Hence the idea of being leery to use that comparison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40818779885.0" user="BRD2004" delta="False">
    <text>Who were one of the victims of the Holocaust? Also, who are the victims of today's agriculture? Answer these and then think. You'll get it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40819006048.0" user="VymI" delta="False">
    <text>I'm genuinely unsure what you're getting at here. If your argument that animals were treated especially poorly during the holocaust, that's a weird argument.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
