<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40721332349.0" user="Ok_Wedding_963" delta="False">
    <text>You point rests on the qualification that Jews are similar if not identical on most characteristics to animals. However, Jews are Homo sapiens. The persecution of the Jewish population by nazis was homo sapien on homo sapien killing. The slaughter of the sus domesticus by homo sapiens is one animal on another animal killing. Where I think I would differ to you is that I do not view the life of a pig to be equal to the life of a human. I think humans are superior to pigs, despite the pig’s sentience, and hence I feed on its flesh regularly to sustain myself because it is a valuable, convient, pleasurable and efficient source of nutrition. Human flesh is said to also be very tasty and nutritious. However I do not kill and eat other humans because I view them of a higher value to a pig.

Humans are fundamentally different to all other animals. We have far superior knowledge which has allowed us to rape the earth to provide for our needs as well as tame other animals. All in all, even though animals can be intelligent, to me they are naught but tasteful additions to my plate that serve me and the human race’s pursuit of relentless progress.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
