<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40833479651.0" user="AmIRightoAmIRight" delta="False">
    <text>If we could upload into a computer and be completely an entity inside, would you call us AI? 

If you answer yes then I won't be able to change your mind.

If no, then you already know that there is a difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40833800523.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>What an interesting way of looking at it! I think I would say that, if it was possible to transfer a human existence into a digital format, it would prove that AI is capable of achieving consciousness. I’m just not sure I believe that it’s possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40841676480.0" user="AmIRightoAmIRight" delta="False">
    <text>Whether it is possible or not doesn't seem to be part of your premise. Your claim is that there is no difference between AI that has reached sufficient ability that it wouldn't be distinguishable from a human other than its physicality. But would you call a human whom is now uploaded into a computer artificial intelligence? 

I can't, because it originates as a human and was created naturally. But at some point that may be further skewed. What is natural? If it CAN occur, wouldn't that be nature at work? And therefore natural.... 

Either way it could, at some point, be boiled down to being the same. But, as a matter of meaning, artificial is accepted as something man-made. Beyond making a human via sex vs. Ctrl+C Ctrl+V, which is part of the boiling....

I guess it's a matter of definition. Might not change your view but current accepted definition would not equate human to artificial intelligence.

Great thought experiment!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
