<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40830071678.0" user="naimmminhg" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, this is "My perfect ideal of what an AI is going to be eventually is indistinguishable from life".

I think the reality is that one major part that will differ between AI and human is first of all, density. We've got a ridiculous number of neurons, which to the best of my knowledge has not been matched by computers yet, and we're getting to the point where the heat generated in computers is such that we're struggling to get more computer power out of a denser area. We can't run it on the same level. So, first of all, you need supercooling and a huge amount of energy to sustain a supercomputer. That's going to be a major difference. The supercomputer can never be autonomous. The best that you're going to have is a master/slave relationship where the supercomputer has a series of robots to ensure its sustainability. And maybe they get it to the point where size doesn't matter, or just build the computer really big, but it's still always going to struggle to match human brains for computing power, particularly dense computing power. And distance is probably going to matter.

Secondly, we have the reality, if not advantage, that our brains evolved down an evolutionary line that involved a number of different stages and were built for different things. It's not inevitable that a supercomputer would ever be developed on those lines, and that's going to result inevitably in huge variation in how we think versus the supercomputer. Just think about how varied humans are right now, and we're about the most related to each other that we could be. Think how different our society is from say a Chimp or Gorilla society, and we're nothing like Lions, even though we've got a lot of the same featuers. And all of these features, and the level at which they're embedded in our whole body experience, affect things. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Also, we've got the reality that most of our minds were designed to respond to external stimuli, and lots of them. We don't know how many stimuli are going to matter in the supercomputer's realm. But knowing that it's not going to be a walking talking robot, that's going to matter. Also, even if it were a walking talking robot, the things that it makes sense to design a robot to, which if we imagine a really nice design is a nearly indestructible machine that doesn't have a great deal of weak points, and isn't going to be affected in the same way at all by potential threats as humans, but is going to probably have to deal with the laws of magnetism, the necessity of charging, the chance that their sensors are just going to go haywire for no reason for like 5 minutes and they can't see anything... and so on and so forth, that's all very different from how people approach the world. We don't expect our limbs to give up sporadically, for instance. We just have to protect them at all times, because we're not getting another one, and it won't be as good if we did. Also, a robot doesn't get ostracised because it has a new arm. Also, we don't expect that after even quite mild injuries, that we're going to be fine again. No, that time you fucked your leg up playing football stays with you the rest of your life, even though you've had 30 years to heal. On the contrary, a robot has the reality that every year we've probably designed a newer and better version. The cost-benefit analysis of losing a leg is like "100% chance that I get more features, more capabilities, faster response times". Probably waiting 6 months on one leg might even be worth that. The issue is that a robot until you've got lots of them, will never have to realise that the other thing that happens is you blow through the budget and the project gets discontinued, and then all the things that were keeping it alive disappear and it dies. Maybe it could infer that, but research scientists are going to treat the robot as the most important thing, probably. A baby doesn't understand these things, why expect that of a robot?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40833297909.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I agree. In retrospect, my premise is flawed even if my view of its ramifications is sound.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
