<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40843920627.0" user="JohnWasElwood" delta="False">
    <text>Nonsense.  AI cannot replicate the intricate workings of a human mind.  Having affection for someone or something that may have caused harm or emotional distress in the past.  Having the ability to process and respond to many different inputs of data &amp;amp; conditions all at the same time and responding to the different signals successfully - Take "driving a car at highway speeds while it begins to rain (turning on the windshield wipers) while having a conversation with someone on the phone and hearing a song that you like come on the radio...  All while avoiding the pedestrian / bicyclist that has almost gone in front of your car... When just moments ago you felt hunger pangs and wondered what you'd have for dinner later that evening...???"  A computer will "fail open" at the slightest variations in its programming if it cannot process all of these highly variable and quickly changing scenarios all at the same time.  
And then there are claims of ESP, phantom pain after losing a limb, dreaming in your sleep, etc.  Scientists are still coming up with more amazing things that they're learning from our body's DNA / brain / cardiovascular system all the time.  Computers will likely never dream or have intuitions or be discerning like we mere humans.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
