<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40829701333.0" user="melodyze" delta="False">
    <text>The clearer way to make the base of your argument is:

- All aspects of consciousness are emergent properties of computation in the brain.
- Computation is fundamentally platform independent. 
- Therefore, a machine could be built that replicates all aspects of human conscious experience.

If you make the argument that way, very few neuroscientists or machine learning researchers will disagree in principle. Those underlying assumptions aren't very controversial and the conclusion follows.

But they will disagree pretty hard on practicalities, like why would we even try to build that? Even if we wanted to do that, how would we measure whether we have succeeded at creating subjective experience for a machine at all, let alone one similar to a human? How would we even begin to understand which kinds of computation give rise to phenomena that we cannot measure at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40833497804.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response and simplification, that helps a great deal. And I would have to agree that testing for a consciousness presupposes a complete understanding of it, which is an enormous leap to take. In retrospect, my premise is flawed even if my view of its ramifications is sound.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
