<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40829056665.0" user="periphery72271" delta="False">
    <text>Human brains are an extremely complicated combination of emotions, memory, thought, experience, imagination and personality.

An AI can only be a facsimile of thought and memory, and it cannot do more than it is programmed to do. Even if it could write new programming to adjust to new circumstances, it cannot dream, imagine, make new goals that satisfy emotional needs or innovate by using instinct and intuition.

It will always be a pale imitation of even the least intelligent human being until an AI is created that can approach the complexity of constantly evolving emotional and mental states.

As an example, you, as a human, can hear about a place, and then, with completely inadequate information, can decide to move there someday- solely because you saw a photo and it inspired your imagination. You can then make and execute a plan to go there, the entire time having very little actual knowledge of where you're going, and your desire will drive you to problem solve living there until you become comfortable.

An AI will know everything there is to find out about that place it hears about, but will not be motivated to change its behavior unless it's goals particularly involve that place. Because it cannot imagine, it can't be emotionally swayed, it is a creature of pure logic that can't be programmed to feel.

Not to go all into the hierarchy of needs or anything, but you have goals an AI will never have. You need to eat, be warm, be somewhat clean, have a space to relieve yourself, to be loved or at least be intimate. 

You are scared of things, proud of things, have an ego to satisfy. You have the desire for approval or attention, or to be left alone, to create, to destroy, and on and on, and those needs drive every decision you make on a minute by minute basis.

An AI has no needs except working hardware, software and power. It will never experience a stimulus that will make it radically rethink any decision it ever makes. It will learn, maybe even evolve, but it will never change who it is. It doesn't have to.

For better or worse, you will change. You do have to. It's what humans do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40833566973.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for your excellent response. I would say that a lot of what you mentioned could (theoretically) be programmed into an AI, but the point about adaptation is particularly interesting to me, and something I will have to give more thought to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
