<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40828900924.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; indistinguishable from a human

to who and in what context?

&amp;gt; a digital consciousness 

digital consciousness seems like a much different bar from "indistinguishable from a human", especially depending on the context in which one is trying to distinguish the two.

&amp;gt;  I’m struggling to find a difference between the two

we can't really talk about a theoretical distinction about a theoretical "digital consciousness" that is ill defined and doesn't exist.

if we don't have a good definition of what "consciousness" is, and we don't know what this theoretical computer would look like to know what particulars to focus on in relation to differences related to consciousness, I don't see how one would expect to be able to speculate on what the differences will be.

If you handwave and say, hypothetically, there are no differences we can distinguish, then you ask will there be any differences, you just moved the question into your premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40829636963.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, very good points. My OP is not as well presented as it could be.

I feel like consciousness must be something more than just reacting to new data based on our existing datasets the way an AI would, but I can’t find any evidence to support that feeling. This is leading me to wonder if consciousness has physical properties and limitations, or could it be nonexistent, at least in any terms we currently think of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40830756795.0" user="Inevitable-Year-9422" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I feel like consciousness must be something more than just reacting to new data based on our existing datasets the way an AI would, but I can’t find any evidence to support that feeling. 

The reason you can't find it is that consciousness is just about the greatest mystery that exists in science today (with the possible exception of life itself). Nobody knows what consciousness is, where it comes from, how it exists, or what it's made of. This is part of what makes the AI frontier of technology so fascinating. Because when we make a truly conscious computer, that will answer some fundamental questions about consciousness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40833470564.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed. Very well put. Thank you for the responses.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
