<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27909711469.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Let's start here:  To our knowledge, the TSA has never stopped anything.  All of the policies you see in effect were put there AFTER someone got something past them (the no liquids thing, the taking your shoes off thing).  In other words, they're only good at checking for things that everyone already knows about.

You said you don't remember time before 9/11, so I'll say that you would have felt safe then, too.  I used to fly frequently before 9/11, and you went through a very simple security screening.  I never felt unsafe flying.  

Terrorists are not stupid, no matter what political cartoons might like to say.  If they want to get something onto a plane, they're going to.  The TSA fails pretty miserably at checking for the things they KNOW they're supposed to be checking for.  That doesn't even touch on the things that they aren't aware of yet.

Think of the TSA as a version of McAfee that's been outdated for like 7 update cycles.  Yeah, it'll catch stuff if someone is dumb enough to try a give you a virus from 2002.  But anything reasonably new is going to slip right through.

Except imagine that McAfee was putting you through a radiative scanner, going through all of your personal shit, and telling new mothers that they can't take breast milk on a plane to feed their infant.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909723311.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>But would you rather just not have the TSA at all? Let anyone bring any liquids onto the plane?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909756484.0" user="bgaesop" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, absolutely. Keep in mind the trade-offs here. It's not just TSA versus no TSA (though I would still pick no TSA in that instance), it's TSA versus no TSA plus an extra $7 billion per year (enough for seven New Horizon probes every year) plus (using your half hour estimate) saving travelers 38,000 man-years per year plus all the stuff that gets confiscated pointlessly (I would still have my multitool and my 'dangerous' lightning bolt shaped belt buckle, for instance).

The cost of the TSA is literally astronomical. The benefit is, as far as anyone can tell, literally zero.

edit: oh yeah, plus no more cancer-causing rapiscan machines!

second edit: not to mention the unintended side effects of disincentivizing air travel, which [Cornell estimates as causing 242 deaths per month](http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=677549), so, y'know, way more than terrorists

The TSA: literally worse than Osama bin Laden</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27910993507.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>1. I completely disagree and think it's stupid to risk lives to save you 30 minutes

2. That study is absurd and you know it. People aren't flying as much because of costs not because of the TSA taking up too much of their time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909756708.0" user="MageZero" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27910265431.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Yes.  That is exactly what I would like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911005080.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>It's easy to say a security agency isn't doing their job until you take them away and suddenly see what happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911018912.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>The same thing that happened before 9/11 when we didn't have a TSA?  Which was pretty much nothing *except* 9/11.  Not to belittle 9/11, because it was obviously horrible, but without a security agency, it happened once in 100 years of aviation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27914458542.0" user="JustinATaylor" delta="False">
    <text>Yup. 

Save a whole lot of money and we will be just as safe. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
