<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27909845201.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>The TSA is a prominent example of "security theater".
Others in this threat have cited the 95% failure rate from their performance test earlier this year. What exactly about that is so confidence inspiring for you?
If I missed 95% of the questions on a test, but insisted to my professor that I really felt like I had learned the material and had worked hard DOESNT MATTER FAILED TEST.

The TSA is useless, and more than useless in that it has created, at least for you, a false sense of security. Because you were so inconvenienced, you have to be safer. Right? Otherwise there wouldn't be a point.

Well, pretty much all of the evidence we have says that there isn't any point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911001532.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>You're not disproving my point though. The TSA is inefficient, I get that. But that doesn't mean we should get rid of it. It means that we should improve it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911264911.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>Either you are moving the goalposts on me or you are making a strawman argument. Your post said not that the TSA, a huge bureaucratic organization needs to be maintained, but that their procedures are necessary. I directly confronted that assertion because it is what you posted about. 

I didn't argue for eliminating it, and if you think I did please reread my post. All I said is that the return on investment isn't there. Even your original post didn't pose it as a choice between eliminating it or reforming it. I'm happy to have that conversation as well, but to be clear, that was not the original framing of the discussion.

That being said, I do think that eliminating it would make sense. 
As I said, the only "security" they contribute to in a meaningful way is a false sense of it. That is a bad thing. They also cost a lot of money. That too is a bad thing. You have not pointed out a single, factual good thing that has come about due to the TSA and their invasive searches.

I think that we should get some positive benefit out of government programs and if they can't prove any positive benefit, what is the point of keeping them around?  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
