<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27909845443.0" user="jayman419" delta="False">
    <text>The TSA is a farce. It does next to nothing to make you any safer. Terrorist attacks are highly unlikely. Making each person take off their shoes and throw away their shampoo doesn't do much to change those odds.

Terrorists are not crack teams of bad guys determined to thwart heightened security. *Die Hard* is just a movie. Terrorists are bullies. They are looking for people who are distracted. People who are complacent. 

If terrorists wanted to disrupt American air travel, they'd simply attack the crowds waiting to get through security. They would attack American allies without the extensive security procedures. Your odds of being involved in an attack aren't changed by their efforts.

The reason terrorists haven't blown up in an airport is because they have other priorities. That's why movie theaters, schools, and shopping malls have become targets.

If the TSA ensures the safety of anything, it protects *aircraft*, not human lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911003870.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>But why are you opposed to having a general list of strict rules on what is okay and what is not okay to bring onto a plane? No one is telling me why any of that is bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911296539.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>That's because you didn't ask that question. You asked an entirely separate question about their extensive searches.

I don't think anyone in this thread is advocating for being allowed to bring firearms onto the plane. But having to take off your shoes and belt? You know that under their guidelines you could bring an empty nalgene and a bunch of small bags or bottles of water and refill it immediately after having passed through security even though you would have had to dump it out for being in a single bottle. (Edit: Missed the second half of this thought and just added it. Everything in the preceding sentence after the word security) The problem is not that the list of things is ridiculous, but that the actual security procedures are utterly nonsensical.

You seem to want people (and I say this after I just responded to your answer to my first post and then reading this) to answer a completely different question to what you have asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27912069938.0" user="jupiter78" delta="False">
    <text>But what about reforming the TSA and removing the very nonsensical security procedures?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27912399252.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>This is a pretty overblown response to your short and reasonable question. But I've been drinking so the impulse control just isn't there.

I think to some extent that may just be throwing good money after bad. I understand that it could be reformed and made into a respectable organization with significant expenditure of time and effort, but ultimately why bother? What are we getting out of it?
Why keep a bloated bureaucratic organization on the books when it can be demonstrated that it basically does us no good? I'm not generally one for privatization of services, but even airports and airlines could probably handle security in a much more efficient way.
 
And, for me the problem is that we are not only getting next to nothing back from our investment in the TSA, but we are also normalizing invasive security procedures, which can now be seen in other contexts such as subways and ports.

This is how you start the initially slow, but then alarmingly fast descent down a slippery slope. Something that would once be considered authoritarian government overreach is introduced in special circumstances for a short time, and then when the crisis is over, it is claimed to be an indispensable tool and never goes away. That is what happened with warrantless phone and internet surveillance in the wake of 9/11. 

People should ALWAYS be skeptical of things like this, and when they are demonstrated to be completely ineffective we should leap at the opportunity to restore some convenience and privacy in our travel, and to eliminate wasteful spending.


Just think about how different this conversation would be if it were any other part of government besides the security apparatus. Look at the horrible way that the US Postal Service has been demonized and gutted for political ends. 
To use a horribly cliched example, if we took the $4.6 Billion and distributed it evenly amongst the approximately 50 Million public school students, they would each have an additional $92 per year in text books, school lunches or what have you. 

But no, rather than lunch and a new textbook for little johnny, you get to have a sexual encounter with a large middle-aged man in a small room deep in the bowels of the airport if you happen to share a name with someone who once did something bad.

We as a country need to realize that September 11th was an anomaly, and that we don't need to base our every decision off of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27911910424.0" user="jayman419" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's unnecessary and unwarranted. Back in 1972, a [sitcom solved the problem](https://youtu.be/-lDb0Dn8OXE?t=51s). 

But more seriously... Extensively searching everyone before they get on a plane doesn't make *you* as a passenger any safer. In fact, it makes it more likely that something will happen to you.

Suppose someone wanted to hijack an airplane and use it as a weapon again. Well, there's probably going to be dozens of passengers they will have to overcome. There's the entirety of American air defenses they'll have to deal with. There's the fact that **the cabin is locked and inaccessible during flight** to deal with.

At best they can threaten to harm the people on the plane. One plane, maybe if its a coordinated thing they can threaten the people on a couple of planes.

But instead of even trying to take a plane, the TSA has given them hundreds and hundreds of passengers, enough to fill a dozen planes or more, all standing around in a crowd, waiting to get through security. And these people are absolutely defenseless. *You* are absolutely defenseless when you're in that crowd. The terrorists know, everyone knows, that the crowd won't be armed. They're not allowed to take weapons on the plane. That just leaves the airport security to overcome. And if it's a suicide attack, you don't even have to overcome anyone or anything, you just blow up your bag before security checks it. Hundreds of people could be harmed.

Extensively searching everyone before they get on the plane doesn't make you any safer. No one is going to attack a plane with a full-size bottle of shampoo.

Air travel used to have no restrictions. Then when hijackings became a thing they started looking for guns and bombs with x-ray machines. Then after 9/11 ... when hijackers using box cutters forced their way into the cabin... they made it so the cabin door can't open during flight. That solved the problem. It ended the threat of hijackers taking over an aircraft.

It didn't end the threat of a bomb on the aircraft. If someone just wanted to destroy the plane, they could. Checked luggage is far more permissive as to what's allowed, and not every bag is even checked. It doesn't even have to be a suicide attack. A half-dozen people could check a dozen bags on several flights and then simply go home. If one of the devices is found it may cause a security clampdown, but what if one of the planes is already in the air? What if they detonate the bomb back in the security area?

But after going through the screening, you certainly *feel* safer. You're not. You're not any safer. Any time you leave your front door you're putting yourself at risk. It's just how much of a show do you want authorities to put on for you.

edit: Accidentally a word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27912411298.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>Wow. I had never thought of it in quite those terms of how it just doesn't significantly benefit passenger safety, but you're right. 

For me ineffectiveness and being unnecessary are the things I've always paid attention to, rather than being made redundant by other security changes passed at the same time.

That is an insightful new (to me) angle on this. Thanks for sharing it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
