<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27909809537.0" user="celeritas365" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I have never felt unsafe on an airplane.

Good they are statistically a very safe place to be.

&amp;gt; I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies.

Highly unlikely. 

&amp;gt; It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

In Why We Make Mistakes by Joseph T. Hallinan he references a study in which the TSA missed 1 in 4 loaded guns, as well as 60-75% of explosives or explosive components. 

&amp;gt; I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. 

It is not the time that is the problem. Even the privacy is not a huge concern of mine in this context (even though I am generally a privacy fan). The TSA is simply a huge waste of energy and money. The government spends tons of money (billions) on the TSA to solve a problem that kills a negligible number of people in a way that is dismally ineffective. We would be better off spending the money on something else. The government could save more lives for their money in lots of other ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909860467.0" user="thehonbtw" delta="False">
    <text>As far as the dangerous devices are concerned, OP would have no way of actually knowing this unless he had tried and failed to do so. Otherwise that statement is merely a product of the piece of mind that TSA gives him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27910998826.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>So the problem is that the TSA is inefficient, not that it's worthless.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
