<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27911316689.0" user="SOLUNAR" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds good and all in theory...

but in practice?

&amp;gt; In all, so-called "Red Teams" of Homeland Security agents posing as passengers were able get weapons past TSA agents in 67 out of 70 tests — a 95 percent failure rate, according to agency officials.

There has been numerous tests where the failure rate is 90%+

Just google, TSA Failure rate.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
