<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="206717484.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3f2o8c/cmv_i_have_no_problem_with_the_tsa_and_would/">
    <title>CMV: I have no problem with the TSA and would honestly feel less safe if there wasn't the extensive searches</title>
    <original_poster>damienrapp98</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have never felt unsafe on an airplane. I used to have some fears related to them but those were mainly due to fear of turbulence and such, not terrorism. I think that this is mainly due to the TSA's policies. It's damn near impossible to bring any dangerous devices onto a plane.

I will disclose this. I was born in 1998 (17 years old). That means that I don't remember 9/11 (I remember that day, but not the significance) and I don't remember life before the TSA's newer policies. I grew up with them.

I just feel like the extra 30 minutes it takes to go through security is no big deal and generally gives me peace of mind. I totally understand minority complaints and I'm not arguing about those at all, but what I am saying is that the general (neither expedited or extended) search is totally reasonable and generally I don't feel annoyed or like my rights have been taken away in any sort of way.

CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27909714863.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>Homeland security agents tested the TSA and found a [95% failure rate](http://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/investigation-breaches-us-airports-allowed-weapons-through-n367851).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909721006.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>So are you saying the TSA shouldn't exist or that it could be better? I'd argue the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909761304.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying there's no evidence of any benefit from the TSA. Increased security always comes with a trade off of loss of time, hassle, or privacy concerns, but you expect some security to come with those negatives. In regards of the TSA, you've had all those negatives with no positive. I don't think that should exist in any situation. 

If there is a positive, I would put the peace of mind people tend to get from heightened searches. In reality though, that shouldn't be required since the odds of being on a plane that gets hijacked is minimal based on the total number of flights that happen. 

As a side note, I highly doubt an organized terror plot would include plane hijacking since that's what happened last time and that's what we so aware of and focused on preventing. Much like no one expected hijackers to fly planes into buildings, none wI'll expect whatever the next major attack is, if one happens. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27909932556.0" user="HOU_Civil_Econ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I highly doubt an organized terror plot would include plane hijacking since that's what happened last time

It won't. 9/11 only worked because every other plane hijacking ever was for money or (non-murderous) political reason where-in the hijackers would demand that the plane be safely landed some where and then negotiate. Therefore the standard suggested response to a plane hijacking was sit back and enjoy your flight to Cuba. This is how just a few individuals were able to hijack planes with box cutters. 

Post 9/11 the standard response to a hijacking has probably changed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27910996761.0" user="damienrapp98" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know they haven't stopped drug smuggling/illegal weapons coming onto planes. It's not like they've never found a weapon or a gram of coke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27912453860.0" user="mormakil" delta="False">
    <text>You are asking him to prove a negative; He can't do that because it's impossible.
However we can say with some confidence that they would have told us if they had actually prevented a terrorist attack. They haven't advertised it, and that is almost certainly because it hasn't happened.

Would you really feel less safe on a plane if one of your fellow passengers had a gram of cocaine?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
