<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40928421375.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that if poverty caused significant penalties to IQ, asian people in the USA would be among the worst off of all minorities, since most asian immigrants came from very very excessively poor backgrounds. My parents are both Chinese peasant stock and knew a level of poverty beyond any American of any race - their childhood involved rationing on basic necessities like bread and rice. My father scavenged books from the trash and rebound them and sold them for pocket money. Commonplace things like butter were completely alien to them when they arrived in the USA.

The fact that they did incredibly well in school, and that asians on average score higher than white people in almost every measurable test in America suggests the opposite conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928962953.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>Asians actually have higher average IQ in the world today and it's very consistent with the top 6 countries all being predominantly Asian.

https://www.worlddata.info/iq-by-country.php

But they also happen to be countries with low homelessness and poverty. 

China is the odd exception. I am not sure if their data was honest. 

But then the question is, have Asians fared better or worse than white people through all history? Through the last few centuries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929206125.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely worse for several centuries. 99.9% of China was peasant farmer stock for the last 300 years.

I have personally gone to school in both China and the USA and I think the reason China tends to score higher on most forms of measurable testing is because in China students are strictly taught to tests, and there's huge emphasis on rote memorization (which most forms of testing, including IQ tests, heavily reward).

Every high schooler in China is taught towards college entrance exams, because the entrance exams are almost the entirety of the measurement a college will use.

Unlike the USA where extracurriculars, GPA, and other achievements also weigh into your college application.

\---

I will also add that the US college exams (the SAT and the ACT) cover much easier and more basic material than Chinese exams do. The Chinese college entrance exam I looked at, for example, had questions involving calculus and statistical regressions, whereas most high school students in the US are never taught that high. In fact, many US college students never get that high.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929231702.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;are strictly taught to tests, and there's huge emphasis on rote memorization (which most forms of testing, including IQ tests, heavily reward).

This would certainly throw a wrench and trying to prove or disprove my hypothesis. Do you have evidence that rote motorization is an effective way that you can study for IQ test?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929788231.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>I can think of several common puzzles and problems in IQ tests where strong rote memory skills would absolutely help improve both speed and accuracy, which impact IQ measurement. For example, questions like [these](https://www.smartbrainpuzzles.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/MathPuzzle.jpg) are common in IQ tests and if you know the order of operations by heart you will solve it much faster than someone who does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932291348.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>So the question you showed is not a question you would find on an IQ test. The IQ test does not test addition, pemdas, or any other concept you learn in school. 

Usually they are puzzles and pattern recognition. They are designed so that anybody without an education could score just as well as somebody with an education. Most IQ tests don't even have written English questions because the IQ test recognizes that not everybody knows how to read. Or when people who are illiterate take it, they have some proctor who prompts them.  The IQ test is designed so that you can't study for it. 

This is an example of a question you would see on an IQ test: 

https://images.app.goo.gl/KqYCsXu8dVZFsgmX6</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932715508.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>I literally stole that image from an out and out IQ test. Some of what IQ tests do is test pattern recognition, but many of its ideas are based off math puzzles, and basic math is one of the skills that benefits from rote memorization the most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933448631.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>You probably did, but a lot of IQ tests are scams. They're usually just shottily put together to try to get people to pay them money.  The Mensa test is one of the best tests.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933461648.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, let's go with a puzzle straight from the MENSA international web page that [requires math skills](https://www.mensa.org/node/1295/take/1).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933978169.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm access denied. I don't think I can log into Mensa unless I am invited.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
