<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40928158426.0" user="Li-renn-pwel" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain why you think these are racial IQ disparities and not economical/class disparities? For example, how does IQ change between rich white Americans and poor white Americans. Or a rich Nigerian verses a poor Nigerian. 

[Also, IQ has a heavy racial bias](https://www.brookings.edu/articles/the-black-white-test-score-gap-why-it-persists-and-what-can-be-done/amp/) and it does not properly measure non-white or non-European intelligence. People with an IQ below 50 is considered intellectually disabled and have trouble living on their own and taking care of themselves. [Yet Nepal has an average IQ of 42 and Liberia of 45.](https://worldpopulationreview.com/country-rankings/average-iq-by-country) By Western standards, the majority of the country should have great difficulty even functioning. In reality, Nepalese are able to work and live life normally. The test just does not properly test their intelligence. They might be able to make a DIY cart and perfectly plan out a farmer’s field for maximum harvest. They just can’t answer algebra questions because no one taught it to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928770634.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Can you explain why you think these are racial IQ disparities and not economical/class disparities? For example, how does IQ change between rich white Americans and poor white Americans. Or a rich Nigerian verses a poor Nigerian

My point is that it is an economic disparity, but that the economic disparity being rampant through multiple generations through multiple centuries as a trend, may begin to manifest as a racial disparity. 

&amp;gt;The test just does not properly test their intelligence. They might be able to make a DIY cart and perfectly plan out a farmer’s field for maximum harvest. They just can’t answer algebra questions because no one taught it to them.

I don't think you know how IQ tests are administered. They don't test algebra or English or anything you learn in school like an SAT. 

 It's shape and pattern recognition, puzzles. Some iq tests are even for infants. They don't usually even have text.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40930011891.0" user="Li-renn-pwel" delta="False">
    <text>I will admit that algebra was a poor example I gave off the cuff. However IQ tests most certainly **are** highly structured off what you learn in school. Or at least, most of them are structured off what a typical white, middle class Westerner learns in schools. Right of the back, the person taking them needs to be able to read well enough to understand the majority of the questions. Which might sound like basic education but keep in light only 88% of men and 79% of women in the world are literate. 

Then you will test best of it is written in a dialect you know. For example, a question might be “how are a torch and a remote similar?” A British person might write “they are both battery operated” but the question becomes harder for Americans who are used to torches being flaming sticks and not battery operated flashlights. 

Then there are the cultural differences. You might have an IQ test use imperial for a question but the person taking it was educated using metric which makes the question significantly harder. How about the question “loquat is to two as ackee is to___?” Many Asian people would read it and think “well the only pair of things I can think of a loquat having are the seeds. Ackee is also a fruit but with 4 seeds so that must be it!”  However many people in other areas would have literally no idea how to answer this without googling it. It is actually very difficult to create tests that be fairly given to everyone free of any bias. 

[You can read more about that here.](https://via.library.depaul.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2432&amp;amp;context=law-review)

As to your first point, I still don’t see how it would be a racial disparity. There are rich and poor people of all races and ethnicities around the world. To be honesty, I don’t know the exact racial make up of poverty around the world. Do you have anything that says that majority of Black (or other race) are living in such poverty and oppression?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932508534.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Right of the back, the person taking them needs to be able to read well enough to understand the majority of the questions. Which might sound like basic education but keep in light only 88% of men and 79% of women in the world are literate. 

Even that though, IQ test don't normally have English questions. At least not legit IQ tests.  They don't require knowledge of anything, not even how to read.  Sometimes there is a prompt there is usually a proctor that will tell you in your native language the prompt. 

This example also wouldn't be found on the IQ test because it requires knowledge of what a loquat is. 

&amp;gt;loquat is to two as ackee is to___?”

This is an example of an IQ test question:

https://images.app.goo.gl/RMPdDUhKd1yPAJD59

The proctor would tell you the prompt "draw/pick the correct shape for the missing piece"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932624494.0" user="Li-renn-pwel" delta="False">
    <text>I was going to write a longer answer but… if you go to that link you sent and click on the wiki it comes from, you will see the image is labeled. That label says it is one **type** of question from **one** IQ test. There are any IQ tests and many have logic or non-visual comparisons. If you scroll down a bit there is a section on the wiki titled “reliability and validity” which talks more about this issue. Particularly this one paragraph (I’ve left the citations in case you wanna skip right to reading the sources):

“A 2005 study found that "differential validity in prediction suggests that the WAIS-R test may contain cultural influences that reduce the validity of the WAIS-R as a measure of cognitive ability for Mexican American students,"[103] indicating a weaker positive correlation relative to sampled white students. Other recent studies have questioned the culture-fairness of IQ tests when used in South Africa.[104][105] Standard intelligence tests, such as the Stanford-Binet, are often inappropriate for autistic children; the alternative of using developmental or adaptive skills measures are relatively poor measures of intelligence in autistic children, and may have resulted in incorrect claims that a majority of autistic children are of low intelligence.[106]”

Something to add to the discussion that the wiki reminded me of… the Flynn effect is that our IQ has been steadily rising. There have been a few reasons purposed for this. I think a likely one is that we are improving our education system and the health and nutrition of society. Western societies tend to be more developed today (not that this is absolute) but I see no reason why we wouldn’t expect other countries to follow once things like universal healthcare, removal of led, universal education, etc are implemented in their countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933418835.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely think that the flynn effect is improving I don't think it has to do with education. I think it has to do with people being healthier. There are strong correlations between improved iq and brain health, better sleep, better eating, less stress, more time outside 

Think people see correlations between well-educated countries and high iq, and they assume that education leads to a higher iq. But there is very little data to show that. It's not uncommon for somebody who has received no education to outscore people who have received a full education. I think it's probably more likely due to living environment. I wish people took the IQ test more seriously because it would encourage a healthier environment for children. I think it's been abused a lot in the past and that is why people stay away from it. 

The WAIS R is sort of adjacent to an IQ test. It includes things like vocabulary, comprehension, and arithmetic. And it is found to being indicator of iq, because test participants tend to score very close to iq. But there are issues with it because often uses symbols, might be more better understood In some cultures than others. It uses concepts that are taught in schools like arithmetic. 

There's definitely a lot of IQ tests that miss the mark, there's a lot of scammy tests out there. and there's been a lot of abuse of IQ test in history. Mensa is usually considered the best test.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933649987.0" user="Li-renn-pwel" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have example of people with no education outscoring someone with a full education? I’m sure it happens but would be incredibly rare. I think you are thinking of education in the hard facts they teach and not the skills they teach. A school system teaches you not only hard facts (this country was founded on this day) but also how to learn things and strengthen your mind. For example, we often are given word scrambles or word searches in classes. While this is usually just a fun activity, it is also a skill you learn and generally get better each time you do them. Someone who has never done a word search would very likely take longer to complete it on their first try compared to someone who has done them every day for years. Even if their vocabulary is actually significantly bigger than the trained word searcher. We are taught about patterns and how to recognize them. There could be a question “21, 34, 55, 89, ___” and someone who know what the Fibonacci sequence could almost instantaneously write down 144 because they know the pattern while someone who had never heard of it would need to actually figure out the pattern. For times tests, these seconds or minutes add up and cause a significantly different score even if in actuality they are of the same intelligence. However one has been training certain academic skills for years while the other was putting their brain power in more practical areas for them such as farm work. 

Why would you say WAIS R is an ‘adjacent’ IQ test? It **is** and IQ test. It doesn’t fit into your narrowly defined perimeters but I’m not sure why you have drawn such a hard line in the sand. Are you saying you only recognize he validity of tests that solely ask people to finish pattern sets? What is your basis for deciding that? Is there a paper or book you read that convinced you they were the only valid ones? Your reply makes it seem as if you think I’m saying Facebook IQ tests are valid but that is not the case. I’m talking about Wechsler Preschool and Primary Scale of Intelligence, Otis-Lennon School Ability Test, Differential Ability Scales, Woodcock-Johnson Tests of Cognitive Abilities, etc. it is interesting your bring up MENSA as an example of being one of the best because their tests are not exclusively pattern based. Some example questions are “which four letters can be attached to the beginning of the following words to make five larger words”, “re-arrange the letters in ANY TIME to give a seven letter word” (some trained in word scrambles will be quicker at this), “Jane went to visit Jill. Jill is Jane’s only husband’s mother-in-law’s only husband’s only daughter’s only daughter. What relation is Jill to Jane?” (Someone coming from a culture where family terms are different might struggle here), “Marian bought 4 oranges and 3 lemons for 90 cents. The next day she bought 3 oranges and 4 lemons for 85 cents. How much did each lemon and orange cost?”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933804128.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you have example of people with no education outscoring someone with a full education?

I mean here's a 3-year-old, with an IQ of 160. That is comparable to einstein. 

There's a 2-year-old with an IQ of 146. (98 is the average.)

https://www.google.com/amp/s/abc7.com/amp/2-year-old-mensa-american-kashe-quest-iq-146/10702553/



&amp;gt;Why would you say WAIS R is an ‘adjacent’ IQ test? It is and IQ test. It doesn’t fit into your narrowly defined perimeters but I’m not sure why you have drawn such a hard line in the sand. Are you saying you only recognize he validity of tests that solely ask people to finish pattern sets? What is your basis for deciding that?

There are actually studies looking at the validity of different IQ tests. The wais r is believed to be valid because it correlates closely with other outcomes. But there's a lot of papers that are discussing it being problematic for cultural reasons. 

&amp;gt;Some example questions are “which four letters can be attached to the beginning of the following words to make five larger words”, “re-arrange the letters in ANY TIME to give a seven letter word” (some trained in word scrambles will be quicker at this), “Jane went to visit Jill. Jill is Jane’s only husband’s mother-in-law’s only husband’s only daughter’s only daughter. What relation is Jill to Jane?” (Someone coming from a culture where family terms are different might struggle here), “Marian bought 4 oranges and 3 lemons for 90 cents. The next day she bought 3 oranges and 4 lemons for 85 cents. How much did each lemon and orange cost?”

Can you show me that these have been on the Mensa test? 

Mensa offers a free practice test. It might be worth taking a second to scroll through the questions to see how it works . 

https://www.mensa.org/public/mensa-iq-challenge</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
