<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40931877745.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Read The Mismeasure of Man by Stephen Gould. It breaks down the whole IQ myth. IQ doesn't really tell us anything aside from the fact that poverty and lack of education exists in these populations with lower IQ.

Unfortunately a lot of racism still exists in science and people want to jump to genetics when there are a lot of other factors to be addressed first. Even taking IQ tests requires a lot of prior knowledge.

And "lower IQ" is used as a way to explain poverty. In reality, how well does IQ translate to real world tasks? Do we look at IQ tests for college admissions or job placements? No.

Did anyone think low IQ India or China would become information technology hubs? No.

The assumption is that because they are low intelligence, they cannot produce the needed technology and do the work needed to develop their country. When in reality they do a lot of high level work but it is done for the benefit of Western corporations. They are barred from sharing in the technology and investment that the West benefitted from. They are forced to pour their resources into paying debts instead of building schools. 

Even if their IQ is lower by whatever reason and it's permanently lower, doesn't mean that they can't do what everyone else does. 

The real issue is not IQ. It is our neocolonial world order built on exploitation and debt peonage that keeps people in poverty. Change that and people will be fine, regardless of IQ, which is a completely meaningless number in this context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932570800.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And "lower IQ" is used as a way to explain poverty. In reality, how well does IQ translate to real world tasks? Do we look at IQ tests for college admissions or job placements? No.

Not in the usa, but IQ is strongly associated with outcomes. Including wealth, SAT scores, and grades. 

&amp;gt;Even taking IQ tests requires a lot of prior knowledge.

That's not true, at least not with legit tests. You can't study for an IQ test. 


&amp;gt;Even if their IQ is lower by whatever reason and it's permanently lower, doesn't mean that they can't do what everyone else does. 

If the average was permanently lower, it would mean doing most tasks would be harder or take longer. 

I don't think you understand how IQ tests work. It is not a knowledge based test.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933015626.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>It is correlated. Correlation does not equal causation.

And yes, you can actually study for an IQ test.
For example, this study showed a massive increase in IQ scores after training in creative problem solving.
 https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7709590/

This article talks about how IQ scores have steadily risen because of better and more challenging schooling. There is nothing innate about IQ. 
https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/more-school-more-challenging-assignments-add-higher-iq-scores/

Read Mismeasure of Man. It'll help you understand where IQ tests come from and give you a fuller understanding.

Also, it literally doesn't matter in real life if a task takes someone a little longer. I work as an engineer and literally it does not matter if I can do complex math in my head quickly or not. It is completely irrelevant to actual real life tasks. Which is why no one cares about IQ except for right wing racists who want to say minorities are inferior genetically or special education teachers who need to understand what kind of help a developmentally disabled child needs. In every other application IQ is pointless.

Look instead what people are actually *doing.* And if they're not doing it, why. Even if IQ measured something real, talking about IQ is just lazy analysis. It explains nothing about why the world is how it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933329185.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even if IQ measured something real, talking about IQ is just lazy analysis. It explains nothing about why the world is how it is.

I don't really think that's true. We do know that you can improve IQ with things like eating healthy, sleeping well, getting exercise, spending time outdoors. I think there was a lot of misuse of IQ through history, and so people wanted to invalidate it. But I think that if society embraced IQ again, that you would see a more humanitarian approach to raising children and improving their environment. I think that IQ disparities explain a lot of problems in our society today. 


You also have to be careful with the two studies that you showed because of the exact same reasons that you listed. Correlation does not equal causation. It's maybe the reason students are getting higher scores at difficult schools, or after spending several years training, are achieving better scores because those students come from better families, who prioritize their child's education, and may also provide a more stable home life. I cannot read the entire study. Do you know if the studies controlled for this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933716837.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>The study clearly showed that the students who did problem solving exercises performed much better than the control group. This is a controlled study, so we can be pretty confident about the causation here.

On the other article about rising IQ scores, yeah we don't know exactly why. But this also beats back against two claims. One, that IQ is genetic and innate and is completely determined by biology. And two, your claim here, that poverty has permanently made black and brown people low IQ. Clearly as conditions improved and education improved, IQ scores also increased.

IQ disparities do not explain anything. What we want to solve is wealth disparities. If IQ disparities tell us anything it is that different populations do not have the same resources and the same education.

So IQ is telling us something we already know. If you're poor and you are not as well educated you will not be as "intelligent." I put it in quotes because even then most people can do most jobs through education and training and anyone can learn and improve their intelligence and test scores and job performance.

The only use for IQ is to figure out if a child has a mental disability.

Also yes poverty does impact student performance but we have a lot of data showing that controlled for those factors, schools are still biased against minorities. So Black students, everything being equal, perform worse than White students. And it's not because of innate intelligence. It is because of racism and biases. And these kinds of things affect testing too, like IQ and SATs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933818111.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The study clearly showed that the students who did problem solving exercises performed much better than the control group. This is a controlled study, so we can be pretty confident about the causation here.

This is a 3-year training. Are you saying they locked children in a lab for 3 years and tested their iq? It would be impossible for them to control for other factors.

&amp;gt;And two, your claim here, that poverty has permanently made black and brown people low IQ. Clearly as conditions improved and education improved, IQ scores also increased.

&amp;gt;IQ disparities do not explain anything. What we want to solve is wealth disparities. If IQ disparities tell us anything it is that different populations do not have the same resources and the same education.

This is a conversation we're having on another thread about genetic markers. It seems that genetic markers caused by poverty are somewhat heritable, but they are also easily erased. 

https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/isw856n?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share&amp;amp;context=3

I also want to be clear about my argument. My argument is definitely not that poor people are always dumber than wealthier people. I'm just saying *on average* they are. And that's not even my opinion, that is consistently proven through multiple studies. Because stress of poverty actually does inhibit brain function. 

I think a lot of people don't like to give IQ a good rap, and I understand that it has been misused. People don't like it because they believe it's permanent and people like the rhetoric of "anybody can do anything". 

 But IQ could actually really benefit society if people took it more seriously. The only way to improve your IQ that is really known, is things like better sleep, better eating, less stressful environments, more time outside, more exercise, and other things that improve brain health, especially for young people. Imagine if we actually considered that a valid metric in schools? Rather than just the SAT where the only way to improve your scores to do 5 hours of homework a night and sit in your room all summer and cram for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40934500533.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>These are the facts:
1. IQ can improve over time.
2. IQ tests can be studied for.
3. For the most part, anyone can do anything. This is not rhetoric. 
4. IQ scores have increased in the US over time. So those impoverished people from 200 years ago did not stay dumb. 

Facts 2 and 4 alone should be more than enough for you to change your view.

You still haven't shown what value IQ adds. The SAT is a better measure of student performance as it measures actual relevant knowledge that the student has studied. 

If a student does well on the SAT what does it matter what his IQ score is?

And even the SAT - in fact all standardized tests - are flawed because testing itself does not necessarily capture what a student has learned and how well they apply it.

A holistic assessment of the student that takes into account their overall well being and knowledge is what schools are moving toward. Moving away from excessive homework or cramming (neither are necessary to do well in SATs btw).

Later on, what matters is how well you can do your job. What does it matter what your IQ is? It's pointless here as it is in school. 

It's not just that IQ is misused in the past. And you are make that same
mistake here, trying to box people into groups and classes based on IQ. 

It's more than misuse, it's that IQ itself (derived from g) is the result of bad statistical analysis, driven by people desperate in trying to find some innate marker of intelligence (and hence a marker of racial superiority in white people).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40934719468.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If a student does well on the SAT what does it matter what his IQ score is?

I'm not saying that the SAT is not a good metric. The SAT is a great metric for learned knowledge. It is a good metric for things like discipline. Problem with the SAT and other similar tests, is that none of them encourage things like healthier lifestyle, more sleep for children, better food for children, more time outside for children, at least not nearly as much as they encourage cramming information into students heads for 10 hours a day through your entire childhood. 

&amp;gt;Later on, what matters is how well you can do your job. What does it matter what your IQ is? It's pointless here as it is in school. 

It's just a predictor like any other predictor it's not going to be 100% correct. You could ace the SAT, but be really bad at your job. It's just less likely than somebody who flunked the SAT. That's also true for IQ. 


People love a meritocracy and I understand that the idea of those who work the hardest to get the most is the favorite Hollywood theme. Especially in america, where work input is often put above health. 

 But the reality is for some people they don't have to work nearly as hard as other people and so they have an easier time succeeding in most jobs on average. 

I honestly think though that if people took the IQ test more seriously, you would also see improvements in the average SAT score. Because people would prioritize their health and stress more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935601569.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>We have many metrics that tell us about the health of the population. In school we have all sorts of testing to show competency. IQ tests would add nothing. You want another round of testing to tell us what we already know. We know the problems, the challenge is how to fix them.

Cramming and excessive homework has to do with pedagogical style, not with any particular test. 

This is why we don't use predictors in job interviews, we use concrete skills. Even colleges are moving away from test scores and looking at students holistically. 

Schools are also moving away from grades and ranking, and are teaching to mastery. i.e. everyone learns the material to the full extent. 

Using IQ tests now not only adds nothing, it also takes us backward.

I agree we don't have a meritocracy but what you're describing is not even close to being the reality. The reality is that your income has nothing to do with your intelligence. 

Most well paying office jobs are actually not that hard. It is also well documented that the key to getting jobs and promotions is nepotism and networking, not intelligence or skills or even how well you do your job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935703164.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>If IQ was a requirement to succeed at certain life goals such as getting into college, or even getting a job, it would mean that health is now one of the things people need to take into account to achieve these big milestones.

Of course there are lots of ways to measure health, but we do not live in a society that promotes people to be healthy. We promote people into jobs, schools, based on how much they cram, and how much they exert themselves. 

&amp;gt;The reality is that your income has nothing to do with your intelligence. 

"In 2012, Vanderbilt University psychology researchers found that people with higher IQs tend to earn higher incomes, on average, than those with lower IQs. Past studies have also shown that high IQs are comparably reliable in predicting academic success, job performance, career potential and creativity." 

https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.cnbc.com/amp/2022/07/11/does-iq-determine-success-a-psychologist-weighs-in.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942463142.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"In 2012, Vanderbilt University psychology researchers found that people with higher IQs tend to earn higher incomes, on average, than those with lower IQs. Past studies have also shown that high IQs are comparably reliable in predicting academic success, job performance, career potential and creativity.

Again, this is correlation not causation. As you've already agreed. Because poverty, lack of education, etc, affect IQ scores. So IQ isn't telling us anything we don't already know through school assessments, health metrics, etc. 

IQ also is just a predictor that someone might be able to do some job. It is meaningless to anyone who is looking for concrete skills. In a job interview you don't go in talking about your IQ, you talk about what can you actually do. 

How much people cram or how they study has nothing to do with IQ tests or SATs. It has to do with how schooling is setup. And it has to do with our hierarchical educational system which actually was justified using IQ. 

The reason I said it has nothing to do with your intelligence is that many high paying jobs are actually not more mentally difficult than low paying jobs. Being promoted and getting into high paying positions has nothing to do with performance but rather nepotism and networking and connections. 

And the fact is, if IQ actually mapped onto income, you would see that most people would earn middle incomes, and very few would earn higher incomes. But what is actually true is that income is skewed far in favor of the top 0.01%, who make billions, while the rest of the people make nothing. 

That's because income and wealth are not tied to intelligence or skill, but rather are tied to property ownership and investments. Your wealth is decided by what you own, not what you do. 

Some of the smartest people are making minimum wage as adjunct professors. Artists, doctors, engineers were highest earners in the Soviet Union, not so in the capitalist countries, where capitalists are the richest followed by finance workers.

You can also consider the fact that a doctor can make way more in New York than in Louisiana. It all depends on the labor market. He can make way more in Louisiana in a private practice than in a public hospital. And he can make way more in a public hospital in Louisiana than he can in rural Chihuahua, Mexico. 

So the wealthier doctors are not smarter or better doctors, it's just where they live and who they work for. 

But of course because of the inherent biases in IQ, it's possible that the New York doctor just gets a higher score than the Mexican doctor. Nothing to do with their intelligence or what they are capable of, just after-the-fact justification of their wealth disparity.

It also becomes a pointless metric that tries to prove superiority in some "innate" spiritual sense rather than looking at what people are actually doing.

Jean Paul Sartre once said, you are defined by what you do. Just look at what people are doing. What are their school assessments, what do they know, what jobs they are doing, etc.

If you want to change the culture and our infrastructure to be healthier, then do that. IQ has nothing to do with it. Remember, you can't fatten a pig by weighing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942524505.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How much people cram or how they study has nothing to do with IQ tests or SATs. It has to do with how schooling is setup. And it has to do with our hierarchical educational system which actually was justified using IQ.

Our schooling system is not set up to aid iq. It is set up with the goal of achieving High SAT scores and high standardized testing scores. Our system rewards schools who output students who score well in these metrics. Because of that it encourages crazy amounts of homework and cramming, rather than encouraging a less stressful environment. 

As far as who is making what, you are pointing out anecdotes, and I am talking about averages. Of course there are examples where incredibly intelligent people make almost no money. There's examples where people that are really not intelligent make a lot of money. But they are outliers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942651527.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Since we can study to improve IQ scores, they will just transition from cramming for SATs to cramming for IQ tests.

But also I'm not sure how you expect anything to change just because children are taking IQ tests? They still need to actually learn the material, which is where the cramming and homework comes from.

It's not anecdotes. We have data on who makes how much and where. We have salary data based on location. My point is not to show you that some smart guy doesn't make a lot of money, but that that IQ is not the defining factor in what you make, it is a lot of other factors including economic outlook, demand for your profession, location, which employer you work for, etc.

We also know through data, not anecdotes, who the richest people in this country (and the world) are. They are not the smartest, they are simply owners of property and investments. Hope that clears up my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942698244.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Since we can study to improve IQ scores, they will just transition from cramming for SATs to cramming for IQ tests.

That's the beauty of it though. You cannot cram for an IQ test. In fact, it's likely that the stress that you put on your brain from cramming would cause with lower your IQ score. They are designed so that you cannot study for them. The best IQ test in the world are the ones that are least impacted by any form of studying. 

The only way you can that is studied that you can use to improve your IQ is to do things to improve brain health. Mainly by all the other methods that I listed earlier. Exercise healthy eating etc.

&amp;gt;but that that IQ is not the defining factor in what you make

I'm only arguing that it is a strong indicator. 

&amp;gt;We also know through data, not anecdotes, who the richest people in this country (and the world) are. They are not the smartest, they are simply owners of property and investments. Hope that clears up my point.

Actually, the wealthiest people in the world on average have highest IQ. Of course there are outliers. But these are the averages. 

https://images.app.goo.gl/WwUJGBzkHGVzkS1g9</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942932222.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>The stress issue is already one reason why we are moving away from testing in education. Of course some kids are more affected by stress than others, and that impacts their scores. Including IQ scores. This is a mark against IQ.

Cramming is also not going to go away. Kids will still do it. Everything about the school will be the same as they still need to learn the material, whatever their IQ. Cramming is an independent problem to what you're suggesting.

And we can study for IQ tests and schools will continue to develop ways to beat the tests, using all sorts of strategies and tricks. I don't believe that there is any IQ test that you can't get better at through studying and practicing. Would love to see an example of one. 

It is just added load and stress on schools and children and as I've shown, tells us absolutely nothing. Aside from are they innately intelligent and maybe they will do better at their job but who knows.

What you've shared about wealth is also a mark against IQ. How do you not see this proves my point? We know wealth is correlated with IQ, but where does wealth come from?

Wealth isn't the result of IQ but rather ownership, and where you work, etc. So again, correlation, but not causation. 

And that shows incontrovertibly that IQ is not measuring intelligence but rather measuring noise which includes culture, language, health, access to better education, racial bias, etc.

I think I've given you enough information that for me should be more than enough to shift your view somewhat. Let's agree to disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935711344.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Read my other reply but also consider this: if you took an IQ test of everyone at my company (we make and launch rockets), the highest paid and most knowledgeable people in the company will probably have the lowest IQ scores.

Why? Because we used to have far more lead in our environment a few decades ago, when gen X were growing up and coming of age. 

Leaded gasoline wasn't actually banned until 1996. And we know the impact of lead poisoning on IQ--it's not good. Gen X lost on average 5.9 points. 

And what about the epigenetic markers? Their kids are all doing well, they are all professionals.

Add onto that the flynn effect I mentioned before (how IQ keeps going up over time), for sure all the young idiotic kids have higher IQs. But they are not as good at their jobs as the older generation.

To me it just tells me IQ is irrelevant. People can lose several points of IQ, literally have lead poisoning, and still become rocket engineers. And all this data we already have on IQ has not helped us solve any social problems. What is more data going to do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935931477.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>So a couple things where you're wrong. I wouldn't be surprised if leaded the gasoline had a negative effect on iq. But the average IQ has increased over time, to there are probably other factors that have contributed to this rise, most likely improvements in the standard of living. 

It's also worth noting that IQ changes with age. Older people tend to lose IQ points. 

But there is evidence that IQ is a very strong predictor of things like creativity, job performance, and financial success

https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.cnbc.com/amp/2022/07/11/does-iq-determine-success-a-psychologist-weighs-in.html

"In 2012, Vanderbilt University psychology researchers found that people with higher IQs tend to earn higher incomes, on average, than those with lower IQs. Past studies have also shown that high IQs are comparably reliable in predicting academic success, job performance, career potential and creativity."

&amp;gt;Add onto that the flynn effect I mentioned before (how IQ keeps going up over time), for sure all the young idiotic kids have higher IQs. But they are not as good at their jobs as the older generation.

Sure because older generations probably have more learned knowledge, and that is also important. But if you have two teenagers joining a workforce with different IQs, even with similar work experience, the one with a higher IQ would probably be a better investment for a company.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942524189.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Right, it is a predictor because richer people who have higher standards of living and thus have higher IQs also have access to higher paying jobs. It's not even just that they are higher IQ so they get these jobs. No, most people are kept out of becoming high paying professionals and wealthy entrepreneurs through financial restrictions. You have to pay for college, you have to have connections to get jobs and get investments, etc. 

 But my point is that even the lower IQ older generation are still doing a better job than many high IQ younger people.

&amp;gt;Sure because older generations probably have more learned knowledge, and that is also important. But if you have two teenagers joining a workforce with different IQs, even with similar work experience, the one with a higher IQ would probably be a better investment for a company.

There are too many factors involved in who becomes a better employee for anyone to make that claim. The claims that IQ predicts job performance have now been debunked.

Read this article, it brings up a lot of issues with IQ and its analysis.

[https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4557354/](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4557354/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942602032.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>The link that you sent does not debunk anything. It is not a study, it is an article. Anybody can write an article that criticizes how data is collected. On top of that, this article is trying to criticize meta studies. And not just meta studies, *corrected* meta studies that have corrected for possible control error. 

Meta studies are the most reliable source of information we have in our society. They often compile tens of thousands of data points. 

It also does things like criticize what people that view as valid job performance. Because this is subjective of course. But you can't just pretend commonly used metrics that are used to quantify job performance are irrelevant just because you don't like the idea of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40942694510.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>The idea they are criticizing is not quantifying job performance, but saying that IQ predicts job performance. 

In fact, the concept of IQ itself, as I have mentioned before and this article delves into, is dubious. 

Yeah, a lot of studies have been done on IQ. Which is why I recommend you read The Mismeasure of Man as it goes into how bad historically the research around IQ has been and how IQ comes from a statistical error. 

You're trying to find this "innate" quality that doesn't exist. And that's why they keep trying to find correlations and say after-the-fact that it's caused by IQ, when there are a host of other factors that are ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
