<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40927786365.0" user="Amoral_Abe" delta="False">
    <text>I 100% agree that poverty has significant impacts on the ability to learn and be successful in careers however, I disagree that it leads to permanent racial barriers.  As people become more economically successful, they allow greater opportunities for their children who then see higher rises in scientific learning.  
  
For example, look at China.  For over 100 years china was incredibly impoverished and was taken over by foreign powers.  However, currently, China now has greater scientific output than any other nation (publishing over 400k scientific papers vs USA's 275k scientific papers).  If there was a permanent divide because of the poverty that occurred, this wouldn't be possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40927907782.0" user="htiafon" delta="False">
    <text>Number of papers isn't a relevant metric, and China has huuuuuge academic fraud issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928019171.0" user="Amoral_Abe" delta="False">
    <text>China absolutely deals with fraud, however China currently has the world's largest high speed rail network, some of the largest tech companies in the world (including TENCENT and Alibaba), the 4th most powerful supercomputer, Along with massive scientific corporations.  You can argue that China has corruption and problems and I would absolutely agree.  However, China's current global standing would not be possible if poverty lead to permanent racial disparities in scientific and intellectual capabilities.  China's poverty was extreme all the way up until the 1980s when it started to shift (although it really didn't see economic growth for its people until the 2000s).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928083657.0" user="htiafon" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, sure. I agree with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928157484.0" user="Amoral_Abe" delta="False">
    <text>If you agree, I'd appreciate a delta</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928183633.0" user="htiafon" delta="False">
    <text>My mind didn't change. (I'm not OP.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928706513.0" user="MDFornia" delta="False">
    <text>Lol ravenous</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928460274.0" user="president_pete" delta="False">
    <text>Just some back of the napkin math suggests China isn't producing nearly as many articles per capita as the US is. They have around 4x the population and are producing 1.5x as many papers. To achieve parity, they should be publishing something like 1.1mn papers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40930751656.0" user="bobdadude" delta="False">
    <text>A large volume of papers being published doesn't mean they are of quality. One of the driving factors behind the replication crises in academia is the "publish or perish" phenomenon. Essentially, a lot of papers are rubbish.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
