<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40929889804.0" user="nightly11111" delta="False">
    <text>This is the reason why critical race theory is very important ....

Because you fall to acknowledge how minorities were routinely killed by angry jealous mobs whether it was isolated incidences of independent groups of the KKK or the race riots of the early 1900s  
There hasn't been a whole lot of time for the accumulation of wealth of a lot of African-Americans families .....

There's definitely scars that remain in the psyche that need healing that with equal opportunity would remedy the situation
.......

Although I will say across the board when it comes to poverty regardless of race it's very common for them to have generational trauma including psychological, physical and sexual abuse ....
In general poverty puts people at risk for Early childhood or adolescent trauma and people who experience trauma as children do worse on average</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
