<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40928210235.0" user="fckingbutterflies" delta="False">
    <text>the main reason that lower income areas are well known for having people with lower IQ is because lower income areas simply cannot pull in as much money to fund education. the people there simply aren’t well educated. and very few of those in lower incomes go on to college or university. because we’ve redlined the hell out of poc, especially black poc, and the fact that moving up in economic class is so hard, poc are especially stuck in this situation. 
we need to stop listening to pundits and rich people insisting trickle down economics works and realize it’s *not* working and it won’t ever work. because they know as well as any well informed person that they’re doing it to keep their wealth at the top. there need to be ways to aid those in lower income areas and those below the poverty line. hell, help the people who are just skating above the poverty line, they’re not getting by as well as they should and are on top of it denied welfare. 

TLDR: this is true simply because black poc are the majority population in many low income areas, leading to underfunded and poor education, and we need to do better to lift up those who have been held down for so long.

*also don’t equate having a low IQ with being genuinely stupid. a lot of those with low IQ’s are simply not well educated and that can be caused by a number of factors, in this case being poor and going to an underfunded school. i’m also pretty sure that IQ was created by a eugenicist, you can fact check me on that.*

edit: i didn’t read the part about theorizing about DNA. **no, please don’t say this.** there’s no data that backs the idea black people inherently have lower IQ’s or are ‘stupider’. there are currently 3 children who have the highest IQ scores in the world and the 3 of them are black. this “inherent stupidity” idea is held by racists, neonazis, and ethno-nationalists to justify slavery and genocide of black people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928804314.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>I can't really engage with your response because you don't have a fundamental understanding of how IQ tests are administered. It's not like an SAT, it doesn't test on concepts you learn in school. You can't study for it.  How much education you have is completely irrelevant.  Somebody who never went to school or received any form of education can score higher than someone who did. 

It's purely puzzles, pattern recognition, there isn't even usually written questions in the test itself. 

Like this is an example of a question from an IQ test:

https://images.app.goo.gl/yr1SFrgt11jVqUGw8</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932965713.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29911926/#:~:text=Intelligence%20test%20scores%20and%20educational,a%20longer%20education%20increases%20intelligence.

Also, clinical IQ tests are NOT just puzzles.  There are several sections: Verbal comprehension, Visual Spatial, Fluid Reasoning, Working Memory, and Processing Speed.

These tests CAN be useful for children, when assessing how to best teach them (for example, in a kid with ADHD, seeing how much of the difficulty in learning is coming from the ADHD vs raw intelligence.  If the kid is high IQ, then they can focus on teaching around the ADHD exclusively.  If the kid is below average, then they have to factor that in for more intense support) but using them to asses the *value* of adults is problematic to say the least. 

It is impossible to make an IQ test completely culture fair.  Someone has to write the questions, and their backgrounds will influence that.  It doesn’t matter how careful you are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933678552.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are several sections: Verbal comprehension, Visual Spatial, Fluid Reasoning, Working Memory, and Processing Speed

I'm not sure about verbal comprehension, but the rest of these things are usually tested with puzzles. 

On Mensa website, there is a 20 question practice test that you can take for free. I would recommend that you try taking it even just as a learning experience. Or don't even take it just skim through the questions.

I do know there's a lot of tests out there that aren't very good and can be affected by cultural factors. I think mensa has one of the better ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40951228147.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>I have done.  It is a sample.  It is *fun* if you like puzzles, but it is not comprehensive.  Mensa will do proctored IQ tests, but they don't do *clinical* IQ tests.  They also admit quite readily that their tests are biased towards English speaking westerners. (At least, last time I checked.  They used to suggest alternatives if you didn't meet that demographic.).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40951385550.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>ALL tests.  All of them. 

There are a lot of assumptions that we make about what intelligence looks like that are built into to culture.

As an extreme example, if you were to ask a bushman who practices persistence hunting what kind of questions he would ask to determine if someone is smart, he'd probably posit a questions that require inductive reasoning from incomplete data sets that we are not used to reading (look at these tracks here, about how long ago did the gazelle pass by?  What animal was likely following it).  We would fail this test hard.  We know, because people that weren't raised this way tried to do it.  Adults from different cultures seem almost incapable of learning it at all. 

You see a lot of these pattern sequence things in so- called culture fair tests, and sure, that's better than making someone read a differnet language, but it isn't and can't be completely fair.  

Our education system and even early childhood media is filled with this type of problem.  "One of these things is not like the other.  One of these things just doesn't belong".  "Find the next number in the sequence" problems in math class.  "If Jill has a dinosaur and all veliciraptors are dinosaurs, does Jill have a Velociraptor? Yes, No, Unable to determine".  We play with plastic and wooden shapes as puzzles and toys from infancy. 

If you are from a culture that does not bombard you with multiple choice tests (where problems have one, definitive, correct answer), or even worse, rarely teaches with markings on paper at all, you'll be at a huge disadvantage on an American style IQ test.  If you hand people who are unused to it one of these sequence problems, they may not even know what is expected of them.  If you give them instructions, but not in their native language, that puts them at a disadvantage as well. 

And, where you do have verbal comprehension tests, this puts people who routinely use a different *dialect* of English then American standard at a disadvantage as well.

As an example: Many African Americans code switch - they are bi-dialectic.  They learn American standard, but it is not their mother dialect. They certainly will do better on a verbal American standard test than you would on a Verbal AAVE test (What is the difference between "They married." And "They *been* married."?) but it would be unreasonable to expect native AAVE users to do as well, as a group, on American standard verbal tests against people who use that dialect 100% of the time.  The same would be true if you were to take a verbal test written by British people (who might ask things like: Is "learned" or "learnt" correct in the following sentence?).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935162945.0" user="fckingbutterflies" delta="False">
    <text>aren’t IQ tests administered to children before entering grade school in order to know if they need to be put into special needs classes or into regular education? i also know you can opt to go take one when you’re older as well, which was something i did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935375865.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>You can take an IQ test at 2 years and 6 months. Sometimes they are used for special ed, but they are available to anybody.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40935438438.0" user="fckingbutterflies" delta="False">
    <text>ah okay. i’m not well versed in that realm, only really socioeconomic stuff. also i just searched up “were iq tests created by a eugenicist” and this paper published by depaul university came up. it goes over the origins of IQ testing along with the correlation it has with eugenics. i’ve only skimmed it so far but i think it’d be a good read. here’s the link: https://via.library.depaul.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1270&amp;amp;context=law-review</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
