<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40927872799.0" user="tirikai" delta="False">
    <text>Europe was a backwards hellhole compared with most of the rest of humanity for most of the existence of humanity. If you were to compare the lives of a Scandinavian with an Ethiopian in 1000BC few people would think the Scandinavian had the better lifestyle. 

Prehistoric poverty evidently does not 'permanently damage' DNA such that your descendants are cursed to be dummies just because many generations of your family were not as well off as other people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928308145.0" user="arhanv" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly - I’ve argued this a little further in my comment but if poverty metrics really had any devastating genetic effects they would still not be enough to make any of us considerably different from each other given that most of our ancestors lived in far worse conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928558997.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure if it would be as important in prehistoric times as more recently. I would need a study showing the tie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928981626.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>Why the hell would it be different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929010420.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>Well because genes have more time to change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929248429.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>The ability for gene expression to differ according to environment is just as much a part of our evolution as anything else.  It did not spring into existence whole cloth in the past 300 years or so.

If our environment can affect gene expression now, it’s because our genes are designed to do that.  Meaning, it must have been going on for a while. (Slight tangent: One could imagine many effects that would be bad for the individual, but good for getting the genes into the next generation, that may express when the individual is stressed.  The epigenetic effects of poverty are unlikely to be harmful with no germ line payoff, since we seem to have evolved these responses)

If you are saying that we got “hearty” against the ill affects of poverty because they spanned thousands of years… why would we have lost that heartiness in relatively few generations, allowing poverty to more profoundly affect us now?  

I think the burden of proof is on you, because that isn’t a very reasonable assumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929262655.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>I asked the other person what they thought about this study after giving them a delta. Because this was the first thing that came up on Google honestly. 


https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4517414/#__ffn_sectitle

There is a section on epigenetic heritability. I honestly don't understand a large percentage of the lingo. But It seems to say that it's possible but it's hard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932859826.0" user="PotatoesNClay" delta="False">
    <text>It’s also reversible. Say that people have increased methylation because of increased stress throughout their lifetime.  Say that it is so bad that the methylation affects their gametes.  

They pass some of this methylation on to their kids.

(Note that it is very difficult to separate out the effects of a continued stressful environment here.)

Well, if the environment changes, the second generation may undergo demethylation (unmarking), undoing some of the damage and passing on less of it to their kids.  It only takes a couple generations for things to be put right.

It may be partially responsible for the Flynn effect.

Though, when talking poverty, I would like to remind you that teasing out the effects of methylation from the much larger effects of being poor and stressed out is very difficult.  We don’t know to what degree, if any, that methylation really effects IQ.  Some studies have shown that the environmental impact on IQ seems to decrease over the lifespan. 

https://medcraveonline.com/JNSK/factors-influencing-intelligence-quotient.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933642392.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;(Note that it is very difficult to separate out the effects of a continued stressful environment here.)

&amp;gt;Well, if the environment changes, the second generation may undergo demethylation (unmarking), undoing some of the damage and passing on less of it to their kids. It only takes a couple generations for things to be put right.

Well that's super interesting. So my op is half right. The effects of poverty are hereditary, but it also seems to be easily wiped out, or reversed. 

What happens if the environment doesn't change between generations. If you had subsequent generations of just terrible poverty for ten straight generations. Hypothetically could these markers compound?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929163126.0" user="TheMiz2002" delta="False">
    <text>Source?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
