<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2068653566.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/">
    <title>CMV: Poverty may actually cause permanent racial IQ disparities</title>
    <original_poster>Laniekea</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know. It sounds FUKIN terrible. But there is a lot of evidence that is pointing in this direction, and I'm *hoping* somebody to convince me otherwise. 

First, let's start by saying that there is a significant amount of evidence that shows that poverty has a negative impact on IQ. Which shouldn't really be too surprising. Stress, lack of sleep, poor eating or exercise, unhealthy food inhibit brain function. Poverty causes all those things. Minorities are more likely to experience poverty. That part isn't really controversial, there is a notable difference between poor and wealthy children's IQ. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20children%20from%20low%20SES,this%20difference%20had%20almost%20tripled.

There's really massive twin studies that have found that IQ is at least partially hereditary.

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242404/


On top of that, there's also evidence that poverty actually damages genes. 

https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2019/04/poverty-leaves-a-mark-on-our-genes/#:~:text=They%20discovered%20that%20lower%20socioeconomic,the%20genes%20in%20the%20genome.

And this is kind of the part where I'm hoping people can convince me otherwise. Because I don't understand that much about DNA and I'm hoping people can either show me a study that definitively proved otherwise, or can explain DNA a little better so that I can understand. 

My hypothesis is that multiple centuries of consistent poverty, slavery, abuse in Africa, wars in the middle east, poverty in India has done so much damage to genes that it is actually causing minorities to be born with a lower average IQ. 

I would love if somebody knew of maybe a multi racial adopted sibling study,  or a study that found another way controlled for poverty that found no difference.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40928296007.0" user="arhanv" delta="False">
    <text>The study you cited about genetic markers related to poverty is not nearly as much of a smoking gun as you would need to make any vast claims about global and racial disparities since it only included subjects from the Philippines - and it doesn’t have any evidenced implications on IQ. Here’s the DOI for the full study: http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ajpa.23800

In order for such genetic differences to compound into geographical or racial differences over time, there would probably also have to be some sort of indication that high IQ individuals only have children with other high IQ individuals or vice versa, which seems especially unlikely in developing countries where marriages are much more traditionally conducted.

If your argument is that (1) poverty is associated with low IQ (2) some component of IQ is genetic and (3) poverty can have genetic effects, that is far far far far from sufficient evidence about this topic. Poverty being associated with low IQ is not merely the same as there being a causal relationship between the two. Genetics being a factor in IQ does not mean that they are somehow entirely determinant of IQ or even that there isn’t a much stronger relationship between IQ and something else that could entirely override it. For all we know, drinking orange juice or getting some magic vaccine as a child could have a massive effect on IQ development. Similarly, poverty affecting some genetic processes at a very microscopic level does not inherently mean that IQ is one of those factors, and we cannot even be *slightly* sure of that until it is empirically tested. I’m sure someone has brought this up, but most people in academia (probably including the people who wrote these studies) would not consider IQ a useful measure of intellect even from a purely scientific perspective. But I’m treating it like it is potentially a valid metric and it still doesn’t make much sense for this connection to be evidenced by any of these studies.

All of us are descendants of people who have experienced abject poverty and complete medical neglect by today’s standards. If someone experiencing our definition of poverty was going to leave harmful genetic markers, we would all already have far more of them in common. Just because Europeans managed to colonize Asia and Africa in the past ~400 years doesn’t really change the fact that everyone before that was living in tragic conditions, and you need to consider time periods that long in any conversation about genetics. 

Evolution is an impactful but slow process if the “survival of the fittest” theory applies, but there’s also no indication that poverty leads to low rates of reproduction since poverty actually causes low rates of family planning and thus larger families in most countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40928870754.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Genetics being a factor in IQ does not mean that they are somehow entirely determinant of IQ or even that there isn’t a much stronger relationship between IQ and something else that could entirely override it. 

I completely recognize that it likely is influenced strongly, possibly significantly more strongly by other factors. But I don't think that means it can be "overridden". But it might effect broad averages. 


&amp;gt;Poverty being associated with low IQ is not merely the same as there being a causal relationship between the two

At least this much has been proven. We definitively know that poverty impedes brain development and stress impedes brain function. 

&amp;gt;Similarly, poverty affecting some genetic processes at a very microscopic level does not inherently mean that IQ is one of those factors, and we cannot even be slightly sure of that until it is empirically tested

I understand that my view is merely a hypothesis. I'm hoping for evidence that definitively shows otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929677346.0" user="arhanv" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I understand that my view is merely a hypothesis. I'm hoping for evidence that definitively shows otherwise.

Let's use a common scientific metric to test this - [falsifiability](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Falsifiability). What sort of evidence would someone need to provide in order to disprove or prove your view? I'm not exactly sure how someone can disprove an idea this vast if no attempts have been made at proving it or finding a *method* of proving it.

So instead, I think you should reflect on what led you to this hypothesis in the first place. You are not wrong in saying that poverty can affect a person's intellectual development. You are also not wrong in acknowledging that some research has been done into poverty's genetic impacts on a biochemical level and the genetic links of intellectual development. All I'm saying is that, to reach the hypothesis you have formed, you also need to make assumptions that are actually way more significant than any of this evidence really is.

Anyway, this is the crux of my actual objection:

When you suggest that a **permanent** disparity in IQ could arise through poverty (which in your view would lead to a subsequent disparity in IQ across racial and geographical lines), you are suggesting that the *effects* of poverty (low access to education, healthcare, developmental stability) could damage the genetic *predictors* of IQ in certain populations such that their descendants are going to be predisposed to lower IQs. This also has the direct implication that it would be less likely for them to acquire a higher IQ if they somehow escape poverty, correct? This is why I would say there is simply no evidence for this -

1. If the effects of poverty could have such a drastic impact on genetics, we would all already have FAR more debilitating genetic defects from our ancestors' poverty than any sort of poverty could create in the present day. The vast majority of people today have access to an exponentially higher level of basic healthcare - even in the most remote parts of South Asia and Africa - than the richest people did about 200 years ago. If all of our ancestors would have had low quality-of-life metrics by today's standards anyway, then it is obvious that our conditions change more drastically as a species than they do in terms of any other sociocultural divisions.

2. Many of the richest racial and ethnic subgroups in prosperous countries are minority groups that recently immigrated from "poor" countries. Case in point - Asian-Americans earn about $100,000/year on average in the US. If poverty really had any permanent effects on IQ, this would be a very strange statistic because we know that most people who lived in Asian countries were abjectly poor until at least World War 2 by any modern standards. Even if you put aside all the centuries of common experiences we share across racial lines, we know that the average West-European lived in far better conditions than the average Asian for much of the past 400-500 years. Where are these differences materializing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929704317.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What sort of evidence would someone need to provide in order to disprove or prove your view? I'm not exactly sure how someone can disprove an idea this vast if no attempts have been made at proving it or finding a *method* of proving it.

I kind of talk about it in the op. 

I think the best way to prove it would be if you could find a sibling study that looked at adopted siblings between different races, where you have two siblings of different races that are adopted by the same family, grew up in the same conditions, and had their IQ tested in adolescence. And then have a large enough data pool to find consistent trends. That might prove a racial disparity, if you could find that one race was on average outperforming their sibling at similar ages. 

The second best way I could think of is to test adolescent IQ across different races and then control for parents socioeconomic status. 

I'm definitely not arguing that this would be the only thing that impacts IQ. I certainly think that someone's lived poverty is probably an even larger indicator, since there is plenty of evidence to support that conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40929839907.0" user="arhanv" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, here you go -

1. Here’s one from the journal American Psychologist discussing empirical data on intellect and genetics: https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037/a0029772

2. Here’s another one from an affiliated research team for the journal Psychological Science that looks at standardized testing over time: https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01802.x

**But given that you asked for a study about adoption to show the distinction between environment and racial factors** -

3. A study that does exactly that from the American Psychologist journal: https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037/0003-066X.31.10.726</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40932383689.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not really sure what the first study has to do with this post. 

The second study is maybe the closest. It is talking about the flynn effect. Which is the idea that humans are generally improving and intelligence over time. It debunks claims that black people are not improving with the rest of the population. It found that black people have seen the greatest improvement from the Flynn effect, closing the IQ gap between black people and other races by 4 to 7 IQ points.  But it is not controlled at all for socioeconomic factors. The IQ Gap could improve because black people standard of living has improved comparably. 

The last study doesn't quite do what you think it does. What it actually does is look at black children who were adopted by wealthy families and then compares them to the *mean* White student. 

In order to actually control for poverty, you would need to compare them to a white sibling or someone of similar socioeconomic status, not just the average joe white person. 

The study found that being raised in socially advantageous conditions improves iq, which I talked about in the op is generally agreed upon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933081013.0" user="arhanv" delta="False">
    <text>If socioeconomic improvements are drastically closing the IQ gap, and we know that it is at least likely that being raised in socially advantageous conditions raises your IQ regardless of your biological birth conditions, then what evidence is there that the genetics of poverty have any permanent impact on IQ? You’re setting categorically different burdens of proof for both sides. If you concede that socioeconomic factors can completely change the aggregate IQ gap of adopted children regardless of race, it seems rather illogical for you to believe that anything about this is a “permanent” change given that your genetic argument was highly speculative at best.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40933940537.0" user="Laniekea" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah, I fully recognize also in the op that my argument is completely speculative. It's a hypothesis, and I'm wondering if the data exists that can either prove or disprove it. Somebody has actually been able to provide this in another thread we've been talking about genetic markers. 


https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/y7mfb2/cmv_poverty_may_actually_cause_permanent_racial/isyd8s2?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share&amp;amp;context=3

It seems that I am half right. Poverty can impact genetic markers, and those marked genes can be inherited. However, these markers can also easily be erased by improving the environment that somebody lives in. So, while not everything is known about this, it seems its not permanent and can be easily undone after a few generations.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
