<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="207157398.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fc3o6/cmv_people_who_give_their_kids_two_last_names_are/">
    <title>CMV: People who give their kids two last names are inconsiderate</title>
    <original_poster>NeoshadowXC</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a lot of fun at the expense of people with two last names. This is a tough one, because I do believe a woman shouldn't be socially pressured into taking her's husband's last name, and gay spouses also have a conundrum of their own. 

However, I think that a family should have a family name, because otherwise you are choosing to make everyone else's life difficult. One small example is if you work in an industry where you deal with a lot of names and families and meeting people blind (like I do). It's helpful to know in advance who is related to who by just looking at a piece of paper.

BUT, if the wife and the husband choose not to share a last name, please God settle on one name for your kid. Just flip a coin for which last name your kid takes if that's what you need to do. Don't make everyone around him have to deal with saying and writing out Reginald Henry Lieberman-Montgomery. 

A metaphor I would make for this would be gender pronouns. You have the right to tell me whether you identify as a man or a woman, but I swear to God if you insist that everyone around you refer to you strictly with the gender neutral pronouns Ni, Nem and Nir, I will be having none of it. 

As a counterpoint, I will say that I can't ever imagine myself taking my wife's last name. And if she chose not to take mine, I think I would feel a little disappointed. Further, I can't imagine feeling comfortable with my kid not taking my last name. So I already recognize a bit of the hypocrisy. In that way, I see that I am posing a problem without an apparent solution. On top of your rebuttals, I would also be curious to hear alternative ideas/social structures that could work to level the playing field, AND prevent me from having to say a mouthful. 

**EDIT:**

Apologies for the day long delay-- car emergency took all night and all morning.

Thanks for all your responses! Here are some of my views you've changed. 

Spain &amp;gt; 'Murica. There's a clear system in place in Spanish countries that actually speaks to my "one family name" point. People consistently take the fathers, then mother's surname. Then the kid's kids will do the same. Gives you family history and also something to put on your mailbox. 

What I personally like about this is that it's uniform. If two last names were adopted country-wide in America, I would have much less of a problem with it. 

I also want to clarify: My problem with the "mouthful" of hyphenated last names does not mean that I would also suggest gentrifying the Krzyzewskis and the Chevaprevadumrongs of the world. To shorten your family name is to bastardize it. No ill feelings to those with shortened last names of course-- my last name was actually gentrified two generations ago. 

Finally, here is a post that very well summarizes my American sentiments: 

&amp;gt; While this drifts from your true argument, these lines of thinking quickly move into the larger name-choice debate, which in my experience usually boils down to “People who name their kids something I like or understand are exercising reasonable freedom of choice. People who name their kids something I dislike or don’t understand are selfish and stupid.” You have not said this, but I think it is worth pointing out that are cultural biases about names are deep-seated.

&amp;gt; You want people to have choices about identity labels - - - as long as every choice is based on what you find easiest and most comfortable. If a stranger's choice is not based on your preference, they are selfish and inconsiderate. When a family you do not know fills out a birth certificate, you ask that the FIRST priority be guessing your experience if you meet their child at work in twenty years, and the SECOND priority be articulating their identity as a family in a way that feels personally appropriate.

My American sensibilities that shorter is better are deeply ingrained and will probably be there 'til I die. That said, at least I can recognize them so that I know to keep them in check. 

While I will continue to make fun of people who have two last names, it will be with the same conviction that I make fun of everyone else. No hostility here.

Thanks guys!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27914074889.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>Inconsiderate to whom? You? Who do they owe?

Is this about how much you dislike those names and if people didn't do it anymore you would love that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
