<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40973072675.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

I'm a slutty gay guy in a 10+ year open relationship, so maybe this doesn't apply to me. A huge reason relationships don't last is because of poor communication and weak emotional intelligence. Meeting someone on an app or in a bar and getting them into bed requires far less social and emotional skills than maintaining a long-term relationship. I mean honestly it can often be as little as a few messages.

This makes sense -- long term relationships tend to have higher expectations of people in terms of emotion and social components. Like, I don't care if the guy I fucked last night is curious about how my day is or why I'm feeling anxious or excited, but I expect my partner to care more about these things. It's not important that my fuck buddy get along with my friends and family; it is important for my partner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973164544.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>It’s hard for me to really understand or gauge how promiscuous heterosexual males actually leverage their social skills in these situations. I don’t think it’s easily comparable to people in other groups, but I’m also not completely sure what their situation actually is.

Privilege is a big thing that affects things u/destro23 tried to talk about it but they focused too much on the experience of women (which is irrelevant to the view I was wanting changed).

Is it just social capital and little social skills? There are quite a few different possible scenarios. 

I changed my view already on the basis of understimating the ceiling of monogamy. I changed my view somewhat on a notion of complexity theory which nobody in this thread was actually willing to address even when I explicitly stated I’d give a delta if they engaged on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973213300.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Privilege is a big thing that affects things u/destro23 tried to talk about it but they focused too much on the experience of women (which is irrelevant to the view I was wanting changed).

Dang, you really didn't listen to *anything* that I was saying did you? 

My entire argument was about your misunderstanding of "agency". You think promiscuous men have more agency. I say that all men have the same agency in that each man may make the choice to be either promiscuous or to peruse monogamous relationships. That is where the agency lies. That is the choice. To be (promiscuous) or not to be (promiscuous). No matter the side you choose, it was your agency that chose it. Choosing promiscuity does not give you more agency in life. It only puts you on a path that will present you with options different from the person on the path of monogamy. 

But, both chose to be on the path, and that is where the agency lies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973241749.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It’s hard for me to really understand or gauge how promiscuous heterosexual males actually leverage their social skills in these situations.

Are you defining "social skills" or "emotional skills" as "ability to get laid." Perhaps that's where we differ. To me social skills are more about the ability to successfully navigate all sorts of social situations with appropriate engagements, contributions, reactions, etc. 

And these social skills are far more important when it comes to developing and maintaining a long term romantic relationship than just getting laid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973330194.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>And my thought on it is that such development should occur consistently on both, the fact it doesn’t indicates other factors on either one affecting developmental trajectories. For example privilege.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973473597.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused about what you're saying and how it relates to my comment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
