<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40972099314.0" user="babyrapking" delta="False">
    <text>IMHO both male and female promiscuity are dangerous, unhealthy, disgusting acts</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972112685.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Why so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972140242.0" user="babyrapking" delta="False">
    <text>In females, it degrades them, when it comes to sex work it reduces their social value and is the best example of capitalisms corruption of society. It makes women less capable of holding relationships, more likely to cheat and more likely to be abused and subsequently become abusive. 


In males, it makes them borderline sociopathic in their treatment of women, it creates a correlation between women and meaningless, drug-like sex that is used for both but instant gratification. They will learn to objectify women, their relationship will become shallow and they will become much more likely to cheat or be abusive seeing as the way they perceive women is warped. 


The culture of men "scoring" when they have sex is wrong ,no doubt and the culture of women being scorned or praised for being promiscuous is also wrong. Disregarding my own personal religious views, I think from a purely scientific and social perspective promiscuity is a dangerous part of society and overall does nothing but harm people, it shouldn't be illegal or downright shunned but it is wrong and it is dangerous</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
