<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40978169307.0" user="hydramess7" delta="False">
    <text>Monogamy is necessary for survival of today word.
Male not getting girl make them incels, I rather stick to one girl than dating many.Its only for men work when they have high status and wealth and exponential social skill.

There be a lot of men(especially young men 16-30) who don't have any one of that what happened to them.These guy are the main work force of the society, if they are not able to have child and sex what the point of working.

They might group together and revolt against the government.And it be like bad old times where everyone getting killed.

If you look in history only(.0000001) have the ability to joy the lifestyle which are either born in royalty or warriors.And only those society survive and thrive and will thrive that follow monogamy.

You might bring Islam has counterpoint,than most of Muslim countries have to of oils and have the most backward law which doesn't give respect to woman.And other wife mostly likely with widow or divorced.
And most Muslim countries are not the most peaceful countries.And they don't follow Islam too. I'm not trying to say Islam is bad, bortherhood is key point of the religion and also the best part of it.

P.S- It also time consuming and after a while a hole is a hole it's nothing new and become boring.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
