<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971184910.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>[Promiscuity] requires ~~more~~ **different** social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships)

I think being promiscuous has it's own relative-'ease' to it as well because you don't have to worry about another person, just yourself. It's selfish, and therefore 'easier' in some ways. I don't think one is easier than the other, in the end, just different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971824231.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's probably true. What degree of overlap do you think exists between the two skillsets?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971831072.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Being a good listener: that's probably it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971906130.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Is that a hard skill? Because it seems like an easy one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971911441.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Hearing is easy, but is listening?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971959254.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>What portion of the population do you think are good listeners? And let’s contrast that with a skill that might be more relevant to casual sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971985651.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What portion of the population do you think are good listeners?

I have no idea

&amp;gt; And let’s contrast that with a skill that might be more relevant to casual sex.

Like what? And why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972000737.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>To compare easiness vs hardness</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
