<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922422608.0" user="thedeliriousdonut" delta="False">
    <text>Hiya.

So, I'm from the US. And while I agree with you that the government needs to get their shit together and raise the wage for these employees, you should still tip.

**Why?** Because what option is the ethical or moral option is based on the current situation.

The current situation is these employees have low wages. Sure, they shouldn't have to have low wages, just like puppies shouldn't have to be abused, but they do have low wages and your wage is likely higher.

And sure, if the government gave them higher wages, it would not be too much of a moral discrepancy to not tip, but that's not the case. I could say, before killing someone, that if this weren't an old lady and she were threatening my life and is also the next Hitler, then I am justified in this killing. But none of that is the case. This is an innocent old lady, no variant I can imagine changes that.

Yes, push for legislation to make wages better. But if someone has a low wage, tipping helps them. It's that simple.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922459250.0" user="litle5o" delta="False">
    <text>I somewhat agree with you. But can I ask what your opinion on if we stopped tipping or wait staff demanded higher pay through union strike, would this help aid the situation? IMO tipping is adding to the problem and allowing establishments exploit their employees as they see it as 'no need to raise wages, they're pretty happy making wages that are not set in stone from people who aren't me'. If this was challenged could this help? 

Like I said, I'm from the UK and the restaurant industry is very different here. So maybe my lack of knowledge is where my view comes from.

I'm all for helping people out and I do tip on occasion (here in the UK) is the server is going above and beyond with astounding service, but that's normally with returning custom. I guess my problem is with the moral obligation to tip rather than the act of tipping. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922481776.0" user="thedeliriousdonut" delta="False">
    <text>The industry here is so lousy with their wages that the amount of damage you do in the short term when you don't tip outweighs the possibility of the long term change, especially given that you can tip and push for legislation that increases the wages of these workers, which would be the best of both worlds.

I think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922742442.0" user="suddenly_ponies" delta="False">
    <text>But the argument isn't "I won't tip", it's "I don't like it". I for one DO tip because of what you said, but I hate it and would support it being illegalized (the part about structuring someone's pay based on tipping)..</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
