<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27923711245.0" user="commandrix" delta="False">
    <text>I see tips for people like waiters and taxi cab drivers as being the same as paying a freelancer to do a job for you. It's an incentive for that person to actually be productive. Last time I took a taxi cab, I had a $20 bill in my hand and he knew that was what he was going to get regardless of how long it took him to get from the airport to the hotel, so he knew not to take any unnecessary "detours". And not that long ago, I went out to eat with a group of friends and a couple of them weren't getting that food. Long story short, the kitchen hadn't gotten their order and they ended up putting the food into some takeout boxes to take home. Not only did they not have to pay the tab, but the waiter didn't get the tip he would have gotten otherwise. Tip jars originally had "To Insure Promptness" written on them. If you were in a hurry, you could toss a few coins in that jar and the waitress would get to you first, and that phrase eventually got shortened into the word "tip". If the waitress knows you're a pretty good tipper, she's going to get around to you pretty quickly. That's just the way it is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
