<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922381684.0" user="TheMentalist10" delta="False">
    <text>Depending on where you are, you may have misunderstood the causes of tipping culture.

In, for example, the UK, tipping is supplementary: you're adding something to a not-great, but not-awful wage as a thanks for good service. It would be unusual *not* to tip something, but by no means is it a huge deal.

In the US, tipping is factored in as part of the wage. Employers pay less, as I understand it, on the basis that tips will make up the rest of an acceptable, 'living' wage. This is a pretty disgusting practice, but makes not tipping a serious statement of discontent. Think of the tip as part of the budget for the dinner, not as a little extra.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922396375.0" user="litle5o" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I have misunderstood it as I am from the UK, and can only comment on my time spent in the US and what I've heard. 

Still very confused on why tipping is factored as part of the wage? I'm all for helping people out and tipping if it's above and beyond astounding service, but I don't think that it's my responsibility to like I said, subsidise wait staff for their capitalistic employers? Surely this is an issue that needs to be taken up with government about living wage? I see tipping as adding to the problem rather than solving it. If we stopped tipping, surely employers would be forced to pay a higher wage as wait staff would either strike or walk out/get another job

Edit: I don't know if I'm being naive here to the work scheme of the US, just a genuine confusion for the situation  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922404890.0" user="Circle_Breaker" delta="False">
    <text>The general thought is that you pay for the food, then you pay for the service. 

No waiter would ever want the current system to change. Because as is most can make well above minimum wage, which is what they would be making if the government intervened. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922404893.0" user="TheMentalist10" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree: it's a pretty despicable, brutally Capitalistic idea, in my opinion. It comes, I suppose, in part from a sense of encouraging people to earn their pay. One of those wonderful delusions of 'if you work real hard, you could become a millionaire on your tips alone, kid!' which has never (and will never) come to fruition.

In practice, it's just exploitation, and—again, *in my opinion*,—damages the whole service relationship as there's a pretty explicit sense of pretence. I think it undermines good service *for its own sake*.

This extract from [an Esquire article](http://www.esquire.com/food-drink/restaurants/a23132/why-tipping-should-be-illegal-15603180/) is quite pertinent:

&amp;gt;You are not technically stealing if you don't tip the customary 15 to 20 percent, but that's probably the best that can be said of you. The tip you pay is a sort of wage: federal law allows tips to be used to make up the difference between a server's salary and minimum wage, meaning they can make as little as £1.28 ($2) to £1.93 ($3) per hour from their restaurant employer. Tips are absolutely depended upon to make up the shortfall.

When you leave a bad tip, you are docking a person's wages. This may either be because you're confused about what's expected or because you're an asshole, and you really believe that your sea bass arriving lukewarm is justly punishable by making it a little harder for the guy who brought it to you to pay his rent.

In terms of changing your view, I think not-liking tipping is fair enough. But, in the US, at least it's something I feel you're morally obliged to take part in.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
