<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922614747.0" user="jayman419" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it only the people waiting your table that gets your ire? Is it because you think all they do is carry a plate from the kitchen window to your table, discounting all the other little things they do to make your dining experience more enjoyable?

What about taxi drivers, delivery drivers, the kid who brings your newspaper, room service, bellhops, concierges, hairdressers, masseuses, bartenders, housekeepers, shoe shiners, coat checkers, babysitters, movers, the sommelier, the list goes on and on. What about all of those people?

Because most of those people aren't *taxed* on their tips. Maybe pizza drivers pay taxes on expected tips. But for table wait staff, it doesn't matter what they make per hour. Even in states where they are paid more than $2.80 an hour they are still taxed at a minimum rate based on their receipts in a given shift.

And they're not union workers. They're "at will" employees in most states. Even if they did organize a strike, and the restaurant didn't just fire them all and hire new "at will" employees... it's not just a matter of paying them more money (increasing the cost of food, by the way) .. it's a matter of changing the tax laws at a federal level. You can't do that with a strike. Add the new mandatory health coverage that's kicked in recently and most waitresses don't even get a paycheck. They get a receipt for (barely) covering their expenses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922800717.0" user="litle5o" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just wait staff, it's tipping in general. Those waiting my table where an example of my view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922839700.0" user="jayman419" delta="False">
    <text>But they're probably the worst example for the situations you've described, since they don't have a union to protect their jobs and have to pay mandatory taxes on an expected level of tips. (Bartenders may have to declare their tips after every shift, too. I'm not sure on that.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922845359.0" user="litle5o" delta="False">
    <text>See, I was asking if a union strike or walk would be plausible and effective to help the situation. So rather than it being a bad example; it was probably the only example I could give, so I could get a reasonable answer. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
