<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922550858.0" user="cold08" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant

You're paying for the service through the tip. That's why you pay the same for the food whether you get take out or someone waits on you. A tip is a service up charge, not a donation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922743750.0" user="suddenly_ponies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A tip is a service up charge, not a donation.

Service is part of the job and tips should have no bearing on it. It's a donation. Charity for someone who's wages are screwed over by bad laws and policies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922797477.0" user="cold08" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so let's say I buy a laptop. Now I can pay extra money to have it set up for me, or I can take it home and do it myself for free. You can insist that the setup should be part of the cost of the laptop all you want but it isn't. You wouldn't call paying for that service charity for the company that sold you the laptop would you?

What confuses people is that since you're legally allowed not to pay it, it's not a legitimate charge, but since I don't get a discount for take out when I choose to serve myself, the cost of the service is not included in the food, therefore you have to pay extra for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922827691.0" user="suddenly_ponies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You wouldn't call paying for that service charity for the company that sold you the laptop would you?

Nope. I would call that paying for extra service. But this analogy doesn't work for service in restaurants. The people in a restaurant SHOULD be polite, quick, and accurate. That's what I pay for when I go there because anything less would be sub-standard.

What we're doing is paying them extra to meet a low bar that they should be meeting as a matter of course. To use your analogy, it would be like going to a store where the service of setting up your laptop is advertised as a free benefit, but if you don't pay an extra tip or service change when getting this "free benefit" you are considered rude and hated on.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
