<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922677318.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>The thing I think you're not accounting for is that restaurants set their prices with the cost of an average tip in mind. If we abolish tipping, that same amount would just be added to the cost of the meal. Tipping simply gives you the freedom to pay a little more or a little less based on your satisfaction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922745405.0" user="suddenly_ponies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; f we abolish tipping, that same amount would just be added to the cost of the meal. 

Good. Let's do it now. Today. Yesterday even. The hassle and awkwardness of tipping is a barrier to authentic good service and should be abolished.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922936645.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>How is it a barrier to authentic good service? A tip is a way of commenting with your wallet on the quality of service. It allows you to give feedback that matters because it affects the server's and restaurant's bottom line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27923238898.0" user="suddenly_ponies" delta="False">
    <text>If they believe they won't get a good tip anyway (restaurant is too busy, they judge that you can't/won't tip), they have no reason to treat you well. Also, I don't believe service with the intent of begging for tips is authentic.

&amp;gt; It allows you to give feedback that matters because it affects the server's and restaurant's bottom line.

So does repeat business or never coming back or complaining/praising to management. Tips are a waste of time and largely end up only being a negative thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
