<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922608301.0" user="myshieldsforargus" delta="False">
    <text>A tip allows customers to directly provide feedback to service staff about their quality of service.

then by laws of natural selection, servers who are bad will not earn enough and will be competed out of business, they will go look for some other jobs where they can perform better, and they will naturally gravitate towards jobs where they are better at.

customers are best to provide this feedback, because they are the ones receiving service.

This only works, of course, when customers actually have the balls to not tip. Modern US customers are so spineless they would rather tip a bad server than to confront them and tell them about how bad they are. Also the fact that they always get tipped resulted in a sense of entitlement. If people only tip when service is good or exceptional, and refuse to tip when service is bad, servers will learn real fast to increase their quality of service, or quit.

so the problem is not of tipping, but of modern american cowardice.

tipping is allowing the free market mechanism to work on the servers market at full force, and free market is the best at allocating resources, in this case, allocating good servers to server positions.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27923245236.0" user="ThingsIWishICouldSay" delta="False">
    <text>Do a google search for 'study on tipping' and find one single study that doesn't find young, attractive, white, women are apparently the best at customer service. Apparently young, attractive, black, women need to work on their customer service skills so they can make the natural selection cut.  

Tips as a means for reflecting customer service is ridiculously overstated. Almost everybody has a base calculation they start from and tweak a few percentage points when service is really bad or really good.  

Let's take a look at the bad that comes with all this good service level correction:  

•Racism- minorities consistently get tipped less  
•Servers ignoring small tables to work tips on big tables  
•Sexual flirting to bolster tips (check out the 'touch his arm' technique)  
•Sexism- Men earn less than women  
•It allows employers to avoid paying their waitstaff through normal channels and shifts the burden to the customer  
•Taxation is a mess of approximation where those who make the least in tips pay the most in taxes and those who make the most pay the least  
•Customers face social obligations to pay more for their meal if they are a 'good person who tips well'  
•All the fights and theft issues over cash being left out on tables and determining who gets a cut  


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27923939335.0" user="myshieldsforargus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and find one single study that doesn't find young, attractive, white, women are apparently the best at customer service.

if they are getting more money, then i will argue that they are providing a better service.

if a patron would rather be served by a young attractive white women, then why shouldn't they be paid more?

&amp;gt;minorities consistently get tipped less

perhaps because minorities need to work on customer service? by the way, asian females get more tip than whites, and asians are minority too.

&amp;gt;Servers ignoring small tables to work tips on big tables

well, then the smaller tables will need to increase the tips to attract better servers

&amp;gt;Sexual flirting to bolster tips

why is this wrong?

&amp;gt;Men earn less than women

if women earn more, then i will argue that women provide better service, why else would people pay them more?

&amp;gt;It allows employers to avoid paying their waitstaff through normal channels and shifts the burden to the customer

all the burden is on the customers, anyway, since all the expenses paid by the employers, including wages, come from sales which is paid by customers, so you are only just shuffling it around, there is no actual change

&amp;gt;Taxation is a mess of approximation 

this is a problem of the state trying to take money from people who earn their livings by working. it can not be used to suggest that tipping is bad.

&amp;gt;Customers face social obligations to pay more for their meal

or customers can grow some balls and not do something they otherwise wouldn't want to do. surely you can not blame tipping for a bad consequence of social mechanism and not tipping itself

&amp;gt;All the fights and theft issues over cash being left out on tables and determining who gets a cut 

this problem could easily be solved by the employer making clear rules on the issue

none of your problems are actual problems on tipping, it is either a problem of something else, or a mistaken belief that everybody should be paid the exactly same amount all the time, i.e. anti-free market socialist view. the free market is never sexist nor racist, it's only in trying to enforce equality of outcome is the problems of racism and sexism exacerbated 


</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
