<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208127102.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fwvwe/cmv_if_there_is_nothing_we_can_do_about_climate/">
    <title>CMV: If there is nothing we can do about climate change we should destigmatize suicide as soon as possible</title>
    <original_poster>EndOfTheLine00</original_poster>
    <original_post>As threads like [this](https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/3fqtyj/speed_of_glacier_retreat_worldwide_historically/) show, the world is on a slow motion path to oblivion. Notice how all discussions about what can be done all boil down to "Nothing. Enjoy your life". Maybe some people can take solace in that but not all. Even climate scientists [are showing signs of PTSD (and I think I might be as well)](http://www.esquire.com/news-politics/a36228/ballad-of-the-sad-climatologists-0815/).

Society should encourage the use of voluntary euthanasia. Aggresively campaign to tell people that anyone who chooses it is NOT a coward, is NOT selfish and they should NOT be mourned. In fact, they should be celebrated, because they have either transcended their base desire for survival (or never had it in the first place) and have made a decision that not only benefits them but the world at large as well.

It is sick how people are forced to keep playing the game of life even though they have already lost. People are brought into this world by the surpremely selfish desires of their parents who are either completely oblivious to the fact that their children will die drowning in their blood of the bodily fluids of their violators cursing their parents' name while the latter will likely sleep soundly in their graves or because they want to make their own "tribe" to fight in the ashes convinced of their own superiority. The children never had a choice. If any of them did and could be conscious enough to understand it, no one would be borne.

I don't see the point in living in a post collapse world. I hate exercising. Most people I know are incapable of having a conversation that doesn't involve sports, travel or the weather and I can only assume the number will grow as access to the Internet collapses. The thought of having to grow my own food makes me sick, let alone the thought that 12 hours of my day will have to be spent there. Probably until my back gives out and I'm left to die by the outside "community" that took me in before they realized I was "weird" and was looking for an excuse to murder me.

I don't want to learn self defense, I don't want to fight. I want to live in a world where specific people exist to protect me and as long as I don't do anything stupid, they won't hurt me. I want to live the rest of my life doing what I am told and being rewarded for it. I don't want to become a leader, I don't want to be responsible for people's well being. I never had any sort of relationship and perhaps it's for the best because if I did have a family during the collapse, I don't know what I would do.

More people like me must exist. We must help them.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27923126079.0" user="Life0fRiley" delta="False">
    <text>We should keep it stigmatized because in a post collapsed world, you guys are great for doing the farming for us who want to live and enjoy the world. Since social stigma is the thing keeping you alive, we can just pressure you as a society to do the grunt work.  We can continue to use your service till you actually commit to taking your own life. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27923148657.0" user="EndOfTheLine00" delta="False">
    <text>In an overpopulated collapsing Earth you need MORE people? Maybe I have the ratios mixed up but isn't the sort of farming that would be possible have very low yields thus making it mostly for your benefit? A TON of what we grow is incredibly reliant on herbicides and pesticides, and if you want to grow organic, you get FAR less food for FAR more work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27923170415.0" user="Life0fRiley" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's the thing. You need enough people to work.  Let's say you produce enough for you and for another .1 of a person. That means we need 9 people producing the same to support 11. That one person can do something else. 

My ideology is based on a caste system were the people who cant defend themselves and want to commit suicide will do work to benefit other people.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
