<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209099690.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ghqcq/cmv_the_tactics_used_at_the_bernie_sanders_rally/">
    <title>CMV: The tactics used at the Bernie Sanders rally interruption did not consider the primary and most effective mechanism of enacting change via direct action</title>
    <original_poster>uoaei</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people today don't understand how protest and action actually lead to change. 

It doesn't work by shouting down the person who has the power to do things about it until they relent to the power moves and aggressive posturing. It succeeds when the minds of the general populace are changed at a high rate toward the verbalized cause. Through the witnessing of such actions and protests, suddenly the people turn their gaze toward those in power, who feel the stare of everyone looking at them, oppressing them with genuine and widespread mistrust of their stances. The people display a collective "what are you going to do about it now?" and the power of those at the top is actually threatened by the people who support them from below. 

This is the moment when those in the comfortable seat of power relent, and no sooner. 

It is public shaming via conversion, not force. Those at the top hate to be hated by the majority: it translates to mutiny. 

And I don't mean conversion from 'against' to 'with' the movement. Instead, I mean conversion from 'passive' to 'active'. Calling an entire crowd of 15000+ people "racists" does not change a people's minds, it puts them on the defensive. This is basic psychology. It helps no one when it's one voice at a time that's angry, it helps a lot when everyone's angry at the same person, at the same time. The boos at the rally in question did not start en masse until the entire crowd felt attacked by the name-calling (why does everyone overlook this? Why have absolutely none of the thoughtpieces I've read so far reference this blatant and obvious fact?). The people in the crowd were not against the movement to begin with, and they still aren't. You can hear the cheers yourself. 

I understand these people are not representative of the entire movement. This is not an attack on the movement in general (which I am a supporter of, though not an active player due to my expatriation), this is a critique of a particular tactic that I think ignores medium- and long-term consequences of short-term actions. Especially shrieking "WE ARE REASONABLE!!!!" quite unreasonably and name-calling those from whom you demand respect and silence.

P.S. Please direct me somewhere I can have an intellectual discussion about this, without it being interjected with people agreeing with me simply because they're racist and have their own agenda to push, running their mouths and distracting the conversation from my original points. That keeps happening to me and it delegitimates my statements when they are associated with such vitriol.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27932423737.0" user="iGotlove" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Many people today don't understand how protest and action actually lead to change. It doesn't work by shouting down the person who has the power to do things about it until they relent to the power moves and aggressive posturing.

Are you sure about that? The Montgomery Bus Protests worked by shutting down the bus system in the city causing so much disruption that officials finally had to acknowledge the protest and the protesters' demands. So historically, shouting down people in power until they relent *has* worked. 

We shall see if BLM continue to shut down candidate rallies, and more than just Sanders rallies. Currently that is their stated plan. BLM actually released a press release in conjunction with their protest at Sanders' rally, which is very disappointing to me that news outlets are not talking about it, but it's linked [here](http://www.dailykos.com/story/2015/08/08/1410064/-Bernie-Sanders-Interrupted-by-Black-Lives-Matter-Again), and they state their purpose is specifically to stop business as usual, because how can business as usual continue while black people are being killed left and right? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932441248.0" user="uoaei" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The Montgomery Bus Protests worked by shutting down the bus system in the city causing so much disruption that officials finally had to acknowledge the protest and the protesters' demands.

That only further proves my point, in my opinion. The people, who relied on the bus system to maintain their livelihood and day-to-day activities, had become severely inconvenienced. *The eyes of the people were focused on those who had the power to do something about resolving this conflict.* They could have done it violently, which would have pushed things to further extremes, or they could have done it nonviolently, which happened when they acknowledged the protestors' demands. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932448433.0" user="iGotlove" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The people, who relied on the bus system to maintain their livelihood and day-to-day activities, had become severely inconvenienced. The eyes of the people were focused on those who had the power to do something about resolving this conflict.

I don't see the difference. That's what the rally protesters were trying to accomplish as well. They aren't done yet. According to them they're going to keep doing this at every rally for every candidate because "business as usually cannot go on while black lives are being lost." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932459255.0" user="uoaei" delta="False">
    <text>I thought Sanders handled the conflict rather well. He asked to speak and he was denied that right, so he said

&amp;gt;If this is your attitude I have nothing more to say to you

and stood by while they finished. Are you saying that the people were engendered to the cause when this happened? Because if so, the sentiment might have been overshadowed by the rather personal attack of being called "white supremacists."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932466706.0" user="iGotlove" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are you saying that the people were engendered to the cause when this happened?

No, I'm just saying that you can't say this type of protest never works. It has in the past. I'm sure many people who needed the bus in Montgomery were also pissed and the sit in did not make them sympathetic with the civil rights protesters but instead made them hostile to the protest. Regardless, it worked eventually. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932493638.0" user="uoaei" delta="False">
    <text>This is a good counterexample. The comment about the peoples' initial sentiments toward the protestors, I mean. I still don't see it as enough to give credence to the actions of the protestors, or that it is parallel enough to the topic at hand. One is actively violent (verbally, at least), and one is nonviolent altogether.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
