<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209099690.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ghqcq/cmv_the_tactics_used_at_the_bernie_sanders_rally/">
    <title>CMV: The tactics used at the Bernie Sanders rally interruption did not consider the primary and most effective mechanism of enacting change via direct action</title>
    <original_poster>uoaei</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people today don't understand how protest and action actually lead to change. 

It doesn't work by shouting down the person who has the power to do things about it until they relent to the power moves and aggressive posturing. It succeeds when the minds of the general populace are changed at a high rate toward the verbalized cause. Through the witnessing of such actions and protests, suddenly the people turn their gaze toward those in power, who feel the stare of everyone looking at them, oppressing them with genuine and widespread mistrust of their stances. The people display a collective "what are you going to do about it now?" and the power of those at the top is actually threatened by the people who support them from below. 

This is the moment when those in the comfortable seat of power relent, and no sooner. 

It is public shaming via conversion, not force. Those at the top hate to be hated by the majority: it translates to mutiny. 

And I don't mean conversion from 'against' to 'with' the movement. Instead, I mean conversion from 'passive' to 'active'. Calling an entire crowd of 15000+ people "racists" does not change a people's minds, it puts them on the defensive. This is basic psychology. It helps no one when it's one voice at a time that's angry, it helps a lot when everyone's angry at the same person, at the same time. The boos at the rally in question did not start en masse until the entire crowd felt attacked by the name-calling (why does everyone overlook this? Why have absolutely none of the thoughtpieces I've read so far reference this blatant and obvious fact?). The people in the crowd were not against the movement to begin with, and they still aren't. You can hear the cheers yourself. 

I understand these people are not representative of the entire movement. This is not an attack on the movement in general (which I am a supporter of, though not an active player due to my expatriation), this is a critique of a particular tactic that I think ignores medium- and long-term consequences of short-term actions. Especially shrieking "WE ARE REASONABLE!!!!" quite unreasonably and name-calling those from whom you demand respect and silence.

P.S. Please direct me somewhere I can have an intellectual discussion about this, without it being interjected with people agreeing with me simply because they're racist and have their own agenda to push, running their mouths and distracting the conversation from my original points. That keeps happening to me and it delegitimates my statements when they are associated with such vitriol.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27933426057.0" user="barbadosslim" delta="False">
    <text>The people who oppose this were never going to agree anyway.  They need to be socially pressured into progress.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
