<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209151241.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3giu4p/cmv_i_have_no_sympathy_towards_violent_criminals/">
    <title>CMV: I have no sympathy towards violent criminals at the point of crime</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can never understand people when they lament about how they feel sorry for someone who just commited a violent crime.

I understand being sympathetic towards a non-violent thief who might be destitute, or a murderer who has done his time and apologized.

But someone who has just done a horrible act of violence towards another person (and hasn't repented yet) doesn't deserve sympathy from anyone, unless they genuinely believe he/she is innocent, or committed the crime in self-defense.

One argument people make is that the guilty crime was committed "in the heat of moment". I see this often being used to defend road ragers and drunk wife-beaters. I can't agree with this argument because it unfairly takes responsibility away from the criminal. If we left every criminal go easy because the crimes were "emotional" or "spur of the moment", we'd have a lot of unstable people out on the streets ready go to off at any moment and hurt others.

Another argument I hear is that the criminal was a "victim of the circumstances", i.e. he was poor or grew up in a dysfunctional family. This is a totally reasonable argument if the crime is non-violent, but being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up. Anyone who makes a conscious choice to hurt someone physically is simply an asshole.

I oppose the death penalty and am in favor of restorative prison reform, so I hear people giving these criminals moral slack (at more than just a legal or health-based level) all the time, and it drives me crazy. But I want to see the POV they are coming from, so please try to CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27932912550.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>If you think that the criminal justice system is overly harsh in punishing criminals, you might feel bad for the person who will have to endure a very harsh punishment.

So for instance, the US has incredibly draconian laws in relation to possession of child pornography.  Someone who is caught possessing child porn, but who has not assaulted any children, is likely to spend a decade or more in prison, and the rest of their life with the modern equivalent of a scarlet letter in the form of sex offender registration.

If you feel that punishment is overly harsh, you might feel sympathy for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932947631.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>I think some laws are unjust, that doesn't mean I feel any kind of respect towards unrepentant and violent deviants. And for me, if I don't have any respect for someone, I can't and won't sympathize with them.

I think they deserve to have a second chance and a fair shake at forgiveness. This sentiment is not out of sympathy for the criminals, but out of a sense of justice.

For these people, sympathy and respect must be earned. If they repent and admit that their actions hurt others, then maybe I can begin to see eye-to-eye with these people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
