<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41052868674.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just the companies who take partial measures. If the only path to avoiding climate change is the drastic approach you propose, then it's safe to say that most of humanity is also content to take partial measures. Consider that, today, people are still buying things, driving things, and creating things at their jobs despite being told of the oncoming impact already.

Frankly, it's wishful thinking to conjure up a scene where humanity stops producing and just waits for a few decades for Mother Earth to catch her breath. Instead, we are an ingenuitive species who will innovate to find a way to live with partial measures until we HAVE to apply more drastic ones.

We'll donate money to charities to help people whose lives are affected by warmer temperatures, more destructive storms, and rising coastal waters, while those who are not directly impacted (and there are many) will continue with their partial measures unless and until they are impacted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052948815.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>I agree it's wishful thinking, however all we have right now is false hope. It's like going to get your chakras realigned to cure your cancer rather than take direct action with chemo, and once the cancer has spread far enough, chemo won't even help.

The West doesn't really realize (or admit?) that the people who's lives are being affect by warmer temperatures are the ones that provide/support our cushy western life. We import our goods for cheap from the Global South, so once those are gone our life will change drastically, and at that point it's wishful thinking to think we can adapt overnight.

It's very unlikely the entire human race will go extinct, however it's incredibly likely the global south will be largely impacted over the next decades, while the West will be impacted by their decline in productivity. 

Also climate change is here. We've had so many forest fires and floods/hurricanes in the last 10 years that are so unnatural, yet we think it's a thing in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052990922.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that the West doesn't realize/admit it. There will be adjustments to business strategies (locations for manufacturing, technologies to develop, etc) to lessen the impact.

Consider that the impact from climate change that you cite (forest fires, floods), have not greatly affected the daily lives of most humans on the planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053007420.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Consider that the impact from climate change that you cite (forest fires, floods), have not greatly affected the daily lives of most humans on the planet.

This is anecdotal but I live on the west coast where forest fires have causes mass evacuations of larger towns in the area, and covering my city in smoke for the larger part of Summer. It pales in comparison to what the Global South deals with, you are totally right, but it's catching up to us.  


Despite this, people ignore it because we believe we are making the right choices with recycling, buying solar panels for our homes, but it's not enough. We need to push for radical government change, which we refuse to do because $$$.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053166326.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>Per the link, there were about 400,000 evacuations per year from 2017-2019 major fires in CA. That's 1% of the CA population, which while sizable, is still too small to be considered an issue the average Californian needs to think about everyday.

https://escholarship.org/content/qt5w85z07g/qt5w85z07g\_noSplash\_a1016d9a321138365ab7e2311309a373.pdf?t=q7c4sj

As to your overall case, don't let the perfect be the enemy of the good. Partial measures may be worse than full measures, but they are not worse than ignoring the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41060819525.0" user="DreamingSilverDreams" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Partial measures may be worse than full measures, but they are not worse than ignoring the problem.

This is not assured, though. According to the latest data our predictions are not entirely correct. For example, Europe is warming faster than predicted. The scale and destructiveness of extreme weather events are much higher than expected.

It may very well be that partial measures are as effective as doing nothing and ignoring the problem. You can't stop a flood with just one sandbag.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41092317979.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>That is Consequentialism. Sure, knowing what has happened and looking back  is easy. But when you don't know if a flood or a trickle is coming, bringing a sandbag is a demonstrably better risk mitigation strategy than bringing nothing at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053189497.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>This is objectively false and shows your privilege. So much of the world has already been impacted and it's typically poor people who are taking the brunt of it. Look at Pakistan right now. The megacorporation farms are basically thriving because of the flooding completely knocking working class farmers out of the economy. That's one example of many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053517696.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>The daily lives of most humans on the planet have not yet been greatly impacted by global warming. Consider the planet has 7,000,000,000 people.

That's not to say (and I didn't say) that millions aren't impacted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41054506554.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it has, dude. Here are are a few examples among many, big and small:

\- Natural disasters have gone up from roughly 150 per year in the 80s to roughly 400 per year in the last decade.

Over 20 million people have been displaced by natural disasters.

\- AC bills have gone up. 

\- Roughly 40% of the US experienced moderate-to-severe droughts in 2021 alone.

\- Instances of record temperature highs are now doubled the instances of temperature lows. To compare, the ratio was roughly 1.1 to 1 in the 80s

\- The increase of temperature is a breeding ground for viral diseases. And, well, look around. 

\- 2% of mammal animal species have gone extinct since 1900, compared to less than 0.5% in the previous few centuries.

And most of these pertain to only the US alone. The countries stuck in the danger zone, largely central American, African, and South Asian countries, have been hit even worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41092356849.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>Your first point I acknowledged, and I agree: millions have been impacted by natural disasters induced by climate change. As you will agree, **this is a small % of humanity** (but still of course worthy of fighting for!)

As I said before, and which induced your swipe at my privilege, I repeat: 

*Consider that the impact from climate change that you cite (forest fires, floods), have not greatly affected the daily lives of most humans on the planet.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41092413196.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>I gave only a few examples. Most people have been affected in some way. Temperatures are way up across the board. So are many other things. I literally study this lmao. If you can find any climate scientist who agrees with your assessment I would be absolutely stunned. What you are claiming is not even remotely accepted in the climate science community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41092665118.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>If you study societal impact of climate change, by all means please share your data. I have not seen anything from you that contradicts my argument that  


*...the impact from climate change that you cite (forest fires, floods), have not greatly affected the daily lives of most humans on the planet.*

And while it's not possible for me to prove the negative position I took, I can show that over the past 40 years, the % of Americans who have died from heat-related illnesses is about 0.0003%. Bad, of course, but not remotely impacting the daily lives of most humans in this country.

https://www.epa.gov/climate-indicators/climate-change-indicators-heat-related-deaths</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41092695707.0" user="ElizaThornberry4" delta="False">
    <text>Even if I accepted a premise that it is not affecting the "daily lives" of most people (wrong), it's a ridiculous premise. Basically nothing greatly affects the "daily lives" of "most people" in the way you are categorizing that. That's true of cancer, suicide, poverty, fascism, accidents, COVID, etc. It's an extremely bizarre barometer by which to evaluate something.

Also, heat death is only one extreme measure. This doesn't account for water shortages that affect people in lesser but still notable ways, its affect on crop prices, heat stroke that results in hospitalization, heat stroke that forces people to miss work, increase of disease and mosquitos, reduction of fish populations, the massive economic losses as a consequence of all this, and so on. And that's ONLY for droughts. Not even the many other major consequences of climate change.

And furthermore, .0003 is a massive number in the aggregate. For instance, there were 33.9 million global commercial flights in 2019. If .0003 of them crashed, that would amount to 10,700 crashes. Imagine the scale of that. We'd call that a disastrous situation that would need to be tackled immediately. Airports basically come to a hault if there's even one. Imagine if there was one every three days.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41093055413.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>1. Whether you think my claim is bizarre or not is immaterial to this discussion. It was you, in fact, who engaged first, saying my 'bizarre' claim was objectively false and was an error attributable to my privilege. That sort of belies your belief that the metric in my claim is 'bizarre'. I would venture that most people concur that measuring the degree to which a phenomenon impacts the lives of humans is an extremely important metric. For example, COVID's impact on humanity was far greater than that of the seasonal flu based on this same metric.
2. I can continue providing data on each of these if you lack the sources. Food prices in real terms have been stable since the 1960s, with the uptick in the past 1-2 years aligned with inflation.

[https://www.fao.org/worldfoodsituation/foodpricesindex/en/](https://www.fao.org/worldfoodsituation/foodpricesindex/en/)

Malaria cases are down 25% since 2000.

[https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SH.MLR.INCD.P3](https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SH.MLR.INCD.P3)

Heatstroke-related hospitalizations impact 0.0002% of US population in 2020.

[https://www.epa.gov/climate-indicators/heat-related-illnesses](https://www.epa.gov/climate-indicators/heat-related-illnesses)

3. I'm a little bit surprised that you say you work in climate studies after that pretty sizable math error of yours! Also, please remember that my claim was that...

*...impact from climate change that you cite (forest fires, floods), have not greatly affected the daily lives of most humans on the planet.*

This is not the same as claiming that the impact from climate change is not large and getting larger, nor that we are 'safe' to sit on our laurels instead of doing something to reverse the on-going trends. Clearly millions of lives impacted is a tragedy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053451575.0" user="htiafon" delta="False">
    <text>...yet. when Miami is underwater, you might feel differently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053568204.0" user="Bmaj13" delta="False">
    <text>Feel differently? I feel we need to act now. And corporations taking steps to address their carbon footprints is a societal good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
