<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41055847990.0" user="this-is-very" delta="False">
    <text>Why should we not trust capitalism when it has worked so well? A vacuum cleaner today is a massively improved product that needs fewer materials to be made, less electricity to do the same job, can last longer compared to models decades ago. It is capitalism that’s most efficient at cutting costs. Cutting costs is the way to sustainability. Artificially crippling the economy isn’t something the people will accept, ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41055965349.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, human ingenuity caused all of those things; all capitalism did was find the cheapest ways to make it and made too many of them.

Vacuum cleaners in the 1950's lasted a very long time, had replaceable parts, repair shops, and it was unlikely you'd throw it out after 5 years of use.

Vacuum cleaners that don't require constant replacing are upwards of $400, so most people are buying the cheap ones that break often.

All capitalism did was cheapen the  costs of the parts by outsourcing the labour to other countries, then importing the vacuum cleaners to the west, pocketing most of the savings.

Capitalism does nothing to help the environment. It isn't profitable to cut down on emissions by lowering the output rate. It isn't profitable to forego your car manufacturing plant to focus on trains and busses.

All capitalism does is grow, and try to grow infinitely on a finite planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41058140831.0" user="this-is-very" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Vacuum cleaners that don't require constant replacing are upwards of $400, so most people are buying the cheap ones that break often.

I bought one for less than $100 recently. The engine it has gets a 10 year guarantee. All parts are easily replaceable. I have no idea where you get your vacuum cleaners, but you're wrong.

&amp;gt;Capitalism does nothing to help the environment. It isn't profitable to cut down on emissions by lowering the output rate.

Who said capitalism is all about profits? Where does this myth come from? Capitalism is about what people want. Yes, they do want to enrich themselves often, but other than that capitalism reflects the people as they are. It's a liberal system, it's the people you don't like. Change what people think, and they will be better for environment under capitalism, there is no better alternative to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41058940371.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>“Who said capitalism is all about profits?”

It’s literally in the name, “capital”ism. It’s about gaining capital and growing that capital in any means necessary. If someone doesn’t grow under capitalism someone else will take their capital for them. It’s a ruthless system based around exploitation and growth which is incompatible with how the earth works because infinite growth is impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41060866577.0" user="AloysiusC" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, human ingenuity caused all of those things

Which capitalism directly incentivizes. 

&amp;gt; all capitalism did was find the cheapest ways to make it and made too many of them.

Finding cheaper ways of doing something is what it means to be efficient. That's a good thing. And making too many makes no sense. Nobody makes more than they can sell on purpose. 

&amp;gt;All capitalism does is grow, and try to grow infinitely on a finite planet.

You seem to subscribe to the shrinking market fallacy. Curiously, that's what Hitler believed too and he was wrong too. We can indeed keep growing indefinitely. Growing is what we do by our very nature. Certain resources being finite in a specific location don't change that. Time and time again people have to learn this lesson.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41061838419.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"Finding cheaper ways of doing something is what it means to be efficient. That's a good thing. And making too many makes no sense. Nobody makes more than they can sell on purpose."

It really isn't, though. The only reason we've found cheaper ways to do things is by outsourcing all of our manufacturing and resources to other countries. The fact that it's cheaper to import avocados to california than eat the ones grown in california is ridiculous, and that's capitalism at work.

You have fruit that is grown in africa then shipped to china to be packaged in to smaller packages to be shipped to america to save money. Did you ever think maybe we shouldn't be paying 0.99 for a bunch of bananas shipped halfway around the world? It's called exploitation. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;"Curiously, that's what Hitler believed too and he was wrong too. "

Comparing what I'm saying to Hitler is just insulting. 

I'm calling it "Degrowth" which is probably the same as the shrinking market "fallacy" you speak of. How can we grow indefinitely on a finite planet? How can we grow our population and what we consume on a planet with finite resources? We can't. It's physically impossible at some point. We've already passed peak oil, we've fucked up the biodiversity of so much land due to overfarming and overgrazing. To deny any of this is ignorance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41072252201.0" user="AloysiusC" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It really isn't, though.

Come on. Cheaper means more cost *efficient*. I.e. it's more efficient. 

&amp;gt;The only reason we've found cheaper ways to do things is by outsourcing all of our manufacturing and resources to other countries.

No. That's just one way. Things have also gotten cheaper through efficiency. eg: airliners are more fule *efficient* which makes travelling is cheaper. Scaling production is another way. Automation etc. There's plenty of incentive to make things cheaper and so businesses try to do it wherever they can. Saying it's all just because of cheap labor is ridiculously badly informed. 

&amp;gt;Did you ever think maybe we shouldn't be paying 0.99 for a bunch of bananas shipped halfway around the world? It's called exploitation. 

Would you rather we didn't buy their goods? Do you think that would improve their situation? 

&amp;gt;Comparing what I'm saying to Hitler is just insulting. 

I didn't mean to upset you. It's not just you btw. Many people have this belief. It's one of the hardest dying myths. 

&amp;gt;How can we grow indefinitely on a finite planet?

Your choice of words gives you one (of multiple) answers: One can find resources outside of this planet. Seems absurd? No. It's mostly a cost issue at this point. And that also answers what happens when finite resources start to get low. They don't disappear, it just becomes increasingly expensive to mine them. At some point it's cheaper to find an alternative or find them elsewhere. 

And that's not including paradigm shifts. Hitler's view for example was that empires would require natural resources to sustain themselves and countries like Germany that had too few natural resources but rely modern industry would be overtaken by countries that have those resources and can eventually develop their own modern industry. Turns out he had no clue what free trade would do - computer industry, revolutionary technological development, new markets. 

And that's the point. We don't know what new things will be developed and paradigm shifts will occur. It's extremely counterproductive to deliberately hinder the potential for such things simply because people like you haven't learned the basics and don't consider opportunity cost. Do you even know what that means? 

&amp;gt;How can we grow our population and what we consume on a planet with finite resources?

This planet can sustain *many* more people than we have now. And population growth in principal is a very good thing if you have cheap energy and (the potential for) prosperity. People are the single most valuable resource. 

&amp;gt;We can't. It's physically impossible at some point.

Actually earth can probably sustain trillions of people. At least theoretically. And I don't mean packed like sardines. Even with relative comfort and space. 

&amp;gt;We've already passed peak oil

Lol. We've been "passing peak oil" for I think over a century already now. It's just getting ridiculous at this point. Did you even know that one can synthesize oil? It's just, guess what, expensive relative to digging it up at this time. 

&amp;gt;To deny any of this is ignorance.

Nothing about this exchange suggests I'm any more ignorant than you. I've heard all of your points before many times. They're little more than ideology. That's why you're so upset. It's the point of the ideology to make you upset and turn you into a warrior that spreads the ideology further. You'll never stop being upset while on that path btw. Even if you get everything your ideology tells you to want, it'll make sure you keep being supplied with new threats and emergencies to try and tear down the system. 

And THAT is what is truly not sustainable. The poorer you make people the less they will care about anything but survival. You can warn somebody of the coming apocalypse as much as you want but if they don't have enough food to get through the day, you won't get them to join you. But if things are bad enough, you might just become the meal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
