<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41054353163.0" user="thinkitthrough83" delta="False">
    <text>Climate change is part of nature. You may have seen articles about Viking remains being revealed do to snow and ice melting off. That means that less then a thousand years ago that snow and ice was not there. One of the founding members of Greene peace which was not started as an environmental movement has a video in you tube explaining the science behind world wide weather patterns.
If you really care about doing better for the environment you need to look at all stages of production for the goods that you use and purchase.
No matter what companies do the climate will change and swing back and forth between hot, cold, wet and dry cycles. The earth goes through a lot of changes sometimes over short periods and sometimes over thousands of years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41054543676.0" user="Charlie-Wilbury" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The earth goes through a lot of changes sometimes over short periods and sometimes over thousands of years.

Sigh... yes it does. None of those periods included humans that burned fossil fuels. We're adding carbon to the atmosphere that is suppose to be locked inside the crust. 


https://scienceexchange.caltech.edu/topics/sustainability/evidence-climate-change

https://www.google.com/amp/s/climate.nasa.gov/evidence.amp

https://royalsociety.org/topics-policy/projects/climate-change-evidence-causes/basics-of-climate-change/


Please, seriously, educate yourself and stop spreading harming misinformation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41055628333.0" user="thinkitthrough83" delta="False">
    <text>Supposed to be? Nature does not work on supposed to be. Nor will I participate in spreading fear when there is still a lot we don't know and the technology to give us the data we need to make the best informed decisions is still being created and put into practice.

And I do actually read scientific articles but I also don't focus on one argument for or against issues. The human species has already undergone mass flooding events centuries before we were born.

No matter what we choose to believe nature loves to throw us curve balls.
 this theory but is interesting.
https://www.ancient-origins.net/history-important-events/comet-sparked-worldwide-flood-myth-009168

Another interesting article from Nasa
https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2915/the-atmosphere-getting-a-handle-on-carbon-dioxide/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41056383048.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>Did you even read your article from nasa?

First paragraph:

Earth’s atmosphere is resilient to many of the changes humans have imposed on it. But, says atmospheric scientist David Crisp of NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Pasadena, California, that **doesn’t necessarily mean that our society is.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41056550839.0" user="thinkitthrough83" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I did read the article and I also paid attention to the part about where the highest concentrations of carbon are. Frankly this was a surprise to me as I expected them to be higher over major cities like California NY and the main industrial areas of China and possibly India. I also noticed the bit where it could be at least a few hundred years before things become deadly to the human race. Hopefully in that time our population will have balanced out as a result of  research into better and safer birth control methods. Thus lessening our modern dependence on questionable energy methods. If not (barring a 100% natural disaster I.e. comet or major volcanic eruption)we will eventually end up either killing large numbers of people off in war as countries fight over power and resources or we will end up with having an extreme upsurge in disease that will make those of history look insignificant.
For now I plan on planting some corn next spring as last I heard it was very efficient at capturing carbon. There's some experiments I would like to try with the stalks and leaves as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
