<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41054476069.0" user="Charlie-Wilbury" delta="False">
    <text>I have one simple problem with this theory. Something is literally, infinitely better than nothing. Even a pittance  of effort by a large company to be more green can have so much more effect than me switching to electric vehicles myself. If they can greenwash the population into switching, that's great. I dont think I've seen anyone actually argue that will fix climate change entirely.

 Furthermore, scientists still exist. They are the reason we know what we know about the climate now. They will be the reason we know what we do in two decades. You can 'trick' a population into being more green but you can't trick scientists into seeing results that aren't there. Arguably, we are a far more educated society than ever. We're not going to listen to Chevrolet tell us they'll fix the climate. We're going to listen to what the scientists say about their plan.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
