<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41052937859.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>That makes me think that we need more capable society, not a less capable one. 

I don’t see how we could possibly decelerate our way out of climate change. As far as I can tell per capita, countries that are less advanced, produce more carbon at least at a given level of productivity. 

When we look at comparative efficiencies of styles of living, it’s usually that the more technologically advanced, we are the more capable we are of being climate, neutral, or negative. I think, given the fact that we’re already passed a certain level of carbon emission, what we need to do is build new technologies to ameliorate the effects of climate change. I don’t think running away from productivity or technology is gonna solve many problems. We need those things desperately to even notice that we’ve got these problems in the first place.

I don’t think a shrinking more agrarian style economy can support things like satellite driven climate studies. 

I don’t think that early agrarian living is more climate friendly in the long term — at least not, unless it’s accompanied by a massive drop in the population. And I don’t think I’m hearing you arguing for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052980820.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>"I don’t see how we could possibly decelerate our way out of climate change. As far as I can tell per capita, countries that are less advanced, produce more carbon at least at a given level of productivity."  


[Because we export our emissions to these countries.](https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2017/4/18/15331040/emissions-outsourcing-carbon-leakage)

Also we leverage [South America for lithium for batteries,](https://www.euronews.com/green/2022/02/01/south-america-s-lithium-fields-reveal-the-dark-side-of-our-electric-future) thus pushing up their carbon footprint to lower ours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053008884.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>No that’s not why. That can be a true phenomenon while it still being true that lower tech living is more carbon expensive. 

Consider what it takes to produce an hour of daylight equivalent light output at different levels of technological capability over time. 

Compare the energy consumed and carbon released in a wood fire, a candle, an incandescent lightbulb, and not the relatively recent led lightbulb. 

If we want *more* carbon efficiency, we need to keep going — while aiming at the right targets. We got into a bad state because we were too ignorant, not too knowledgeable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053035700.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>I can agree to parts of this. (Half delta?)

I agree that lower tech living is not the way to go. We need this tech, however we need this tech along with degrowth.

We need electric public transit, not a fleet of electric cars using a ton of resources to make new cars that turn over every 5-10 years.

We need sustainable multi-family dwellings, not sustainable single family homes that take up more space than needed for the amount of people we have.

I think it's pretty clear: if the whole world lived the lives the west did, [the earth wouldn't be able to sustain us.](http://awsassets.panda.org/downloads/wwf_eu_overshoot_day___living_beyond_nature_s_limits_web.pdf)

So can't it be both? Tech with degrowth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053101626.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt; I agree that lower tech living is not the way to go. We need this tech, however we need this tech along with degrowth.

Keep in mind, that if you had made this argument a few years ago, we would never have gotten the LED tech. 

And if we do it now, what solutions will we never get to?

- fusion?
- climate cooling tech?
- pandemic vaccines?
- asteroid steering for preventing impacts?

&amp;gt; We need electric public transit, not a fleet of electric cars using a ton of resources to make new cars that turn over every 5-10 years.

I mean… the alternative if corporations don’t participate isn’t transit it’s internal combustion. 

These are independent concerns. 


&amp;gt; I think it's pretty clear: if the whole world lived the lives the west did, the earth wouldn't be able to sustain us.

Unless we invent new solutions. 

&amp;gt; So can't it be both? Tech with degrowth?

I don’t see how. The growth of tech is fueled by economic growth. Part of “degrowth” is losing out on things like the JWST and all the discoveries it would bring. It means fewer climate satellites and fewer mars missions. Part of the less is less capability for solving hard problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052996509.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>"I don’t think that early agrarian living is more climate friendly in the long term — at least not, unless it’s accompanied by a massive drop in the population. And I don’t think I’m hearing you arguing for that."  


I'm not pushing for this so much as I'm pushing for a more radical change towards degrowth and lowering of the west's consumption.   


The best example I can think of is the [solarpunk movement.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solarpunk#)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052998205.0" user="WikiSummarizerBot" delta="False">
    <text>**[Solarpunk](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solarpunk#)** 
 
 &amp;gt;Solarpunk is a literary, artistic, and activist movement that envisions and works toward actualizing a sustainable future interconnected with nature and community. The "solar" represents solar energy as a renewable energy source and an optimistic vision of the future that rejects nihilism and climate doomerism, while the "punk" refers to the countercultural, post-capitalist, and decolonial enthusiasm for creating such a future.
 
^([ )[^(F.A.Q)](https://www.reddit.com/r/WikiSummarizer/wiki/index#wiki_f.a.q)^( | )[^(Opt Out)](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiSummarizerBot&amp;amp;message=OptOut&amp;amp;subject=OptOut)^( | )[^(Opt Out Of Subreddit)](https://np.reddit.com/r/changemyview/about/banned)^( | )[^(GitHub)](https://github.com/Sujal-7/WikiSummarizerBot)^( ] Downvote to remove | v1.5)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
