<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209151241.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3giu4p/cmv_i_have_no_sympathy_towards_violent_criminals/">
    <title>CMV: I have no sympathy towards violent criminals at the point of crime</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can never understand people when they lament about how they feel sorry for someone who just commited a violent crime.

I understand being sympathetic towards a non-violent thief who might be destitute, or a murderer who has done his time and apologized.

But someone who has just done a horrible act of violence towards another person (and hasn't repented yet) doesn't deserve sympathy from anyone, unless they genuinely believe he/she is innocent, or committed the crime in self-defense.

One argument people make is that the guilty crime was committed "in the heat of moment". I see this often being used to defend road ragers and drunk wife-beaters. I can't agree with this argument because it unfairly takes responsibility away from the criminal. If we left every criminal go easy because the crimes were "emotional" or "spur of the moment", we'd have a lot of unstable people out on the streets ready go to off at any moment and hurt others.

Another argument I hear is that the criminal was a "victim of the circumstances", i.e. he was poor or grew up in a dysfunctional family. This is a totally reasonable argument if the crime is non-violent, but being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up. Anyone who makes a conscious choice to hurt someone physically is simply an asshole.

I oppose the death penalty and am in favor of restorative prison reform, so I hear people giving these criminals moral slack (at more than just a legal or health-based level) all the time, and it drives me crazy. But I want to see the POV they are coming from, so please try to CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27933050885.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>I feel bad for the circumstances that lead to the crime. 

http://www.vice.com/read/oakland-is-giving-kids-post-traumatic-stress-disorder

Do you feel bad for these young children?  One day, many will commit some type of crime. I'm not going to excuse the crime, but I can't help but see that five year old when I see a criminal. Or the person with a mental disorder. Or drug addiction. 

We don't grow out of being five, we simply add to it. We give that five year old more experiences and cognitive development. How much cognitive development do you think a child with PTSD undergoes?  How much of their world is painted by violence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27933070100.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>They can choose not to commit a violent crime. PTSD or any other mental illness is not an excuse (in absolutely any way) to go kill or beat someone up.

And even if they get affected to point where they can't think straight or even have little cognitive function at all, there's no reason to have sympathy for them once they commit a violent crime. As I said above,  it's ludicrous to be sympathetic towards bears or tornados who kill people, and yet neither bears nor tornados can think like typical humans do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27933153892.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>There's fault and responsibility. 

The act is their fault, but not completely their responsibility. If it were completely their responsibility, we wouldn't have systems in place that hopefully prevent crime. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27933190848.0" user="Mavericgamer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As I said above, it's ludicrous to be sympathetic towards bears or tornados who kill people, and yet neither bears nor tornados can think like typical humans do.

That's because no bear or tornado has the capacity for empathy. Humans, by and large, do, unless they have been severely damaged. The empathy people feel for violent offenders is born out of realizing the potential for good of the human mind gone so wrong. It's the realization that there really aren't such things as monsters. It's realizing that it wasn't some inborn trait that they were created with; they have the same brain as we do, and because of the bullshit they've been through, they turned out to be violent and hateful. Had the roles been reversed, we can't really say we'd have turned out any differently with any degree of certainty.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
