<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209151241.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3giu4p/cmv_i_have_no_sympathy_towards_violent_criminals/">
    <title>CMV: I have no sympathy towards violent criminals at the point of crime</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can never understand people when they lament about how they feel sorry for someone who just commited a violent crime.

I understand being sympathetic towards a non-violent thief who might be destitute, or a murderer who has done his time and apologized.

But someone who has just done a horrible act of violence towards another person (and hasn't repented yet) doesn't deserve sympathy from anyone, unless they genuinely believe he/she is innocent, or committed the crime in self-defense.

One argument people make is that the guilty crime was committed "in the heat of moment". I see this often being used to defend road ragers and drunk wife-beaters. I can't agree with this argument because it unfairly takes responsibility away from the criminal. If we left every criminal go easy because the crimes were "emotional" or "spur of the moment", we'd have a lot of unstable people out on the streets ready go to off at any moment and hurt others.

Another argument I hear is that the criminal was a "victim of the circumstances", i.e. he was poor or grew up in a dysfunctional family. This is a totally reasonable argument if the crime is non-violent, but being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up. Anyone who makes a conscious choice to hurt someone physically is simply an asshole.

I oppose the death penalty and am in favor of restorative prison reform, so I hear people giving these criminals moral slack (at more than just a legal or health-based level) all the time, and it drives me crazy. But I want to see the POV they are coming from, so please try to CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27934061405.0" user="HBombthrow" delta="False">
    <text>As a law student and lawyer I've studied gang violence.  Keep in mind that even in the worst neighborhoods, only about 5% of kids fall into gangs -- it's never something a person *has* to do to survive, 95% of people find a way to avoid it.  One of the things you come to learn about gang membership is that the primary determinant of whether someone falls into the gang life is having a weak, malleable personality and a lack of authoritative guidance.  That is, gang members are usually weak-nerved, impressionable people looking for guidance who are groomed and latch onto the wrong people.

I had one client.  The kid was an immigrant from Mexico.  His father was killed by corrupt federal police in Mexico, and his family fled to the U.S.  His mom had to work 3 jobs to make ends meet and had little time to supervise him. He had an uncle here who took responsibility for raising him, until that uncle was killed by a stray bullet.  Another uncle took over, and *that* guy was killed in a drive-by.  This kid was meek and quiet and got jumped every day after school.  Eventually he learned that he could avoid beatings by walking with certain kids, who introduced him to gang life.  These guys were the only people that he felt close to, and eventually they got him drunk, stoned, and pressured him into participating in a drive by.  He fired nine shots, hitting two people (non-fatal).  He was 15.

This kid is obviously responsible for what he did, but still, in another life...  If this kid were born in the U.S. to a middle class family, I'm certainly he would never have committed a crime.  If he'd had even a good teacher who was a role model for him, or a soccer coach, or something, I think he would have been fine.  He was a kid who didn't want to disappoint authority, a naive child, but the authority that presented itself was corrupt and criminal.

I feel sorry for this kid.  He made very bad choices, but the world failed him too.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
