<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209151241.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3giu4p/cmv_i_have_no_sympathy_towards_violent_criminals/">
    <title>CMV: I have no sympathy towards violent criminals at the point of crime</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can never understand people when they lament about how they feel sorry for someone who just commited a violent crime.

I understand being sympathetic towards a non-violent thief who might be destitute, or a murderer who has done his time and apologized.

But someone who has just done a horrible act of violence towards another person (and hasn't repented yet) doesn't deserve sympathy from anyone, unless they genuinely believe he/she is innocent, or committed the crime in self-defense.

One argument people make is that the guilty crime was committed "in the heat of moment". I see this often being used to defend road ragers and drunk wife-beaters. I can't agree with this argument because it unfairly takes responsibility away from the criminal. If we left every criminal go easy because the crimes were "emotional" or "spur of the moment", we'd have a lot of unstable people out on the streets ready go to off at any moment and hurt others.

Another argument I hear is that the criminal was a "victim of the circumstances", i.e. he was poor or grew up in a dysfunctional family. This is a totally reasonable argument if the crime is non-violent, but being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up. Anyone who makes a conscious choice to hurt someone physically is simply an asshole.

I oppose the death penalty and am in favor of restorative prison reform, so I hear people giving these criminals moral slack (at more than just a legal or health-based level) all the time, and it drives me crazy. But I want to see the POV they are coming from, so please try to CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27933103614.0" user="warsage" delta="False">
    <text>You lack empathy. You can't see things from the point of view of the criminal. If you could understand the way they think, the experiences they've had, and the emotions they were feeling, you would pity them, not hate them.

Have you read Ender's Game? One of the most important character traits of the main character, Ender, is his empathy towards his enemies. He truly understands them. Even when they have tried to injure him, he still understands them and feels bad for them.

From the book:

&amp;gt;I think it’s impossible to really understand somebody, what they want, what they believe, and not love them the way they love themselves.

---

It's important that Ender's pity for them didn't stop him from destroying them completely. He felt for them, yes, but what they were doing was still wrong, and he stopped them from ever doing it again.

You said the following:

&amp;gt;being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up

Of course it's not, and they should face the consequences of their actions. But have you ever heard the saying "hate the sin, love the sinner?" Can't you condemn their actions while still feeling bad for the suffering and lost potential that go with their actions?

---

You also seem to have some fixation on violent crime:

&amp;gt;This is a totally reasonable argument **if the crime is non-violent** 

Plenty of nonviolent actions can cause lots of damage. A hacked bank account hurts more than a black eye. Why is nonviolent crime forgivable, but violent crime is not?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27933174624.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>I don't lack empathy. I understand why a criminal might commit a crime.

But I'm not sympathetic towards unrepentant violent criminals. I have no pity or sorrow for these people.

&amp;gt; You also seem to have some fixation on violent crime

There are many non-violent crimes that may be perpetrated due to economic need. If you need to feed yourself and have no other option, I understand stealing food from a supermarket, and I feel bad for someone in that situation.

But there is never a good reason to kill or beat someone up unless actively provoked (i.e. self-defense). Also the end consequences are far greater with violent crimes. You can't completely erase a person from the earth by hacking their bank account. But you just do just that through murder.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
