<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="210687705.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3hfro9/cmv_im_wasting_my_time_and_money_by_going_on/">
    <title>CMV: I'm wasting my time and money by going on vacation overseas.</title>
    <original_poster>beq451991</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a somewhat recent college graduate and am about to take my first trip overseas, to Italy. I have a full-time job and am taking two weeks off for this trip. Now that the trip is coming up in a couple weeks, I am wondering why I thought it would be a good idea. I don't like the idea of two weeks of not being able to workout in a gym, eating decadent food, and spending as much money as I am on the trip. I am the stereotypical American who actually likes working and I try to work more hours than other people, punishing myself in the gym (if I'm not sore after lifting weights or out of breath after cardio, it's not a workout), and eating simple foods. I am going on this trip mainly for the historical aspect, but I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much, as ridiculous as that sounds. People tell me I'm going to work myself to an early death, but I see working as my purpose in life, as a man. I don't care if I drop dead from a heart attack at 40 if I worked as hard as I could and accomplished as much as possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27947232285.0" user="riggorous" delta="False">
    <text>Awesome! I live in Italy (intermittently) and it's one of the best countries in the world (no bias there).

First, for practical advice:

1. It's great that you're going in September, as there will be fewer tourists, all the Italians will be back from vacation, everything will be cheaper, and the weather will be a little cooler. Most Americans go in August-July, which is the stupidest thing in the world, so good on you!

&amp;gt; not being able to workout in a gym

2. I don't know what your hotel arrangements are like (if you have a gym in your hotel, that's the obvious solution), and I don't know where you're going to be, but whereas Italy is a little more challenging to work out, it is still very doable. Firstly, my favorite way of getting to know a new city is going out for a morning jog. There aren't many jogging/biking trails in Italian cities (grr), but many city centres are pedestrian-only, so don't worry about cars. Rome has a few villas (big parks) located near the city center (Villa Borghese, Villa Doria) which are great for jogging, especially since the city is quite hilly, and doing calisthenics (they have overhead bars etc). Turin, Rome, Genoa, and Florence, have nice boardwalks which are scenic and more or less unpopulated tracks. That said, if you're going to a natural reserve like Cinque Terre, or exploring the out-of-the-way parts of Tuscany, Liguria, or the Amalfi coast, consider going on a hike. The Italian coastline and mountains have many excellent nature walks of varying difficulty, plus activities like sailing, surfing, mountain climbing, horse riding etc if you have some extra money. I would definitely recommend that you stay at an agriturismo (an Italian rural BnB) away from the typical tourist cities, because that way you can both get active and get a chance to experience a slice of real Italian life (and eat some cheap natural food).

&amp;gt; eating decadent food

I definitely have a problem with this because I'm a big foodie, but this isn't necessarily the case in Italy. The portions are usually big, but very few things are fried or have sauces, so if you avoid creamy types of pasta, you should be fine. Unlike the French, Italians preserve the natural flavors of foods, so when you get, say, a steak, you just get the steak without any oils or sauces, and you have to order any side dishes separately. Plus, Italian cuisine has excellent fish dishes, which are very low in calories. I wouldn't recommend that you stick to a strict diet on your trip, because you should go out and try new foods, but if you don't order 3 course meals every day, you should be fine. Try not to eat in touristy places (if the menu is in English, it is a touristy place), as that will be both cheaper and taste better. In general, Italy (especially southern Italy) is quite cheap for food.

&amp;gt; spending as much money as I am on the trip

This depends on how you like to live. You can travel very cheaply in Europe because 1) public transport is cheap and ubiquitous, 2) food is cheap, 3) cheap accommodation is possible with a little bit of planning. That's my general advice so far.

&amp;gt; I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much

Sorry if this is harsh, but it sounds like a lot of your "preferences" are self-imposed punishments. If you genuinely enjoyed pushing yourself to your limits, working 80 hours a week, and eating simple foods, you wouldn't be afraid that taking a 2 week vacation would throw you out of those habits, since, if we enjoy something, we're gonna keep doing it no matter what. It seems like you doth protest too much. You sound like you're scared of discovering another side of yourself on this trip.

But discovering another side of yourself, making a hard decision, and sticking to it is the very definition of not living softly. There's no glory in working yourself to death if working yourself to death is what you're built to do. It's not like we're amazed that birds can fly, right? That's why it's great that you're going on this trip, seeing as you're either very inexperienced and unsure of who you are, or you're trying to deny yourself. Especially if you're going alone, you're going to learn a lot about who you are as a person and what you want out of life, in part by engaging in things that seem uncomfortable at first (i.e. going out of your comfort zone). I also enjoy going to the gym, working, and eating plain food, but I understand that this lifestyle is a sort of comfort blanket that I use to remain surreptitiously in control of my life, and that it will get disrupted eventually (as will yours), and I will have to know how to deal with that - but most of all, after a time, it just isn't challenging anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
