<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="210687705.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3hfro9/cmv_im_wasting_my_time_and_money_by_going_on/">
    <title>CMV: I'm wasting my time and money by going on vacation overseas.</title>
    <original_poster>beq451991</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a somewhat recent college graduate and am about to take my first trip overseas, to Italy. I have a full-time job and am taking two weeks off for this trip. Now that the trip is coming up in a couple weeks, I am wondering why I thought it would be a good idea. I don't like the idea of two weeks of not being able to workout in a gym, eating decadent food, and spending as much money as I am on the trip. I am the stereotypical American who actually likes working and I try to work more hours than other people, punishing myself in the gym (if I'm not sore after lifting weights or out of breath after cardio, it's not a workout), and eating simple foods. I am going on this trip mainly for the historical aspect, but I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much, as ridiculous as that sounds. People tell me I'm going to work myself to an early death, but I see working as my purpose in life, as a man. I don't care if I drop dead from a heart attack at 40 if I worked as hard as I could and accomplished as much as possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27947273918.0" user="jetpacksforall" delta="False">
    <text>Let me put it to you this way: ARE YOU FRICKIN CRAZY?!  

Italy is one of the most amazing countries on earth. The land is beautiful, the art and history are endlessly fascinating, the beaches are among the finest on earth and the food, my god, the food. Italy would be worth traveling halfway around the world even if the whole place looked like Nebraska, just for the food. 

To address some of your points:  

* "Decadent" food. I'm not sure where you get this idea, but Italian food is nothing like the calorie-heavy nightmare of garlic and cream and melted cheese that you see in some American Italian restaurants. Portions are smaller, vegetables and herbs are almost invariably fresh, and there's a huge variety of different cuisines and styles to try. It isn't all pasta, although pasta is wonderful. There's also a huge variety of seafood, meats, game, vegetables, porcini mushrooms which get their own category, pestos, salads, cheeses, etc. In short you can eat very very well but also eat *well*, meaning healthy, balanced meals. You can also, of course, pig out on polenta, pizza and dolci (desserts).

* "I see working as my purpose in life." Have you considered instead of the usual tourist destinations doing factory tours, visiting olive oil growers, wineries, auto manufacturing, housewares, textiles, glass blowing, ceramics, traditional crafts, etc.? Italy has great food and beautiful places to visit, but it is also one of the world's premiere centers for ultra-high quality manufacturing and artisanal work, not to mention historical processes that have been preserved for centuries. Depending on what you do for a living, you might even have colleagues who could hook you up with counterparts in Italy who would be happy to show you how business works over there. Despite what stereotypes may tell you, Italians are hard-working people who appreciate the value of well-made things (typical workdays are 9-1, lunch/siesta, then 3-8). There are also a number of political &amp;amp; institutional barriers and difficulties that are also instructive to learn about. 

* "Working out." Obviously Italy has gyms, and you should be able to get a two week membership assuming your hotel(s) don't have a facility (Italian gyms aren't like in the US... you don't have to sign an ironclad 2-year agreement that you can't get out of). They also have every outdoor sport you can think of with the possible exception of surfing (not many good breaks), and so plenty of opportunities to run, bike, climb, hike, swim, sail, study martial arts, dive, hang glide, kayak, zipline, etc. 

Voltaire said "to know the world, one must travel," and at your age &amp;amp; with your experience you could definitely benefit from that truism. Even if you are an all business kind of guy, there's nothing like having knowledge of the world and experience of other people &amp;amp; places to draw upon as one of your general skills when you go back to work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
