<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="210687705.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3hfro9/cmv_im_wasting_my_time_and_money_by_going_on/">
    <title>CMV: I'm wasting my time and money by going on vacation overseas.</title>
    <original_poster>beq451991</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a somewhat recent college graduate and am about to take my first trip overseas, to Italy. I have a full-time job and am taking two weeks off for this trip. Now that the trip is coming up in a couple weeks, I am wondering why I thought it would be a good idea. I don't like the idea of two weeks of not being able to workout in a gym, eating decadent food, and spending as much money as I am on the trip. I am the stereotypical American who actually likes working and I try to work more hours than other people, punishing myself in the gym (if I'm not sore after lifting weights or out of breath after cardio, it's not a workout), and eating simple foods. I am going on this trip mainly for the historical aspect, but I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much, as ridiculous as that sounds. People tell me I'm going to work myself to an early death, but I see working as my purpose in life, as a man. I don't care if I drop dead from a heart attack at 40 if I worked as hard as I could and accomplished as much as possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27947048578.0" user="JacksInsomnia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am the stereotypical American who actually likes working.

I don't think you know what a stereotypical American is. Most of us are lazy as hell and try to find any way possible to *not* work.

&amp;gt; I don't like the idea of two weeks of not being able to workout in a gym, eating decadent food...

Why can't you work out? I'm sure the hotel will have a gym. And you're going to Italy once of the best places for "decadent" food next to France. You will be just fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27947328036.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>Americans work more hours than most industrialized countries.  Whether you think Americans are lazy or not, the typical American is a very hard worker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27948701885.0" user="lobster_conspiracy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And you're going to Italy once of the best places for "decadent" food next to France. 

The wording is ambiguous, but I think OP is concerned about eating (being forced to eat?) decadent Italian food, not being deprived of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
