<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="210687705.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3hfro9/cmv_im_wasting_my_time_and_money_by_going_on/">
    <title>CMV: I'm wasting my time and money by going on vacation overseas.</title>
    <original_poster>beq451991</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am a somewhat recent college graduate and am about to take my first trip overseas, to Italy. I have a full-time job and am taking two weeks off for this trip. Now that the trip is coming up in a couple weeks, I am wondering why I thought it would be a good idea. I don't like the idea of two weeks of not being able to workout in a gym, eating decadent food, and spending as much money as I am on the trip. I am the stereotypical American who actually likes working and I try to work more hours than other people, punishing myself in the gym (if I'm not sore after lifting weights or out of breath after cardio, it's not a workout), and eating simple foods. I am going on this trip mainly for the historical aspect, but I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much, as ridiculous as that sounds. People tell me I'm going to work myself to an early death, but I see working as my purpose in life, as a man. I don't care if I drop dead from a heart attack at 40 if I worked as hard as I could and accomplished as much as possible.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27947429670.0" user="DeliriousPrecarious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am going on this trip mainly for the historical aspect, but I am afraid of living too softly and enjoying myself too much, as ridiculous as that sounds. 

It does sound ridiculous because you are in full control over how your vacation plays out. So you don't value the culinary aspects of Italian culture? Good, don't go to fancy restaurants and try and eat crazy things. You can have a very authentic experience just eating what the locals eat (because you know they aren't eating super crazy every day). 

If you're going for the historical aspect maximize that aspect of your trip and don't worry about frills. Stay in hostels, eat simply, and try and see as many museums, sites, and monuments as you can. Many thousands of people go on those sorts of vacations every year and are perfectly satisfied.

Truthfully it sounds like you are nervous for reasons opposite of what you are saying. You aren't worried about being "overly soft/enjoyable" you're afraid of doing something different that is outside your comfort zone. You like going to work, going to the gym, and eating the foods you are accustomed to and are concerned that you will be unhappy without those things.


</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
