<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="211207339.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3hqwmj/cmv_i_understand_the_backlash_against_political/">
    <title>CMV: I understand the backlash against political correctness, but that does not give one the right to lie</title>
    <original_poster>n00dles__</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Tl;DR My view is that you are entitled to your opinions, as politically incorrect as they may be, but not your own facts.**

So, I've seen a lot of posts on PC-ness lately and I'd thought I'd give my own angle to this.

In the wake of Donald Trump rising in the polls, I would agree that he has done so by being unapologetic about his views and opinions, and that he has proven that we have taken political correctness too far. However, I think framing it like that is missing the point.

I'd like to make the following comparison: gangsta rap. Now, I haven't seen the *Straight Outta Compton* movie, but I have listened to guys like NWA and I very well know how controversial and politically incorrect their lyrics are. However, it is my view that they were trying to be as honest as they can, and that they did their best to show the lifestyles and attitudes associated with street life. Sure, I do not condone advocating violence against the police, but as far as I'm concerned they were not blatantly lying, making up their own facts, or making any sweeping claims in their songs, nor did they ever intend to ([here's an Eazy-E interview](https://youtu.be/SuUDuPU1TFk?t=50s) as part of my argument). 

Fast forward almost 30 years later and we have Donald Trump running for president. Yes, I could say he's being almost as politcally incorrect as gangsta rappers were, but the big difference is his dishonesty in his rhetoric. He is lying about Mexican immigrants in saying that the vast majority are rapists, bringing crime, and bringing drugs ([here's a study from the Center for Immigration Studies](http://cis.org/ImmigrantCrime)). To me, this isn't about political correctness, and more about politicians lying. And that is my problem with Donald Trump. He's making up his own facts and making false sweeping claims that only happen to be politically incorrect, when it's his lies that are the real problem.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27952083706.0" user="gabrielmodesta" delta="False">
    <text>It's a campaign.  Important to note the difference between hyperbole and an actual claim of fact.  I think you'll have a tough time find a quote where he literally says every single one of them are criminals, and he's clarified that many times.

Please don't take this as support for Trump as such, just that, I think you may be reacting emotionally to how the press portrayed his statements instead of really picking apart his actual statements and follow-ups on that particular matter.

And for the record... if you DO look into the ratios of criminals coming in from Mexico, you might find yourself on the wrong side of the debate at some point if you don't become aware of what the problem actually is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
