<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="212784161.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3iopb5/cmv_accepting_discriminating_charity_is_better/">
    <title>CMV: Accepting discriminating charity is better for society than not accepting that charity at all.</title>
    <original_poster>ZenRain</original_poster>
    <original_post>Alright, so this was inspired by the recent debate in about a Toronto man who was issued a letter denying him government-subsidized housing at a Muslim-specific residence because he wasn't Muslim, and how this discrimination was wrong.

However, the housing unit in question was built by the Muslim community in question, and would not have existed without their financing.

My view is that this is okay, because even if they're removing 166 Muslim families from the overall pool, this discriminating practice (which costs only 15% of what a discrimination-free housing unit would cost) they're functionally adding 166 'spots' for non-Muslims to the available pool of subsidized housing.

That's the first query I'd like a response to. The second is far more... direct, because I've gotten no response from any of the people I've put the query to, and I'm interested to see how people willing to challenge their own beliefs would take it.

The Scenario is as such:

**Hypothetical question:** You see two homeless people and want to buy them each a meal, but can only afford one. Someone else comes up and says "I'm willing to buy that Muslim person a meal. I'm not willing to buy for the other homeless person, but I'll buy for the Muslim person."

Both the homeless people are now being fed instead of one of them, *if you agree to the offer.* Do you turn it down based on principal and let one of the two go hungry?

If you say no in this scenario either you're feeding someone you would have fed anyway and letting the Muslim person go hungry for no good reason but to feel better about how equal and egalitarian you are, or you're feeding the person who has another offer of food and letting the person with no other offers of food go hungry.

Because you can't feed both. You have money for one, and someone is offering to feed the other, no matter how bigoted their offer may appear.

Would you watch someone actually go hungry for theoretical moral superiority, or would you be willing to recognize that the greater good in this instance is making sure both people are fed?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27966123256.0" user="shibbyhornet28" delta="False">
    <text>Your analogy might work for a private donor considering whether to help the victims of Muslim discrimination, but the government has an option a random donor wouldn't: to increase everyone's taxes and pay for housing for both Muslims and non-Muslims with that money. It might be that discriminatory charity is better than letting people go homeless, but that's a false dichotomy, and you seem overly ready to accept it as a conclusion ("My view is that this is okay, because [...]"). Government money should not be used to subsidize discriminatory behavior (and in the Toronto case, those residences were city-subsidized) when there are viable alternative means to the same end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966137992.0" user="ZenRain" delta="False">
    <text>Here's the thing.

Demonstrably, the parity of private vs public funding for these discriminatory housing projects rests at about an 85:15 ratio, being generous to the 15% which is the government's involvement.

Also, this assumes that raising the taxes isn't an option. Toronto Public Housing is sorely under-budgeted as-is. Raising the budget to provide 100% subsidized housing to those in need within a decade without occasionally leaning on race/gender/religion/etc-specific charities is categorically impossible unless we can literally create money from nowhere.

Also, the other half of the post: Is letting someone else go hungry for your stance of egalitarianism something you would do? Yes or no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966150833.0" user="shibbyhornet28" delta="False">
    <text>If the 85:15 ratio were accurate (you haven't cited this figure and I haven't been able to find it Googling this news story, but let's say it's accurate), that would mean that the government pulling out of the subsidization would mean roughly an 18% drop in Muslim-specific housing - it's only logical for the Muslim community to adopt the discriminatory stance if they think the government's going to go along, meaning refusal to do so could end the discrimination.

&amp;gt;categorically impossible unless we can literally create money from nowhere.

Or from other places in the city's budget. If you're basing your entire argument on the need to prioritize principles after housing the homeless, surely there's some part of the budget you would view as more expendable.

&amp;gt;Is letting someone else go hungry for your stance of egalitarianism something you would do? Yes or no.

I saw the question in the original post, and as I said, it's a false dichotomy. A yes or no isn't relevant to the CMV as explained it - that what the Muslim community is doing in Toronto is 'okay'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966170090.0" user="ZenRain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I saw the question in the original post, and as I said, it's a false dichotomy. A yes or no isn't relevant to the CMV as explained it - that what the Muslim community is doing in Toronto is 'okay'.

The fact you don't understand why I'm asking the question highlights why you'll never change my view, frankly.

At the core of your beliefs, you're utterly unwilling to engage in the concept that working with someone bigoted can ever be a positive thing for society.

Because it is relevant: The housing project mentioned wouldn't exist at all without a lot of Muslim money and time dedicated to the project, far disproportionate to the government aid received.

As for the 85:15 ratio... I've posted the math before, but I've got no problem C/Ping it now:

Ahem.

"The average cost (today) of constructing a multi-story apartment building is roughly $70,000 per unit, without considering factors such as maintenance, upkeep, and even upgrades (all things that the building in question provide out of community pocket).

This also doesn't cover utilities reductions due to upgrades (the building in question was purpose-built to a better standard and routinely upgrades), so there's that.

Let's get down to basic math.

Let's assume that the for the 166 units available, the cost of the building was $11,620,000 to build in today's money, based on that basic standard and not the superior building costs involved. It was likely more (given that it was built to a higher standard), but let's just assume. This doesn't cover the cost of the land, which would have inflated that cost to near $14,000,000 based on the real estate figures I could find for the location.

Now again, simple math, let's take that cost and apply it to the twenty years. Let's assume a $800 per unit, per month subsidy as applied by the government, without applying the upgrades the community provided to the building or the utilities savings said upgrades also provided, or the fact that the community also staffs and manages the day-to-day maintenance. Let's just go with the most basic math here.

Over the course of twenty years, the government would provide an additional $2,656,000 dollars in funding. Added on top of the $14,000,000 which we can reasonably assume was spent only because of the community's intense involvement in the project, and the burden the government shared for the entire project over a twenty-year compared to a egalitarian, bigot-free development is 15%, meaning the Ahmadiyya Abode of Peace has helped shoulder 85% of the financial burden for a building that would not have been built without their involvement for a period of 20 years of government subsidization even before including 20 years of maintenance, upkeep, and improvements.

For the last 22 years, since the Ahmadiyya Abode of Peace was founded, the community has managed those all of those factors, including upgrades which were well before their time."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
