<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="212784161.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3iopb5/cmv_accepting_discriminating_charity_is_better/">
    <title>CMV: Accepting discriminating charity is better for society than not accepting that charity at all.</title>
    <original_poster>ZenRain</original_poster>
    <original_post>Alright, so this was inspired by the recent debate in about a Toronto man who was issued a letter denying him government-subsidized housing at a Muslim-specific residence because he wasn't Muslim, and how this discrimination was wrong.

However, the housing unit in question was built by the Muslim community in question, and would not have existed without their financing.

My view is that this is okay, because even if they're removing 166 Muslim families from the overall pool, this discriminating practice (which costs only 15% of what a discrimination-free housing unit would cost) they're functionally adding 166 'spots' for non-Muslims to the available pool of subsidized housing.

That's the first query I'd like a response to. The second is far more... direct, because I've gotten no response from any of the people I've put the query to, and I'm interested to see how people willing to challenge their own beliefs would take it.

The Scenario is as such:

**Hypothetical question:** You see two homeless people and want to buy them each a meal, but can only afford one. Someone else comes up and says "I'm willing to buy that Muslim person a meal. I'm not willing to buy for the other homeless person, but I'll buy for the Muslim person."

Both the homeless people are now being fed instead of one of them, *if you agree to the offer.* Do you turn it down based on principal and let one of the two go hungry?

If you say no in this scenario either you're feeding someone you would have fed anyway and letting the Muslim person go hungry for no good reason but to feel better about how equal and egalitarian you are, or you're feeding the person who has another offer of food and letting the person with no other offers of food go hungry.

Because you can't feed both. You have money for one, and someone is offering to feed the other, no matter how bigoted their offer may appear.

Would you watch someone actually go hungry for theoretical moral superiority, or would you be willing to recognize that the greater good in this instance is making sure both people are fed?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27966132373.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>a charity has to list their donors. If I ran a charity and I got a check from the KKK for 100,000 dollars I wouldn't accept the check because I would be associating my organization with the KKK. Even thought I could use their money for multiple different reasons that could help many people, the baggage of that check would simply be too much. 

I wouldn't want to have to explain to fellow donors why I took financial support from an hate organization. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966143815.0" user="ZenRain" delta="False">
    <text>For one: False dichotomy, there. The organization isn't a hate-group by any stretch of the imagination. In point of fact, they're a subsect of Muslims who are oppressed and belittled by other Muslims for their beliefs, and they don't actively encourage violence or oppression of any kind towards any group.

For two, they didn't donate a bit of money. The literally designed, built, maintained, and *upgraded* the property which was rent-subsidized for the last twenty-three years, at a much greater cost to themselves than the government subsidization.

For three: The second half of the post. Does someone go hungry for your egalitarian beliefs, and if so, how do you justify that stance?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966152417.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>How to I justify this stance? Simple. If I get my organization associated with an organization that counter to the beliefs of the majority of my donors than my donor list dries up and I close my doors. 

A check isn't a loaded gun forcing you to chose it. A check from a tainted donor can be toxic regardless of how many meals it will pay for. 

To have a situation that better parallels what you're talking about, it would be in the best interest of a special ed. organization to not let in a group home provide services just for white kids. That type of association could be toxic to the entire special education organization.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
