<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="212784161.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3iopb5/cmv_accepting_discriminating_charity_is_better/">
    <title>CMV: Accepting discriminating charity is better for society than not accepting that charity at all.</title>
    <original_poster>ZenRain</original_poster>
    <original_post>Alright, so this was inspired by the recent debate in about a Toronto man who was issued a letter denying him government-subsidized housing at a Muslim-specific residence because he wasn't Muslim, and how this discrimination was wrong.

However, the housing unit in question was built by the Muslim community in question, and would not have existed without their financing.

My view is that this is okay, because even if they're removing 166 Muslim families from the overall pool, this discriminating practice (which costs only 15% of what a discrimination-free housing unit would cost) they're functionally adding 166 'spots' for non-Muslims to the available pool of subsidized housing.

That's the first query I'd like a response to. The second is far more... direct, because I've gotten no response from any of the people I've put the query to, and I'm interested to see how people willing to challenge their own beliefs would take it.

The Scenario is as such:

**Hypothetical question:** You see two homeless people and want to buy them each a meal, but can only afford one. Someone else comes up and says "I'm willing to buy that Muslim person a meal. I'm not willing to buy for the other homeless person, but I'll buy for the Muslim person."

Both the homeless people are now being fed instead of one of them, *if you agree to the offer.* Do you turn it down based on principal and let one of the two go hungry?

If you say no in this scenario either you're feeding someone you would have fed anyway and letting the Muslim person go hungry for no good reason but to feel better about how equal and egalitarian you are, or you're feeding the person who has another offer of food and letting the person with no other offers of food go hungry.

Because you can't feed both. You have money for one, and someone is offering to feed the other, no matter how bigoted their offer may appear.

Would you watch someone actually go hungry for theoretical moral superiority, or would you be willing to recognize that the greater good in this instance is making sure both people are fed?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27967076399.0" user="Epitomeric" delta="False">
    <text>In accepting discriminating charity, you're accepting that discrimination in some way.  You've accepted that because of some (possibly unrelated circumstance like skin color) you deserve that money over someone else.  This comes down to individual choice and whether or not your willing to accept the stigma that comes with it, whatever that is.

Hyperbolic conclusions are often drawn by the public based on  differences (and often differ based on what viewpoint one takes).  In acknowledging differences we create the illusion that more contrast exists than existed before, and in either case, it's not a good thing.  It allows people to make excuses for themselves and the behavior of others, and can reinforce the idea that we all have different self-worth or tendencies based on things over which we have no control (like race).  Weighing that against a financial benefit is something that's difficult to do, but I would guess that the repercussions of a divided society would be much more expensive in the long run than a bit of cash saved by allowing discriminatory charities/contributions or discrimination of any kind.

If this is based on things we do have control over, it incentivizes certain behavior, but still further divides those of differing views.  In this case, maybe more of less-wealthy population would become Muslim.  This could carry with it some interesting implications.

That being said, your viewpoint seem a bit near-sighted and I would encourage you to look also at some of the long-term, dynamic, destabilizing implications of supporting or allowing such charity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
