<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="212784161.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3iopb5/cmv_accepting_discriminating_charity_is_better/">
    <title>CMV: Accepting discriminating charity is better for society than not accepting that charity at all.</title>
    <original_poster>ZenRain</original_poster>
    <original_post>Alright, so this was inspired by the recent debate in about a Toronto man who was issued a letter denying him government-subsidized housing at a Muslim-specific residence because he wasn't Muslim, and how this discrimination was wrong.

However, the housing unit in question was built by the Muslim community in question, and would not have existed without their financing.

My view is that this is okay, because even if they're removing 166 Muslim families from the overall pool, this discriminating practice (which costs only 15% of what a discrimination-free housing unit would cost) they're functionally adding 166 'spots' for non-Muslims to the available pool of subsidized housing.

That's the first query I'd like a response to. The second is far more... direct, because I've gotten no response from any of the people I've put the query to, and I'm interested to see how people willing to challenge their own beliefs would take it.

The Scenario is as such:

**Hypothetical question:** You see two homeless people and want to buy them each a meal, but can only afford one. Someone else comes up and says "I'm willing to buy that Muslim person a meal. I'm not willing to buy for the other homeless person, but I'll buy for the Muslim person."

Both the homeless people are now being fed instead of one of them, *if you agree to the offer.* Do you turn it down based on principal and let one of the two go hungry?

If you say no in this scenario either you're feeding someone you would have fed anyway and letting the Muslim person go hungry for no good reason but to feel better about how equal and egalitarian you are, or you're feeding the person who has another offer of food and letting the person with no other offers of food go hungry.

Because you can't feed both. You have money for one, and someone is offering to feed the other, no matter how bigoted their offer may appear.

Would you watch someone actually go hungry for theoretical moral superiority, or would you be willing to recognize that the greater good in this instance is making sure both people are fed?

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27966139401.0" user="whattodo-whattodo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  My view is that this is okay, because even if they're removing 166 Muslim families from the overall pool, this discriminating practice (which costs only 15% of what a discrimination-free housing unit would cost) they're functionally adding 166 'spots' for non-Muslims to the available pool of subsidized housing.


In my view, you're looking at the wrong metric.  This only tells us that charity is better than no charity. It does not tell us anything about discriminating VS non discriminating charities.  It just assumes that it's all or nothing.  It's a lot like saying that a medicine is great because it saves a handful of lives.  We can agree that it's better than not having any medicine, but we can't agree on the idea that no better medicine can possibly exist.

Charitable donations are eligible for Tax credits.  This means that some proportion of your choice to give is subsidized by the government.  Even if I say nothing more, it still means that accepting discriminating charities also means that the government sanctions discrimination by virtue of it's investment.  This already presents a conflict of interests with its residents.  

The above also indicates that people who donate do, so (in some part) for self serving purposes.  Through clever accounting, the amount in tax credits often allow them to operate their business better.  For instance, contractors are often given permits to create huge buildings for the rich, but they must do so on a condition that X amount needs to be spent serving the public good.  So the government first allows the contractors to build and profit and later expects them to repay.  The problem there is that if they get to pick a small subset of the population to repay to, the government is paying directly into discrimination.  More to the point, these companies will always want to repay because it provides them the opportunity to create the lucrative buildings in the first place.  

I will stop at these two as they are the most influential points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966149953.0" user="ZenRain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This only tells us that charity is better than no charity.

So wait, you're arguing that a movement which offers much-reduced housing costs to a certain sect of people, which in turn allows the government to allocate resources to the rest of their potential recipients... Is bad?

Because reasons?

You're essentially arguing that 50+10 is worse than just... 50. Because it's unfair. Somehow. And that maybe they're cheating on taxes and being dicks about it, because some people can do that so we have to assume that people willing to build a building in concert with the government, entirely to serve people who can't afford rent themselves, should be held to the same standard as Donald Trump when constructing his latest monstrosity.

You just did an end-zone return on leaping to conclusions, friend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966167362.0" user="whattodo-whattodo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Because reasons?


I just reread my post.  I think you should too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27966176390.0" user="ZenRain" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, didn't change my view.

You're functionally arguing that because we don't know the specifics of this charitable organization which literally built a 166-unit apartment complex which was a decade ahead of its time for people who couldn't afford to live there and has spent the last twenty-three years maintaining, managing, and even upgrading the property... We should assume they're Lux Luthor levels of evil, rather than giving them even the slightest bit of doubt.

You also argue that the developers may have done so for the purpose of tax breaks, ignoring the fact that said tax breaks for charitable developments such as the building in question are designed to encourage rich businessmen to donate more, and not less of their money to endeavors which help the needy.

I reread your post. It's still **shite**, and you don't know a thing about the thing you're arguing against outside of arguments so vague as to be meaningless.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
