<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="217468142.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lh3hq/cmv_stubhub_and_other_ticket_resale_sites_should/">
    <title>CMV: StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal and considered scalping.</title>
    <original_poster>aikdaman</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, 38 states have laws allowing the reselling of event tickets as long as the sale does not take place at the event site. The other 12 states have varying degrees of regulation, including registration requirements and maximum markups.

Why do we allow this middle man corporation to exist as a loophole for scalping and legally marking tickets up to exorbitant amounts.

At the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups. I understand supply and demand but find it ridiculous that often the re-seller makes the most money per ticket involved in a sold out production for doing essentially nothing. Oh the American way...

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28006432459.0" user="Shalashaska315" delta="False">
    <text>What if you don't have the means to sell your ticket? If I buy a ticket to a concert and end up not being able to go, must *I personally* find a person myself who wants my seat? Why can't I pay someone else to do it, which is essentially what StubHub is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006470541.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I can definitely see it being a viable company for that situation. I am specifically attacking the "scalping" which is generally seen as selling tickets over face value at a venue. Which StubHub is essentially allowed to do via cell phones. People buy tickets while at the venue on them all the time.

If you need to dump a ticket I think that's fine, if you purposely bought 10 tickets to the final Grateful Dead concert to instantly sell and make thousands of dollars then that's wrong.

EDIT: Spelling </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
