<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="217468142.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lh3hq/cmv_stubhub_and_other_ticket_resale_sites_should/">
    <title>CMV: StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal and considered scalping.</title>
    <original_poster>aikdaman</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, 38 states have laws allowing the reselling of event tickets as long as the sale does not take place at the event site. The other 12 states have varying degrees of regulation, including registration requirements and maximum markups.

Why do we allow this middle man corporation to exist as a loophole for scalping and legally marking tickets up to exorbitant amounts.

At the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups. I understand supply and demand but find it ridiculous that often the re-seller makes the most money per ticket involved in a sold out production for doing essentially nothing. Oh the American way...

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28006392557.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The reason that off-site sales are allowed largely goes back to the notion of property rights. You buy something, and you own it. It's yours to do with as you wish, including selling it.

I'm not in favor of anti-scalping laws of any kind, but at least with the on-site ones there is some argument that could be made that you're interfering with the box office selling tickets, causing a public disturbance, and/or that this is nothing more than a  "reasonable time and place" restriction. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006455878.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like such a racket. At this point companies and individuals spend their days keeping tabs on these events and force them to sell out earlier than they should by buying up as many tickets they can with multiple payment sources with the sole intention of reselling them.

I understand what you're saying that since they bought them they are allowed to do as they please. That makes me think what really needs to be changed is how a ticket is defined when you buy it. I've attended events that required the attendees names to be assigned to a ticket when purchased. I hope more move to this in the future. 

In my opinion since the re-seller has no rights to the intellectual property of the artist or the properties of said sports teams then it isn't a whole lot different than downloading and burning a copyrighted CD/DVD and selling it.
 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006468842.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>There are lots of things that one might describe as "rackets". Hell, selling junk food might be. 

Outlawing selling your personal property seems like a very bad way to go about it.

I might agree with you about it being better overall if tickets were sold to individuals... but you then have to ask: Why don't venues already do this? 

And the answer is that it's a logistical pain in the ass to check ids when letting people into large venues. So to the people running the venue, any "benefits" they might get from this wouldn't really pay back the costs... and you as a person attending the venue wouldn't be happy about it either. 

The right answer is that venues should sell tickets for market prices that reflect how much people are actually willing to pay for them. Then there would be no reason to scalp, as your expected return would be zero.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006508455.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I don't want to outlaw selling person property, lets not get ahead of ourselves. Just limiting profits and people making a living off flipping tickets.

I did think about venues pricing tickets more appropriately, I dig this idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006588814.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>I guess the question is: what makes tickets *soooo* special that we have to limit profit on selling them? The same kinds of arguments could be made for anything, from gold to pork chops. 

I get that it's irritating to people wanting tickets, but ultimately, one of two things will happen: either the "scalpers" will lower their prices as it gets closer to the event and they haven't sold, or they will actually sell most of their tickets even at the higher price.

If the latter happens, then that higher price really *is* what people are willing to pay. That's the "correct" market price for the tickets. If they were willing to take the risk, the venue could sell them for that price.

If the venue prefers to push off the risk that they might not sell their tickets at the higher price to someone else, well... that someone else is taking a risk. And there doesn't seem like there's really anything wrong with that. It's basically like selling any product through distribution channels rather than directly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007751181.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>Here's why I think tickets are "special".

Gold and pork bellies have market value across the board that fluctuates. Tickets values are so different case by case that you can't slap a market value on all tickets. You also can't turn your pork belly future for an actual pork belly at the store. If you bought a ticket the event already is planned and exists so you physically bought something. A seat at a venue for a certain date. That event may happen in the future but it isn't a future.

If you're going to compare the two you'd have to do it at the farmer to processor/distributor to retail level. The farmer sells the pig to the company that processes it and distributes it then they sell it to the retailer and then to the consumer. It's regulated and there aren't people who buy it from the retailer and sell it to another person for huge profits.

You also aren't reselling the same product. The pig has been butchered into pork belly and other cuts. So the farmer is getting a fair price for what they sell. An artist on the other hand is the only person aside from crew and people putting the production together (who are paid by artists and venues). Then a third party comes on and capitalizes because a venue is too small. The product truly never changed. The only reason there is more demand is because people didn't hear about it until it was too late since ticket sales to shows are usually only 3 or 4 month before it happens (often a lot less). Things like gold and pork bellies can be purchased at anytime, ticket sales are often very limited and don't give everyone the same opportunity at the original purchase. 

Edit: Spelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007918202.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not really sure what all of that has to do with my point.

If you want a more accurate analogy that fits how the ticket sales you're complaining about, then fine:

People that buy products wholesale from a distributor, and sell at retail, typically make a markup of at least 100%, and often closer to 200% or more. 

They take inventory risk, market risk, infrastructure costs, etc., etc., etc. So do ticket resellers. It's not just concert tickets, either. Expedia buys airline tickets and hotel space in bulk and resells them to their customers at higher prices, too. 

The biggest problem with concert tickets is actually summed up by this quote I saw at the New York Times: 

&amp;gt;Few products are so underpriced that an entire subsidiary industry exists to take advantage of the discrepancy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007997847.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>A show isn't a sweater that was mass produced and sold in bulk though, it's a service. It happens, then it's over. An artist also isn't able to buy their raw materials in bulk allowing them to sell tickets at a wholesale price. 

Expedia might take risks like that with airline tickets that but how does StubHub? They aren't the ones buying and selling the tickets. Users are on their interface and they take the commission from both sides. If the ticket doesn't sell they simply don't make a commission. 

How are these sales any different than the ones considered scalping in some states? People buying tickets off their cellphone at the venue or at a StubHub location is the same as an individual buying a ticket at the venue. It interferes with the box office in the same way. StubHub can't have their cake and eat it too. There have to be universal laws in place for all. 

I think people are missing how much of a closed off, insider, and unregulated system it is. It's not fair to put laws on individuals but say it's OK if you do it through StubHub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006513404.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The right answer is that venues should sell tickets for market prices that reflect how much people are actually willing to pay for them. Then there would be no reason to scalp, as your expected return would be zero.

It's possible that event producers prefer to sellout shows well in advance so they have cash to pay for the event. If they sold tickets at market prices, then they might not sell most of their tickets until the day of the event, forcing them to take out a loan to pay for the production, and leaving open the risk that their box office receipts will be less than production costs.

If this is true, companies like StubHub do the event producers a service by giving them access to cash and accepting some of the risk in exchange for some of the profit.

edit:spelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006590125.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Socratic method for the win... yeah, that was the next point I was going to make after this one was settled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006503421.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In my opinion since the re-seller has no rights to the intellectual property of the artist or the properties of said sports teams then it isn't a whole lot different than downloading and burning a copyrighted CD/DVD and selling it.

That's a bad analogy. A better analogy would be if I bought a physical CD, waited for it to go out of print, then put it on Ebay and sold it to the highest bidder. There's nothing wrong or illegal about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006505236.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with this. A ticket is for a one time performance which you don't own after you leave. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006517976.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>Then how about this analogy: I buy a limited-edition box of cereal. But instead of eating it, I wait until it's no longer in stores, then sell it on Ebay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006699285.0" user="most_low" delta="False">
    <text>I think for this analogy to work you would have to *directly cause* it to no longer be available in stores.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006788369.0" user="praxulus" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, you did directly cause the one box you bought to no longer be available. Before you bought it, it was in the store. After you bought it, it was no longer available in the store.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006797130.0" user="most_low" delta="False">
    <text>There's a distinction between buying one of something and buying almost all of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007330934.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Yea that's a real dick move and should not be allowed.  You are not buying it for its intended purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
