<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="217468142.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lh3hq/cmv_stubhub_and_other_ticket_resale_sites_should/">
    <title>CMV: StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal and considered scalping.</title>
    <original_poster>aikdaman</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, 38 states have laws allowing the reselling of event tickets as long as the sale does not take place at the event site. The other 12 states have varying degrees of regulation, including registration requirements and maximum markups.

Why do we allow this middle man corporation to exist as a loophole for scalping and legally marking tickets up to exorbitant amounts.

At the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups. I understand supply and demand but find it ridiculous that often the re-seller makes the most money per ticket involved in a sold out production for doing essentially nothing. Oh the American way...

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28006681914.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>For what it's worth, a lot of the secondary ticket market is season ticket holders selling extra games (or a couple premium games to offset all their other games) or people whom had to cancel their plans.

A few days before a concert, I had to sell the tickets because of scheduling conflicts.  I priced them at $90, well above the 'face value' of $65.  Except I actually paid $90 for the ticket.  Face value doesn't include ticketmaster / venue / shipping fees.  Then stubhub takes a cut, so I actually would up taking a slight loss.

Ticketmaster is a worse middleman than any scalper, hands down.

It's pretty common for sold out shows to announce additional dates.  When that happens, the scalper loses a ton of value.

I don't love scalpers, nor have I done it.  I just think you're overstating the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
