<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="217468142.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lh3hq/cmv_stubhub_and_other_ticket_resale_sites_should/">
    <title>CMV: StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal and considered scalping.</title>
    <original_poster>aikdaman</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, 38 states have laws allowing the reselling of event tickets as long as the sale does not take place at the event site. The other 12 states have varying degrees of regulation, including registration requirements and maximum markups.

Why do we allow this middle man corporation to exist as a loophole for scalping and legally marking tickets up to exorbitant amounts.

At the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups. I understand supply and demand but find it ridiculous that often the re-seller makes the most money per ticket involved in a sold out production for doing essentially nothing. Oh the American way...

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28006480574.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>If we ban all kinds of ticket exchanges - Guess what will emerge? That's right! Unregulated black markets.

It's much better to legalize and regulate. That way ticket exchanges happen in orderly fashion, people know exactly what the market price is, and possibility of fraud is low.

if we ban all exchange venues, we will just be back to shady characters hawking questionable tickets near the stadiums, and on back pages of cheap newspapers. All at exorbitant prices.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006503653.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I should have put the part in bold where I said there should at the very least be restrictions and regulations.

I'm not saying ban all transactions but attempt to put a stop at price gouging and limit maximum markups so people can't just make a living off re-selling tickets. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006531751.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not saying ban all transactions but attempt to put a stop at price gouging and limit maximum markups so people can't just make a living off re-selling tickets. 

Yeah, the title of your OP says: "StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be **illegal** and considered scalping. "

Is your view changed?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006539092.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I should have included more info. I still haven't had anyone change what I meant. So maybe I needed to reword and say explicitly sales for profit need to be regulated.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006631622.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>That's VERY different from "StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal."

This is not just re-wording.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006636658.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I touched on this in a different response.

"I'll agree I should have made a better title and explained that I meant specifically in cases for profit (when I posted it I wasn't even thinking of transactions that don't result in huge payouts, my bad.)"

The OP title is a bit misleading I understand but I do explain my issue in the description better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006533866.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't price gouging. It is more supply and demand. If people really want to see a show they will pay those prices. If they don't they won't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007331356.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic scalping should be legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007418633.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>You make no sense. 

Price gouging is when you take a need and jack up the price. Going to see a concert isn't a need. people will spend as much as they are willing to spend. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007445394.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, are you actually defending scalpers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28007566547.0" user="lost_send_berries" delta="False">
    <text>Scalping is and should be legal, it's called the right of first sale.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
