<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="218083246.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lua3y/cmv_fire_departments_usa_shouldnt_be_able_to_bill/">
    <title>CMV: Fire departments (USA) shouldn't be able to bill people/companies for fighting fires, rescuing people or doing any other aspect of their job.</title>
    <original_poster>chrislstark</original_poster>
    <original_post>Lately I've seen an increase in news stories of individuals and companies being handed multi thousand dollar bills because the fire department had to come do their job. First it was just for people who were doing malicious or criminal things (like setting off illegal fireworks). Then I started seeing them for people doing stupid but not illegal things (like trying to drive across a fast moving river or kill a spider using a lighter and a can of hairspray). But it has more recently been for people who are victims of accidents and people who tried to do things correctly and with the best of intentions (like the guy who fell off a cliff while on a mountain bike ride or the church who was fined after their model rocket science project malfunctioned and started a fire). 

I believe this is a dangerous trend. Fire departments are paid with tax dollars. If fire departments begin to rely on funds from individuals it becomes incentive to allow problems to get worse before coming to solve them because it means a bigger bill at the end. We have already seen this happen with police departments and traffic tickets. They used to be issued as a deterrent to dangerous behavior but now, since police departments rely on the revenue to even function properly, they are being issued for things that aren't even illegal with the knowledge that most people won't fight it. A red light camera investigation exposed several around the country as being intentionally timed to ticket people who ran the yellow and not the red. 

Fire departments should continue to be paid by tax dollars so they never have a monetary incentive to do their jobs poorly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28011522204.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>Fire departments have to get their funding from somewhere, and if they don't get enough through tax dollars, they'll charge you when they have to come put out a fire at your house. Firemen and policemen are public service jobs, and as such they don't tend to pay too well. It's not like this "dangerous trend" of "gouging" people's pockets has them rolling in dough. They may charge excessive amounts or silly fines, but it's not going towards lining their pockets, it's paying for their equipment and meager salaries. Fire fighting and police equipment is expensive, and tax dollars don't pay for it all. 

So we can either pay higher taxes so fire departments will get the funding they need, or let the people who use their services pay for it. It's a gamble, but I'd rather pay less tax and hope my house never catches on fire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011549141.0" user="chrislstark" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, then 100% of their funding should come from the people who use them and they should bill EVERYONE for their services, not just SOME people. Because currently there is no way of knowing in advance whether or not you'll receive a bill. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011569213.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>I'm admittedly not familiar with how fire departments bill people, whether they only bill certain people or just anyone who they respond to. It could very well be that they *do* bill everyone for their services, but only *some* people find the bill ridiculous and complain publicly about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011767826.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>Then the people who are being protected need to pay out in taxes; short of that what do you want?  Them working for free?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011841679.0" user="phcullen" delta="False">
    <text>Actually a lot of fire departments are volunteer </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011932370.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>True. But you're depending upon the expertise and altruism of free labor. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011985236.0" user="ductyl" delta="False">
    <text>And the trucks were donated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012584852.0" user="phcullen" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;what do you want? Them working for free?


I was just commenting on this not advocating for anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011801321.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>In many areas, fire departments are volunteer organizations not paid for by taxes.  In my area, you get a fixed bill/donation request at the beginning of the year.  If you pay the bill, you are covered for any fire that might happen.

If you don't buy in, they will still come when you call, but they bill you afterwards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011809213.0" user="DingleberryDouchebag" delta="False">
    <text>If you got a bill or know someone who did its  time you vote out your politicians and elect someone willing to address the problem.

Grow those grass roots.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011811454.0" user="WanderingIdiot2" delta="False">
    <text>I personally find it ridiculous that a country where its citizens pay billions and billions of dollars in tax money each year can't afford to fund fire departments and pay firemen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011839865.0" user="phcullen" delta="False">
    <text>Well fire departments and their funding are handled locally.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011943746.0" user="WanderingIdiot2" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that. But the taxes we pay we pay in exchange of services that we, as a society, need. I'm not American, but seeing how things are in America I believe that the taxes people pay don't go to serve them at all. The American people pay taxes and then pay for every essential from their own money and that makes no sense to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012075087.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  that makes no sense to me.

It's even more confusing from the inside.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013296247.0" user="WanderingIdiot2" delta="False">
    <text>I bet it is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011986854.0" user="ductyl" delta="False">
    <text>Well... we already spent the tax money on tanks... we could start giving them extra tanks like we do the police, do you think that would help? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012014693.0" user="WanderingIdiot2" delta="False">
    <text>$1.3 trillion and all you can afford is tanks. Man! Honestly, this conversation could only lead to a conversation about how tax money is spent and I guess this isn't about that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011818144.0" user="dazerdude" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that essential public services (like fire, police, and medical) should be fully paid for by public tax money because it is in the best interest of everyone to ensure that everyone should have these things be reliably available.

When you charge someone for fire service, it introduces doubt of whether they should call the fire department because they may not be able to afford it. This, at best, introduces delay into a system where reaction times matter a lot. Small increases in the time it takes for fire fighters to be on scene can easily cause a whole apartment or block to be consumed instead of merely an apartment.

Additionally wildfires (where there is no one to charge) can be reported and fought in a timely and effective manner before they threaten human settlements. Fighting the wildfires in eastern Washington right now wouldn't be even remotely possible without calling on and redeploying a large number of publicly funded fire fighters from around the country. There is no one to charge here except the tax payers, and it benefits everyone by preserving large natural timber reserves, national parks, and people's lives.

In this way paying taxes so that others can be safe (and public fires can be fought) actively protects your house from catching fire in the first place. Fire fighting is able to be *preventive* and not simply reactive in the way that your model is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
