<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="218083246.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lua3y/cmv_fire_departments_usa_shouldnt_be_able_to_bill/">
    <title>CMV: Fire departments (USA) shouldn't be able to bill people/companies for fighting fires, rescuing people or doing any other aspect of their job.</title>
    <original_poster>chrislstark</original_poster>
    <original_post>Lately I've seen an increase in news stories of individuals and companies being handed multi thousand dollar bills because the fire department had to come do their job. First it was just for people who were doing malicious or criminal things (like setting off illegal fireworks). Then I started seeing them for people doing stupid but not illegal things (like trying to drive across a fast moving river or kill a spider using a lighter and a can of hairspray). But it has more recently been for people who are victims of accidents and people who tried to do things correctly and with the best of intentions (like the guy who fell off a cliff while on a mountain bike ride or the church who was fined after their model rocket science project malfunctioned and started a fire). 

I believe this is a dangerous trend. Fire departments are paid with tax dollars. If fire departments begin to rely on funds from individuals it becomes incentive to allow problems to get worse before coming to solve them because it means a bigger bill at the end. We have already seen this happen with police departments and traffic tickets. They used to be issued as a deterrent to dangerous behavior but now, since police departments rely on the revenue to even function properly, they are being issued for things that aren't even illegal with the knowledge that most people won't fight it. A red light camera investigation exposed several around the country as being intentionally timed to ticket people who ran the yellow and not the red. 

Fire departments should continue to be paid by tax dollars so they never have a monetary incentive to do their jobs poorly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28011790613.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Fire departments need to do this to fund separate operations. I was inclined to agree with you for a long time, but on long term fires, firefighters must pay private parties to set up base camps etc. In no short order. For example on the rough fire out in California, Cal fire received a $60,000 bill from Hume lake for "use" of their facilities. This is in light of the fact that the fire fighters set up, to fight the fire that was threatening the hume property. Given that there was an evacuation notice etc. Hume didn't lose any revenue because the firefighters were there. They were simply allowed to levy a charge because they set up base camp on the property line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012806847.0" user="thiazzi1" delta="False">
    <text>This is just another side of why the money-grabbing system in which US fire departments operate is bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012874260.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>How so? Its not the fire departments fault that they need an operations base near the fire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012902449.0" user="thiazzi1" delta="False">
    <text>Here it's money-grabbing on the part of the private landowner. Much better to have a functioning society where the fire department and private entities aren't just trying to milk each other for cash and just do what needs to be done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013530952.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying you would prefer the alternative of forced requisition and eminent domain? If a private entity is being impeded on they deserve compensation. Alternatively, the government wielding eminent domain must be strictly enforced because the government cannot haphazardly take people's land from them, whatever the reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28014604408.0" user="thiazzi1" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying the government should have the power to seize land willy-nilly, I'm saying you're a massive dick if you demand $60,000 from the fire department for temporarily using your field as a base for fighting a huge fire. Sure, it's within their rights, but it's not culturally healthy for a society to work in that way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
