<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="218083246.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lua3y/cmv_fire_departments_usa_shouldnt_be_able_to_bill/">
    <title>CMV: Fire departments (USA) shouldn't be able to bill people/companies for fighting fires, rescuing people or doing any other aspect of their job.</title>
    <original_poster>chrislstark</original_poster>
    <original_post>Lately I've seen an increase in news stories of individuals and companies being handed multi thousand dollar bills because the fire department had to come do their job. First it was just for people who were doing malicious or criminal things (like setting off illegal fireworks). Then I started seeing them for people doing stupid but not illegal things (like trying to drive across a fast moving river or kill a spider using a lighter and a can of hairspray). But it has more recently been for people who are victims of accidents and people who tried to do things correctly and with the best of intentions (like the guy who fell off a cliff while on a mountain bike ride or the church who was fined after their model rocket science project malfunctioned and started a fire). 

I believe this is a dangerous trend. Fire departments are paid with tax dollars. If fire departments begin to rely on funds from individuals it becomes incentive to allow problems to get worse before coming to solve them because it means a bigger bill at the end. We have already seen this happen with police departments and traffic tickets. They used to be issued as a deterrent to dangerous behavior but now, since police departments rely on the revenue to even function properly, they are being issued for things that aren't even illegal with the knowledge that most people won't fight it. A red light camera investigation exposed several around the country as being intentionally timed to ticket people who ran the yellow and not the red. 

Fire departments should continue to be paid by tax dollars so they never have a monetary incentive to do their jobs poorly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28011784588.0" user="alkyjason" delta="False">
    <text>I live in California and there have been numerous times where people have been stuck on the side of a mountain or stranded in a flood control channel during a flash flood. Sometimes it's a genuine accident that they end up in those predicaments and other times it's out of the persons own sheer stupidity. As a taxpayer I should not have to foot the bill when people decide to pull stupid stunts. Those people should be accountable and pay for their own idiocy. 

Another example is when somebody reports their little brat kid missing and a massive manhunt ensues. This involves personnel, search-and-rescue dogs, people on horseback, ATV's, helicopters, etc. and then it turns out "Oh, ha-ha, cute little Billy was hiding in the attic the entire time, what an adorable little prankster". Screw that. The family should absolutely be billed &amp;amp; forced to pay. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011921828.0" user="D3gr33" delta="False">
    <text>I'm kind of on the fence with your second example.

Do we really want a situation where parents think their kid is missing and then wait to call the fire department or police because they don't want to get fined?

What's especially fucked up is how this will disproportionately affect the poor. If a rich kid goes missing, the parents can just call the cops and get them searching. If it ends up being nothing, then they can just pay the fine. But if a poor kid goes missing, the parents might only have enough money for rent that month OR to pay the fine if they're wrong that their kid is missing.

While your suggestion doesn't seem terribly unreasonable at first, we have to consider that this leads to a system where children of rich parents will be more likely to be searched for than parents of poor parents. That's really fucked up. 

Maybe we could have the fine be a percentage of income? That would at least help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28011983352.0" user="ductyl" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe we just tax Billy 1% of his income for the remainder of his life. That'll teach him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012124817.0" user="WinglessFlutters" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, parents should wait to call the fire department or police. They should wait a reasonable amount of time, or enough to know something abnormal has occurred.

Billying in the attic was obviously an incorrect use of community resources. Parents should have checked for Billy, and frankly the Police/Fire Dept should also check in the obvious places, like the house, for Billy as well before starting a search.

We're trying to use our resources efficiently, so that those who need them have them available, and yes, that means that Police/Fire Dept should probably not be the first course of action.

The cost thing is tough. This is why taxes exist, and if taxes don't cover it, then taxes need to be increased in order that they do. Without basic services covering the entire community, we've gone full Somalia.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013456502.0" user="simonjp" delta="False">
    <text>If Billy's missing and he was abducted, surely every minute counts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013617180.0" user="WinglessFlutters" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, if Billy is missing or abducted. But, not if Billy is reading quietly in the closet. Then, instead of searching helping someone who needs it, we waste resources searching for someone who doesn't need it.

Limited resources need prioritization to accocate them efficiently. Otherwise, they're unavailable when they're needed. Hospitals call it triage, and it's rather accepted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013625730.0" user="simonjp" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely. So by calling the authorities quickly they can help triage the situation- no doubt by asking if the house had been searched, probably to search the house themselves. They'd want to do this themselves anyway, so why not get that done ASAP?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013685209.0" user="WinglessFlutters" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think an appropriate full sequence would be, and at what point should a parent call the police? 

I think that it's obvious that there are situations in which the police should not be the first step.  I believe you also see this, and we're babbling to each other about semantics when there's really a very large common ground.

If I hear a child crying, the first step should NOT be to call emergency services. It should be to assess the situation, and determine whether that's warranted.  The vast majority of crying children do not need emergency services.


If a child doesn't come to the dinner table when called, the first step should NOT be to call emergency services. It should be to assess the situation, and look for them.  The vast majority of children not showing up to dinner also do not need emergency services.

[Emergency services are there for critical public safety issues](http://www.911.gov/911-issues/using.html), not personal inconveniences.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013734521.0" user="simonjp" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I totally agree. I just wouldn't want to think that there was any hesitation by a family in crisis because of a potentially ruinous bill. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012077752.0" user="WalterFStarbuck" delta="False">
    <text>In no small part I agree with you. People that unreasonably strain city and state resources should be made to pay some amount to cut down on how often that happens.

But I think you should also recognize that helicopter crews must remain 'current.' That is, they have to fly every so often to maintain their skills. That's actually in federal regulations for licensing for everyone from rescue pilots down to your average private pilot. They all need regular flight hours. And you as the taxpayer are going to pay for those hours whether the pilot is actively on a SAR flight or flying patterns or patrolling the city. SAR personnel (cops, rangers, etc...) have to be doing something all day. Sure if they're off on an erroneous search that's ultimately frustrating, but it is not much less valuable to the community than their daily work of patrolling or citing people for safety offenses. 

What would become a problem is if our SAR personnel, firefighters, etc... only responded to reported emergencies after everyone was really super certain there was a real emergency (X number of calls on the same thing, X days missing, etc...). Going out on a false alarm and listing the hours as a training exercise and using it to improve procedures is a better outcome than not being able to stop a fire in time because you waited too long to start fighting it or someone dying in the woods because they were stranded for days without needed medical attention.

People can (and should) always be smarter about how they take risks with their life and the lives of others, but we pay taxes for emergency services specifically so they are available at a moment's notice to rescue us from a situation we can't stop ourselves. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012445814.0" user="nrhinkle" delta="False">
    <text>Also worth mentioning in the Search and Rescue example that the vast majority of SAR responders are volunteers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012808353.0" user="thiazzi1" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty sure that if a police department uses *armoured vehicles* to search for a missing child, it's them being excessive, not the family.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28012829479.0" user="alkyjason" delta="False">
    <text>But I never mentioned armored vehicles?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28013277765.0" user="FlamingSwaggot" delta="False">
    <text>I think he is unclear on what an atv is</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
