<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="218083246.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lua3y/cmv_fire_departments_usa_shouldnt_be_able_to_bill/">
    <title>CMV: Fire departments (USA) shouldn't be able to bill people/companies for fighting fires, rescuing people or doing any other aspect of their job.</title>
    <original_poster>chrislstark</original_poster>
    <original_post>Lately I've seen an increase in news stories of individuals and companies being handed multi thousand dollar bills because the fire department had to come do their job. First it was just for people who were doing malicious or criminal things (like setting off illegal fireworks). Then I started seeing them for people doing stupid but not illegal things (like trying to drive across a fast moving river or kill a spider using a lighter and a can of hairspray). But it has more recently been for people who are victims of accidents and people who tried to do things correctly and with the best of intentions (like the guy who fell off a cliff while on a mountain bike ride or the church who was fined after their model rocket science project malfunctioned and started a fire). 

I believe this is a dangerous trend. Fire departments are paid with tax dollars. If fire departments begin to rely on funds from individuals it becomes incentive to allow problems to get worse before coming to solve them because it means a bigger bill at the end. We have already seen this happen with police departments and traffic tickets. They used to be issued as a deterrent to dangerous behavior but now, since police departments rely on the revenue to even function properly, they are being issued for things that aren't even illegal with the knowledge that most people won't fight it. A red light camera investigation exposed several around the country as being intentionally timed to ticket people who ran the yellow and not the red. 

Fire departments should continue to be paid by tax dollars so they never have a monetary incentive to do their jobs poorly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28013839591.0" user="bleahbloh" delta="False">
    <text>well this is a problem because the fire departamentes are not 100% private and get funded by insurance companys

your house is on fire and you dont have a insurance bad luck

your kid got lost and you dont have a insurance bad luck

etc</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
