<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28036006284.0" user="dantheman91" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of speech is entirely different. Freedom of Speech allows people to perform an ACTION without having to worry about being arrested for having a differing opinion. Without freedom of speech, the day to day activities of people would change. The government would be oppressing people by making it so they can't DO something.

Freedom of privacy is something that's nice to think you have. You already don't. Do you work for a company? They can go through your company computer, communications and anything else. Do you use Gmail? Google already goes through everything. Do you use facebook? Same deal. Do you use a cellphone provider? They have logs of messages. Logs of calls. 

The only difference is that it would be the government who has access to this information as well. Since you're still using these services, you've already established you don't care that much if SOMEONE has that data. Why should this change anything? There will still be protocols in place for who can use this information. If law enforcement doesn't get the courts approval, they shouldn't be able to use this in a court case. 

Then since we've established the information is already out there, why do you really care? The government doesn't care what you do. Saying that they could then crack down on (Insert Illegal activity here) is a terrible argument. They are breaking the law. If you disagree, you have an issue with the LAW, not with the fact we enforce those laws. 

Think of all of the good you could do. Would you like it if theoretically we could take every meth dealer off the street? If we could stop an attack on our country, would that not be worth it? What if we could have stopped 9/11, but in exchange you have to let the government have access to your data. What if they couldn't use this data for anything other than national security. Would you be willing to trade that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
