<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28035405520.0" user="DesertstormPT" delta="False">
    <text>This would be how it would work in a perfect world but we don't live in one.

Actions have greater repercussions than words. Saying "I want to kill that bastard.", is quite different than actually doing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035485553.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>Hi, would you mind further explaining your point? I can't connect how it's relevant without making some assumptions to what you might be suggesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035535244.0" user="DesertstormPT" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of action, is linked to freedom of privacy, is linked to freedom of speech.

There's an old saying *my freedom ends where another man's begins*. We need to draw the line somewhere on what is and is not acceptable. 

Words are harmless (for the most part), when it comes to actions it's a different story. People can cause permanent direct changes in reality through actions. 

If these changes are good we'd all be fine with them, but if you think about this for a second you realize it's not so linear, what's good for you might not be what's good for me, so who defines what's good? We can both stand by our points freely and express them without much effect in reality, but if and when we take action bad things can happen.

And this is the problem, when it comes to privacy we're talking about predicting situations where people might act in detriment of others, since we don't have the ability to look into the future or change the past.

If you want to be able to predict these things before they happen, openess and access to all available information is essential.

The alternative being keep being subject to the aformentioned *bad* situations and deal with them after they happen. At which point it's a matter of picking your poison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036294490.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; when it comes to privacy we're talking about predicting situations where people might act in detriment of others

So, I think you are right but you somehow implicitly state that this predicting situations is only limited to harmful "action" that might lead to hurting others. I'd say that when it comes to privacy we're also talking about giving the government the power to know how I plan on exercising my right to free speech.

So, the harmful action that I am planning may not be to perform a mass shooting but to hold a rally against some unjust governmental policy. The government can now effectively preemptively silence or discredit me. You are assuming that granting the government this power means they will have the best interests of the people but overlook the possibility that the best interest of the people may not be the same as the best interest of the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036346893.0" user="DesertstormPT" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You are assuming that granting the government this power means they will have the best interests of the people.

I'm not, and this is indeed a problem, who should have such power and to what extend could they act upon it, only an entity that is itself completely open to scrutiny and regulation should be given that power.

I'm completely against it if we're talking about a one-sided game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036389346.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, okay. Then I think we're in agreement on some things. In an ideal world... yeah, maybe this would be a great idea, but then, so is socialism. A huge problem with both is corruption. This debate definitely needs to be had because we are at the point that the technology exists (and I'm hugely grateful to Edward Snowden that we are able to have it) but think I've decided that in all current societies that the answer should definitely be to defend our right to privacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036412478.0" user="DesertstormPT" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A huge problem with both is corruption. 

Exactly, one aspect where I believe we would all benefit is if these things were much harder to hide or disguise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
