<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220687613.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ne3nh/cmv_rap_music_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Rap Music Sucks</title>
    <original_poster>chronicallyfailed</original_poster>
    <original_post>So it may just be that all the rap I've listened too has been bad, but I really can't think of a rap song or a song featuring rapping that isn't just unlistenably bad. 

The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs" - not that I have anything against songs about penises and drugs, just the way it seems to be done in rap that I've heard is just boastful and repetetive.

Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

But I don't really want to just dismiss rap music like that, so please explain to me how it's not shit, and examples of it not being shit would be nice too.

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28035439359.0" user="dub_agent" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs"

Or you can have double rhymes and consonent heavy lyrics delivered without taking a breath.

&amp;gt; Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

What does qualify as music? One of the best tunes I ever heard was a rock beat with middle C on a piano being hammered to the beat over the top. I can't give you a link because it was *never* released. Practically all the music I like, if not independent, is underground.

&amp;gt; Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

99.85% of the music on my laptop doesn't have a video. I don't call that music, I call it multimedia entertainment.

Stay away from the mainstream, it's toxic.

Having had a quick peek at the other links on the comments, Stateside artists - this [guy](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qdECTKBWRZg) and this [guy](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p_SQEUZomug)(who runs house music these days) are from the UK.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
