<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220687613.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ne3nh/cmv_rap_music_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Rap Music Sucks</title>
    <original_poster>chronicallyfailed</original_poster>
    <original_post>So it may just be that all the rap I've listened too has been bad, but I really can't think of a rap song or a song featuring rapping that isn't just unlistenably bad. 

The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs" - not that I have anything against songs about penises and drugs, just the way it seems to be done in rap that I've heard is just boastful and repetetive.

Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

But I don't really want to just dismiss rap music like that, so please explain to me how it's not shit, and examples of it not being shit would be nice too.

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28034809111.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Since you asked for examples here's some stuff I was listening to just yesterday: 

* Mos Def - [Love](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kc8eD0prHIM)

* Black Star - [Thieves in the Night](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W5kBz7D3rHo&amp;amp;list=PLkXefTT68AlcHCQmHNuQQOXVvFCPLkXv3)

* Abhi the Nomad - [Fireflies](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2upzIl4L2RI)

* Tut - [Sunday Service](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zx8ZcRXGcqQ)

You know that music video rap? Most of it is complete trash, in my opinion. You need to listen to some better rap. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28034812570.0" user="chronicallyfailed" delta="False">
    <text>I think that might be the issue, yeah, I've only ever really been exposed to the super-mainstream, super crappy kind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28034817580.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's probably what's happening. Just like there's lots of really great country music people base their entire opinions on the music of just a few people. I guess that's just how it works. ¯\\\_(ツ)_/¯</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035091265.0" user="Outofmyelephant" delta="False">
    <text>Take a listen to some of these as well:

Intelligent

Aesop Rock - [Labour Days complete album](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5DezrSOSR8)

Greydon Square - [Stockholm Syndrome](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l2yjpYz3Uc8) - If you're not an atheist you might not consider this so intelligent I guess.


A Bit of Fun

HilltopHoods - [Cosby Sweater](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aB16fJpoj-I)

Prof - [Bar Breaker](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KoMQBeaDNlc)

Political

Immortal Technique - [Revolutionary Vol. 2 full album](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CH3HnokBh8g)

Brother Ali - [Mourning in America](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dKHsGh-y8d8)

Edit: To be clear, I just wanted to point out how that there is variety in hip hop, some sucks, some is amazing. unless you just don't like Hip Hop which some don't, I'm not a fan of Country music or the vast majority of Pop, such is life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035104500.0" user="JSRambo" delta="False">
    <text>I was just about to link [Dance with the Devil](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qggxTtnKTMo) by Immortal Technique, which is a heart-wrenching and extremely well-told story. Point of No Return from Revolutionary Vol. 2 (which was posted above) is the other example that immediately came to mind. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28311993519.0" user="illSeeMyselfOutNowOk" delta="False">
    <text>I felt the way OP a long time ago but then found Aesop Rock and Immortal Technique.

Thanks for the introduction to Greydon Square

edit: oops this is four months old.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28312096627.0" user="Outofmyelephant" delta="False">
    <text>No worries, glad you like it. Greydon is definitely part of my permanent rotation. Though I haven't listened to his most recent two albums. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
