<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28036006003.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>While both are important things, I think you don't really gain much by trying to analogize between these two, because they are fundamentally different. The abstractions will always be "leaky".

Now, if your intent is to just spur conversation, there's nothing wrong with leaky abstractions... they can generate tons of conversation. But if you're trying to really *understand* something, they generally get in the way.

1) Freedom of speech is the right to do something. Freedom of privacy is a misnomer, because it's not a "freedom" at all. It's a protection against someone else doing something. 

2) Even if you have nothing to say, you still have the *right* to speak. However, in many cases if you actually *do* have something to hide, the government *does* have the right and power to find it out. 

Freedom of privacy can be (and must be) violable based simply on reliable information of wrongdoing. This is why we have warrants. The kind of protection needed for privacy necessarily has these kinds of relatively weak holes in it. 

Violating freedom of speech, on the other hand, requires an entirely different level of compelling government interest.

3) On the other side of things, freedom of speech does not protect you against charges of libel. There are things you can do with speech, purely as speech, that have to be illegal to protect others from genuine consequences of your speech.

Privacy, on the other hand, can't harm anyone by the nature of it being private at all. There's always something *else* that you have to do to actually harm someone... privacy alone cannot do it. 

4) Freedom of speech is inherently inalienable. No action you can take actually can give up freedom of speech (as a general freedom...of course you can agree not to speak about something, but that doesn't make it impossible for you to do so in any way). However, you can easily give up privacy voluntarily, and conclusively, and billions of people do this every day. 

Basically, both rights are important, but they are very different. Very different arguments have to be made regarding the boundaries of how much of each you have. Very different actions can affect them. Etc. Etc.

It's a good conversation starter, but it's really not very accurate to say that they are the same.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
