<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220687613.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ne3nh/cmv_rap_music_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Rap Music Sucks</title>
    <original_poster>chronicallyfailed</original_poster>
    <original_post>So it may just be that all the rap I've listened too has been bad, but I really can't think of a rap song or a song featuring rapping that isn't just unlistenably bad. 

The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs" - not that I have anything against songs about penises and drugs, just the way it seems to be done in rap that I've heard is just boastful and repetetive.

Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

But I don't really want to just dismiss rap music like that, so please explain to me how it's not shit, and examples of it not being shit would be nice too.

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28034789694.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I can't make you like anything, but what was the last rap song you listened to? Big penises and drugs haven't really been a staple of rap for like a decade now.

I think it's interesting that "gangsta rap" is the rap everyone is talking about when they deride the genre. It's a huge genre filled with tons of artists who rap about all sorts of things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28034797460.0" user="chronicallyfailed" delta="False">
    <text>Last rap song I listened to was this: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W7FfCJb8JZQ , which I actually thought must have been a parody it seemed so ridiculous. Just the camera and the posturing and the dancing and the clothes, everything really.

Other than that, this https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IGKug8fiQjo , which I actually thought was quite good, although it only had a tiny bit of rap at the end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28034910698.0" user="LadeyAceGuns" delta="False">
    <text>Busta Rhymes is actually a fairly silly rapper, and that song is from 2001, and the first single off of that album. So, you're judging it based on music fourteen years old now. Alot of the music videos from that time were absolutely absurb.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035538774.0" user="chronicallyfailed" delta="False">
    <text>I thought that might be the case. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035077538.0" user="hellshot8" delta="False">
    <text>you cant pick the worst songs in a genre of music and base all of that genre off it. I could do that for literally any genre of music you enjoy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035538601.0" user="chronicallyfailed" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I'm not doing that intentionally, it's just I've never seen, for whatever reason, anything other than the shit songs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
