<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28035020424.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>There is a pretty substantial difference between the right to privacy and the right to free speech. The right to privacy restricts what the cops allowed to do to find those who are committing wrongdoings, whereas the right to free speech creates a new wrongdoing. The right to privacy deals with the executive branch whereas right to free speech is legislative (although there is obviously overlap).

This is a massive difference. You are saying that not wanting a bigger police presence in areas with lots of bars (increasing executive power to prosecute) is the same as making alcohol illegal (restricting what people can do).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035054382.0" user="MoonbirdMonster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are saying that not wanting a bigger police presence in areas with lots of bars (increasing executive power to prosecute) is the same as making alcohol illegal (restricting what people can do).

I never mentioned the police, I'm saying that if you allow your data/information to be controlled, you will eventually lose your other rights. They're kind of one and the same, if you give up free speech, you won't be allowed to voice dissent when Big Brother shows up to watch you in the shower, just to be sure you aren't doing anything wrong, I mean, why would you when *you have nothing to hide?* ;)

The right to privacy is not limited to "what cops are allowed to do to find those committing wrongdoings." It's the idea that a man should be able to sit at home, by himself, without wondering if he's being watched. He might mutter to himself about how he hates how money runs the country and the people don't matter. But uh oh, here comes the thought police, "*WARNING, DETECTING USER DISSENT, EXECUTING PROCESS 25*" \*lasers*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035083219.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument in the title is:

 1. People should object to loss of right of privacy even they don't commit crimes.
 2. People should object to loss of freedom of speech even if they don't say things that would be considered unacceptable.
 3. The above relationships are the same, thus they are both right or both wrong.
 4. 2 is right, thus 1 is right.

My argument is that premise 3 is wrong, since in 1. A crime has already been committed, whereas in 2. Something that was previously permitted is now illegal. That is substantially different.

In your comment you are saying that allowing data to be controlled will lead to losing all your other rights.

 Firstly, that is a totally different argument than your title. 

Secondly, your examples are red herrings since they only talk about what happens when you lose free speech. If you really had the goverment executing people for dissent they don't need to know all your information to do that (see any totalitarian government anywhere). The problem is that they are restricting free speech, not that they are intruding on your privacy. 

Thirdly, to be consistent that means you think anytime we make more information available to the government, we are losing other rights. Do you also believe compulsory census is causing us to lose rights, which allows the government and researchers to better tailor social programs? What about tax info IRS needs to do its job? What about traffic cameras which allow the government to better predict traffic flow and make your commute faster? Is that making you a peon of the government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035099910.0" user="MoonbirdMonster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People should object to loss of right of privacy even they don't commit crimes.

I never said anybody has to commit crimes. You can be for right to privacy without being a criminal.

I will admit that I changed the argument in my comment, that wasn't my intention. However, here
&amp;gt;since in 1. A crime has already been committed

You state that a crime is the only place where privacy exists. (In order for there to be a loss of privacy, a crime must be committed.) I suppose the real problem is when governments are not transparent about their activities.

\*To add to the above point, things like census info, tax info, and traffic info are targeted at a singular subject with a limited scope of data they collect (they are designed specifically to BE limited in that regard). What we have in the surveillance Snowden spoke of is potentially unlimited specificity from data sources that encompass well past the majority of all modern communication. Additionally, in the examples you gave, the government tells us of what information they are collecting and the methods of collection. Obviously transparency was strictly against protocol when it came to management of this new surveillance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035184076.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>In your own comment, "nothing to hide" implies you aren't a criminal. Obviously you can have a right to privacy without being a criminal.

My point was in 1. The loss of privacy does not turn a legal action into an illegal action, it instead gives more powers to cops to investitgate those actions. Whereas in 2. Freedom of speech being curtailed means a legal action (saying your mind) is now illegal, which is a whole different ball game.

For the last point, you are saying a general principle that more information for the government curtails our rights. If you don't think that is true for small scale, current programs, you have to justify why it is different for large programs. Where on the scale from census to traffic cams to credit card data to cellphone metadata to reading all your texts does it go from benign to harmful?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035220180.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>Just chiming in because I'm interested in this debate. I'd say that revoking the right to privacy makes trying to encrypt data from your government illegal. It's not a right that's as exercised as speaking freely but it is similarly turning a legal action illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035312583.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure that is true, since it happens currently all the time. (See Blackberry encryption being used everywhere, and surely if it was illegal they would just deny the phone from being sold)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035464184.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand me. I was commenting on your point here:

&amp;gt; My point was in 1. The loss of privacy does not turn a legal action into an illegal action

Yes, currently with the right to privacy, it is not illegal for Blackberry to make their platform encrypted. However, if the government started infringing on that right (as they have done with other large companies), then it would become illegal for Blackberry to encrypt their users data, or to refuse to share that upon governmental request.

All I'm saying is that your argument doesn't hold up. Taking away either the right to free speech and/or the right to privacy turns a legal action into an illegal one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
