<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220687613.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ne3nh/cmv_rap_music_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Rap Music Sucks</title>
    <original_poster>chronicallyfailed</original_poster>
    <original_post>So it may just be that all the rap I've listened too has been bad, but I really can't think of a rap song or a song featuring rapping that isn't just unlistenably bad. 

The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs" - not that I have anything against songs about penises and drugs, just the way it seems to be done in rap that I've heard is just boastful and repetetive.

Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

But I don't really want to just dismiss rap music like that, so please explain to me how it's not shit, and examples of it not being shit would be nice too.

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28040937286.0" user="xxelinaxx" delta="False">
    <text>Rap itself is not shit. Mainstream rap however has become really shitty indeed. I really like rap but it's so hard to find good artists nowadays. 

When I was younger I used to listen to Eminem a lot. He had great songs and still continues to release good stuff.

From his old songs I recommend:
-Lose yourself https://vimeo.com/60259400 
-Mockingbird https://vimeo.com/71118898 (he wrote this for his daughter)

This is a newer song which is one of my favorites:
-Legacy: https://vimeo.com/78224432 
He's rapping about how he was bullied at school and how he overcome it. 
I prefer rap songs like these that tell a story that you can relate to. Not all rap songs are about doing drugs and having sex.

Sometimes I find good artists on youtube too like 

Mic Righteous - Wild Boyz
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iITY2Xelwmk

-Ghost Town
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pvGemBlLNwQ


Or what I love these days is korean rap music.
(Before you judge give it a try)

Drunken Tiger /Tiger J.K - 8:45
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NEEHmN504yM
He wrote this for his grandma who died at 8:45. 
This is the official music video but if you are curious about the lyrics check this out: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hN-65fyy2eA
It's a very emotional song.

Or "Outsider" he's the fastest rapper in Korea 

-Hand
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=udN5ocjq8RY

-Acquaintance
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8CHp4j6bbaQ

Okay I know this goes into a totally different direction but it's still rap and I enjoy it. 

I like this a lot more than Techno or Dubstep music that has no meaning at all.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
