<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28035204080.0" user="YerroRiceJr" delta="False">
    <text>be super careful of your choice of wording. saying "i dont care" is not the same as "i dont need." In this case, because you are referring to i dont care, the counter argument is super simple:
no matter how much you dont care, you still have the freedom of speech and the freedom of privacy, you wont lose them just because you dont care. No if's and but's. No harm to anybody, all it is, is that you voiced your opinion using the 1st admendment that you dont care. doesnt affect anything.

however, saying i dont need is where things go apeshit. i dont need the right of privacy, or i dont need the right of speech. the difference is in their progress. In the freedom of speech, the more you say, the more the Government operates to achieve your desires/needs, even if it means to cleanse itself (like impeaching a president). In freedom of privacy, the more you keep to yourself, the more inactive the Governemnt is, because without information, there is no justification to make new laws that would value the people or the nation itself. Now if i dont need privacy, and thus allow the government to intervene on our personal lives, they could collect the information designed to safegaurd our lives, even if it means opressive governments. if i dont need freedom of speech, than the Government will be unable to voice our opinions, and thus no new laws can be establish unless the desires of the people are heard. note that if in any scenario combining freedom of speech and right of privacy, if i dont have freedom of speech, than i would have right of privacy and vice versa. 

overall, you cant say both are the same in concept. If people dont speak, governments cant represent. this includes voting, paying taxes, talking, they all constitute as a form of communication between us and the governenment. if people dont care for privacy, governemnts can extract communication from people. This includes what people search in the internet for, where people live, their bank security, everything. This allows the governemnt to function arbitarary to the people's desire, by opening a form of communication. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
