<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220687613.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ne3nh/cmv_rap_music_sucks/">
    <title>CMV: Rap Music Sucks</title>
    <original_poster>chronicallyfailed</original_poster>
    <original_post>So it may just be that all the rap I've listened too has been bad, but I really can't think of a rap song or a song featuring rapping that isn't just unlistenably bad. 

The lyrics, even when they're not breathtakingly sexist and homophobic, tend to be boring, unimaginative crap along the lines of "my penis is big and I do drugs" - not that I have anything against songs about penises and drugs, just the way it seems to be done in rap that I've heard is just boastful and repetetive.

Musically, I just hear incessant, grating melodies played over a shitty drumbeat while someone talks over the top of it. A lot of the time I don't really see how it qualifies as music.

Also, the amount of ridiculous, pretentious crap in the music videos just makes it hard for me to take them seriously at all.

But I don't really want to just dismiss rap music like that, so please explain to me how it's not shit, and examples of it not being shit would be nice too.

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28034842811.0" user="SticklerMrMeeseeks" delta="False">
    <text>You aren't alone in your thought process, but you are off base, I'd argue. 2015 has been hailed as one of the greatest years for hip-hip in 2 decades. There are so many examples of brilliant artists putting out game-changing music. Though if you think rap "is all about big dicks and money" then I'm not sure that alone would convince you of anything. Frankly, I don't think you've given it an adequate chance - you seem to be operating based off of a very limited perspective and have not put much effort into exploring beyond it. It takes 2 seconds to google "best rappers" and you'll find some of the best poetry of the last 30 years.

 If you're looking for current hip-hop, Kendrick Lamar fits the bill for generally accessible and classically talented. [How Much a Dollar Cost](http://youtu.be/fJT3b4urwcU) is a great example of conscious rap and storytelling. Now, he also has songs about dicks and money: that's part of the culture. Understanding *that* requires you to understand an inner-city lifestyle and history that, no offense, I'm guessing you don't have right now. Hip-hop is so much intertwined with black culture, masculinity, violence, and other themes which you don't seem to be overwhelmingly well-versed on. 

Now, you can easily find many songs that focus on *none* of those things. Plenty of rappers talk *only* of their story, their life. And that's usually how many people begin getting into the genre. But when you really allow yourself to understand hip-hop, it's influences, it's history - you begin to see why certain songs you've treated as "trash" before may not be. You begin to see why talking about "bitches, gang violence, cars, etc." does not necessarily diminish the quality of the song or the artist. Now, I should emphasize that there is indeed terrible rap songs out there, as with any genre. Metal, pop, country, no genre is immune to having shit. But you shouldn't let that prevent you from exploring a genre deeper. Especially not write it off entirely by just saying "it sucks."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
