<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2226173922.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/10temsi/cmv_human_reliance_is_the_greatest_bottleneck_to/">
    <title>CMV: Human Reliance is the Greatest Bottleneck to Individual Freedom</title>
    <original_poster>GenoHuman</original_poster>
    <original_post>Human reliance is one of the greatest bottlenecks to individual freedom, as it places limitations on the choices and actions individuals can make. This is because people require time and salary to produce the things they need or want, which can restrict their ability to express themselves and experience life to the fullest. AI on the other hand can rid us of these limitations and produce things for us quickly and cheaply.

A modern example of this is AI art, most artists dislike this idea but there is no denying that millions (or even billons) of people now have the capability to produce art to their own liking (to varying degrees) that would never have been possible before. Another example is [Elevenlabs.io](https://elevenlabs.io/) that can copy and recreate perfect human voices from a single minute of audio sample. This allow me as an individual to listen to a voice that I like and create new content with it that would not have been possible before.

I think there is this idea going around that things cannot be of high quality or worthwhile if it didn’t take a lot of effort to produce but this is a human thing and even then it isn’t always true either. A lot of our products are made quick and cheap by machines that we still enjoy regardless.  The conclusion to all of this is that the more automation you have the greater our individual freedom is to express ourselves and experience new things in life and it ought to expand into most if not every part of society when the time is right so we can produce anything we desire ourselves be it videogames, movies, music, conversations, voices, applications and so forth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41793118180.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>That's the optimistic version.  The more realistic version is that, as automation and AI increases in sophistication, we just see more job loss.  

Theoretically, something like outsourcing jobs overseas could have meant that we paid less for products or didn't have to work as many hours, or both, but neither happened.  Because the system doesn't work that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793258131.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>This is not a fault of AI or automation but with our underlying capitalism system. Getting rid of jobs is a desirable outcome because this forces the government to consider other options for a sustainable future that isn't driven by profits for the wealthy at the expense of the human race and our planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793439794.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>So you might say the underlying capitalist system is the real bottleneck</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793465361.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>No because capitalism only exist because we have to rely on people to produce.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793566980.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>So you're talking about a fully automated system ala Wall-E?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793572770.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Yes we replace humans with AI and machines to produce instead. My focus here was primarily on the creative side like art, music, movies and games but of course this includes everything in society, so yeah like WALL-E.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793615875.0" user="premiumPLUM" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's a whole other thing, I'm not sure how you don't see that.  Using AI to build CGI special effects more efficiently is one thing.  A self-sustaining society run completely by AI in which humans have no interaction (to the point that we don't even need engineers to maintenance any working part of it), is a beyond ridiculous scenario that could only be conceivably believable in a children's movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793727162.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Sure but we are phased out of these systems over a longer period of time and eventually we might reach something akin to WALL-E. We already have AI that can create human-like voices, art and conversations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41794906445.0" user="FullAutoLuxuryCommie" delta="False">
    <text>So your view is that "fully automated luxury communism" is the way forward. Look, I'm not against this, but it is HIGHLY hypothetical. We don't live in a world anywhere near what you're describing, so we have no way of knowing what the pitfalls would be. In WALL-E, for example, so much labor was extracted away that people were locked into their chairs because of their health. I think maybe not having full use of your limbs is a bigger impediment than reliance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793299727.0" user="AlwaysTheNoob" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Theoretically, something like outsourcing jobs overseas could have meant that we paid less for products or didn't have to work as many hours, or both, but neither happened.

I'd say it did keep costs down.  You think the Dollar Tree could exist solely on American-made products?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793308624.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed, that is a concern but at some point transition to automation at scale could be actively managed, that is regulated, to avoid those problems.

For example, require first automating production and delivery of necessities before implementing automation that "frees" people from having to work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
