<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2226173922.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/10temsi/cmv_human_reliance_is_the_greatest_bottleneck_to/">
    <title>CMV: Human Reliance is the Greatest Bottleneck to Individual Freedom</title>
    <original_poster>GenoHuman</original_poster>
    <original_post>Human reliance is one of the greatest bottlenecks to individual freedom, as it places limitations on the choices and actions individuals can make. This is because people require time and salary to produce the things they need or want, which can restrict their ability to express themselves and experience life to the fullest. AI on the other hand can rid us of these limitations and produce things for us quickly and cheaply.

A modern example of this is AI art, most artists dislike this idea but there is no denying that millions (or even billons) of people now have the capability to produce art to their own liking (to varying degrees) that would never have been possible before. Another example is [Elevenlabs.io](https://elevenlabs.io/) that can copy and recreate perfect human voices from a single minute of audio sample. This allow me as an individual to listen to a voice that I like and create new content with it that would not have been possible before.

I think there is this idea going around that things cannot be of high quality or worthwhile if it didn’t take a lot of effort to produce but this is a human thing and even then it isn’t always true either. A lot of our products are made quick and cheap by machines that we still enjoy regardless.  The conclusion to all of this is that the more automation you have the greater our individual freedom is to express ourselves and experience new things in life and it ought to expand into most if not every part of society when the time is right so we can produce anything we desire ourselves be it videogames, movies, music, conversations, voices, applications and so forth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41793314589.0" user="yogfthagen" delta="False">
    <text>You're talking about a post-scarcity economy. It's the utopian ideal that some point in the future, people will be able to have whatever they desire as the costs of producing anything will be so small that they won't matter. 

Ian Banks' Culture books and Star Trek are examples. 

The fundamental issues with us not hitting a post scarcity economy are that we don't have infinite resources, and that greed still appears to be infinite. A billionaire has no actual *need* to be a billionaire, but we still have hundreds of them who are degrading the living conditions of hundreds of millions (if not actual billions) of other people, simply so they can have more fun with their toys and projects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793385885.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>We don't have infinite resources in the physical world but digital content like movies, games, music, etc... is practically infinite but at this point severely limited due to human reliance in producing that content for us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793396242.0" user="yogfthagen" delta="False">
    <text>Time is also a limited resource. 

So is the equipment necessary to run the AI needed to produce that content.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41906749269.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>My 1060 6GB GPU (from 2016) can chew out more images per hour than a thousand artists combined. Which do you think require the most energy and which one uses that energy most efficiently?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41907594842.0" user="yogfthagen" delta="False">
    <text>How long to develop the AI, again? A person still needs to write the code. And what's the purpose of the images? Just a random set of images, or is there some kind of narrative you want to relay? So far, AI isn't very good at storytelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41907890703.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>How long it takes to write the code, excuse me? That's not how neural networks work, you train them by giving them data (images, voices, etc...), there is no coding involved in that process. 

Have you never heard of commissions? They are very common for artists to do and usually it's NSFW in nature like hentai, furry and other such content. Also there is a lot of work being put into img2video which is something artists cannot offer at all but soon AI will be able to take an image as input and create an entire video with that person or environment so there is a lot of value to get out of these systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41908023050.0" user="yogfthagen" delta="False">
    <text>Do you honestly think that if you just load a bunch of gifs into a computer that you will make a neutral network?  That the processing behind it happens by magic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41912471716.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>No, I literally said you train them by giving them data which is true. A company like OpenAI or Google build a large language model and then that can be used for well, everything and you can even build your own model on top of theirs with fine-tuned parameters and so forth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793790537.0" user="Shooshooxx" delta="False">
    <text>I so agree. We seem to think happiness lies in having/doing everything we want. True happiness is in interrelating with others and bringing them happiness. A big struggle for billionaires...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
