<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2226173922.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/10temsi/cmv_human_reliance_is_the_greatest_bottleneck_to/">
    <title>CMV: Human Reliance is the Greatest Bottleneck to Individual Freedom</title>
    <original_poster>GenoHuman</original_poster>
    <original_post>Human reliance is one of the greatest bottlenecks to individual freedom, as it places limitations on the choices and actions individuals can make. This is because people require time and salary to produce the things they need or want, which can restrict their ability to express themselves and experience life to the fullest. AI on the other hand can rid us of these limitations and produce things for us quickly and cheaply.

A modern example of this is AI art, most artists dislike this idea but there is no denying that millions (or even billons) of people now have the capability to produce art to their own liking (to varying degrees) that would never have been possible before. Another example is [Elevenlabs.io](https://elevenlabs.io/) that can copy and recreate perfect human voices from a single minute of audio sample. This allow me as an individual to listen to a voice that I like and create new content with it that would not have been possible before.

I think there is this idea going around that things cannot be of high quality or worthwhile if it didn’t take a lot of effort to produce but this is a human thing and even then it isn’t always true either. A lot of our products are made quick and cheap by machines that we still enjoy regardless.  The conclusion to all of this is that the more automation you have the greater our individual freedom is to express ourselves and experience new things in life and it ought to expand into most if not every part of society when the time is right so we can produce anything we desire ourselves be it videogames, movies, music, conversations, voices, applications and so forth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41795506708.0" user="iSilent_Nebula" delta="False">
    <text>So while ai and automation would certainly be a plus, it would ease production and availability guaranteed, we would still rely on people. Ai is as complex as human minds, and many have experimented with ai and emotional understanding. The posed problem is that, with such an unpredictable computerized mind, the ai could at any point determine itself as having free will. Then an endless string of what if scenarios, not what matters, at the end of the day to prevent ai overlords from becoming a thing, we rely on people, not another ai.

For debate sake, let's say we create an ai that is specifically for one task alone and has no chance of becoming an independent mind.
We rely on humans to update the ai as new demands come in. We rely on the humans to code the ai to start, and we rely on humans to make sure the ai functions without fault. We rely on humans to do finalized inspections on what this ai is producing, because no matter how perfect a computer is, knowing that a human with their own eyes inspected the product, and verified it is perfectly made is what brings people comfort.

Say I buy a car made by an ai and without any human involvement in the making of it. Sure I'd initially buy it and just trust it's made right, why sell it otherwise? The endless options come up, it could be perfectly made. Fine. It could have a small cosmetic fault. No problem I can fix it myself. Maybe it's a bit worse and it was missing a seat. That's not good I'll have to call about this. Perhaps it was a deadlier fault, it came without airbags and I didn't find out until getting into a wreck. No we have a serious legal problem. Who do we charge, the company or the ai itself. We can't hold a computer liable so we then turn to humans. We might not necessarily need to rely on other for everything, and say if Legos production was completely automated, I doubt anyone would complain. But when it comes to faults in ai that cause legal problems. Moral problems. Human problems, you can't automate human minds. They work on their own pace. 

We rely on humans to fix human problems. We can't hold ai legally accountable for anything, because it isn't a person. Humanity structured itself in a way that would cement itself. We can add ai to production of products, but humans are still responsible for the ai and the final products. 

If you have counter points I would love to hear.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
