<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2226173922.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/10temsi/cmv_human_reliance_is_the_greatest_bottleneck_to/">
    <title>CMV: Human Reliance is the Greatest Bottleneck to Individual Freedom</title>
    <original_poster>GenoHuman</original_poster>
    <original_post>Human reliance is one of the greatest bottlenecks to individual freedom, as it places limitations on the choices and actions individuals can make. This is because people require time and salary to produce the things they need or want, which can restrict their ability to express themselves and experience life to the fullest. AI on the other hand can rid us of these limitations and produce things for us quickly and cheaply.

A modern example of this is AI art, most artists dislike this idea but there is no denying that millions (or even billons) of people now have the capability to produce art to their own liking (to varying degrees) that would never have been possible before. Another example is [Elevenlabs.io](https://elevenlabs.io/) that can copy and recreate perfect human voices from a single minute of audio sample. This allow me as an individual to listen to a voice that I like and create new content with it that would not have been possible before.

I think there is this idea going around that things cannot be of high quality or worthwhile if it didn’t take a lot of effort to produce but this is a human thing and even then it isn’t always true either. A lot of our products are made quick and cheap by machines that we still enjoy regardless.  The conclusion to all of this is that the more automation you have the greater our individual freedom is to express ourselves and experience new things in life and it ought to expand into most if not every part of society when the time is right so we can produce anything we desire ourselves be it videogames, movies, music, conversations, voices, applications and so forth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41794438539.0" user="prasicleru4527" delta="False">
    <text>I've never heard someone with such unabashed misanthropy try and justify it like that. You say using AI would remove human limitations but the two examples you gave were using AI to replace a human characteristic, which is creativity. It's clear by your comments that you view those characteristics as positive but just want to remove the human aspect. Sounds a whole lot like "hey look, I can enjoy creativity thru art, music, video games, etc and hear a human voice but I don't want any of the human associated with it". A human voice is significant because it reflects a lived reality, not some inanimate computer program trying its best to imitate it. Art (incl. video games, music, visual arts, etc) can be understood in many ways, but I've never heard someone naive enough to interpret it without reflecting on its inherent HUMAN nature. You simply do not understand art. Honestly, I don't want people like you making decisions about the world. Therapy might be a good option.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
