<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2226173922.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/10temsi/cmv_human_reliance_is_the_greatest_bottleneck_to/">
    <title>CMV: Human Reliance is the Greatest Bottleneck to Individual Freedom</title>
    <original_poster>GenoHuman</original_poster>
    <original_post>Human reliance is one of the greatest bottlenecks to individual freedom, as it places limitations on the choices and actions individuals can make. This is because people require time and salary to produce the things they need or want, which can restrict their ability to express themselves and experience life to the fullest. AI on the other hand can rid us of these limitations and produce things for us quickly and cheaply.

A modern example of this is AI art, most artists dislike this idea but there is no denying that millions (or even billons) of people now have the capability to produce art to their own liking (to varying degrees) that would never have been possible before. Another example is [Elevenlabs.io](https://elevenlabs.io/) that can copy and recreate perfect human voices from a single minute of audio sample. This allow me as an individual to listen to a voice that I like and create new content with it that would not have been possible before.

I think there is this idea going around that things cannot be of high quality or worthwhile if it didn’t take a lot of effort to produce but this is a human thing and even then it isn’t always true either. A lot of our products are made quick and cheap by machines that we still enjoy regardless.  The conclusion to all of this is that the more automation you have the greater our individual freedom is to express ourselves and experience new things in life and it ought to expand into most if not every part of society when the time is right so we can produce anything we desire ourselves be it videogames, movies, music, conversations, voices, applications and so forth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41793498315.0" user="Such_Butterfly8382" delta="False">
    <text>To what end?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793529416.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Minimize suffering and maximize the ability for individuals to express themselves and experience novel things, something like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793775500.0" user="Such_Butterfly8382" delta="False">
    <text>One could argue that goal, minimize suffering and maximize experience could be achieved without this.

But to you, what is suffering and how does AI address? Maybe pick one thing so we’re concise. 

This will help explain the concept I am referring to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41793861032.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Suffering is doing something you don't want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41794490303.0" user="babyswean0409" delta="False">
    <text>Doing something you don't want to do isn't suffering, it's just either being lazy or unmotivated. I'd argue suffering is having a certain degree of unnecessary pain or stress enacted upon you either from an individual or a system. Would you consider doing the dishes as suffering when compared to a slave being whipped for not performing a task well enough?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42330739154.0" user="GenoHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Yes if you are forced to do the dishes each day I would consider that suffering, the fact that some suffer more than others is irrelevant because your personal experience is the only thing you know, a lot of people suffer horribly in this world yet I can still suffer sitting in an office all day or whatever it may be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42331922401.0" user="babyswean0409" delta="False">
    <text>I am forced to do the dishes every day and I don't suffer, it is a necessary task that needs completing and I recognize that while I would rather not do them, I am not suffering. You would really compare your "suffering" of "sitting in an office all day" to that of a slave? Or that of a farmer? You realize that you can talk to people and learn of their experiences and empathize and sympathize and come to the conclusion that maybe you don't have it so bad as you perceive? Maybe it could move the goalposts on your idea of suffering?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41797788121.0" user="Such_Butterfly8382" delta="False">
    <text>Ok fair enough. Have you ever not wanted to do something but then enjoyed it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
