<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28070643589.0" user="obviousoctopus" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to point out that all OP's comments have been downvoted. And that this post has over 100 comments but very low vote numbers. 

Obviously a controversial topic. 

Also, arguments keep repeating the point of sugar existing in many foods, ignoring OP's mention of added sugars. 

As for my opinion: OP, if you can sustain an (added) sugar-free diet, you will reap many benefits. I know I do as well as a few of my close friends. I cannot and do not want to change your opinion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28070859263.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I don't mind.  
I did go a bit too far and tried to single out added sugar in daily foods(not just snacks/sodas!) as the main culprit, which it isn't(but of course, it is one of big factors). Others argued that the market can be controlled by demand - something I don't quite believe, since addiction does play great part here.  
Lastly, the word "drug" is not the best here - so many people assumed I wanted to ban sugar severely or entirely - but as far as I know there is no better term.  
My thread fallen victim to poor phrasing, poor sourcing and too many assumptions on both sides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073957767.0" user="obviousoctopus" delta="False">
    <text>http://mobile.nytimes.com/blogs/well/2015/08/14/what-eating-40-teaspoons-of-sugar-a-day-can-do-to-you/?referer=

http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/subjects/s/sugar/index.html

Sugar is addictive, is harmful, is everywhere. The food industry uses it for its addictive qualities. And is scared to the point of bullying anyone trying to do anything about it, like the WHO. 

Your posts being downvoted into oblivion looks suspicious to me. Arguing is one thing, silencing your opponent is another. 

I hope you keep the conversation going, and not only on reddit. The best argument is living without it and sharing your experience. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
