<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28061585314.0" user="Holy_City" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean you cannot rely on the market to create a competitor to sugar? That's like saying you can't rely on the market to create a competitor to water or flour. It's fundamental to cooking. 

I bake bread. I put sugar in it to proof the yeast. My bread tastes good, and it's cheaper than buying store bought bread of the same quality. 

So if you regulate sugar, does that mean I can't bake bread anymore? Am I to be beholden to the prices and quality of only brands available at the store? 

Why is it the role of government to regulate our diets? Can we not make our own decisions? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061611426.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>No, you misunderstood. I did not refer to sugar as a raw product, merely added sugar, especially in soft drinks and other foods.  
Since sugar is so essential while being also a harmful drug, I do not advocate its ban, merely a reduction of added sugars daily products where they're not essential or u. 


It's not just a dietary concern, because you deal not with a mere food product but with a drug - it's hence a worldwide health concern.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062028034.0" user="Holy_City" delta="False">
    <text>What makes sugar in food or drink added? When I cook and I want something to be sweet, I put sugar in it. If I need to balance other flavors, I'll sometimes use sugar as well. If I'm making a drink like a mojito or homemade lemonade, I'll add simple syrup in order to sweeten it because it doesn't taste as good without. Why should flavor be shackled because of people who make unhealthy choices? 

It's no secret that sugar in excess is bad for you. And for kids who may not be as educated, then the honus is on their parents to do so or limit their access to such foods. It's not society's job to make up for lazy parenting and unhealthy decisions. 

So why should I, someone who responsibly enjoys sweet things, have access to less choices of what to eat and drink because some people make bad decisions? 

I can acknowledge our nation has problems with obesity. But I think a larger problem is that unhealthy foods are cheap. What I would suggest is by educating people on simple cooking, higher taxes on those unhealthy foods to make them a luxury, which they already are to an extent. Promote the healthy lifestyle and limit the unhealthy foods through incentives, but don't outright deny me access to the things I want occasionally. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062072123.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if a product has "sugar" added in the ingredients label, lol. My argument was never with raw sugar(as in white/brown sugar) or syrups or pastries or anything else that requires sugar by nature(bread to some extent, rice etc). Nor do I suggest a ban on any product(unless it's products for children)  
But do soft drinks *need* this much sugar to be tasty? No, they have it almost fully just to be more addictive.  
Do daily food products that used to have little to none sugar 30 years ago need that much sugar now? No, they don't. *That's* my point. To roll back on that and put upper limits on sugar added; if you want you can add more, but that doesn't mean anything that should be reasonably healthy can't be.  
It's common sense how you'd deal with an addicted person. If you'd meet an alcoholic and would want to convince him to give up drinking; do you think only educating him on alcohol is going to be sufficient, when his fridge and his local shop is filled with alcohol?  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063531283.0" user="MenaceInside" delta="False">
    <text>The main addiction in soda is usually the caffiene, not the sugar.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
