<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28061576915.0" user="Abohani" delta="False">
    <text>The link you provided on sugar being addictive is not a scientific paper but a blog and all it says is that sugar produces dopamine, from what I understand everything that feels good is related to serotonin and dopamine and the latter being responsible for addiction and repeating behavior, this is not limited to sugar, sugar is as addicting as anything in life that feels good including a healthy well prepared meal or winning a video game  .

I think the other understanding of addiction is consuming something that is naturally produced in the body and in time the body stops producing the substance naturally and so creates dependency, that doesn't seem to be the case with sugar .

I don't contend the idea that sugar content should be regulated (I am undecided) but the specific point about sugar being addicting is invalid . </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061618036.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I admit I did not take the time to make a good selection of sources.  
There was one fairly decent study made that proved that [cocaine is more addctive than sugar.](http://www.forbes.com/sites/jacobsullum/2013/10/16/research-shows-cocaine-and-heroin-are-less-addictive-than-oreos/)  
Like I said in other comments, I do not suggest a ban nor even a reduction on the raw product, merely make a stance on added sugars in most daily products, such as yoghurts, cereal, soft drinks, and so forth, not counting pastry products for instance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061620585.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>Why do pastries get a free pass?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061639306.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Because their main attractiveness is based on sugar. I think there would be a difference between regulating added sugars on soft drinks(which do not need as much sugar) as opposed to pastries which very often are *based* on sugar. The intent is important in my opinion; sugar is a core ingredient to pastries while it's only an extra addictive and extra satisfaction ingredient to most other foods. I do not believe the same argument can be made for the latter.  
Edit: Pastries also consider basic foods like bread, which are essential to most diets.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061643034.0" user="Abohani" delta="False">
    <text>I don't get what you mean by addictive because the release of dopamine is not unique to sugar and to think that it is a reason for regulation will lead to having everything pleasurable in life regulated.

The article discusses a study that says sugar is more addictive than cocaine (you have it reversed), The observation that the rats were more attracted to oreos than cocaine does not mean the conclusion is correct.

First Are oreos just sugar, for the experiment to be correct they should have tested it with plain white sugar or fructose .

Second opioids are produced in the body in small amounts and the addiction involves stopping this natural production, I don't think that is present in sugar. 

The article points to other research that contradict this notion 

&amp;gt;The idea that people can take or leave cocaine or heroin in the same way they can take or leave Oreos seems inconsistent with research that supposedly shows how powerfully reinforcing these substances are. Studies published between 1969 and 1985, for instance, found that rats and rhesus monkeys “will prefer cocaine to food” and “will self-administer cocaine until death or near-death,” as Stanton Peele and Richard DeGrandpre note in a 1998 Addiction Research article. But the animals in these studies were isolated from other animals, deprived of interesting stimuli, and prevented from engaging in normal behavior while tethered to catheters providing “an unlimited, direct flow of high concentrations of cocaine at all times at little or no cost” (in terms of effort). Research conducted in more naturalistic settings finds that monkeys and rats are much more apt to consume cocaine and morphine in moderation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061656618.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>True, I may have chosen poorly for the study, it's shaky at best now that I look at it deeper.  
[How about this one?](http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2235907/)
My apologies for poor choice of sources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061707039.0" user="Abohani" delta="False">
    <text>I am going to be completely honest here, I didn't read the whole article and I don't think I will because I can't muster the attention span and because it is pretty specialized with terms I don't understand.

What the researchers did is that they starved rats for about 12 hours, waited 4 more hours and then gave the rats soluble sugar and the rats overtime developed addictive behavior, my thoughts on this are as follows 

1- Why were not the rats divided to groups that are fed different kinds of food after the starving period ex : one group gets sucrose one fructose and one fat and one protein to view if a certain macro nutrient induce addiction more than other

2- The definition of addiction used by the researchers as they indicated in section "2. DEFINING ADDICTION" is the definition that I previously said can be applied to anything pleasurable, the researchers pointed to articles that describe sex and gambling addiction and there are papers pointing to the same mechanism in [videogames](http://journals.lww.com/journaladdictionmedicine/Abstract/2007/09000/Dopamine_Genes_and_Reward_Dependence_in.3.aspx) 


Given that anything pleasurable can be addictive I don't think this psychological addiction is a reason enough for something to be regulated, if I believed that I would think that everything should be regulated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061680368.0" user="hey_aaapple" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;that proved that cocaine is more addictive than sugar

That seems kinda obvious, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061683853.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Well I'm no cocaine user so I had no idea before making this thread :P I admit I learned a few things about sugar even whilst holding the opinion in the original post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061687885.0" user="hey_aaapple" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, cocaine is widely recognized as a drug, albeit far from being the most addictive one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061701236.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I think hard drugs are generally considered more or less comparably addictive and are not given serious thought when it comes to such differences given so few people use them.  
 
That's good to know. I'll make sure to remember when I'm treated to cocaine by friends, thanks.  
^^^^^^Justkidding:P
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
