<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28061716942.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>Um,  have you personally or any person you've ever met actually felt any high or addiction to it?  I sincerely doubt it. Salt makes food taste good and could be considered as "addictive" as sugar. Too much is also associated with negative health effects. Should we ban everything that can possibly harm you..... OR would it make much more sense to let people decide for themselves?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061730827.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I'm on a diet. Yes, I do feel symptoms of withdrawal. And yes, I did notice shops not selling pretty much anything healthy or without sugar which kind of motivated me to post this thread :D  
Salt is not addictive in the same way sugar is; you cannot physically salt in large amounts without killing yourself and excessive amounts of salt result in bad flavor, while "too sugary" is hardly a thing for most people.  
I never advocated banning anything, merely stopping the trend of increasing of added sugars in daily foods by introducing reductions and incentives/disincentives.  
Given how added sugar penetrated the society's diet, there is no "decision" or much "choice" to be made, as nearly everyone consuming added sugars is more or less addicted and the products introduced will only be more sugary over time; only a need to help the society be less so addicted and put a stop to this trend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061741703.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>Did your food hunt stay exclusive to bakeries and candy stores or what? You can't go down an aisle at the grocery store without seeing reduced sugar and health foods. It is very easy to not eat a sugar rich diet unless you subsist entirely on prepackaged foods.  I guess some people think it's better to think for others then let them make possibly poor decisions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061751478.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>No, just a general FMCG market.  
I think we're way past the "decision" point; people are obese - added sugars amount in daily produts is one of the main causes - and imo states should act now unless you're okay with your country being obese. (I'm not)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061761192.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>What on earth are you talking about? Everything you eat is your decision. If you want a low sugar diet it isn't difficult. I certainly concede sugar is used as a cheap filler, so processed foods are usually cheaper, but nobody is preventing you from buying ingredients and cooking. Why should a regulator remove my decision making ability when the product can easily be used appropriately? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061781199.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying the matter is not of a decision, because there's so few healthy choices as opposed to sugary/unhealthy ones and the former will never be mainstream solely because they're not as addictive(or cheap, when it comes to processed foods).  
When the mainstream daily products are unhealthy and are growing unhealthier by the year(given how much sugar is added and how much more there over the years when there is no need for as much or none), is it the consumer's decision to resign from daily foods for comparably much rarer dietary foods? It might seem silly Regardless, given the level of societal obesity, whose responsibility is it to deal with that issue? In my opinion, no level of education or decision making would help solve the general population's obesity; sugar should just not be so easily added to daily products and hence I believe the state should intervene or daily products will just continue to have gradually more sugar and people will grow more and more obese as a result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061796929.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>What you're saying simply isn't reality dude. A decision is a decision. There are not "so few healthy choices".  Mainstream product is a meaningless term,  human diets vary an amazing amount. The trend in food is increasingly healthier, not worse. Regardless of your opinion studies show obesity is a downward trend and education is a major component. Products are constantly reducing sugar and using alternative sweeteners. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061816073.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to see a study that's proof to what you just said.  
[My source says otherwise, though it does span more years so it may be a recent trend I'm not seeing.](https://i.gyazo.com/c443e6d0ef23f09f5cdcf0bc25325dbb.png)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061827816.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.cdc.gov/obesity/data/childhood.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061831539.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>All right :) And adults?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061836874.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>https://jaymans.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/obesity1.png?w=595&amp;amp;h=446</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061848586.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, I just don't consider that decrease significant considering the increase in the last 30 years. I still believe a stronger measure should be made other than education and market offering healthy, often more expensive alternatives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061855075.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>Lol so if data showing what you're saying isn't true won't change your view what possibly might? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061863328.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I consider the two separate points and I never disagreed education being effective and healthy alternatives existing; i just said given the data you presented it's just not enough to make me concede my point that more direct measures need to be made(like regulation I proposed).  
I mean alternatively you may try giving unused alternative, not as market-invasive but equally or more effective measures .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061878526.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how your plan would be effective. If sugars addictive as you claim kids will switch to orange juice instead of soda. Pastry over low sugar pop tarts. Or they'll just eat double the foods. 

Education is really the only way to change things imo. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061895921.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Natural sugars are better than added sugars anyway so that's not a necessarily bad thing.  
I think if daily products didn't involve so many added sugars, you'd see an improvement starting from children into adults.   
I think only then will dietary education make sense, when normal foods are actually healthy as they used to be and when iced tea is more tea than sugar.  
I doubt companies would out of their own will reduce sugars in their products because sugar = addiction = demand = profits. It is very little education can do to make a profit backlash and it can only last for so long until people start getting used to the gradually increased amounts of sugar.  
It's not an easy issue to solve to be sure and I'm not a fan of market intervention unless it's absolutely necessary but I don't see a better solution.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061906739.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>Added Sugar is the same as natural lol. You sound like you pull your info from very agenda driven sources,  what the real point they probably bastardized is is that natural sugar is accompanied by things like fiber and vitamins. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061920073.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;natural sugar is accompanied by things like fiber and vitamins.  

That's precisely what I meant by it being better.  
Also my perhaps bias is because I'm on diet and suffering from sugar withdrawal lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061943394.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Chemically sugar is sugar. The added sugars are the same as the natural ones. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061947984.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Chemically yes, practically natural sugars are accompanied by healthier ingredients(since it's only juice and milk it exists in) so that's what I meant by that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061953570.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Natural sugars exist in all foods. That is what allows meat to brown for example. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
