<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28061669495.0" user="______POTATOES______" delta="False">
    <text>Oxygen is a drug too (think oxygen bars). 

Note: I actually agree with you generally speaking but calling it a "drug" is just connotation manipulation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061679336.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Is there a more apt term I could use? English is my second language so I couldn't think of a better one.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061686573.0" user="______POTATOES______" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know that there is,  honestly. Plenty of English speakers might call sugar a drug - you're in good company. I just don't think it's a very precise argument to call it a drug is all.

E.g. You can die from drinking too much water, just like you can die from dehydration, yet I don't think I'd call water a drug.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061703695.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Being Polish we have a distinction between drugs(which we call narcotics, which are hard drugs) and używka(ie stimulants, which encompasses both soft drugs both harmful and not). I meant to point at the latter but "stimulant" is an even worse term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061886140.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>No Stimulant is milder term by several orders of magnitude to the word drug. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061897963.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Stimulant could have been misunderstood, I still don't think I could have named it more appropriately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061902699.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Not as misunderstood as the word drug. In English drug is reserved for strong medications, and illegal "hard drugs" with the latter being the most common. When you say it is a drug in English you are communicating that you want it fully banned or so heavily regulated that it is difficult to get and use. 

Sugar is not that. Sugar is a basic food, that while often overused in modernity is necessary for the functioning of the body and survival of humans. When you heavily regulate food as a government you are being dictatorial and for most of Western Society the sacrifice of freedom to said dictatorship is not acceptable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061907201.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Ah. I see. I guess that explains why people think I want to ban it even though I did no such mention. I can see how that might've been a misunderstanding.  
My intent was mostly aimed as a suggestion at a reasonable limit for added sugars for daily products.  
Not sure how I could have communicated the health risks and addiction/withdrawal effects through another word than "drug".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061938610.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>True, though it should be noted that the addictive properties of sugar are not the same as the addictive properties to other drugs. The addictive properties of sugar are due to their necessity for survival and so we evolved to have a very strong, and pleasant reaction to finding sources of sugar. It is food, and is energy dense food at that which is something that we did not have common stable access to until around 200 years ago. 

Mandating what people are allowed and not allowed to eat is very very invasive and controlling of people's lives. It is also quite frankly not the job of the Government in most people's opinions. It is dictatorial and overstepping of authority and so it will prompt the strong resistance you are getting on its own without the issue of the word "drug" in English. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061942516.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I'm not considering a ban nor a complete removal of sugar in products or affect the raw sugar product, but introducing an upper limit to sugar % in daily foods does not sound abusive, if anything its a measure that's meant to help against abuse of companies to addict their consumers by adding large amounts of sugar.  
While we may have had an issue with its scarcity 200 years ago, over 30 years sugar amounts in foods we should consider normal or even healthy are way beyond reasonable.  
As for addictive properties, what do you mean by "not the same"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061946966.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>And once again, the government does not have the authority or right to put such a limit on what people eat. Eating is a basic part of survival. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061950009.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't it also a matter of survival if the very same sugar amounts are one of the leading causes of obesity in majority of the population?  
Isn't the population's survival therefore be the state's interest?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061952408.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The individuals rights override the State's interests. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061957970.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>State's interests are that of the populace(or should be, anyway).  
This is kind of devolving into a individual vs community argument...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061959265.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>That is because that is the argument that the topic is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061967009.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Right to choose to eat what you want seems little comfort when dying in obesity.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061972610.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Obesity itself is not a disease, it is a symptom of several diseases and over-consumption. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061983706.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>My point being; consumption is not something that can be controlled by the consumer when he's addicted(or at the very least, the ability to do so reasonably is impaired by the addiction) and hence the fault lies on the side of the market which offers such sugary products; since consumers cannot control the market - being addicted - and since the market will not yield to see lower profits when they can have more with more sugary products, who should intervene to solve the issue of sugar-induced obesity?  
I'd say it should be the state. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
