<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2238937822.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/11107ha/cmv_the_legal_term_mass_shooting_should_be_broken/">
    <title>CMV: The legal term “mass shooting” should be broken into two categories: ‘mass shooting’ and ‘mass shooting spree’. This will allow there to be much more context in regards to such instances of extreme gun violence.</title>
    <original_poster>SouthrenHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: ALL GUN VIOLENCE IS BAD AND JUST BECAUSE A MASS SHOOTING TOOK PLACE AMONGST GANG MEMBERS DOES NOT MAKE IT ACCEPTABLE TO ANY DEGREE. MURDER IS MURDER, AND VIOLENCE IS VIOLENCE - ITS ALL WRONG. That said, I do believe that there is a lot of context missing when these news stories break out, and the people deserve to be in a position where they are not misled - intentionally or unintentionally. 


In the US, the legal definition of “mass shooting” refers to any instance in which three or more people are shot in a short amount of time. On a surface this may make sense to a lot of people. However, I believe that this terminology is too much of a blanket statement. I say this because due to the media perception and the more extreme cases, many people see this term synonymously with a white, teenage male running into a mall or shopping center and letting loose on random people. In reality, the majority of mass shootings (in the US, at last) are often gang related or due personal disagreements that escalate. 

For example, let’s say there was a gang related drive-by shooting in St. Louis, and for people got shot. That will automatically be considered a mass shooting. Although this would technically the correct terminology, when new outlets post the headlines “mass shooting in St. Louis leaves 4 people wounded”, many viewers would likely imagine another hate crime, terroristic attack, shooting spree, etc. Although 4 people getting shot is HORRIBLE IN ANY CONTEXT excluding self defense, there is a clear difference between a shooting like this and a “Uvalde” type situation.  

This is why I believe there needs to be a new legal term (which would be “mass shooting spree”) in place to differentiate the two. This way, the public - along with legal authority - would be able to avoid any possible confusion on such occurrences. I believe it would also help pinpoint the root causes of these instances of gun violence. “Mass shooting spree”, of course, would refer to situations where multiple random and/or unsuspecting people were shot. 

When you hear “America had x amounts of mass shootings last year”, it’s hard to tell the amount of these that were personal or gang related (in which the victim(s) and perpetrator(s) knew each other) or occurrences which actually involved random, innocent bystanders dying en mass (usually due to hateful or political motivations). By adding the word “spree” at the end when necessary, we would then be able to easily differentiate such cases, and possibly even help ease the public’s hysteria - since it would become clear that it’s not always just random people becoming some lunatic’s target practice.  Meanwhile the term “mass shooting” could continue to be in place for non-shooting spree incidents.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41865047156.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>Why is this a discussion? This has no impact on gun violence. It's like discussing drunk driving and talking about importance of splitting drunk drivers in post 1980 Ford pickups and pre 1980 Ford pickups.

If the goal is to reduce gun violence, why does the discussion spend 95% of its focus on 1% (or less) of the violence? Seriously, this argument is over how to break down two categories that combined are about 1% of the violence.

People can claim (in all caps even) about how all violence is horrible, but ignoring the overwhelming majority of gun violence in the discussion sends the message that those lives don't matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41865684506.0" user="1block" delta="False">
    <text>It matters because the national discussion around gun violence is usually focused on that 1% problem, and when we make policy or funding decisions about how to make ourselves or our kids safer, we might be focused on the wrong things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41865772302.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>Hume's guillotine. Are we talking about what what *should* be, or what actually is?

If we are saying that we *should* split these up to foster a more honest discussion, the corollary is that honest discussion would only allocate 1% of the discussion to this topic, so we *should* work towards putting the bulk of the discussion on non-mass shootings.

*Should* arguments and *is* arguments don't play well together. If the goal is to make society safer from guns, step one is not ignoring 99% of the problem right off the bat.

The point is that every time we put disproportionate emphasis on mass shootings, we *are* focused on the wrong things. Why *should* the less than 1000 people dead in mass shootings get a larger focus than the other 30,000 dead from gun violence?

They shouldn't.

Any discussion about honesty, accuracy, and not 'focusing on the wrong things' (to use your terminology) needs to start by focusing on what the actual problem is. Not what 1% of the problem is. Because that's the wrong things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41866672441.0" user="1block" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not following you. I'm saying we ARE focused on the 1% right now by putting time money and effort into locking down schools and teaching kids how to hide in a classroom rather than on the actual threats that exist.

That happens because people think school shootings are likely to happen to their community/schools, apparently. Or at least likely enough that they support focusing our efforts towards that, and conflating all these issues through broad statistics is part of the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41866741295.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not following you. I'm saying we ARE focused on the 1% right now by putting time money and effort into locking down schools and teaching kids how to hide in a classroom rather than on the actual threats that exist

Yep. We are spending all our energy trying to save tens of people while thousands die, ignored, because less than 2 other people died with them.  So the poster's original comment that we should subdivide the 1% for precision and honesty doesn't change the fact that if we are looking at that 1% while ignoring the 99%, the honest discussion ship has already sank.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41867492446.0" user="1block" delta="False">
    <text>Got it. OK. I guess I would disagree with the idea that the ship is sailed on that, since we've never had the discussion in any meaningful way about the 99% outside of "get tough on crime" bills that never work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41867612592.0" user="Talik1978" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so you're saying the discussion has never been an honest effort to reduce gun violence?

There are a lot of ways we can discuss the 99%. Two off the top of my head are:

Suicide awareness and outreach, with separate approaches to address men and women, given different statistics for attempts (mostly women) and lethality (overwhelmingly men).

Social safety programs to address the number one predictor of crime, abject poverty.

There is room for honest discussions on alleviating the drivers of violent crime without dehumanizing people fighting to survive. There's space to do that. And doing so would likely impact deaths due to violent crime far more than cracking down on rifles with a black finish because some teenager took one into a church.

The issue is that, when looking at all violent crime, per capita, it trends downward (while still too high). It's difficult to be alarmist and to successfully monger the fear with that accurate portrayal. It doesn't shock as much. It doesn't horrify.

So the discussion goes to the misleading, because the misleading approach that ignores most victims of violent crime has the benefit of being really good outrage bait.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41868479769.0" user="1block" delta="False">
    <text>I think we pretty much agree.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
