<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2238937822.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/11107ha/cmv_the_legal_term_mass_shooting_should_be_broken/">
    <title>CMV: The legal term “mass shooting” should be broken into two categories: ‘mass shooting’ and ‘mass shooting spree’. This will allow there to be much more context in regards to such instances of extreme gun violence.</title>
    <original_poster>SouthrenHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: ALL GUN VIOLENCE IS BAD AND JUST BECAUSE A MASS SHOOTING TOOK PLACE AMONGST GANG MEMBERS DOES NOT MAKE IT ACCEPTABLE TO ANY DEGREE. MURDER IS MURDER, AND VIOLENCE IS VIOLENCE - ITS ALL WRONG. That said, I do believe that there is a lot of context missing when these news stories break out, and the people deserve to be in a position where they are not misled - intentionally or unintentionally. 


In the US, the legal definition of “mass shooting” refers to any instance in which three or more people are shot in a short amount of time. On a surface this may make sense to a lot of people. However, I believe that this terminology is too much of a blanket statement. I say this because due to the media perception and the more extreme cases, many people see this term synonymously with a white, teenage male running into a mall or shopping center and letting loose on random people. In reality, the majority of mass shootings (in the US, at last) are often gang related or due personal disagreements that escalate. 

For example, let’s say there was a gang related drive-by shooting in St. Louis, and for people got shot. That will automatically be considered a mass shooting. Although this would technically the correct terminology, when new outlets post the headlines “mass shooting in St. Louis leaves 4 people wounded”, many viewers would likely imagine another hate crime, terroristic attack, shooting spree, etc. Although 4 people getting shot is HORRIBLE IN ANY CONTEXT excluding self defense, there is a clear difference between a shooting like this and a “Uvalde” type situation.  

This is why I believe there needs to be a new legal term (which would be “mass shooting spree”) in place to differentiate the two. This way, the public - along with legal authority - would be able to avoid any possible confusion on such occurrences. I believe it would also help pinpoint the root causes of these instances of gun violence. “Mass shooting spree”, of course, would refer to situations where multiple random and/or unsuspecting people were shot. 

When you hear “America had x amounts of mass shootings last year”, it’s hard to tell the amount of these that were personal or gang related (in which the victim(s) and perpetrator(s) knew each other) or occurrences which actually involved random, innocent bystanders dying en mass (usually due to hateful or political motivations). By adding the word “spree” at the end when necessary, we would then be able to easily differentiate such cases, and possibly even help ease the public’s hysteria - since it would become clear that it’s not always just random people becoming some lunatic’s target practice.  Meanwhile the term “mass shooting” could continue to be in place for non-shooting spree incidents.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41864670799.0" user="aren3141" delta="False">
    <text>You know there are too many guns when you have to come up with new terms to distinguish the different kinds of shooting murders</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
