<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223826952.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p9dzc/cmv_college_athletes_are_modern_day_indentured/">
    <title>CMV: College Athletes are modern day indentured servants and deserve to be paid.</title>
    <original_poster>yobittner</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s about time we start paying student athletes, or at the very least grant all participants full scholarships. Coming from a Division I athlete myself, I never really thought of the subject until undergoing the most stressful past few months of my life. If being a student isn’t enough, try waking up by 8am for your first class, finishing around one, and then going to practice for 4-5 hours. After practice, you grab a bite to eat and by the team you even have a chance of starting your course work, the clock says 8pm. It’s looking like an all-nighter, oh wait that’s every other night, and you are already exhausted from practice.

According to Forbes, the NCAA basketball tournament, also known as “March Madness,” allows for CBS to make more than $1 billion off the games. Athletic conferences receive millions of dollars from the NCAA when their teams make it far in the tournament. It is even estimated that as a whole the NCAA makes $6 billion annually. (It’s registered as a non-profit by the way…) Meanwhile student athletes are either going in debt to pay for school, barely have any spending money, or are just fortunate enough to be one of the few that are financially well off. Quite frankly, I feel as though it’s just not fair that an organization can make so much money off of people who don’t receive any benefits. Its modern day indentured servitude.

You can only look back at the video game dilemma to see how much the NCAA generates off of unpaid workers. NCAA Football and March Madness were discontinued after athletes found players that looked exactly like them. Although names were not able to be used, the NCAA would not only have someone on the cover, but have identical players in the game. There was a settlement in which the game was finally discontinued because of the outrageous greed by a nonprofit organization.

One logical argument that’s often ignored is that an athlete can be compared to a cafeteria worker in a university dining hall. Both represent the school and provide a service that generates money. However, the only one who is paid is the cafeteria worker. Does that make any sense? Why would someone that generates less money for the school receive better treatment? It’s common sense…

At the very least, I believe all NCAA athletes should be eligible for full scholarships. There shouldn’t be any limitations at all. You would be very surprised to realize that actually the majority of NCAA student athletes do not receive any sort of athletic financial aid. A lot of this has to do with the limitation on the number of scholarships per team due to policies such as Title IX. Not only are you paying the school through your hard work, but you also might be literally paying the school…

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28063542838.0" user="dontcall_me_shirley" delta="False">
    <text>There are a couple issues that I have with your argument

1) Pardon me if my assuming skills are off, but I'm guessing you don't play football or men's basketball. The fact of the matter is that these two sports are the only moneymaking sports in college athletics. Unless there's a special circumstance, none of the other sports (baseball, volleyball, track, etc) make money for the school. So not every athlete is making money for the school, in fact, most athletes are a net loss for the school. One belief I have is that if universities have to pay ALL their athletes, they would cut many of the sports that don't make money, and leave on the moneymaking sports (FB,MBB) and the necessary sports to maintain their Title IX compliance. This would lead to a majority of athletes who don't get to play their sports at the next level, which in my opinion, would be worse than the situation right now. 

2) if every athlete got a full scholarship, many of the smaller D1 schools would most likely not be able to afford the number of sports they have now, once again leading to cuts. 

2.1) In response to athletes getting paid, this also calls into question the large school vs small school feasibility. An Alabama football player probably makes a lot of money for the school, so they deserve a lot of money. A football player at Central Michigan may still make money for the school, but he makes a whole lot less. Should there be a NCAA D1-wide minimum to allow these smaller schools to comply and still stay competitive? Or would that still be unfair to the Alabama football player who is receiving less than he generates? 

That's all I can think of at the moment. I've been a D1 athlete as well, so I know what you're going through, but frankly I don't think many of your solutions are feasible </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
