<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223826952.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p9dzc/cmv_college_athletes_are_modern_day_indentured/">
    <title>CMV: College Athletes are modern day indentured servants and deserve to be paid.</title>
    <original_poster>yobittner</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s about time we start paying student athletes, or at the very least grant all participants full scholarships. Coming from a Division I athlete myself, I never really thought of the subject until undergoing the most stressful past few months of my life. If being a student isn’t enough, try waking up by 8am for your first class, finishing around one, and then going to practice for 4-5 hours. After practice, you grab a bite to eat and by the team you even have a chance of starting your course work, the clock says 8pm. It’s looking like an all-nighter, oh wait that’s every other night, and you are already exhausted from practice.

According to Forbes, the NCAA basketball tournament, also known as “March Madness,” allows for CBS to make more than $1 billion off the games. Athletic conferences receive millions of dollars from the NCAA when their teams make it far in the tournament. It is even estimated that as a whole the NCAA makes $6 billion annually. (It’s registered as a non-profit by the way…) Meanwhile student athletes are either going in debt to pay for school, barely have any spending money, or are just fortunate enough to be one of the few that are financially well off. Quite frankly, I feel as though it’s just not fair that an organization can make so much money off of people who don’t receive any benefits. Its modern day indentured servitude.

You can only look back at the video game dilemma to see how much the NCAA generates off of unpaid workers. NCAA Football and March Madness were discontinued after athletes found players that looked exactly like them. Although names were not able to be used, the NCAA would not only have someone on the cover, but have identical players in the game. There was a settlement in which the game was finally discontinued because of the outrageous greed by a nonprofit organization.

One logical argument that’s often ignored is that an athlete can be compared to a cafeteria worker in a university dining hall. Both represent the school and provide a service that generates money. However, the only one who is paid is the cafeteria worker. Does that make any sense? Why would someone that generates less money for the school receive better treatment? It’s common sense…

At the very least, I believe all NCAA athletes should be eligible for full scholarships. There shouldn’t be any limitations at all. You would be very surprised to realize that actually the majority of NCAA student athletes do not receive any sort of athletic financial aid. A lot of this has to do with the limitation on the number of scholarships per team due to policies such as Title IX. Not only are you paying the school through your hard work, but you also might be literally paying the school…

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28063549578.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>It's not in any way indentured servitude, because you aren't legally obligated to play.  You can quit at any time without cost, especially if you aren't getting a scholarship out of the deal.

As a clarifying question: if it's just a terrible deal, why do you participate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063562684.0" user="yobittner" delta="False">
    <text>Your question was bit of an ad hominem to say the least, but the majority of student athletes participate because they love the game and have a future with it. I'm in no way saying it's a terrible deal at all to the point where people shouldn't play college sports. I'm saying it's an issue that needs to be addressed so that future student athletes can get what they deserve for their years of hard work...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063570867.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Apologies if you were offended.

I'm simply saying that calling it "indentured servitude" is an unfair comparison.   Indentured servitude would mean that you'd be forced to work for a period of time, and if you wanted to quit, the police and courts would force you to continue.   It may be a bad deal, but its nowhere near close to indentured servitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063573887.0" user="ryancarp3" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; they love the game

They could always play club sports or intramurals if they were only doing it "for the love of the game."

&amp;gt; and have a future with it

Not really.

[Probability of Going Pro](https://www.ncaa.org/sites/default/files/Probability-of-going-pro-methodology_Update2013.pdf)

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063578138.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>But you are saying its a bad deal because they have school to work on too.  If they get paid they still have to work on both football and school.  The way to solve the problem is that they drop football and work on school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28064026847.0" user="yobittner" delta="False">
    <text>However,  I disagree entirely because many employees in today's job market would prefer to hire an NCAA athlete due to their work ethic and time management over a one dimensional college kid...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28064031570.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, being an athlete is valuable by employers.  But how does getting paid as an athlete address your point about having to study and do sports at the same time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28064240340.0" user="ugots" delta="False">
    <text>A full ride is about 50k.  That's about comparable to minor league baseball.  That's fair.  You were a minor leaguer, you didn't make the big leagues, you worked hard and I'm sure you'd say it was worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28064441656.0" user="5510" delta="False">
    <text>What are you talking about, the vast majority of student athletes (even division 1 student athletes) don't have a future with it.  Am I misunderstanding you, or are you saying that almost all student athletes go pro in their sport?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
