<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2238937822.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/11107ha/cmv_the_legal_term_mass_shooting_should_be_broken/">
    <title>CMV: The legal term “mass shooting” should be broken into two categories: ‘mass shooting’ and ‘mass shooting spree’. This will allow there to be much more context in regards to such instances of extreme gun violence.</title>
    <original_poster>SouthrenHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: ALL GUN VIOLENCE IS BAD AND JUST BECAUSE A MASS SHOOTING TOOK PLACE AMONGST GANG MEMBERS DOES NOT MAKE IT ACCEPTABLE TO ANY DEGREE. MURDER IS MURDER, AND VIOLENCE IS VIOLENCE - ITS ALL WRONG. That said, I do believe that there is a lot of context missing when these news stories break out, and the people deserve to be in a position where they are not misled - intentionally or unintentionally. 


In the US, the legal definition of “mass shooting” refers to any instance in which three or more people are shot in a short amount of time. On a surface this may make sense to a lot of people. However, I believe that this terminology is too much of a blanket statement. I say this because due to the media perception and the more extreme cases, many people see this term synonymously with a white, teenage male running into a mall or shopping center and letting loose on random people. In reality, the majority of mass shootings (in the US, at last) are often gang related or due personal disagreements that escalate. 

For example, let’s say there was a gang related drive-by shooting in St. Louis, and for people got shot. That will automatically be considered a mass shooting. Although this would technically the correct terminology, when new outlets post the headlines “mass shooting in St. Louis leaves 4 people wounded”, many viewers would likely imagine another hate crime, terroristic attack, shooting spree, etc. Although 4 people getting shot is HORRIBLE IN ANY CONTEXT excluding self defense, there is a clear difference between a shooting like this and a “Uvalde” type situation.  

This is why I believe there needs to be a new legal term (which would be “mass shooting spree”) in place to differentiate the two. This way, the public - along with legal authority - would be able to avoid any possible confusion on such occurrences. I believe it would also help pinpoint the root causes of these instances of gun violence. “Mass shooting spree”, of course, would refer to situations where multiple random and/or unsuspecting people were shot. 

When you hear “America had x amounts of mass shootings last year”, it’s hard to tell the amount of these that were personal or gang related (in which the victim(s) and perpetrator(s) knew each other) or occurrences which actually involved random, innocent bystanders dying en mass (usually due to hateful or political motivations). By adding the word “spree” at the end when necessary, we would then be able to easily differentiate such cases, and possibly even help ease the public’s hysteria - since it would become clear that it’s not always just random people becoming some lunatic’s target practice.  Meanwhile the term “mass shooting” could continue to be in place for non-shooting spree incidents.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41863276104.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Since 1950 over 90% of mass shooter events that are not gang related, happen in “gun free zones”!

Source Crime Prevention Research Center “CPRC”

Further, Pewresearch (dot) org has the most recent data Feb 3 2022. On a per capita basis all gun deaths are less now, then they were in 1974.

We didn’t have “Permitless carry” aka Constitutional Carry recognized by the current 25 (of 50) States (FL is about to be 26) in 1974, only 5 States recognized “Permitless carry” aka Constitutional Carry then.

Lastly, what the media and politicians call “gun violence” is in fact, thug violence.

We need strict thug control to stop thug violence.

Newtons law of motion the only way to stop force is with a equal or greater amount of force.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863345592.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Further, Pewresearch (dot) org has the most recent data Feb 3 2022. On a per capita basis all gun deaths are less now, then they were in 1974.

Do you have a link to that? 

&amp;gt;Source Crime Prevention Research Center “CPRC”

That's not a source any more than Alex Jones is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863392067.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry you feel that way, however I have to disagree.

Are FBI crime stats found online, and within John Lott’s book “More guns, less crime”, also not a source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863523170.0" user="BrutusJunior" delta="False">
    <text>Saying that you can find it online is not an argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863610277.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not here to have a “argument”. The narrative over the last 40 years has been “gun violence” “gun control”…and things do not change, I am here to bring that reality of bad results from a misguided narrative, to folks attention. For real change the focus must be on the perpetrators! It is thug violence, and we need strict thug control laws! Now that after 40 years we have figured out inanimate guns don’t shoot themselves, and in fact thugs do the shooting, we ask why??? The answers are socio-economic and/or mental health, and unless we get to those root causes…thugs-socioeconomic, and/or mental health then nothing will change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863627079.0" user="BrutusJunior" delta="False">
    <text>Please provide a link to the statistics you mentioned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863639504.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Here is most recent https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2022/02/03/what-the-data-says-about-gun-deaths-in-the-u-s/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41866416179.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  John Lott’s book “More guns, less crime”, also not a source?

Correct. If Alex Jones writes a book about Sandy Hook, it will also not be a source.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41866679866.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2022/02/03/what-the-data-says-about-gun-deaths-in-the-u-s/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41867628318.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think that's saying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41869245900.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Violence policy cites “mass shootings” as 3 or more, regardless of circumstances, their number includes gang shootings aka THUG violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863836963.0" user="barthiebarth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Newtons law of motion the only way to stop force is with a equal or greater amount of force

That does not correspond to any of Newton's three laws of motion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41865645701.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry you feel that way, however I have to disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41867711927.0" user="barthiebarth" delta="False">
    <text>you don't "have to disagree" you can just do a basic google search instead.

if you are going to pretentiously shoehorn in some principle from physics in at least make sure you don't look ignorant about physics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41869255151.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>See number 3 https://www.britannica.com/science/Newtons-laws-of-motion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41871142958.0" user="barthiebarth" delta="False">
    <text>I know what Newton's laws are I teach them for a living.

Every force having an equal but opposite reaction force is not remotely like what you said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41871511160.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting. Are you a physics teacher?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41871521948.0" user="DamianRork" delta="False">
    <text>PS: the reason I ask OT from this discussion, its related to physics, in the simplest terms that I could understand, what does  “molecules, atoms, time space differential” mean?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
