<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223826952.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p9dzc/cmv_college_athletes_are_modern_day_indentured/">
    <title>CMV: College Athletes are modern day indentured servants and deserve to be paid.</title>
    <original_poster>yobittner</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s about time we start paying student athletes, or at the very least grant all participants full scholarships. Coming from a Division I athlete myself, I never really thought of the subject until undergoing the most stressful past few months of my life. If being a student isn’t enough, try waking up by 8am for your first class, finishing around one, and then going to practice for 4-5 hours. After practice, you grab a bite to eat and by the team you even have a chance of starting your course work, the clock says 8pm. It’s looking like an all-nighter, oh wait that’s every other night, and you are already exhausted from practice.

According to Forbes, the NCAA basketball tournament, also known as “March Madness,” allows for CBS to make more than $1 billion off the games. Athletic conferences receive millions of dollars from the NCAA when their teams make it far in the tournament. It is even estimated that as a whole the NCAA makes $6 billion annually. (It’s registered as a non-profit by the way…) Meanwhile student athletes are either going in debt to pay for school, barely have any spending money, or are just fortunate enough to be one of the few that are financially well off. Quite frankly, I feel as though it’s just not fair that an organization can make so much money off of people who don’t receive any benefits. Its modern day indentured servitude.

You can only look back at the video game dilemma to see how much the NCAA generates off of unpaid workers. NCAA Football and March Madness were discontinued after athletes found players that looked exactly like them. Although names were not able to be used, the NCAA would not only have someone on the cover, but have identical players in the game. There was a settlement in which the game was finally discontinued because of the outrageous greed by a nonprofit organization.

One logical argument that’s often ignored is that an athlete can be compared to a cafeteria worker in a university dining hall. Both represent the school and provide a service that generates money. However, the only one who is paid is the cafeteria worker. Does that make any sense? Why would someone that generates less money for the school receive better treatment? It’s common sense…

At the very least, I believe all NCAA athletes should be eligible for full scholarships. There shouldn’t be any limitations at all. You would be very surprised to realize that actually the majority of NCAA student athletes do not receive any sort of athletic financial aid. A lot of this has to do with the limitation on the number of scholarships per team due to policies such as Title IX. Not only are you paying the school through your hard work, but you also might be literally paying the school…

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28063596892.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Only a handful of sports generate any sort of revenue for the university. Does that mean only men's basketball and football players should be paid? If not, then what is different about sports and any other extra-curricular activity on campus? Should the theatre students get paid for putting on plays? Should the orchestra students be paid for putting on a concert? All those events tend to lose money, does that mean that there should be a greater focus on monetizing them? Ultimately, college athletes choose to play. No one is forcing them to do it. 

Furthermore, being a college athlete comes with a lot more benefits than being a cafeteria worker. The top players (the ones who are irreplaceable and generate most of the money for the school) get large scholarships, as well as tons of academic and social support from the school. Cafeteria workers barely make minimum wage, and often spend just as much time working and studying as athletes. Plus their work is actual work as opposed to a game people play for fun. The reality is that most students and workers in the US face demanding schedules, and most aren't rewarded the same way student-athletes are.

Finally, most of the money that sports generate are used to further fund the sports teams. Except at a very small number of top programs (Michigan, Texas, Alabama, etc.) most schools don't make any profit off of sports. There is a huge difference between revenue and profit. Most schools spend more on the programs than they make off of them.

At the end of the day, most college students aren't good enough to play at the professional level. They aren't ever going to be a position where they make money based on their athletic talent. It's true that the very tip-top college athletes are making less than they are worth to a professional team (that's why Lebron James went directly to the NBA.) The slightly less great are making about the same amount that they are worth (through scholarships and the like.) But the vast majority (95% of college athletes) are not good enough to profit off their athletic prowess. The school is providing them the opportunity to play, but they aren't making the school any money. If the college sports system didn't exist, they wouldn't get the chance to play at all, except in recreational leagues.

Ultimately, most (99%) student athletes lose money for the school. Schools take the money generated by the top athletes and funnel it to pay for the less talented ones. You could argue that the top athletes in popular sports at the top schools are essentially indentured servants, but even they are not required to do anything. They choose to play for the school, and can jump to a professional league if they want to (if they can't, then they aren't part of that elite group in the first place.) College athletes work incredibly hard, but not any harder than the millions of other students who are struggling to get by in college. The only thing unique about them is they are part of a big business, but even then, the vast majority are not the profit generating part of the business. Once you recognize that, there  is no real difference between sports and any other extra-curricular activity on campus.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
