<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881139857.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>I was originally inclined to agree with you, but this is hard to prove either way without data, so I tried to look some up. I wanted to find out what percentage of people converted to a religion after adulthood. Based on the data I found, its actually more common than you might think. According to Pew research, over 1 in 4 Americans change their religion from what they were raised as while they are adults. This includes changing between religions or becoming non-religious. Source: https://www.pewresearch.org/religion/2009/04/27/faith-in-flux/#:~:text=The%202007%20survey%20found%20that%20more%20than%20one-in-four,to%20Catholicism%20or%20from%20Judaism%20to%20no%20religion.

I was also curious how many people of each religion were adult converts rather than raised in the faith. I could only find data on Christianity, but it looks like about 30% of Christians were converts and not getting their faith from their family. Source: https://www.is-there-a-god.info/belief/converts/

Now, this is obviously not a majority of people, but it also makes it clear that your claim that an overwhelming majority of people still believe just what their parents told them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
