<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41887842408.0" user="RaysAreBaes" delta="False">
    <text>Growing up, my parents used to cook me a Sunday roast and they eventually taught me to cook it myself. I still cook a Sunday roast now. I cook it because I like it and it makes sense to me. I may not have known how to cook a roast had they never introduced it to me but I’m glad they did. There are also plenty of things they used to cook me that I don’t cook for myself anymore and there are new recipes I’ve learned that I now teach them.

In regards to your point, I may not be Christian if my mum wasn’t but she introduced me to something that I ended up enjoying and it made sense to me. As I grew up, I began to understand things from my own perspective and now we don’t necessarily agree on everything but we share a fundamental belief in the same God. It didn’t make sense to my brother and he would describe himself as atheist now.

I would argue that things your parents introduced you doesn’t stop with that. Most religious people will have done their own reflection and found reasons to continue to worship</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
