<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41926475663.0" user="Kitsune_Ayano00" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely had issues with being apart of the catholic faith for at least the churches I been to and how uncomfortable/ nervous going there is even for confession when priests aren’t up to the same high standards of therapists even though maybe it should be considered to have members going to church feel comfortable and at home instead of not welcome, unloved and unheard. For me confession has always hasn’t helped much and added to my anxiety and negative thoughts. I have a bit of mental health issues and different views on faith should be more like education taught with multiple ways to show you do love your religion even if you don’t go to certain places services . It still amazes me that similar issues is a big issue these days that more people young are either going lgbtq or atheist for good reasons no hate . Cuz certain religions mess up badly to make them feel loved and belonged somewhere. Tad depends on the situation but sometimes religion or certain traditions feel like peer pressure from families/ dead people. At least the tradition thing cuz I saw a post about that on insta. A little kid basically thinking the definition of tradition is peer pressure from dead people. Ironic and cute but true at the same time for certain things. For me I come to far to give up on my religion cause I still have good things I love about it and issues I need to overcome. Been worrying about this for a few days now and even curious how much others with mental health had bad experiences with going to places of worship and the people there etc .</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
