<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41882326520.0" user="anonymous_teve" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know what everyone else's experience, but at some age or point of maturity, the excuse "my parents believe it, so I do too" wears off. Usually around adolescence, maybe a little later. So I think for young kids that's probably true. But as we move to adulthood, everything is naturally evaluated on its own merits. 

It's common for atheists to say this type of thing, implying "religous folks are simple children with simple minds who accept without questioning what their parents say, while I personally have evolved beyond this, I'm much smarter and more independent minded, something of a supergenius, so I was able to rise above this and see the truth". But you can see that such logic really isn't internally consistent. 

Most people, no matter what religion or lack thereof, can easily see core beliefs of theirs that have changed from their parents. I know I can. And if they adhere to some core beliefs of their parents, at some point it's more likely that they've independently agreed their parents were actually correct.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
