<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881102080.0" user="Gumboy52" delta="False">
    <text>How would you measure “true belief” in their religion?


Most beliefs/values that a person has could be described as “peer pressure” from parents / society. 

A person born in America is far more likely to believe in the right to bear arms than a person born in Japan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881145608.0" user="siddharth_pillai" delta="False">
    <text>I don't measure the true belief. I'll ask them this hypothetical question of their parents being a different religion and I'll take their word for it. Most of the time, people do acknowledge that they'd also be following their parents religion and some people just refuse to answer. If someone says that they would still be following their current religion regardless of their parent's religion, I'd consider that as true belief.

Even people who already have parents from a different religion or people who have atheist parents are also people I would say do not come under this category.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881170220.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>Someone can truly believe in a religion even if they think they might not believe if their parents didn't believe. For example, I had Christian parents. They taught me a lot about Christianity that I would probably never have known without their guidance, gave me books and arguments and teachings. I could answer you honestly that I would not have been a Christian if not for them, but that also does not mean I am blindly following their faith or that my own belief is any less real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881200618.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but that also does not mean I am blindly following their faith

What do you think being raised does?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881290295.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>It influences you, surely. Provides you a different perspective. That does not mean that I or anyone else cannot look at the world from a different perspective over time. I can accept that my parents influenced me while also reinforcing my own agency and beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881297774.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I can accept that my parents influenced me while also reinforcing my own agency and beliefs.

Can you also accept that the familial bias is incredibly strong and a very clear indicator of future behavior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881309560.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>Sure of course. I'm not disputing that. I'm disputing the part that says that people's beliefs are illegitimate or false because of that. Maybe some people are just going along with what they are told, but it's also entirely possible to critically analyze beliefs that my parents left me and still end up agreeing with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881322813.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but it's also entirely possible to *critically analyze beliefs* that my parents left me and still end up agreeing with them.

I disagree. I don't think it's possible to critically analyze religious beliefs and come out in support of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881260493.0" user="siddharth_pillai" delta="False">
    <text>The values and teachings are great but your fundamental idea of 'God' would change completely. That part is blind belief. Even if you were a different religion, you would still value the teachings but your idea of God would be different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881300354.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with this completely. I can conceptualize all types of God despite my upbringing. I've studied philosophy and know quite a bit about all different types of metaphysics, and I believe in the one that makes the most sense to me. It's certainly true that my upbringing has influenced me, but nothing about my beliefs is blind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881315654.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I can conceptualize all types of God despite my upbringing.

This is circular. 

You can't remove your upbringing from the equation when the bias is the subject.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881356613.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>You think that people raised in one tradition cannot even conceptualize other traditions' ideas of God? I can accept that we all have biases of course but the idea that even conceptualizing other ways of thinking is completely impossible seem like far too strong a position. I mean, people convert between religions all the time. Christians become Buddhists, Hindus becomes Muslims. Do you think they are all just faking it or what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881381239.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You think that people raised in one tradition cannot even conceptualize other traditions' ideas of God?

I didn't say that. I said you can't remove your upbringing and then say you can believe *in spite* of it. Your upbringing shaped your entire worldview and understanding - it's a foundation, not a component that can be remove.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881460681.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe this in all cases, or just religion? Like can I adopt a different political system than the one I was raised in, or a different moral system? Seems to me that lots of people do change those things about themselves, given time, or the world would never change at all. But then what would single out religion as immune to change?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881467095.0" user="StrangerThanGene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Like can I adopt a different political system than the one I was raised in, or a different moral system?

Of course - with the understanding that you already have an existing foundational understanding built in a bias - like with everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881491025.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I agree. I guess I'm confused about what we are disagreeing on then.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
