<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881387962.0" user="Mad__Hermit" delta="False">
    <text>So your edit kind of disproves your own title. 

You state religion is just peer pressure from parents. You then carve out a huge exemption for a group of people that could disprove that claim.

That aside, the rest is just kind of speculation. You don't provide any real data. As for some of the questions, like if your parents were X wouldn't you also be X? Well no. Perhaps you would practice it as a child since your parents have a lot of control over where you go and what you do, but that is different than actual belief. I know a lot of people who grew up in a religious household and are either different or not religious at all now. 

I think a better way to phrase this would be "religion tends to be the result of parental influence when it comes to kids" or something similar. When you make an across the board claim and then just handwave away the examples that counter it by saying you aren't referring to those people, I'm not sure how someone is really supposed to change your view.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
