<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881203319.0" user="goolixmonster" delta="False">
    <text>Religion tends to be a case of indoctrination but is not always so. More often than not, you follow the religion of your parents from an exceptionally young age, with ceremonies to bring you in before you're anywhere NEAR the age of being able to understand what it means. And then you get punished for asking questions or even researching other's beliefs. 

But the youth indoctrination is not what religion IS. At it's core, people use religion to feel comfort. No one KNOWS the answers to the big questions, i.e. Why are we here, What is right and wrong, What happens when we die, etc. All the other trappings are gravy on top of that. People fear the unknown and religion claims to bring answers to those questions. And speaking for myself personally, finding a religion that meshes with my world view after I had considered myself Agnostic for a long time was both comforting and validating. Religion can be a beautiful thing in that way. Organized religion, in it's modern form or even it's medieval form (here's looking at the Crusades) is a perversion and a racket.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
