<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881138252.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>Your parents are not your peers. The ways in which a parent can put pressure on you is entirely different than how your peers can influence you. 

Maybe this isn't what your CMV is specifically about but the way you are framing it sounds like you think parental influence is as innocuous or harmful as peer pressure and that is not the case. Parents can cause forms of trauma that your peers will never be able to match and parents can also give comfort in ways that peers may come close to but is a fundamentally different feeling. It is important to recognize the difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881232399.0" user="siddharth_pillai" delta="False">
    <text>Well yeah I didn't know the equivalent for parents... familial pressure? I didn't think it mattered much as you could understand from context.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
