<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881345449.0" user="HiHelloHowyadoin123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

Well no, I'd probably be Islamic. People are moulded by their community. If my parents were doomsday preppers I'd probably have a very different value system than I do now. But they aren't. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;If someone says that they would still be following their current religion regardless of their parent's religion, I'd consider that as true belief.

So to be a true believer, do you require someone to state without question they'd still be their religion regardless of who they were born to? Even if it was a tiny village in rural China? Or to the leader of the local Mosque?

Isn't it enough for them to have faith for this lifetime, without all the hypotheticals?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
