<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881379611.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>Could you clarify why you hold this view? At present, it seems like your justification is:

1.) People are likely to have the same religion as their parents

2.) Therefore, their parents must have been pressuring them to do it.

Is this an accurate assessment of your view? If so, it’s missing a crucial step. People could have similar beliefs to their parents for a variety of reasons. They could have been presented with impartial information about God from their parents or other people and be convinced that way, no pressure needed. Or perhaps their attendance at church/mosque/synagogue etc convinced them by their peer group there. It’s possible a conversation with someone outside their peer group, like a pastor, convinced them to go to church, for instance. Heck, some people get their own personal experience of God, independent of whether their parents are religious.

All of these, and more, are reasons someone might have the same religion as their parents. How did you eliminate these possibilities and settle on your one, overarching peer pressure from parents reason above all the others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881450329.0" user="siddharth_pillai" delta="False">
    <text>That's not exactly my view, my bad for not explaining properly. Its more like;

for the vast majority of people who follow the same religion as their parents, don't truly believe in their religion as they would have most likely followed their parent's religion even if it was a completely different religion.

In such a case, one may believe that they truly believe in Jesus, but in an alternate reality where this person's parents are Hindus, they would believe that they truly believe in Hindu deities. Such a person doesn't truly believe in any religion and is rather blindly following their parents' religion. My view is that this is true for most people that follow the same religion as their parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881564282.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>Your view is still unexplained. Specifically:

&amp;gt; for the vast majority of people who follow the same religion as their parents, **don't truly believe in their religion** as they would have **most likely followed their parent's religion even if it was a completely different religion**.

Emphasis mine. The conclusion that they don’t really believe is not supported by the fact that people are more likely to follow their parent’s religion. That’s because there are several reasons why someone might follow the religion of their parents that are because they truly **DO** believe, like being genuinely convinced by their parents or other peers, the influence of their community, etc.

To go that extra step, you have to explain how you know that those who follow their parent’s religion don’t truly believe. This seems to be a core part of your view, but your conclusion doesn’t seem to follow from your premise. What am I missing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881640830.0" user="siddharth_pillai" delta="False">
    <text>Because to truly believe in their religion, they'd have to believe in that religion regardless of their parents and community beliefs. The reason I believe that they would change their beliefs is because I asked them the hypothetical in the post and the few people I asked did realise that they would almost definitely be following their parents' religion. Genuine belief =\\= True belief.

If you are a theist, you can speculate about it too, just imagine your parents being Hindu, wouldn't you also be one and not have any relation to your current religion.

edit:

&amp;gt;you have to explain how you know that those who follow their parent’s religion don’t truly believe

because then they would have said that they'd still follow their current religion even if their parents' religion was different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41881817836.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because to truly believe in their religion, they'd have to believe in that religion regardless of their parents and community beliefs.

First, why do you believe this is the case? There isn't a single belief that any human being has, secular or non-secular, that isn't influenced by the beliefs of the people in their environment. If this is truly your definition of believe, then no person holds any beliefs. Is this what you really mean?

Second, even if that was true, the fact that they have the same belief as their parents is **NOT** evidence that they would have the same belief given different parents. To determine this, you would have to somehow take a person and put them in a completely different environment with different parents and different beliefs and see how they develop. This is impossible as you can't go back in time.

Your thought experiment is not evidence of this either, as it's just a hypothetical. It's as easily defeated as someone telling you that they would still believe their religion even if their parents believed a different religion, and you wouldn't be able to tell otherwise.  In other words, your standard to determine whether someone truly believes is \*unfalsifiable\*. Basing your view on an unfalsifiable claim is as justifiable as any other unfalsifiable belief, and is illogical.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
