<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41882054894.0" user="xXBio_SapienXx" delta="False">
    <text>This is going to be a big one

When you word it like that then in theory anything you are taught from birth is "peer pressure." That includes the practical side of the spectrum like education. Kids learn education from adults in schools and organizations alike across the world and like religion it varies from region to region and depends on who teaches it. And in their own right, they are right. With that being said religion is just as valid as any other teaching and just as subject to change as any other educational finding.

Peer pressure is purely subjective and in this case it's being used as validation. If you wanted genuine feedback I think you'll find that empathy is what you should be employing. Putting myself in your shoes I could assume that you perceive peer pressure as naturally wrong and that religion has no merit because of that. However, It's not always a bad thing to be influenced by others and religion is just another choice of perspective. 

Furthermore it's also important to consider the opinions of those who the statement wasn't aimed to because perspectives are important. What would be the point in disregarding the perspectives of others because in that way you would be no different than the religious or practical crowd.

Religion is belief at its most basic form. Not perverted into whatever society tries to make of it just like other social ideologies and constructs. With any collective group of people, things are bound to get distorted. But there's always an opposite to the backwards, a peace to the relentless, a humbleness to the bold.

The real problem that people who want answers have with religion shouldn't be with evidence but with character. What I mean is, what has been proven to be fact has changed throughout history and will constantly do so well into the future. So when it comes to evidence, every spectrum has had faults at one point or another so one will never yield to the other. There's knowledge all across existence and its endlessness gets the best of the human mind. Yet the outside subservience of religion turns a lot of people away from it but on the contraire, with belief you'll never feel oppressed again. Some people think that religion will slowly fade as time progresses but it will remain as long as there are people who have free will and or want answers. knowledge is an endless pursuit, so is belief, and thus religion. 

Science and religion are full of things we can't explain and or see yet both have "evidence." Science says heaven and or the like can't exist because the concept of a realm where conscious and creation correlates doesn't exist yet the universe does and so do we. Religion is full of miracles/phenomenons and so are the "laws" that explains how a vacuum can create life. The list goes on and will continue to grow. In this way we can imply that science and religion are omniscient occurrences that lead us to the same conclusion but with different understandings because of how broad and unimaginably impressive it is and how limited we are. 

Going back to understanding religion specifically, it's simply a choice like everything in life. Society may or may not influence those choices but people change and so does life. There's nothing wrong with belief because it's in everything we choose. The only bad type of choice is one made out of a lack of purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
