<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2242239967.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/112yzfj/cmv_religion_is_just_peer_pressure_from_your/">
    <title>CMV: Religion is just Peer Pressure from Your Parents</title>
    <original_poster>siddharth_pillai</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think most people believe in their religion. Nor do they believe in the gods they worship. They simply believe in whatever their parents believe. If you're a theist reading this, ask yourself whether you'd still follow your current religion if your parents were Islamic?

You can speculate yourself, don't you think its more likely that you would be Islamic too? If your parents were Hindus, wouldn't you be a Hindu? If your great grandparents were Sikhs wouldn't your parents and in turn you also be a Sikh?

It may not be true for all but its true for an overwhelming majority of people.

Edit: I'm getting some answers asking about people who convert or have non religious parents, my views don't apply to these people</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41881698893.0" user="Ok-Future-5257" delta="False">
    <text>My parents raised me LDS.  And I choose to continue being LDS, because I've studied it out and feel it is truth.  I don't rely on the Appeal to Tradition Fallacy -- I've just been blessed to be born of parents who already had the truth.

If I had been raised in another religion, would I have converted to LDS?  I don't know, and I don't care.  How I would act in alternate timelines is a moot point.  What matters is how I act in this real timeline.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41882194102.0" user="ToxicSalandit" delta="False">
    <text>I'm also a believing member. My mom was coercive about some things relating to the gospel, and my dad was anti when I was growing up. I found out for myself that the pure religion taught by Jesus and his prophets was true, so that is why I believe. 

A quote comes to mind, iirc: "If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine. Whether it be of God or whether I speak of myself."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
