<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="224934418.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3px4ia/cmv_french_is_the_ugliest_language_on_the_planet/">
    <title>CMV: French is the ugliest language on the planet.</title>
    <original_poster>Crayshack</original_poster>
    <original_post>When making a aesthetic assessment of anyone group of things, it is not that strange for one to end up on the bottom.  For languages, French occupies that position for me.  I would just accept this and not give it more thought, except for the fact that I will hear many people claiming french as one of, or possibly *the*, best sounding language on the planet.  I don't understand what they see in the language that makes it that appealing to them, and feel like I am missing something.

For perspective, to me French sounds like someone is trying not to vomit as they speak, and I can't think of anything appealing about how it sounds.  The best sounding languages in my mind is German, but there are a few others that are close enough to be effectively considered my favorite (including but not limited to: Swedish, Hawaiian, Russian, and Gaelic).

To get a delta, either find me a language that sounds worse than French, or give me reason to think that French sounds distinctly better than another language even if that language is not distinctly worse than some others.  I am discounting English and probably Spanish from consideration.  English is my native language, so it is difficult for me to make an assessment on how it sounds without considering the meaning of the words being used in the example.  Spanish is the most common second language where I grew up, so I learned some of it growing up and my opinion on it may be a bit clouded by experiences with communication difficulties between myself and people who spoke Spanish but not enough English.  I might be able to properly assess Spanish given the correct examples or perspective, but I would not count on it.

I will not accept a counter argument that my stance is not objective, because I think that aesthetics can only be assessed subjectively.  If you can argue for there being objective criteria, I will give you a delta.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28073642729.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Adyghe language is pretty ugly.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eab0ETN8fKQ

It's like someone dragging a nail on the chalkboard.

There are like 60 consonants (each harsher than the next), glottal stops everywhere and almost no vowels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073660837.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>This might be something worse than French.  A cursory search gave me only the same guy speaking, so it was hard to judge how much was his voice and how much was the language.  When I get a chance, I will spend some more time trying to find some examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073672889.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Here are some more samples for you to "enjoy":

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zJ7S61SLeRw

http://vk.com/videos27540381?z=video27540381_168552012

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073699522.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>That actually doesn't sound very bad.  It isn't amazing, but it isn't horrible either.  In the first recording you posted, the guy sounded like he had to much saliva in his mouth and the recording wasn't very good.  Hearing better recordings and other people using the language makes it sound much better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073748000.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Are you kidding?  It just sounds like bunch of harsh consonants smooshed together accentuated by sudden stops.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28074535238.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>I like the heavy consonant feel.  The part of find the worst about it is the overuse of the "sh" sound, but it isn't that bad.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
