<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="224934418.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3px4ia/cmv_french_is_the_ugliest_language_on_the_planet/">
    <title>CMV: French is the ugliest language on the planet.</title>
    <original_poster>Crayshack</original_poster>
    <original_post>When making a aesthetic assessment of anyone group of things, it is not that strange for one to end up on the bottom.  For languages, French occupies that position for me.  I would just accept this and not give it more thought, except for the fact that I will hear many people claiming french as one of, or possibly *the*, best sounding language on the planet.  I don't understand what they see in the language that makes it that appealing to them, and feel like I am missing something.

For perspective, to me French sounds like someone is trying not to vomit as they speak, and I can't think of anything appealing about how it sounds.  The best sounding languages in my mind is German, but there are a few others that are close enough to be effectively considered my favorite (including but not limited to: Swedish, Hawaiian, Russian, and Gaelic).

To get a delta, either find me a language that sounds worse than French, or give me reason to think that French sounds distinctly better than another language even if that language is not distinctly worse than some others.  I am discounting English and probably Spanish from consideration.  English is my native language, so it is difficult for me to make an assessment on how it sounds without considering the meaning of the words being used in the example.  Spanish is the most common second language where I grew up, so I learned some of it growing up and my opinion on it may be a bit clouded by experiences with communication difficulties between myself and people who spoke Spanish but not enough English.  I might be able to properly assess Spanish given the correct examples or perspective, but I would not count on it.

I will not accept a counter argument that my stance is not objective, because I think that aesthetics can only be assessed subjectively.  If you can argue for there being objective criteria, I will give you a delta.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28073449126.0" user="Funky_Ducky" delta="False">
    <text>There's an interesting quote by a Roman emperor, Charles V
&amp;gt;“I speak Spanish to God, Italian to women, French to men, and German to my horse.”
According to this [article](http://www.theguardian.com/education/2014/jul/17/what-makes-a-language-attractive) by The Guardian, the sounds of a language are likely due to our perception of country's values and status. Not the inherent value of the beauty or lack thereof in the language.
&amp;gt;According to Dr Vineeta Chand of the University of Essex, if we have a positive perception of a particular community then we tend to have equally positive views of the language they speak.
Language value is also attached to the value of the language, ie how  many more people you'll be able to communicate with due to your understanding of said language. 

There's also a reason many Americans love the sound of Spanish and French (often seen as very romantic languages)
&amp;gt;"English speakers are drawn to the melody of a language such as French or Italian," explains Dr Patti Adank, a lecturer on speech, hearing and phonetic sciences at University College London (UCL). "In comparison, languages such as Thai or Mandarin can sound harsh because they are using tonal distinctions. It sounds very unnatural and unexpected."

So,
&amp;gt;"There hasn't been any research that I know of that has directly exploited the attractiveness of a language and didn't eventually tie it back to the social evaluation of the speaking community."

Your view on the French language as being ugly is more than likely just your perception of French culture and not the inherent beauty of their language. 

PS. I agree what you say in regards to French, but I'm honestly a little perplexed that you think that of French and not of German (I've studied it for several years myself) and I always joke that it sounds like I'm coughing up a loogie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28073604338.0" user="Crayshack" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's also a reason many Americans love the sound of Spanish and French (often seen as very romantic languages)
&amp;gt; &amp;gt;"English speakers are drawn to the melody of a language such as French or Italian," explains Dr Patti Adank, a lecturer on speech, hearing and phonetic sciences at University College London (UCL). "In comparison, languages such as Thai or Mandarin can sound harsh because they are using tonal distinctions. It sounds very unnatural and unexpected."

What is interesting is my perception is the opposite here.  I see Mandarin as a very melodic language, and I have often described it as sounding like singing (I am not familiar enough with Thai to comment on it).  Meanwhile, French and Italian lack that appearance.

&amp;gt;Your view on the French language as being ugly is more than likely just your perception of French culture and not the inherent beauty of their language.

Entirely possible, but if that is true, then it is impossible to make an assessment of the aesthetics of a language without including an assessment of the aesthetics of the culture.  I am still left with thinking that French is a hideous language.  Also, when looking at the languages that I am fond of, while I am familiar with most of their cultures, I am very unfamiliar with Hawaiian culture beyond its language.  I doubt my assessment of the aesthetics of that language is based on my feelings of the culture because I have no feelings for the culture.

&amp;gt;I agree what you say in regards to French, but I'm honestly a little perplexed that you think that of French and not of German (I've studied it for several years myself) and I always joke that it sounds like I'm coughing up a loogie.

I get that feeling from Arabic and Hebrew, but not from German.  I am a fan of the [voiceless uvular fricative](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voiceless_uvular_fricative) in general.  While I can agree with it being a bit overused in languages like Hebrew and Arabic, it feels like it is used to the correct amount in German and I like the feeling of the end result.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
