<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078335753.0" user="Funkmaster_Flash" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop"

I live in a city and work office hours. Crops are thin on the ground and I can't help builders because I lack building site qualifications and they also work 8 hour days for the most part. Your view is a perfect world scenario that is unworkable. 

If I helped the homeless it would be noble but would not really address my fitness needs unless I ran homeless aerobics classes, which is not a top priority for the homeless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078386232.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>You need a perfect world for every gym to be converted into a greenhouse with crops in it? Lug the soil from the loading dock up to the plants and back a few times before you use it if you want. You don't have to be efficient at all with the farming because any efficiency is better than the zero amount that was being done before. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078399837.0" user="Funkmaster_Flash" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You need a perfect world for every gym to be converted into a greenhouse with crops in it?

Yes I live in a city, single pane glass greenhouses would be ravaged from vandalism and probably by all the now unemployed gym staff. 

How quickly do these crops grow because a lot of crop growing is waiting. Do I just run about with soil for a week before planting crops then sit on my arse for weeks/months until the fruits of labour yield?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078406725.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>Most stores have single pane glass windows completely covering the side facing the sidewalk. Are they all ravaged by vandalism? Are you actually suggesting that buildings with glass windows cannot exist in a city without being ravaged? What city do you live in?? Thousands of stores with single pane windows have tens of thousands of dollars worth of TVs, cars, etc etc in them at this moment. But if we put a few thousand half grown onions in the same situation they would instantly be ravaged by vandals? This makes no sense.

And you are applying outdoor growing facts (the seasons) to indoor growing. Why would you plant everything at once and then harvest everything at once later? We do this outside because of the seasons. Inside, you would just stagger it so you always had something to do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078447272.0" user="Funkmaster_Flash" delta="False">
    <text>Most stores also have shutters on the windows outwith business hours. Do you suggest having shutters on greenhouses too? Are you beginning to see how ridiculous this is?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
