<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078934900.0" user="Funcuz" delta="False">
    <text>Simply put : Because I'm not a drone living only to serve society. Why should I be ? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
