<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078320190.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>At the end of the day, it is my body. I have to right to decide if I want to make my body stronger or more healthy. 

If people want to use their time and effort to help others good on them, but we shouldn't be forcing people to do things. People do have free will on how they spend their time. 

Going to a gym is just a personal choice just like any other. People should have the right to make personal choices about their own bodies. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078325756.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>Everything you said is true but doesn't address my view. I never said we should force people to do what I was explaining. What I did is lay out a plan that would be a far less wasteful and selfish way to work out. Of course it is your right to go to the gym, but that doesn't mean it isn't wasteful and selfish to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078337046.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>You have a small problem with authority. 

You may feel that people are selfish for joining a gym, but that's where you're beef ends. 

People do have the right to how they are going to spend their time. 

You could be tutoring kids online for free instead of messing about on Reddit. Are you also selfish because you don't spend all your free time helping people in need. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078339324.0" user="Backstyck" delta="False">
    <text>Volunteering to do a job is not going to give the same results as a focused work out session. You are stating that using one's own free time for self-improvement is outright immoral. What possible way could a person spend their alone time that wouldn't be regarded as immoral under such a view?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
