<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078364547.0" user="guohuade" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds great! Just teleport me to somewhere in the developing world where they need that kind of labor for 1 hour in the evenings after work on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday. I'd also like to do it safely without any risk of injuring myself, and keep track of my exercise so I know my progress, perhaps with a "picking partner" or "building partner" who can spot me when the bricks/bushels are too heavy.

This is ridiculous. Gym labor is not *organized*, and it's beyond chaotic. Everyone there is doing something different, for a different reason, on a different schedule, with different abilities, and without any relationship to one another. To imagine that it would be practical for all of the gym-goers of the world to organize themselves into some sort of free-labor troupe that runs around town building houses or picking crops in their free time is beyond insane.

Yes, 30 guys with building materials and years of experience can build a house. 30 random people from the gym down the street can lift some weights or run on treadmills, but that quite obviously doesn't translate into construction. What the hell are you smoking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078414613.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>You can hurt yourself at the gym, why would this alternative need to be way safer? And why do you think you need to go to the developing world to find people who need food? Almost 50 million americans are food insecure. Many volunteer groups organize the building of low income housing after disasters already, many using exclusively teens with the direction of a supervisor. Why is it so difficult to imagine adults doing the same thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078421200.0" user="guohuade" delta="False">
    <text>I don't live in America, and where I am volunteer work would not fall into an allowable category of my visa. Even if I were in the US, the main thrust of my argument still remains: all of those people who need help are not near me, easily accessible to fit around my schedule, I am not trained to help them, and the rest of my gym buddies and I are not an organized crew.

Good job, you've managed to say nothing of value.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
