<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078343855.0" user="RAGING_VEGETARIAN" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Wasteful

Compared to what?  Driving cars is wasteful.  Eating meat is wasteful.  Flower gardens are wasteful.  Three-bedroom houses are wasteful for most families.  Pizza delivery is wasteful.  Resort vacations are wasteful.  Central air conditioning is wasteful.

So is going to the gym for a few hours a week wasteful enough to matter?  I recognize you view it as wasted effort, and I understand.  But how much labor do you expect someone to do in 3-5 hours per week?  I can't imagine it would be very significant.  So I don't think that going to the gym is wasteful by any meaningful measure.

&amp;gt;Selfish

In your view of the ideal society, would anyone do anything for enjoyment alone?  Do you think people should devote every waking hour to service for others?  Maybe instead of watching movies, people should volunteer to watch surveillance cameras that guard high-crime neighborhoods.  Maybe instead of reading books, people should screen grant proposals for the NSF.

I agree that going to the gym is a self-centered activity, I just don't think that self-centered activities are necessarily *bad.*  I can see an argument against a trust-fund kid who does literally nothing but exercise, but as for the average gym goer pumping iron for an hour after work?  Come on, let people do something for fun.

Let me ask you something in addition.  What do you think about entertainers and athletes, people who whose full-time (+++) jobs don't contribute anything to society besides enjoyment.  Are they wasteful and selfish, too?  Aren't they much more wasteful and selfish than an average gymgoer is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078400448.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>Wasteful:
My point is not that the gym is the only wasteful thing that people do. I never said that. And no, no one person would be able to make much of a difference working a few hours a week. But if hundreds of thousands of people did? The way gyms work now contribute nothing to things like crop yields, and if we did this than we would have X amount more crops per year. With so many people contributing a little bit, it would add up to a significant amount, which is why I think it is wasteful by a meaningful measure.

For the 'selfish' section of your response, you are completely distorting what I said. From my response to someone else above. "The point of my argument is that if somebody performs action A, but action B satisfies the reason why people perform action A as well as benefiting society, then action B is preferable to action A. What you are suggesting is if action A does not benefit society than it is immoral." Movies are not watched for the sole reason that people want to spend time watching a screen, so the surveillance cameras idea is not relevant (although that is a pretty cool idea). If you work out purely for enjoyment, and this far outweighs the physical gains you get, than yes, you are right and farming or something else would not be an acceptable replacement according to my criteria. But I think most people do not go solely because they love doing it, but do it because of the results they get. If these same results could be obtained, and in the process you are helping people, than why wouldn't that be less wasteful and selfish? To reiterate what I said in another post, I have never said that being wasteful or selfish is even a bad thing, let alone the moral sin many of the repliers are assuming I think of wastefulness. Letting emotions get in the way of logic is ridiculous. Ones normative opinion on wastefulness is irrelevant when discussing the descriptive facts of whether something is wasteful or not, so I agree with some of that second to last paragraph. I never said self-centered actives were bad. But even if I thought they were the best thing ever, it would still be the case that they are in fact selfish. I agree with the trust fund thing, and again, I am not trying to stop people from having their fun if that is really why they go.

The last question has its answer contained above but I'll say it again specifically in response to the question. I did not say, and am not suggesting, that everything that is entertainment is wasteful and selfish. I am saying that an activity that fulfills your reason for doing another activity but also contributes something good to society is preferable to the activity that does not contribute anything. There is no activity that matches the reason people become entertainers that is applicable in this situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28295195881.0" user="bubblecrack" delta="False">
    <text>Wasteful and Selfish are entirely subjective. There's no descriptive facts that force an action to be in one or the other. It would still be up to the interpretation. It's like you don't know the language, and you have a make-a-wish idea as a 4th grader. Enjoy the 15 minutes of fame. Your ideas belong in the garbage. :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
