<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="228679003.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3s5duj/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_for_the_police_in/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal for the police in unmarked vehicles to pull people over for traffic offences</title>
    <original_poster>joelzundel</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Argument 1**


Imagine two cop cars driving along a motorway in opposite directions. One of them is marked, while the other is not. 

The unmarked one is going with the flow, which is usually a couple km/h over the limit, pulling people over. They only pull over maybe 4 cars an hour, and everybody else is not slowing down, simply because they can't see the police. From a civilian standpoint this creates a paradigm: the police are there only to collect money for the government. 

On the other side of the motorway, the marked police car is driving normally, and obviously nobody is overtaking them. Everyone stays safe and happy.

IMO: The police should do it's best to keep people safe, not collect money.

**Argument 2**

Some jackass buys a used police car, some lights a siren, and a uniform off Ebay. Drives around in unpopulated areas, pulling people over and robbing them/killing them/whatever other crime. The victim can not refuse to pull over - it's a very serious offence in most countries. It wouldn't be such a problem if traffic police would only use marked cars.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28109509815.0" user="rollingForInitiative" delta="False">
    <text>So what you're saying is that, committing crimes should be allowed if people think they won't be caught? That's very odd. 

A crime is a crime. If you're speeding, you're speeding, and deserve a ticket. Doesn't matter if you *thought* you might get caught or not. 

As for argument 2, that seems far-fetched. How often does this even happen? And it would be a pretty severe crime for those who actually do it. That's the problem, if it's common.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
