<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="228679003.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3s5duj/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_for_the_police_in/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal for the police in unmarked vehicles to pull people over for traffic offences</title>
    <original_poster>joelzundel</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Argument 1**


Imagine two cop cars driving along a motorway in opposite directions. One of them is marked, while the other is not. 

The unmarked one is going with the flow, which is usually a couple km/h over the limit, pulling people over. They only pull over maybe 4 cars an hour, and everybody else is not slowing down, simply because they can't see the police. From a civilian standpoint this creates a paradigm: the police are there only to collect money for the government. 

On the other side of the motorway, the marked police car is driving normally, and obviously nobody is overtaking them. Everyone stays safe and happy.

IMO: The police should do it's best to keep people safe, not collect money.

**Argument 2**

Some jackass buys a used police car, some lights a siren, and a uniform off Ebay. Drives around in unpopulated areas, pulling people over and robbing them/killing them/whatever other crime. The victim can not refuse to pull over - it's a very serious offence in most countries. It wouldn't be such a problem if traffic police would only use marked cars.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28107048528.0" user="vl99" delta="False">
    <text>Laws exist to keep people safe, police exist to enforce those laws. People shouldn't be obeying the rules of the road because police are present, they should be doing it because not doing so would be dangerous for themselves and others.

As for your argument 2, saying we should ban all unmarked cars to prevent people from impersonating police is a bit like saying we should ban all knives to prevent stabbings.

It's not that common, and when it does happen the punishments for it are incredibly severe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107088227.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>re: 1

What people should do is not what they in fact do.  We can say people should drive the speed limit til we're blue in the face.  But without consequences for failing to drive the limit, they won't.

Deterrence is widely accepted to be a valid purpose of actions within the criminal justice system.  And posting of marked vehicles is a highly effective deterrent for roadway violations.

re: 2

Knives have a wide range of useful purposes.  Pulling people over in unmarked cars does not.  Further, it is strictly an internal regulation by the government of its own conduct, not an impingement of anyone's liberty.

If the government can do its job more safely, then the law should reflect that.

Also, there is a third point that pulling over people in unmarked cars is more dangerous for cops.  Unmarked cars can't have as big or prominent of a lightbar as marked cars.  That makes them more likely to be seen late or not seen by motorists when they're at the side of the road.  That makes it more dangerous for the officer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107117327.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that having  unmarked cars is a great was to improve compliance with the law. While some people would not follow the law unless they were watched, unmarked cars used in addition to marked cars can mean people don't know when they're being watched. Then they err on the side of caution and follow the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107334513.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of using an unmarked car for it is that people don't realize there are cop cars around.  It's internally contradictory for a secret technique to be a deterrent.

If you're saying the existence of unmarked cars will create a pervasive fear of cops that will lead to people acting within the law all the time, I'm not sure I buy that.  Certainly it doesn't happen in my experience, even though the police do use unmarked vehicles on roads by me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107109302.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As for your argument 2, saying we should ban all unmarked cars to prevent people from impersonating police is a bit like saying we should ban all knives to prevent stabbings.

I never said all. They can be very useful in investigations, arresting dangerous criminals, etc. What I meant is that the police shouldn't use unmarked cars as a way to give out more tickets.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28108389632.0" user="cpast" delta="False">
    <text>Traffic stops are not just used to give out tickets, though. If police are using unmarked cars for investigations, that will often require them to pull someone over from an unmarked. So, you wouldn't solve the issue of impersonators. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107577402.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Laws exist to keep people safe

Do speed limits keep people safe? This is something we all seem to assume, but does it hold up?

I don't mean driving 'safely', I mean literally posted speed limits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107603723.0" user="vl99" delta="False">
    <text>What sort of picture are you trying to illustrate here. I'll bite, but I'm not sure where you're trying to lead me. I'd say having visible speed limit signs likely results in a safer road than having none.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107620090.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>I'm asking if the difference between roads lacking a speed limit (e.g. 60 mph) has less accidents/fatalities/whathaveyou than the same road if it lacked any such legal limit. By a statistically large or small margin?

Do YOU speed? I bet you do.

Do you care more about what speed you feel comfortable driving, or about the legal limit? If the legal limit is lower than you feel comfortable, how do you react? etc. etc.

I think we take for granted that some of these things.

Clearly driving unsafely high speeds is bad, but there some people who are unsafe at any speed, and some who could drive 15-20 over no problem.

I fundamentally take issue with the situation we find ourselves in. **Laws that are ignored by 99% of everyone are probably bad laws.** Laws that allow enforcers to arbitrary enforce a law that everyone ignores is ripe for abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28110570011.0" user="CptnMalReynolds" delta="False">
    <text>There's a stretch of "highway" out my way when I head to Detroit that has a posted speed of 50 or 55 MPH, but if you're going any less than 65, it's likely that you're actually just going to get hit by someone else driving 70+. So it's "safest" to drive 20+ MPH over the *posted* speed limit, which I'm pretty sure is enough to get a "reckless and endangering" ticket with enough points to lose your license and get your car impounded, because there's an *implied* speed limit known to the drivers that frequent the area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107855148.0" user="jdylopa" delta="False">
    <text>I think a good argument OP left out is that the police are there to act as a deterrent. If a police car is marked, people are obeying the law (out of fear for themselves being pulled over), so everything is safer. If police are unmarked, then they're just punishing, not making anything safer (since usually the flow of traffic will still be above the speed limit). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
