<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="228679003.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3s5duj/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_for_the_police_in/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal for the police in unmarked vehicles to pull people over for traffic offences</title>
    <original_poster>joelzundel</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Argument 1**


Imagine two cop cars driving along a motorway in opposite directions. One of them is marked, while the other is not. 

The unmarked one is going with the flow, which is usually a couple km/h over the limit, pulling people over. They only pull over maybe 4 cars an hour, and everybody else is not slowing down, simply because they can't see the police. From a civilian standpoint this creates a paradigm: the police are there only to collect money for the government. 

On the other side of the motorway, the marked police car is driving normally, and obviously nobody is overtaking them. Everyone stays safe and happy.

IMO: The police should do it's best to keep people safe, not collect money.

**Argument 2**

Some jackass buys a used police car, some lights a siren, and a uniform off Ebay. Drives around in unpopulated areas, pulling people over and robbing them/killing them/whatever other crime. The victim can not refuse to pull over - it's a very serious offence in most countries. It wouldn't be such a problem if traffic police would only use marked cars.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28107114321.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and everybody else is not slowing down, simply because they can't see the police.  

They are breaking the law, why is this suddenly forgivable only because thei think no law enforcers are looking?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107194313.0" user="Searff" delta="False">
    <text>This is the best counter point to the OP. Speed limits on most roads exist to protect cross traffic and pedestrians. We should be policing reckless speeders on these kinds of roads.

 However, speeders on highways are much less dangerous compared to traffic wevers and slow drivers. Police arrest speeders on the highway which is pointless.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107203775.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>It might be pointless or not (I don't think your point is proven), but if the speed limit of a highway is 80, why are you going at 90?  What benefit does it bring?  

If everyone complies with the law at their own criteria and you can dismiss laws because you think they are pointless, where do you draw the line?  Traffic lights are silly?  Seatbelts?  Handbrake turns?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107224278.0" user="Searff" delta="False">
    <text>High Speed, on a highway, is a red herring. Modern crash and safety tests have shown that high speed is rarely the cause or catalyst of highway crashes. Instead improper lane changing, weaving, no use of turn signals, driving well below the speed minimum, road rage, tailgating and incorrect lane use are much more likely to be the cause of highway collisions. 

People drive best at the speeds they are comfortable going. As long as that is not too slow, generally drivers are most safe at whichever speed that happens to be. Forcing drivers, arbitrarly, down to specific speeds can lead to higher rates of tailgating, road rage, and improper lane Use/Changing, which then leads to the real and more serious accidents. 

I'm an EMT. More people die trying to get around slow drivers then ever die speeding down a highway at 90mph. 

I'm not saying break the laws. I'm saying the laws need to be changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107263565.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>Sure but what happens between when a study is released and the laws change?  I think the topic itself is a red herring on how as citizens we should behave.  

&amp;gt; Instead improper lane changing, weaving, no use of turn signals, driving well below the speed minimum, road rage, tailgating and incorrect lane use are much more likely to be the cause of highway collisions.  

I think this is a false sichotomy.  You can drive at the speed limit without doing these things.  Claiming that a speed limit causes these things is not acceptable.  

&amp;gt; People drive best at the speeds they are comfortable going  

Dunning-krueger will tell you this as a rule won't work even if the statement is true.  

&amp;gt; I'm an EMT. More people die trying to get around slow drivers then ever die speeding down a highway at 90mph.  

I am under the impression that as an EMT you are not qualified to determine what speed is safer or any other traffic judgment more than an accountant that is passionate about traffic literature, but rather how the body dies or is kept alive in an emergency situation only. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107279526.0" user="Searff" delta="False">
    <text>unfortunately the people who are qualified to determine traffic rules are separate from the people making the traffic rules. There is mounting evidence that speed limits are a red herring and mounting inaction by state and local governments. 

I will post a number of recent studies when I get home. We tend to discuss this kind of stuff at the station and a firefighter showed me a study the other day from Europe that showed that "tough on crime" impulses are preventing change to traffic law in local/province jurisdictions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107486412.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>With this post I can agree, no need for studies as I am familiar with them.  

My only point is that in the non-zero gap between an accurate study and a change in the law we are to both comply with the law and avoid risky behaviour.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28108769752.0" user="Obi-Wan_Kannabis" delta="False">
    <text>No driver in the world obeys speed limits. Getting a ticket is only a matter of luck, not of obeying the law.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
