<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="228679003.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3s5duj/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_for_the_police_in/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal for the police in unmarked vehicles to pull people over for traffic offences</title>
    <original_poster>joelzundel</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Argument 1**


Imagine two cop cars driving along a motorway in opposite directions. One of them is marked, while the other is not. 

The unmarked one is going with the flow, which is usually a couple km/h over the limit, pulling people over. They only pull over maybe 4 cars an hour, and everybody else is not slowing down, simply because they can't see the police. From a civilian standpoint this creates a paradigm: the police are there only to collect money for the government. 

On the other side of the motorway, the marked police car is driving normally, and obviously nobody is overtaking them. Everyone stays safe and happy.

IMO: The police should do it's best to keep people safe, not collect money.

**Argument 2**

Some jackass buys a used police car, some lights a siren, and a uniform off Ebay. Drives around in unpopulated areas, pulling people over and robbing them/killing them/whatever other crime. The victim can not refuse to pull over - it's a very serious offence in most countries. It wouldn't be such a problem if traffic police would only use marked cars.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28107066109.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the police are there only to collect money for the government.

Or they are there to enforce the law. 

&amp;gt; Some jackass buys a used police car, some lights a siren, and a uniform off Ebay. Drives around in unpopulated areas, pulling people over and robbing them/killing them/whatever other crime. The victim can not refuse to pull over - it's a very serious offence in most countries. It wouldn't be such a problem if traffic police would only use marked cars.

You mean I can't go buy a new Dodge Charger and do the exact same thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107099132.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>You can, but if you write POLICE all over your Charger you're going to get caught pretty quickly.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107101855.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Or they are there to enforce the law.


There are different ways of enforcing the law. The law is for the people, not the other way around. The end goal is to keep people safe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107114147.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  The end goal is to keep people safe

They keep people safe by enforcing the laws and making sure people are driving at **safe** speeds. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107130885.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>Like I said, there are different ways of enforcing the law. And virtually any other one is superior to unmarked police cars ( Speed traps, speed cameras, police presence, etc)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107137174.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>If unmarked cars weren't effective then cops wouldn't use them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107194321.0" user="rvhack" delta="False">
    <text>How are they more effective and what are they effective at doing.

There's an arguement that unmarked cars are more effective at finding people to pull over. You could see that as better law enforcement or as better revenue generation.

People don't see unmarked cars and behave as if they aren't there. On the one hand, the cop pulled someone over who, if they had seen the cop, may have changes their habits in the officer's presence.
 
On the other, many won't slow down in the officer's presence because they don't see him. This would be considered a drawback in that it would be safer if the general pace of the road slowed down. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107209885.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>How are they not? They do the exact same job as marked cars but can blend in better for better enforcement. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107226316.0" user="rvhack" delta="False">
    <text>Not everyone feels that way. Assuming you agree that ultimately it's what reduces accidents that's most important, some would argue that increased visual police presence does that, by slowing the most people down to proper speeds. ( Also assuming slower = safer )

*They might also argue that, while the person pulled over is no longer a liability, only that person is impacted. Furthermore, some consider it suspicious that this without a doubt the best outcome for those benefited proportionally by the amount of ticket revenue generated.

**They may also look to other countries that don't utilize unmarked vehicles as prevalently as an example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107247865.0" user="nude_peril" delta="False">
    <text>Effective at what?  Raising money?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107273118.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>Enforcing the law, making sure people are driving safely</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107104412.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>Chargers are pretty common unmarked cars, some cheap red/blue LEDs and I've got a cop car at night, no ones going to see the side at night when I'm pulling them over</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107115147.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>This  supports my argument</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107123335.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>How? You know all Chargers don't start out as cop cars right? I can go to the Dodge dealership and buy one right now. Really any car could be outfitted with LEDs and look like a cop car at night</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107140386.0" user="joelzundel" delta="False">
    <text>You can make it look like an unmarked cop car, not like a marked one. The light bar on the roof alone will attract a lot of attention. Besides, most people know how their local cars look like (paint color etc), and thats pretty hard not to notice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107149594.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>You don't put the lights on the roof, you put them on the back on the visors and dash like unmarked cars do. When it's dark out can you tell what color a car is in your rear view mirror? When you see police lights at night is your first thought "I wonder if this is some chainsaw murderer whose using a fake cop car to trap me?" 

No, of course not, it's incredibly rare for people to do this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107172755.0" user="rvhack" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of people respect cars that may or may not be police as they'd rather not take the chance.


*respect as in behave as if they are a police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107316355.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that this law would ban cop cars which don't have the lightbar on the roof.  So if you see a car with only a light in the dash pulling you over, you know it's not a cop, because cops can't do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107320907.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen marked cop cars without light bars. 

And criminals are known to follow the law right? They would never break the law and put a light bar on their roof. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107322475.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've seen marked cop cars without light bars.

And if I were writing this law, I'd ban them.

&amp;gt;And criminals are known to follow the law right? They would never break the law and put a light bar on their roof.

The point is that if you do that, it makes it *really* likely you'll get caught, because lightbars are a pain in the ass to install and uninstall, and are really noticeable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107340493.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>I've installed lighted roof racks a bunch of times, it's really not that difficult, the one on my jeep was even removable so I could get into parking decks. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28108394520.0" user="cpast" delta="False">
    <text>*That* would be an absolutely terrible policy. Police have a whole lot of uses for unmarked cars; even in states where they *can't* have unmarked cars assigned primarily to traffic duty (like California), they have uses. Stakeouts don't work well when you have to make it obvious you're doing a stakeout. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28108399812.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I meant that cops wouldn't be allowed to pull people over in cars without the lightbar.  You could still use unmarkeds for stakeouts, warrant service, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107619226.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>There is no bar on the roof of an unmarked car, or a second hand police car. 

If someone mistakes a civilians car for an unmarked car and so obeys the speed limits then that is a bonus for the effectiveness of unmarked cars. More people are obeying the law. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107243672.0" user="BolshevikMuppet" delta="False">
    <text>You do know that when the police sell their old cards they remove the official markings, and there are already laws against impersonating an officer, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28108295801.0" user="Williamcg" delta="False">
    <text>Criminals don't follow laws. Also, it's not that difficult to put LEDs in your dashboard and play a siren sound from a megaphone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28107614388.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>You actually cannot right it all over. When police sell their old vehicle they remove the sirens and lights, they remove any protective cages, and they removing the markings. If you impersonate an officer that is a crime and you are arrested. Using that as an argument against unmarked cars is not legitimate. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
