<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28118200101.0" user="OctogenarianSandwich" delta="False">
    <text>Although I am loath to say it, this is classic victim blaming. By saying someone did something that in someway brought about their own harm is a typical response of people looking to find comfort that it won't happen to them. You say they underestimate their responsibility and capability to change things but it is just as likely you overestimate your own. I don't mean this as an attack. It's a natural response and I only wish I could think of the proper name. It ultimately comes down to how people deal with the lack of rhyme or reason that makes up life. Your approach cannot be said to be objectively better than theirs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118447843.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>If the same event, however unlikely, happened to me i would understand my sort comings which put me there and not wish for people to suffer with me who were not there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118502023.0" user="OctogenarianSandwich" delta="False">
    <text>Again you assume there is a shortcoming. Sometimes bad stuff happens despite every best effort and intention otherwise, particularly in cases involving third parties. I imagine you wouldn't blame someone who got run over by a lorry that ran a read light but your view leads to the conclusion it was their own fault for crossing the road. Can you give me an example of when you would accept your shortcomings have led to harm because I'm finding it hard to think of one? 

&amp;gt;not wish for people to suffer with me who were not there.

I don't think anyone wants sympathy, if not just because it would require harm to occur to them first. That's also not an uncommon view but at the end of the day it's not up to you to shield others despite your good intentions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118517586.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>You assumptions are right about the crossing the road as i suspect risks and preventative measures were ignored.

As i said in the original post, physics or where people have taken appropriate precautions to reduce risk would be instances where this compassion rule would apply.

I remembered a good example in my own life which came close.

I was working on a piece of equipment  and checking for voltage on something i needed to wire. I checked it to ground 3 times to verify the power was off. I grabbed the line and was electrocuted. Now some people would say it's now my fault because someone else broke the electrical code and brought in another power source but my brain instantly thought of ways and tools to prevent this in the future. Now i have another tool to detect power and i do a final direct contact with a ground before i touch the wire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118585086.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, we learn from our experiences and probably learn more from our mistakes than our successes. If people take needless or reckless risks, then people are less likely to feel compassion towards those people but nobody can be expected to account for all potential risks. Let's take your example of the people killed in the concert hall in Paris. Let's say somebody went and had a suspicion that the place might be raided by suicidal terrorists with automatic rifles. This person wears a body armor vest under his clothes and carries a piece that he is well trained and experienced in using in close quarter, urban combat scenarios. This person is standing near the door when one of the raiders walks in the door behind him and caps him in the back of the head with no warning. That guy should have done more in your head and since he didn't, it's wrong for other people to feel the emotion of compassion directed at him? Based on your lay interpretation of a snippet from a wikipedia article?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118613385.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Why stand near the door. I alway sit at places with maximum view of doors and observe people's behavior to asset risk. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28119052855.0" user="TagaKain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why stand near the door. I alway sit at places with maximum view of doors and observe people's behavior to asset risk.

How could you say that it is those places that have the least risk? Have you done a proper risk assessment of every venue at every schedule, and what are your criteria?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118611241.0" user="OctogenarianSandwich" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You assumptions are right about the crossing the road as i suspect risks and preventative measures were ignored.

Why assume that? From the facts the only wrongdoer was the driver who ignored the red light. There is no basis to assume incompetence on the part of the victim.

&amp;gt;Now some people would say it's now my fault because someone else broke the electrical code

The law also agrees which is why you could sue the other person if they were negligent. It sounds to me like you acted in the way any reasonable person would. You checked three times so why blame yourself over the person who didn't do what they were supposed to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118627410.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know facts and assume incompetence instead of compassion. Why do you assume they need compassion?

The other person someone i don't know or ever met. They did something which could have been from the 70's so the point is silly about suing.

See the issue is i knew i could do more for my own safety but ignored the risks. I have no one to blame but my self. There will always be incompatance and human error and i have to defend against it or suffer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118653929.0" user="OctogenarianSandwich" delta="False">
    <text>I don't assume they need compassion. Assuming either way is equally wrong. You also misunderstood the point about suing. The point is even the law which is stereotypically uncompassionate and unwilling to be generous accepts third parties can be the cause of harm. If you think the law is needlessly compassionate you are straying into needless cynicism.

&amp;gt;i have to defend against it or suffer.

You're incapable of doing so. You will suffer that is a guarantee. Holding yourself and others to an impossible to reach standard is pointless.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
