<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28118150245.0" user="TagaKain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

Hmm, you don't understand chess? If you're asking who is responsible for your failure, of course that's a combination of your abilities, along with your opponents. I thought that is something obvious.

To blame solely yourself for an outcome that is the result of two individuals doesn't make sense, unless you have omnipotence. And this is just a simple game we're talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118442452.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it not make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28119048432.0" user="TagaKain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you're asking who is responsible for your failure, of course that's a combination of your abilities, along with your opponents. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
