<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28118133331.0" user="Burt_the_Hutt" delta="False">
    <text>'Suffering not being self-inflicted' is an empirically identified component, not a philosophical one. Buddhists, for example, would say they have no less compassion for those whose suffering is self-inflicted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118136227.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Well take that up with Wikipedia and who ever their sources are. Seems to me it explains where i find compassion and where i don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118146671.0" user="TagaKain" delta="False">
    <text>No, he can criticize that definition precisely because you agree with it. You can't just brush it off because you got it from somewhere else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118441694.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>It's really not going to get anywhere because we function on united definitions created by experts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118535735.0" user="Burt_the_Hutt" delta="False">
    <text>You'll notice wikipedia filed those criteria under 'psychology', meaning those criteria were based on subject's perceptions, not the other way around. Even if you could prove all suffering is self-inflicted, it wouldn't mean people would stop feeling compassion, or contradict anything for doing so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118552797.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying all suffering. Just most of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28119046695.0" user="TagaKain" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, again it is your views that are being challenged, and it is you that needs to justify them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
