<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28118114033.0" user="non-rhetorical" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted

Who's doing the self-inflicting here? The persons killed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118117787.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. One could say everything from their elected officals policies to being infront of isis unarmed in a compromised position of defense led to their untimely deaths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118123949.0" user="non-rhetorical" delta="False">
    <text>A private citizen can't alter the outcome of an election unless you're willing to delve into "butterfly effect."

(Especially if that private citizen is a child. Were the children at fault? Their parents tell them where to go and whether to bring weapons.)

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118129121.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>A person is not a slave or dependant on others government or not. Their actions are theirs alone. 

Age does not mater, what maters is freewill. So to draw a line that you are asking for it would be at what ever age freewill happens at. Before freewill you are not a person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118135648.0" user="non-rhetorical" delta="False">
    <text>Suppose my brother picks a fight with a mob boss. The mafioso promises to kill my brother's whole family, which includes me. I live on a farm; I have no knowledge of any of this. One day a mobster comes to my house and shoots me in the head.

I can't control my brother or my government. How am I too blame for their actions?

Further, governments staff hundreds of thousands with the goal of anticipating terrorist activity. If they failed (because it's hard), how can you look at a family of four and say, "You should have known better"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118440330.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Did not protect your self. Did not deal with brothers clear shot comings. Did not deal with mob problem because why would it affect you. Etc</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
