<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28119217434.0" user="thewoodendesk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

First of all, chess is a deterministic game where both players have perfect information. There is no hand of cards or RNG or fog of war. With perfect information in a purely deterministic ruleset, every action has a foreseeable consequence, and the failure to determine the right outcome is placed squarely on the shoulders of the player. Real life is anything but that. Imagine if you got lung cancer in 2060 because you ate peanut butter, which was proven to greatly increase the risk of lung cancer in an influential study done during the 2040's. How can you in 2015 possibly consider the risk of eating peanut butter when its carcinogenic properties weren't even discovered until 25 years later?

Second of all, game-winning plays aren't purely through the mistakes of players. Chess notation denotes mistakes and blunders with "?" and "??" respectively. But they also denote brilliant plays as well, denoted by "!" and "!!" Yes, there are plenty of games which can be summarized as the player who played the least sloppy, but there are plenty of games where one player legitimately got outplayed by another. So, in the context of the recent Paris terrorist attacks, how do you determine whether it is a blunder of the people to go to the theater and a brilliant move by the terrorists to conduct their terrorist attack on a theater? And if it was indeed the terrorists outplaying innocent civilians, then their troubles are not self-inflicted and thus deserving of our compassion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
