<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="229906900.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3svpas/cmv_i_believe_events_like_the_paris_attack_evoke/">
    <title>CMV: I believe events like the Paris attack evoke a response of compassion which comes from a faulty belief in how we think we interact with the world</title>
    <original_poster>Misogynist-bydefault</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was trying to figure out why i don't feel compassion when everyone else does. So i researched it and found my answer.


"Compassion consists of three major requirements: People must feel that troubles that evoke their feelings are serious, people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted, and that people must be able to picture themselves with the same problems" 


"people require that sufferers' troubles are not self-inflicted."


I believe that we directly affect the world around us and are responsible for our decisions regardless of how minor the decision is. To think anything else is to pretend to are a victim of the world without control of what you do, which is completely incorrect. 


There is no deserving of or innocent, only compliancy of risks. 

 
When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.

 
I believe, regardless of how minor or how great of an events, excluding laws of physics, that this logic can be and should be applied evenly across all events, good or bad.


Is this way of thinking incorrect? Please CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28118111391.0" user="Irish4source" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure what you are trying to argue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118114655.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>That the compassion response should not exist in the case of the resent attacks and how people view the affects of their actions, is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118119475.0" user="Irish4source" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When you play a game of chess you have forsee all possible outcomes and act in a way which advances towards your goal of victory. If you fail to see a risk, or overlook it, you experience failure. Who is to blame for your failure? The game? Your opponent? Or yourself for putting yourself into that position when either you knew the risks or failed to forsee them.


In terms of the recent events how exactly should be people avoid these risks? Lock themselves up to avoid society because someone could be a terrorist? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118122590.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>No, but why should we feel compassion for them? They knew the risks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118124025.0" user="Irish4source" delta="False">
    <text>We feel compassion because it's human nature. Using the fact that they knew the risks is flawed because it assumes people can avoid all risks in life. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118126037.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>I just gave you the requirements for compassion. Knowing risks and avoiding them are two different things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118173867.0" user="ken-ken" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused; are you saying that e.g. the concert goers that night should have known that the risks of going to a concert in Paris include being held hostage and killed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118445030.0" user="Misogynist-bydefault" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Do you think you might get sick by going to a place with lots of people and don't go because your wedding is that weekend or you have an important event?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28118477439.0" user="mistressofallevil" delta="False">
    <text>What in earth are you even trying to say here? Your above post is incoherent. What wedding?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
