<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42211546913.0" user="shooketh_not_stireth" delta="False">
    <text>A picky eater's picky eating is their problem. It's up to them to accommodate themselves. Any picky eater who isn't a literal child incapable of cooking for themselves can fend for themselves. I've cooked both professionally and personally for picky eaters and I have zero remaining patience for their lack of adventure and willingness to force others to accommodate them.

Those who do recognize it as their personal problem and who respectfully take steps to not burden others are fine. But the rest have a character flaw which their family allowed or encouraged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42519890399.0" user="rockitsci12" delta="False">
    <text>This. In my experience, there's always a parent/grandparent or family culture that enabled this. My aunt is nearing 60 and refuses to eat anything other than cheese pizza or a burger and fries - that's it. She threw a tantrum and stormed off if anyone ever challenged her on it, so everyone accommodated her.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
