<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42206282265.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>It’s how you handle it - I’m fairly picky, different foods shouldn’t touch unless they are eaten together, I do fish all of one item then move onto the next, nothing jello like texture or I will gag, all meat is cooked to fuck (no pink in beef, pork chops shouldn’t bend when held over my the side, chicken should be dry like day after thanksgiving white meat), and no soggy bread - not even a French dip.

I don’t go to steak houses ever for example, aside from opinions of me ruining steak by eating it well done - I will get I’ll watching to many people eat it. So to politely decline and explain why. Typically I then invite people to someplace else, like hotpot.

Politely decline jello or similar and only accept tiny portions of puddings, and explain my preference.

My family has a tradition of Christmas dipped beef sandwiches that dates back to prohibition and the profits from bootlegging - in the modern form its pink roast beef, in a bun and then the whole thing is dipped in Au jus. Instead I make a big batch of horseradish and bring some cheese for beef sandwiches. I cooked the roast beef more in a pan, toast the bread with a bit on butter in the same pan to steal all the beef flavor, melt the cheese on top, slather the toasted bun with horse radish, assemble the sandwich and consume. It’s weird but no body bitches at the guy bringing fresh homemade horseradish.


The trick is to handle things tactfully, politely and don’t make it feel like an attack on someone else. And don’t be afraid to try new things - maybe you can’t enjoy something as it is, but with a little work it can be great. 

My Mexican friends do a tripe soup for Las Posadas every year that is delicious but the tripe has one of the singular worst textures I’ve ever had in my mouth. Use the broth as a gravy/sauce for rice and it’s amazing though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
