<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42207391257.0" user="shouldco" delta="False">
    <text>Picky eaters are difficult because food is a socal activity. If you aren't participating you are being unsocial. 

Like I try, but to some degree it's like hiking with a child. is it the child's fault their legs are short and they get tired quickly? No. but if you bring a child hiking they are going to set the pace of your hike. And that not exactly what I'm looking for in a hike.

For example if I make my friends a traditional meal from my culture they don't have to like it but I want them to try to participate. And if they don't want to try new things make up an excuse to not come.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
