<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42204788872.0" user="Kalle_79" delta="False">
    <text>You can dress it up with trauma or vague "sensory issues" all you want, but adults with no allergies/intolerances should be able to eat anywhere without making scenes or inconveniencing their hosts.

And more often than not it's just being picky out of habit and poor food education growing up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204819856.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re telling me you can go into someone else’s home and eat a meal with a smile that makes you want to throw up? Non picky eaters have limits too. There just aren’t as many.

Plus picky adults aren’t gonna be perfect. It takes years for a lot of picky eaters to get to a point of having a wider palette. What could be someone unintentionally making a scene could be someone just starting to diversify their palette or dealing with a food they have a lot of trouble with.

It’s not the case for all of them and the entitlement of some picky eaters really does suck. But most of them are just trying their best.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204850353.0" user="Kalle_79" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;eat a meal with a smile that makes you want to throw up? Non picky eaters have limits too. There just aren’t as many.

If there's a food you really can't stomach, it's up to you to give your host a heads up beforehand. Like "oh, just in case, I don't like artichokes".

And I specifically cited allergies and intolerances as an exception.

But if it's adults acting up like a fussy 4yo because "ahhhh there's broccoli! Me hates broccoli!", yeah no... Grow up.

My cousin used to rotate between three or four dishes growing up, just like his father still does. Trying new stuff was out of question and it was just a chore eating with him.
Then he got himself a girlfriend, started to go out more... And now he has developed a taste for fancier food, even a bit sophisticated.

So people can change, if it's not a legit medical condition. They just need less coddling and humoring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209931719.0" user="Relevant_Maybe6747" delta="False">
    <text>Developmental disabilities exist - not all adults are capable of just growing up the way you seem to expect, and sensory issues are real. They come with more shame attached than allergies and intolerances because it is to an extent a ’choice’. I know I *should* be able to go out to eat anywhere without making scenes, but that doesn’t change the fact that I can’t, that I will physically have difficulty not gagging due to sensory issues. I went through years of feeding therapy to get a diet varied enough to be considered healthy - I did my time of trying new stuff. I know I act like a child, that’s why autism is considered a developmental disability. That doesn’t mean I’m morally obligated to change my diet due to my age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237926672.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>My sensory processing disorder makes me pray for death sometimes. It makes me want to cut off all my skin and my tongue and everything that makes me feel anything at all. It's actually hell. It's literally hell on earth.  I don't know how to survive this way, I don't know if I will, but the absolute least of my worries is somebody's lamb chop not being eaten. Sorry not sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205621957.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point is that if you are very picky about your eating, then your best is not enough so you need to devote more mental energy to challenging your anxiety. Shame isn't a great motivator for any fear related issue but just allowing or accommodating makes the problem worse. Preparing ahead of time is actually making your pickiness worse, instead plan to eat the things you don't like. It's reasonable to have a few things you won't eat because it doesn't impact yourself and others too much. It's unreasonable to have many things because it impacts your entire life and how you interact with others. Only you are responsible for that.   
There is no shame in it like there is no shame for someone who is agoraphobic but you can't just enable yourself and accommodate instead of trying to improve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631141449.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>You can’t plan to eat things that you don’t like unless you plan to eat those things in a restroom so that you can vomit after each bite. Picky eating is NOT just not liking something. Many of us can’t tolerate it without being sick or vomiting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631377269.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>No that's not true. That's likely a false belief. If you are vomiting from eating something you don't like then that is something you can spend time to challenge. If you vomit, you vomit but it's likely psychological in nature and the only way you can overcome it is by doing it many times. The choice is whether to live your whole life unconvincing yourself and other by eating specific things or to do the really difficult work to overcome the disgust and fear of eating it. Both are very hard.

An intolerance to a food is very different than being picky and doesn't under normal circumstances expand to cover many different foods. Vomiting does not occur unless the body thinks it is poisoned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631798223.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>Not true… with sensory processing disorder, textures of food can make people vomit. It causes problems with the idea that everyone should “try” a bite because it stands to reason that if someone cannot tolerate the texture of zucchini without vomiting, that person would likely not be able to eat squash either - but people will berate the person for not trying squash when the person is making the reasonable assumption that squash will also induce vomiting.

Also, as kids, most of us were forced to spend life trying these foods over and over just to please some uneducated adult and it just resulted in hating dinner altogether and constant crying at the dinner table.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42640958069.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Even with sensory processing disorder you can learn to tolerate these foods. I do agree that forcing it on children is a terrible idea though. It has to be something you choose yourself</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42641013359.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>Trust me, it is almost next to impossible to overcome it with sensory processing disorder. The only exception would be someone getting intense therapy at the age of two. However, most people do not even know that they have SPD at the age of two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237884946.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>.....Do you have it? Sensory processing disorder is absolutely hell on earth man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238398399.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly I'm not sure since it's not a formal diagnosis so you can't actually get diagnosed yet but I believe so based on the descriptions and criteria that define it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238485484.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>It's a waking nightmare for a lotta people. My senses are constantly screaming at me, not being able to eat what's in front of me sometimes is kinda on the lower end of my concerns. 

Being able to eat in general without starving myself out is probably the more important part. Or not giving myself some nutrition-based illness. I will just completely not eat if there's no safe food. I've gone days without food before because of how bad it is. My parents tried to starve me out and I ended up vomiting straight acid for days until they realized I couldn't help it. Trying to eat things my brain think is "unsafe" is the same signal my brain gives when I try to eat sand or hair. My throat locks around whatever it is and forces it out. It's like your brain thinks it's going to kill you. 

Idk about you but working against your own brain feels impossible after so much pain and acid reflux it's caused.

This isn't very fun. There's no reason for us to do this on purpose. I really wish this was a joke, I really wish it was like how neurotypical folk think it is but it's not. It's hell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631128986.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>Most of us do NOT make a scene. It is other people who start to count the items on our plates and become angry and make a scene. We have been eating less for most of our lives and are okay with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237872006.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>"Sensory issues" in parenthesis like autism just doesn't exist. Like we're faking having them or something. 

I gotta know, what EXACTLY would we be getting out of faking this? I'm missing out on so much, I want to try all these amazing foods my friends and family make but when I stuff them down my throat my body denies it like I'm eating somebody's hair. 

Sorry not sorry, other people exist. Other biology exist. You are not the baseline.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
