<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42204924735.0" user="OrangeinDorne" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree they should not be shamed, I think it’s ok to gently expose them to new/healthy foods in respectful ways. my partner whom I love dearly was (well still is but better) a very picky eater. After talking to her about it, sounds like a lot of it stemmed from her ex berating her for not being more open to trying new food. Plus she does indeed order her steak well done and her coworkers, servers etc are always hounding her about it. Kinda just made her dig in to her favorites and she misses out on a lot of important nutrients. 

I usually just ask if she wants to try something now and again and while she still usually declines there are some new items she’s added to the rotation and I’m proud of her for it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205025211.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>You’re an amazing partner and the type of support system I wish I always had. 

I have friends like this and they’re great. My family are finally figuring out what works, but it’s too late for them in my head. My parents and siblings were really annoying about it growing up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631018387.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>There could be a religious reason that she orders the steak well done.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
