<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42209488457.0" user="Icy_Highway1830" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with some people on this thread. I never judge my friends for being picky eaters and I try my best to always include them in things like outings to restaurants or other gatherings. However, it does get frustrating. I remember I we wanted to get dinner after an event we went to, I told her what food they will have AND asked her to look at the menu multiple times. I told her if she sees nothing she wanted, we can leave and head to another place close by. We sit down and the server comes over to take our order and she didn't order anything at all. She told me "there was nothing she liked on the menu" and just sat there watching me eat (i wasn't uncomfortable with this at all) it's just the point of, I gave her out multiple times to find something we both like and she doesn't express what she wants.  This isn't the only time she's done this either.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
