<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42204775940.0" user="Trucker2827" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not picky eaters’ fault for being picky, but it is their fault for not handling it better. A lot of picky eaters don’t put the effort in needed to let their non-picky friends know about their preferences. They only express frustration or disgust at the time of eating, when it’s very demotivating for someone who put effort into preparing a dish for them to eat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204799962.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. That’s a very valid point. Communication is extremely important on both ends.

I know for me personally I warn the people close to me in advance (I’m also a picky eater) if I ever feel like I’m gonna be eating with them outside of a restaurant I know has food I can eat or outside my own home. Especially if food shows up as a topic of conversation.

But like a lot of things that should be mentioned in advance, we sometimes forget to mention it (this can apply to things beyond this topic too). Also, a lot of us are embarrassed about it because we know what some of the backlash is like. This paragraph is no excuse by any means. Just something to consider.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204818609.0" user="h8speech" delta="False">
    <text>Ultimately, it's everyone's responsibility not to make their problems *other people's* problems. Whether you've got bipolar disorder or you're a fussy eater, be socialised; be normal. 

That means that fussy eaters don't deserve "more respect", because it's up to you to fit in with everyone else; it's not up to us to fit in with you. Just like, when I'm having a manic episode, it's up to me not to behave like a fuckwit rather than it being up to you to pretend I didn't sleep with all my coworkers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204889145.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>
I was completely with you until “fussy eaters don't deserve "more respect", because it's up to you to fit in with everyone else; it's not up to us to fit in with you”.

That just reeked a little of entitlement from the non picky eaters. Unless we’re being rude about it or trying to change the non picky eater’s plans/meals, why should we be the ones to change? A lot of the solutions I gave in my post are things picky eaters do to avoid being a burden to others around them.

Picky eating is definitely a problem, especially if the person isn’t working towards it. I’m not saying people should be rewarded for being picky. But it’s incredibly easy to make food related things easier for picky individuals without too much effort or catering to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205135573.0" user="h8speech" delta="False">
    <text>I used the comparison of bipolar disorder, and in my view the analogy holds up. I could equally well say "This reeks of entitlement from the non bipolar disorder sufferers", and it's objectively a fact that bipolar is more serious than being a picky eater. But this mindset isn't productive. Expecting others to make room for my illness doesn't help me, and it doesn't help them. It just enables me to be worse. 

&amp;gt;why should we be the ones to change? 

Because what you're doing is unhealthy and unreasonable? This seems like a strange thing to ask.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204982223.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Ultimately, it's everyone's responsibility not to make their problems other people's problems.

That's subjective. From the point of view of the picky either if you inform your friend about their diet that might seem like the responsible thing to do. But from the point of view of the friend it sounds too presumptious and privileged. Either way the picky eater makes their problem, everyone elses problem.

&amp;gt;That means that fussy eaters don't deserve "more respect", because it's up to you to fit in with everyone else

Exactly. The only way to do that without bothering others is to "shut up and bear with it". Which is the only socially acceptable way to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204841628.0" user="MaliciousTibia" delta="False">
    <text>No really. I have a friend who I never exclude from plans, but the rest of us are foodies. They will only order chicken tenders and fries from wherever we go (which is fine, im never embarrassed by the type of food someone orders) and will be completely rude if there isnt something they like on the menu. As if I hadn't messaged them the name of the restaurant and menu AND confirmed "this place has a different type of cuisine than what youre used to" its so disheartening, especially when food is one of my love languages. I have to sit across from them and watch them pout all while they turn down any efforts to ease their frustrations. I love them dearly, but it feels like we brought the kid along on a night out sometimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205039193.0" user="LLKKSSII" delta="False">
    <text>What even is a "foodie"? Someone who likes trying new food? Isn't that just a universal human characteristic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205059813.0" user="very_scary" delta="False">
    <text>it's not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205135572.0" user="LLKKSSII" delta="False">
    <text>I don't get why its a big deal. Food is all kind of the same. I tried pho the other day because everyone said this one pho restaurant would blow my mind. To me it was just soup lol

It's weird to me that people fixate on trying new food, whether they are for it or against it. To me food from different cultures is  pretty good but not that different than what I already eat</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205574167.0" user="rewt127" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely disagree with your premise here. Now pho, yeah it's just soup. Not exactly the best one to argue against. But there is a giant difference between at least, my regular diet, And steak tartar. 

Then you have things like caviar which are such unique flavors. and as someone in the internal PNW, our food availability is generic American. And steak. So frankly even Shawarma is kinda exotic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209066110.0" user="guesswork-tan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; as someone in the internal PNW,

This is off-topic, but I've never seen "internal" used this way before, can you explain what it means? (I live in the Pacific North-West too.) Maybe internal means the same as "rural"? Or perhaps an area that's kind of in the "central" region between Oregon, Washington, and Idaho (like a square with the four corners at Yakima, Spokane, Boise, and Bend)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209289995.0" user="rewt127" delta="False">
    <text>I'm using internal to mean the more arid, non coastal area. Montana in this case. So while not exactly rural. No major metropolitan areas.

Once you get on the other side of the mountains of Central Washington. The landscape, population density, and culture does a 180.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209320835.0" user="guesswork-tan" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I see; that makes sense. I lived in Polson for a few years and the natural scenery was gorgeous. Definitely not as much restaurant variety as Portland or Seattle though. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205699579.0" user="Mad__Hermit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Food is all kind of the same

Eat a perfectly cooked filet then head cheese and tell me they are the same. Or plain pinto beans and then your favorite pizza. Or thousands of other examples.

Food is the same in the sense you eat it, but that is about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42206776023.0" user="Gygsqt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't get why its a big deal. 

This kind of framing always makes the speaker come off like such a tool. It's fine if you don't like food as a hobby, but your inability to understand why others do says way way way more about you than it does about them. I don't know why people love to brag about being unable to practice basic "empathy". How hard is it to grasp why some people like trying new food? Food is tasty. New things are an experience. Food and community are often linked. It's not that complicated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205075788.0" user="MaliciousTibia" delta="False">
    <text>well, as for the friend i mentioned, they know what they like and stick to it and make no attempt to branch out. Personally i use the term lightly. Most of my friends gatherings are centered around food and we turn it into sort of a game when we eat together. We'll do our own versions of chopped in someones kitchen, we pretend to be critics and try to find new words to describe taste. I cook 5 days a week and always make extra to share my new recipes with my friends and coworkers. Food is just a big part of my life and family's culture :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205168108.0" user="Macr0Penis" delta="False">
    <text>I used to be like that, but with drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205435365.0" user="Obsidiannight2010" delta="False">
    <text>I cackled!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205509469.0" user="MaliciousTibia" delta="False">
    <text>The drugs make an appearance occasionally</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205849016.0" user="robotmonkeyshark" delta="False">
    <text>It’s someone who is especially passionate about food, not only trying new foods but learning about why and how the foods are prepared that way.  

It’s like saying hiking is essentially just walking across terrain which is a universal human characteristic, but someone who calls himself a hiker is much more invested in that activity than for basic transporting of their body from place to place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42207067767.0" user="shouldco" delta="False">
    <text>I mean clearly it's not, this thread is about those people.

But a foodie in the most general sense would be someone that actually expresses interest in food as like a hobby. Similar to how basically everyone likes movies, but some people are nerds about them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42630988785.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>I know that this is old, but this is also not completely accurate. A lot of us do not disclose our preferences, but it is because we end up in a more awkward situation when we do. For instance, we can tell someone that we prefer plain baked chicken without any sauces. Yet, people in general lack attention to detail, so they will return with BBQ chicken covered in sauce and say “here is the chicken prepared JUST for you”. Now, we have to gag through it or else we are considered rude for not eating something prepared “just for us”.  Therefore, we rather show up and have choices instead of having the wrong thing prepared. If I just eat a biscuit, that was MY choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237829563.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>i hate eating the white fatty parts of steak so much that my body doesn't even allow me to chew it. it physically denies it, I'm not being ironic about this either. It's like when your body rejects things like rocks and hair and will force you to *not* swallow it. It's literally like that. 

Many unsafe foods are just like this with me no matter how many times I force food down my gullet. 


I want to like more food, I cry about it sometimes because I feel so fucking awful and embarrassed about how much food I'm not able to even swallow. I'm autistic so I have sensory sensitivities to many many things that I can't choose. It's hell, it literally makes my life hell. Feeling somebody brush their hand down my back feels like razer blades sometimes. It's that bad. I don't know what to do about this. Taste buds and your throat also have sensory stuff going on so they're included too.

I'm sorry for not being able to eat what people make all the time. I wish I could eat it. I'm missing out on so much and it depresses the shit out of me. I don't want to be this way. I really really dont.


Before anyone says "Well obviously not autistic people!" How do you know the person with picky eating isn't autistic? How do you know anyone's autistic? You don't, but many of you force them to tell you when you fuss at them for being picky. We don't always want to, but if it stops people from looking at us like monsters then that's all we can really say to explain why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238245343.0" user="Trucker2827" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a lot of stuff you said but really it boils down to this:

&gt; Before you cook, how about you make sure nobody has any food sensitivities? Makes life much smoother.

No, you need to advocate for yourself. Whether or not you take the initiative to share your preferences, you need to eventually state what you’re okay or not okay with. No one is going to do that for you, and it’s somewhere between lazy and selfish to expect others to somehow cater to preferences you’ve never expressed, all because it’s just smoother for you. Someone cooking for others is already going out of their way to be kind and friendly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238406439.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>Personally, I have a personal boundary around the neurotypicals in my life. That boundary is "I won't associate with those who aren't willing to do half of the "translating" (what I mean by translating is using direct communication with me, not adding subtext to my words, expecting me to emote the way they do, or thinking their inherent social model is the only " right" one and I should be the ONLY one adapting just because I was born differently). I am not willing to expend that amount of emotional and mental labour of masking on someone who isn't willing to do half of that labour in return. It seems grossly unfair to me.

For example: You don't expect somebody who is mute to speak right? Then don't continuously gesture at them like you're expecting a verbal answer, or refuse to provide note paper + pen when you want them around you. An easy way to make any disabled person hate you is by refusing to accommodate, if you're curious.

 When it comes to food sensitivities, this is included in that. However in all my friend groups it's pretty well known that I DO have these sensitivities, it shouldn't be a problem unless *they* forget. Again, not a problem if they ask what we'd want to eat beforehand. A thing most people do anyway. 

If they don't ask and suddenly there's food in front of me from a source that *I know* doesn't want to accommodate for me, I'm going to accept it politely and immediately give it to somebody else. Just like when somebody gets you something you hate for Christmas. It's somebody else's now, because I also hate wasting food. If my partner is there then me and her can trade stuff around on each others plates (she doesn't have these sensitivities but she's very accommodating and likes a lot of different foods) so I'm not left hungry. 

Easy fix, just don't get embarrassed by this. If you are then uhm, lol? I'm here pressing holes in my bread sticks at the Italian restaurant so the juices from my pasta fagioli go in them like a spoon made of bread. My girlfriend thinks it's cute, my friends think it's funny, nobody in my circle gives me shit for this so I'll be just fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238757390.0" user="Trucker2827" delta="False">
    <text>
&gt; I am not willing to expend that amount of emotional and mental labour of masking on someone who isn't willing to do half of that labour in return. 

No one is obligated to do any amount of labor for you at all. Someone cooking for you is already doing labor to make you feel welcome and cared for. You taking issue with them not serving your accommodations before you advocate for yourself is just entitlement. Neurodivergence has nothing to do with it. You are always responsible for expressing your preferences in a timely fashion that others can consider. 

&gt; An easy way to make any disabled person hate you is by refusing to accommodate, if you're curious.

I’m sorry, did we all vote you as our representative at some point? I wasn’t at the last meeting.

&gt; However in all my friend groups it's pretty well known that I DO have these sensitivities, it shouldn't be a problem unless they forget. 

Great, so you advocated for yourself and your issues, and people around you remember until they forget and need a reminder, which you give since you’re advocating for yourself. The system works. What did I say that you’re complaining about?

&gt; Easy fix, just don't get embarrassed by this. 

Didn’t you just you say cry all the time out of the embarrassment of being a picky eater? lmao what even is your point anymore

&gt; I'm here pressing holes in my bread sticks at the Italian restaurant so the juices from my pasta fagioli go in them like a spoon made of bread. 

Wow you’re so quirky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238766887.0" user="Orizammar" delta="False">
    <text>"Wow you're so quirky"

yikes. ok bye.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
