<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42204803824.0" user="jt4" delta="False">
    <text>I used to be a picky eater. Then I started to try the things I wasn't eating. If you're at a potluck, maybe try something new that you haven't had before. Maybe you'll like it, maybe you won't, and if you don't, that's okay. Nobody's forcing you to eat it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204857966.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Potlucks and buffets are amazing places to try something new. You can grab whatever you’re comfortable with and people don’t often make a fuss about the “new food” on your plate.

People watching me try something new is a huge turn off for me. Like expanding what foods I eat isn’t a performance lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631119117.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly… everyone in the circle becomes obsessed with the picky eater. It is annoying and makes no sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
