<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42244379909.0" user="CapableDistance5570" delta="False">
    <text>You're using the word "picky eaters" to describe many different groups of people. You're using excuses that apply only to a small portion of them to represent the whole group.

If you say "Picky eaters who have sensory issues and trauma deserve more respect" then it would be a different story but you didn't. Now let me do the same thing you did in my counter-argument. There are also picky eaters who do not have a gluten allergy in any way and then request gluten free, causing more work for everyone in some cases, especially if they go "oh does this have gluten? I need to send it back" and so on. There are two sides on this spectrum and the ones that are shamed are the ones that usually deserve it.

This is coming from someone who was a picky eater, the annoying kind, and getting shamed helped me not be such a prick, for example when my parents made food I didn't like I ended up just eating it and being grateful in my highschool years. And it helped me get over all the issues I had with it and improve as a person.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
