<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42212236830.0" user="cluskillz" delta="False">
    <text>What is a picky eater?

I was once called a picky eater from a coworker who I consider a picky eater.

Because I like good food and when he wants to go to a place that charges 20% more than other restaurants for dried out chicken sandwiches, I decline to join for lunch, especially since he likes to go once or more a week. And it's weird...half the time he goes, he says, yeah, it's not very good today (so why do we keep coming back?!?!?!). This is someone who can eat nothing but chicken kabobs with rice until the end of time and be perfectly happy.

But any time I bring up Chinese food, Japanese food, Burmese food, Indian food, etc, he whines and moans to no end. He actually said that Chinese food, one of the most diverse cuisines in the world "is all the same" so he doesn't like it. Said by someone who basically orders the same thing over and over at each restaurant we go to. I tolerate his poor restaurant choices up to an extent (though there are certain restaurants we both like). I've basically given up trying to get him to go anywhere that's interesting. My other coworkers basically and I have to wait until he's not around to go somewhere we want to try. He's a good guy otherwise (if he wasn't, I wouldn't bother going to lunch with him).

If he wants to eat a narrow range of food so that someone like myself, 20 years younger, has has at least 5x the food experience he does...that's fine. Doesn't affect me except that I think you're really limiting your life experiences. But at least show some kind of reciprocation. Over ten years, I've tolerated his poor restaurant decisions once a week to once every other week. Over that same time, he's maybe tolerated the restaurants I want to go to maybe five times total. But when he called me picky because I don't like getting ripped off for bad food when he will eliminate entire swaths of cuisines, sticking to pretty much exclusively Persian kabobs (doesn't like Afghan kabobs), pizza, sandwiches, and inauthentic Mexican, that's really fucking annoying. Especially when I take pride in being open to trying any cuisine dish at least twice (I have a few exceptions to this, like bugs for example, but there aren't many).

IDK, maybe what I'm saying here is mostly due to a character flaw that's not in most picky eaters. But I can see the non-reciprocation happening very often. I did have an extreme picky eater roommate way back in college and I basically could only go with him to either the dining hall (where if he doesn't see anything he likes which is 90% of the time, he gets a few slices of American cheese, a bowl of pickles, and ketchup for his meal) or restaurants he was okay with (and this was even before I became adventurous with food). Even sharing a pizza could be difficult; he only eats pepperoni pizza and will only eat it by eating the pepperoni first, then the cheese, then the crust flap. Any given night, give me three guesses and I have a high probability of guessing what he was eating for dinner.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
