<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42205073970.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes that shaming picky eaters doesn't encourage them to change their habits.

Also, what about parents of picky eaters? Is it okay to shame them for not teaching their kids to eat healthy and diverse foods like doctors recommend?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205108051.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Sure! Let’s also shame every other person that has a problem they aren’t 100% in control of.

For parents of picky kids, it honestly depends on why the kid is picky and if they’re doing anything to support their kid. If the kid is autistic or has sensory issues and can’t communicate why, then they deserve more leeway than a spineless parent who only feeds their kid’s nuggets to keep them happy/quiet</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205129356.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sure! Let’s also shame every other person that has a problem they aren’t 100% in control of.

I'm not saying it's the right move or the right thing that you necessarily, but does it work? After all, pickiness isn't something people do as part of depression or anxiety, nor is it due to lack of income. So some of the major factors contributing to other eating problems do not apply here.

&amp;gt; For parents of picky kids, it honestly depends on why the kid is picky and if they’re doing anything to support their kid

Fair enough. I used to have a friend who only ate pasta throughout her entire childhood because she asked her parents for that every day and they made that for her. She refused to eat anything else. In my view, that is bad parenting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205220704.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, picky eating can go hand in hand with anxiety and/or depression. My own anxiety contributes to my picky eating and vice versa. 

Also, sure it could work. But it works the same way you’d solve any other eating issues or mental health problem. Shaming the person just makes you less approachable for if/when the picky eater wants to improve. This could even cause the person to put on a brave face and suffer in silence. Eating out is suddenly very anxiety inducing and having people over makes you feel judged. 

Maybe it does cause people to change with no further issues. But it could also cause the person to go the other direction while also shutting themselves out of society when it comes to anything food</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205235781.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>Good points.

&amp;gt; My own anxiety contributes to my picky eating and vice versa. 

I'm curious about this. How and why does your anxiety contribute to you being a picky eater?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42207300548.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>There are multiple factors. This is just me, but others might experience something different.

One of them is the fear of not liking a food I tried, then having to waste the food if no one else can eat it. This could partly be due to me being raised on wasting as little as possible. But I just like knowing that all food can get eaten in one way or another instead of it expiring or getting thrown out. Eating new foods with people I’m close with can help because they’re okay with taking my food and eating it instead. Hell, even sharing some scraps with pets if they’re able to eat it is cool with me too. But in a restaurant with people I barely know or by myself? That food will likely not get eaten if I don’t like it and I feel guilty.

Another thing for me is the social pressure of trying new foods. If I say I’ve never tried ketchup for example. 9 times out of 10, one or more people will try to pressure me to try ketchup when I’m not the mental headspace to try it. If I don’t, I’m the picky person who won’t change. But if I do follow the peer pressure, it’s not on my terms and it can affect the food even more for me, even if I like it. It’s just remembered as the food I was pressured into eating. Those situations also discourage me from talking about what I haven’t tried and instead I just default to saying I don’t like something. 

The solution to these issues is trying food alone or under zero pressure (and in the right headspace). But the two main issues conflict with each other.

Another thing that’s more minor is that it takes me trying something multiple times to be able to add it to my regular palette (with a few exceptions). So even if I tried something and liked it, I can’t just have it served to me as a meal right away. I need to get used to it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42208364648.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>A few things:

1) When you say you don't like to try new foods, does that mean you eat a fairly unhealthy diet, or does it just mean that you're not experimental? If you're eating very unhealthily, medically you're actually wasting a lot. Because you'll need to eat more to be nutritionally sated. And fiscally you'll be wasting if it ends up affecting your health.

2) If it takes time for you to like a food, why not just force yourself to eat things if you want to like them? 

3) It sounds muuuuch more like you have OCD than anxiety.

4) Never feed human food to pets unless you look up beforehand that is okay. They cannot metabolize the same things that we can. For instance chocolate is poisonous to dogs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42208909749.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t worry my mum is experienced with animals. She knows what they can or can’t have. So very little health issues there.

And it doesn’t take me time to like the food per say. I’ll like or tolerate it the first time I taste it. It just takes a few tastes to get used to it

As for my diet, it’s a bit of both. I like a lot of fruits, vegetables and other healthier things and can eat at least a few things from every food group. But I will admit that a lot of my safer foods aren’t the most healthy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209000049.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>Just curious what other things do you have anxiety about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209290272.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>Anything related to social skills is a nightmare. Definitely the big one in terms of anxiety. I’m also weird about watching movies around people and wearing short sleeves or dresses/skirts</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209361148.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>Have you considered seeing a therapist about these issues? They might really be able to help you. Imagine social situations being easy for you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209673733.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>It’s currently not an option for me. But it’s something I’ve considered a few times</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42209765922.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>If it's an insurance problem, there are often ways around that</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
