<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2305400184.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/124kq60/cmv_picky_eaters_deserve_more_respect_and/">
    <title>CMV: Picky eaters deserve more respect and shouldn’t be shamed for being picky</title>
    <original_poster>UsualMorning98</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s not always the picky eater’s fault they’re picky. It could be due to how they were raised (not their fault), trauma or sensory issues with food (something that can be really hard to work through) and many other factors.

A lot of them either try their best to make things easier for “regular” eaters (bringing their own food to events, looking at the menu beforehand, ordering from the kid’s menu, simply not eating that meal/day etc) or feel extreme guilt when they can’t accommodate to those who will shame them.

I’m not saying they should be prioritised over people with allergies or those with other food needs (like vegetarians or those who don’t eat certain foods for religious reasons). But they deserve a little more respect and support because it’s also hard for them being picky eaters. Definitely prioritise food issues that could harm someone. But once that’s sorted, don’t get mad at the picky eaters for just trying to exist.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42204794151.0" user="HassleHouff" delta="False">
    <text>It’s objectively better to have a well rounded diet, than to only eat one or two things.

If ever it’s ok to “shame” someone, it would be to get them to make objectively better decisions.

Even if it’s never ok to “shame” for any reason, it’s certainly not an attribute deserving of respect. People should get baseline respect as a standard, but in no way should refusing to eat certain foods *add* respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42204846541.0" user="UsualMorning98" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree with all of this. Respect is earned, minus the base amount every human gets. And having a larger palette is beneficial for many reasons.

That being said though. The bar for that base respect is often on the floor for picky eaters. I’m not saying people should completely change restaurants or cook an entirely different meal for them every time. But part of that base respect should at least cover not letting someone go hungry, especially if they’re working towards being less picky. Something as simple as having bread on the table or a bowl of salad people can scoop some food from goes a long way. 

With me personally I know being picky can be inconvenient and I try my best to not come off as entitled about it. I’d rather skip a meal than “make a fuss”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42205025501.0" user="HassleHouff" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I’m not saying people should completely change restaurants or cook an entirely different meal for them every time. But part of that base respect **should at least cover not letting someone go hungry**, especially if they’re working towards being less picky. Something as simple as having bread on the table or a bowl of salad people can scoop some food from goes a long way.

I think that’s going beyond the territory of “basic human respect”. 

In particular, look at what I bolded above. If there is food available to be consumed, someone saying “I don’t care for that food” is in no way equivalent to “letting them go hungry”. People who are actually struggling to eat won’t turn down food.

Similarly, the idea of “just put some bread or a salad out” has serious flaws. First, why should we assume that picky eaters will prefer salad and bread over the steak and potatoes? Secondly, that’s no longer “basic respect”- it’s going out of your way to pamper. Which is fine and even honorable to do for a guest, but it shouldn’t be expected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42631112181.0" user="Electrical_Ice754" delta="False">
    <text>While this is true, a lot of picky eating involves textures of food and two of the main texture issues are slimy foods and crunchy foods. Having a bare salad of just lettuce avoids the slimy texture and having bread avoids the crunchy issue. Most people who are picky, barring any medical or digestive issue, would be able to use the bare lettuce or the bread to socialize or, at least, pretend to eat.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
