<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42343970648.0" user="Spanglertastic" delta="False">
    <text>So your argument is that people spend way too much time in nature and we should do everything we can to keep people confined to the cities?

Or is it that things like food are too cheap and we need to make transportation of that food longer and more difficult?

You'll have to clarify if you're trying to screw over nature lovers or farmers before I can properly understand your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344003311.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>I think you either didn't read my argument or didn't understand it.

&gt;  So your argument is that people spend way too much time in nature and we should do everything we can to keep people confined to the cities?

Could you clarify what this has to do with my argument? Why would people be spending less time in nature? If anything they would be spending _more_ time, because there should be less traffic and because some of those roads and lanes could be replaced with parks.

&gt; Or is it that things like food are too cheap and we need to make transportation of that food longer and more difficult?

I'm talking about civilian vehicles. Aka not grocery delivery trucks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344736308.0" user="Spanglertastic" delta="False">
    <text>The majority of people live in cities. 

Smaller roads means less capacity. 

Less capacity means it will take longer for a city person to reach nature and return. 

This means people will either spend less time in nature when they choose to go, or will choose not to go at all.  

&gt;I'm talking about civilian vehicles. Aka not grocery delivery trucks.

So now we need two separate sets of roads? One for civilian vehicles and one for trucks?  Because right now when I drive in the mountains, I drive past farms and ranches.  Those trucks use the same roads as civilian vehicles. 

When you say all roads that are not highways you are including millions of miles of rural roads and state roads. Not every 2 or 4 lane road exists to serve your exact driving needs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
