<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42344083387.0" user="obert-wan-kenobert" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, there is a general trend that *over a period of time*, more lanes leads to more traffic (in part because more lanes usually means an expanding population, which means more traffic). But it's not a direct, immediate correlation. 

If you magically shrank all the roads in Los Angeles to one lane tomorrow, the traffic wouldn't magically evaporate -- it would just become much, much worse, probably to the point where the city would totally shut down. This is because, in large part, the damage has already been done. The population and traffic has already grown alongside the lanes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344235571.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>So close to getting a delta. I just gave one for pointing out that such a transition would have to be gradual, not immediate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
