<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42343952635.0" user="GivesStellarAdvice" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic.

How is 80 cars on one lane an improvement over 100 cars on two lanes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42343986011.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>To reiterate my first sentence, more roads create more traffic. Perhaps not immediately, but over time, reducing the amount of roads and lanes should be more like 40 cars on one as opposed to 100 cars on two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42343994000.0" user="GivesStellarAdvice" delta="False">
    <text>^[Citation ^Needed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344092694.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344149537.0" user="Tamerlane-1" delta="False">
    <text>Can you point to the where in the article the author provides evidence that more roads cause more traffic (i.e. slower travel times).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344161412.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>At least the induced demand article is based on the idea that more consumption will happen because of a decrease in cost. In this case, that means that the additional traffic is because more people are traveling. In order to say that is necessarily bad, are you assuming that there is no value in the additional transportation happening?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344162508.0" user="GivesStellarAdvice" delta="False">
    <text>Those imply that reduced lanes reduces traffic because there isn't any room for the cars.  It says nothing about reducing the amount of traffic per lane.  A reduction from 100 cars on 2 lanes, to 80 cars on 1 lane is exactly the type of traffic reduction they are referring to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344153269.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you just want population control. Just less people on the road because it would cause less climate change? Do I have that right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344327077.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>You mean why do I want fewer cars on the road? There are quite a few reasons. Climate change is the big one. Fewer roads also means that the roads are saved for people who really need them. Fewer cars means fewer drunk driving accidents. Less pollution and therefore less asthma and fewer heart health issues. Less noise pollution for people and animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42345087970.0" user="jstnpotthoff" delta="False">
    <text>Who are you to decide who needs roads?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42345667696.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Fewer roads also means that the roads are saved for people who really need them.

What's the difference between needing a road and really needing a road?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
