<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42346144575.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe anyone when they claim "All" research supports their position.

But okay. I would argue that building an entire road just to have it go one way is pretty silly. Your argument may have some sway if it wasn't for that. What if emergency vehicles needed to go the opposite way? What if a fire broke out 5km from a firetruck, but it was behind the truck on a one way road resulting in a trip of 10km just to get there? Meanwhile people burn alive. But hey! There will be less traffic for the funeral procession... Cool.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42351027529.0" user="rewt127" delta="False">
    <text>He is right, kinda.

He is talking about the tip of the iceberg. There is millions of dollars and decades of public transit and city redesign behind this.

Once you have that iceberg, all the data does agree with him. But he left out that really important bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42352044805.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That had nothing to do with my criticism... Literally nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
