<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42343930314.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This already exists in the form of trains.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42343973778.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what you're arguing. I know trains exist. I am saying roads need to be reduced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344105676.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But what is a one lane road between cities but a track? 

Think about the experience of driving single file in one line. It would be the same as a train, except more potential for accidents (rear endings). But you can't turn, pull over, u turn or really go anywhere but forward. 

It's a train.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344249065.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically said _not_ highways between cities. Besides, the emergency lane is not one that you are supposed to drive in anyway, so that would not be included in my argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344420355.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But there wouldn't be a turn lane. All the cars would have to be going to the same place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344434865.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>If you are going straight in a straightline, and the first intersection goes right and then the next one goes left, then you can go to different places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344470061.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If everything is predetermined, why are trians not a superior idea? I don't understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344476877.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>Trains _are_ a superior idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344502487.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Then let's make roads made of rail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42344529362.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>I'm totally for that, but people love cars, and railways take longer to build than roads due to deconstruct for repurpose. So that would be a much longer term plan.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
