<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42347158281.0" user="Coooo8" delta="False">
    <text>One way roads...okay, so essentially single lane highways is what we're talking about?

When I first moved to my city, I had to take the highway about 20 minutes one way to get to work. At least 2 or 3 times, I missed my exit due to distraction, and ended up being 10-15 minutes late each time, because you can't very well turn around when traffic goes in one direction.

I think your idea is well-meaning but I highly doubt that people would like it. And I don't think that people having to stay home because you've made the roads massively inconvenient is much of a win.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
