<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2335432693.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/12mgfed/cmv_all_us_roads_that_are_not_highways_between/">
    <title>CMV: all (US) roads that are not highways between cities or states should only have a single, one-way, lane of civilian traffic or less.</title>
    <original_poster>Square-Dragonfruit76</original_poster>
    <original_post>The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually _increased._ It would be a rough transition at first, but in theory, traffic would be diminished if you cut down the number of roads and the number of lanes. This would be great for the environment but it also would be great for everyone driving because there would be less traffic. The lanes that are no longer in use could be used to improve our society in a number of ways. They could be made into trees or park area. They could be restricted to only delivery vehicles and/or public transit or emergency vehicles. Or they could be made into bike paths. And if all goes well, perhaps people would even be open to eliminating some roads for civilian traffic all together.

Edit: Again, to reiterate, according to all the current research, more roads actually _create_ more traffic. So if anything, this would reduce traffic, maybe not immediately, but over time. A lot of people seem to not have read that part, so I'm not going to respond to repeats of people who clearly did not read my argument.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0967070X96000303

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Induced_demand</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42352166970.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The main reasoning for my argument is because there at this point has been consistent, replicated, research finding that the more roads you add, the more traffic is actually increased.

This is not actually the correct conclusion being drawn.

You are explicitly **missing** a key element here.

Roads are expanded/added **because there is an identified need to spend millions of dollars to do so**. There are bottlenecks in the transportation infrastructure and adding capacity shifts usage and allows for greater usage (which is demanded). Existing infrastructure just is not meeting the current demand. 

These projects would be considered *failures* if the traffic volume did not increase on them. 

If you want to understand why, consider North Korea or Burma.

https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/mar/19/burmas-capital-naypyidaw-post-apocalypse-suburbia-highways-wifi

https://www.boredpanda.com/highway-in-north-korea-eric-lafforgue/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=organic

If your simplistic conclusion was correct - why are these massive roads full of traffic?

This should make you reconsider your conclusion you have drawn. I mean if adding big roads always means more traffic, then these should be full. If you say 'but wait - there are other factors', I say 'Yep'. And you have completely failed to consider them in your analysis. 

If you fail to meet the demands for traffic, you are going to create *other* impacts. These include traffic jams, issues with receiving goods, and issues with mobility for residents/people in the area.  

Can poorly planned road changes create congestion? Of course. But poorly planned road *closures* can and have been proven to do *much worse*. The conclusion of these studies is that road changes need to be carefully evaluated with the entire road network in view rather can looked at in a vacuum without considering external factors.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
