<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="234217718.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3vg3jq/cmv_when_logic_and_emotion_clash_logic_should/">
    <title>CMV: When logic and emotion clash, logic should always win.</title>
    <original_poster>renaissanceman975</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whenever a decision is made, a conclusion drawn, an idea perused or any other circumstance that might result in logic clashing with emotions I believe people should accept the logical side over the emotional side 100% of the time.

Now when I say a logical point in contrast to emotion I mean a point of view or course of action or what have you that, based on all the information you have available and can have logic applied to it, is different than what your feelings/gut/instinct/intuition/conventional wisdom/etc leads you to.

I know that you can't get off the ground without emotion, and that logic depends on values and life is meaningless if logic is all we use and so on. I don't think we should disregard emotion entirely, plently of situations don't need to employ logic (do I like ice cream or cake better?) and others may coincide with logic (when deciding whether to get married, maybe all the logical aspects agree with your emotions). However, in situations where we have an objective, take all the information we have available to us and apply logic, yet the way we feel about it leads us to a different conclusion, we should go with the logical side.

Sometimes, if there is a logical and emotional course of action and you didn't know how it would turn out the logical course turns out to have been worse in retrospect. But if you follow the logical course 100% of the time you'll maximize the amount of 'optimal choices'.

Let's I want to go to college and pursue a career, and my goals are to maximize my happiness and balance that with financial stability/income. I can choose career X and career Y to pursue. Obviously if I'm purely logical from start to finish I won't get off the ground, so I follow whatever emotional drives I have until logic can be applied for some result. Career X appeals to my emotions because it excites me and has romantic appeal and has a small possibility of incredible success but is likely to result in having poor financial stability, the excitement will usually wears off among people in that field. Career Y doesn't appeal emotionally (at the time of making the choice) because it seems boring but usually people in that field have good job satisfaction, it has steady and moderate advancement but will never be lucrative. *Given my goal of maximizing happiness and balancing it with maximizing income/financial stability* then it seems clear that job Y is a better choice. If the choice is made a zillion times, in the end I'll be happier and more stable with Y more often than not.

If job Y happened to appeal to me emotionally, then there is no conflict and you can go with your gut. If my goal is not happiness/stability but excitement and having a chance to become crazy rich, then X is the logical choice and again there is no conflict. 

I'm not saying emotion is bad. I'm saying emotion should lose to logic if it ever conflicts with it, because it's less reliable.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28155851395.0" user="dangerzone133" delta="False">
    <text>With your career example - what's the point of making a lot of money if you are miserable? Maybe logically one makes sense, but if your gut is telling you something I think it makes sense to listen to it. Maybe going the logical route will leave you feeling unhappy and unfulfilled. 

Plus, as an aside, instinct is something that has huge evolutionary advantage. If you are say in a bad neighborhood and you hear a noise you aren't able to immediately identify, logically you might assume it's not a threat. But your heart is racing, the hair on the back of your neck is raised, something is telling you to be scared. In that situation it's much better to listen to your emotions than to stick to logic. Because if your logical brain is wrong  and your emotions and instinct are right,  you are in for trouble. Listening to instinct is how people make it out of life or death situations, there is a reason why that part of being human has been around for so long and why it triggers such strong responses, it could save your life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155938703.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>If your goal is happiness, then that is a factor the logic would try to include. One might argue happiness isn't logical but that's not the point, if I want to be happy and logic suggests one way will be more effective even though your instinct tells you otherwise, then yes logic can help you decide what will make you happy. 

&amp;gt;Plus, as an aside, instinct is something that has huge evolutionary advantage. 

Firstly there is no reason logic must to contradict feelings or instinct. Secondly just because we evolved a trait doesn't necessarily mean it's the best thing to use/do. Our appendix, xenophobia and male dominance are all leftovers from evolution on some level but aren't our best asset now that we know better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155952815.0" user="dangerzone133" delta="False">
    <text>I know not all evolutionarily things are valuable, that's why I told you why this particular one is.

And there are times when logic and emotion will conflict, that's what your CMV is about.  I simply gave you an example of a time where it is smarter to pick emotion over logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155971716.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>Your example seems to be something like this: "You are in danger, but logic says you are not in danger while your feelings tell you to gtfo, if you listen to logic you'll stay put and bad stuff happens, hence emotions can be as valid as logic."

If you're saying that the risk of putting yourself in a potentially dangerous position, even though logically it's a very low probability, is enough to listen to your instincts. Then sure, that's fine, this doesn't conflict. If you were in a situation where logic said you were safer in spot A than in spot B, but your instinct said you were safer in spot B than spot A, go with the logical choice. Even then, as I stated in my OP, there are factors that can't be accounted for because we aren't omniscient, so we might get it wrong. But on the whole the logical choice will be safer more often.

If we say that A probably isn't but could be dangerous, your instinct says "yes its dangerous and you should gtfo" and logic says "no it's not dangerous", that's not logic telling you to stay put and thus conflicting with emotions. There is no reason you can't leave a safe place to go to another safe place without resulting in conflict between emotions and logic. In this case logic just isn't a factor: should I leave here because I have a bad feeling? Emotions: Yes!, Logic: no input - then going with emotions isn't against logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155987496.0" user="dangerzone133" delta="False">
    <text>More what im saying is there are a lot of instances of people doing things just based on feels instead of logic, and that being the correct decision. I know people who normally take the 35w bridge going from Mpls to st. Paul, but for no other reason besides instinct they went a different path on the day of the bridge collapse. They went completely on feels even though there was no logical reason to take a different route. And if they wouldn't have changed their route, they could have been seriously injured or killed. You hear stories like this after every disaster. 

We do have the ability to sense danger, we just have to pay attention to it, and be willing to ignore logic sometimes. Everyone knows the feeling of "things just not feeling right" . I'm telling you it doesnt come from a logical place, but it shouldn't be ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156126220.0" user="Crulpeak" delta="False">
    <text>But that instinct isn't always right. There's been plenty of times the hair on the back of my neck stood up and told me to run, when in reality it was just my mind playing tricks on me. Then you're just wasting time and not getting stuff done, while the logical decision was the optimal path. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156128880.0" user="dangerzone133" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying it has a 100% success rate, I'm just saying it doesn't have a 100% failure rate. SOME of the time it's better to listen to instinct, that was my point since the CMV is that NONE of the time it's better to listen to it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156221812.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>You're right that the outcome of the logical path isn't better 100%, but since you don't know the outcome at the time you choose a given path, your odds are better when choosing the logical path. So the argument is that you should choose the logical path 100% of the time even though the outcome isn't necessarily better 100% of the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156348442.0" user="dangerzone133" delta="False">
    <text>Then you changed your view. Your CMV is that the logical path is always better. You are shifting goalposts here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156374065.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>I thought I was pretty consistent throughout. My premise was that when choosing between conflicting logic and emotion, you should choose logic. I didn't say logic will always yield a better result, just that it's more likely to yield a better result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156570045.0" user="Crulpeak" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're getting at here, but I'm not sure that's his view. 

His comments here don't articulate it the best, but I think his focus is more on the long term returns, not 100% success rate

&amp;gt;Sometimes, if there is a logical and emotional course of action and you didn't know how it would turn out the logical course turns out to have been worse in retrospect. But if you follow the logical course 100% of the time you'll maximize the amount of 'optimal choices'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156132225.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We do have the ability to sense danger, we just have to pay attention to it, and be willing to ignore logic sometimes. Everyone knows the feeling of "things just not feeling right" . I'm telling you it doesnt come from a logical place, but it shouldn't be ignored.

This isn't convincing to me. What makes you think the opposite doesn't happen? There are two tunnels near my home that can lead me to downtown, they often have maintenance. There have been times my wife or I, or a friend had feeling or vague intuition that the one I usually take (let's call it tunnel A), would be closed for maintenance and after suggesting it to me I take the other tunnel (B), then it turns out B was the one that was supposed to have maintenance that night and A was clear so I ended up in a jam where I would've otherwise been fine.

It's like why Moneyball (if you saw/read that) worked despite all the old fashioned know-how of the managers that could 'spot talent' and had good/bad feelings about players. Instinct is better than nothing, but logic is better than instinct when applicable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28157699473.0" user="serenity-bumblebee" delta="False">
    <text>It is a conflict between logic and emotion, because you're obviously in that unsafe place for a reason and if your logic deduces that it is not unsafe, then it follows that you should stay to fulfill the purpose of being in that area. So it's a case of your emotions telling you to leave because it's dangerous, and your logic telling you to stay because you came here to do X and since it's improbable that something bad will happen, there is no point in leaving without doing X first.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
