<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="234217718.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3vg3jq/cmv_when_logic_and_emotion_clash_logic_should/">
    <title>CMV: When logic and emotion clash, logic should always win.</title>
    <original_poster>renaissanceman975</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whenever a decision is made, a conclusion drawn, an idea perused or any other circumstance that might result in logic clashing with emotions I believe people should accept the logical side over the emotional side 100% of the time.

Now when I say a logical point in contrast to emotion I mean a point of view or course of action or what have you that, based on all the information you have available and can have logic applied to it, is different than what your feelings/gut/instinct/intuition/conventional wisdom/etc leads you to.

I know that you can't get off the ground without emotion, and that logic depends on values and life is meaningless if logic is all we use and so on. I don't think we should disregard emotion entirely, plently of situations don't need to employ logic (do I like ice cream or cake better?) and others may coincide with logic (when deciding whether to get married, maybe all the logical aspects agree with your emotions). However, in situations where we have an objective, take all the information we have available to us and apply logic, yet the way we feel about it leads us to a different conclusion, we should go with the logical side.

Sometimes, if there is a logical and emotional course of action and you didn't know how it would turn out the logical course turns out to have been worse in retrospect. But if you follow the logical course 100% of the time you'll maximize the amount of 'optimal choices'.

Let's I want to go to college and pursue a career, and my goals are to maximize my happiness and balance that with financial stability/income. I can choose career X and career Y to pursue. Obviously if I'm purely logical from start to finish I won't get off the ground, so I follow whatever emotional drives I have until logic can be applied for some result. Career X appeals to my emotions because it excites me and has romantic appeal and has a small possibility of incredible success but is likely to result in having poor financial stability, the excitement will usually wears off among people in that field. Career Y doesn't appeal emotionally (at the time of making the choice) because it seems boring but usually people in that field have good job satisfaction, it has steady and moderate advancement but will never be lucrative. *Given my goal of maximizing happiness and balancing it with maximizing income/financial stability* then it seems clear that job Y is a better choice. If the choice is made a zillion times, in the end I'll be happier and more stable with Y more often than not.

If job Y happened to appeal to me emotionally, then there is no conflict and you can go with your gut. If my goal is not happiness/stability but excitement and having a chance to become crazy rich, then X is the logical choice and again there is no conflict. 

I'm not saying emotion is bad. I'm saying emotion should lose to logic if it ever conflicts with it, because it's less reliable.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28160934939.0" user="chem4u" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, emotion and logic are not mutually exclusive. For most well-functioning people specific emotions are turned on and off depending on how the person percieves his or her situation. This is still a logical response, because when you focus on the reasoning on why for example, a child is crying it may be because he or she was abandoned. This emotional distress associated with this certain event *drives* a child to seek protection from their mother or father. If the child did not have this emotion; he or she will likely not have this response that *ensures* his or her survival. I guess what I'm trying to say is that in situations when cognitive thinking is limited due to age or other limitations, emotions are often times the response that keeps some one alive and making good decisions for their well being.

Emotions are powerful. They give an extra jolt of energy for a person to act. I would imagine that if we didn't have emotions so many people would be sluggish and every action would feel as though it was lagging. Think about it this way, there are a lot of people that are PASSIONATE about certain subjects. For example, there are some people that are so PASSIONATE about art that they will donate all of their money just to fundraise a new museum. This passion then is transformed to energy that a person will give to their cause. With cognitive reasoning alone, I find it hard to believe that people would be this invested in bettering their community etc.

Emotion allows an individual to understand or care about a situation that others may be in; when they themselves are removed from this situation. Well, I guess, I'm specifically referring to empathy. Believe it or not, you learn a lot from empathizing with people and trying to understand their situation. You get a better understanding of where you don't want to be and where you want to be. What you want to do with your life and what mistake you will never do in your life. I'm thinking of one example in particular: there are many people who are born into families of narcissistic guardians. Many of them learn from their emotions how it feels to be left alone and abused... they then transform this emotional experience into a practice that they will not dwelve into as parents. The result is good parenting.

Lastly, I'm thinking of psychopaths. These people are assumed to be high on the logical functioning skills than their emotions. Some may (thinking of killers, here) use their logic and lack of emotion to wreck havoc into others lives. If they had the emotional "stops" and "checks" that a typical person had then they would not commit such horrible crimes. If any thing, I wish they had more empathy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
