<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="234217718.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3vg3jq/cmv_when_logic_and_emotion_clash_logic_should/">
    <title>CMV: When logic and emotion clash, logic should always win.</title>
    <original_poster>renaissanceman975</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whenever a decision is made, a conclusion drawn, an idea perused or any other circumstance that might result in logic clashing with emotions I believe people should accept the logical side over the emotional side 100% of the time.

Now when I say a logical point in contrast to emotion I mean a point of view or course of action or what have you that, based on all the information you have available and can have logic applied to it, is different than what your feelings/gut/instinct/intuition/conventional wisdom/etc leads you to.

I know that you can't get off the ground without emotion, and that logic depends on values and life is meaningless if logic is all we use and so on. I don't think we should disregard emotion entirely, plently of situations don't need to employ logic (do I like ice cream or cake better?) and others may coincide with logic (when deciding whether to get married, maybe all the logical aspects agree with your emotions). However, in situations where we have an objective, take all the information we have available to us and apply logic, yet the way we feel about it leads us to a different conclusion, we should go with the logical side.

Sometimes, if there is a logical and emotional course of action and you didn't know how it would turn out the logical course turns out to have been worse in retrospect. But if you follow the logical course 100% of the time you'll maximize the amount of 'optimal choices'.

Let's I want to go to college and pursue a career, and my goals are to maximize my happiness and balance that with financial stability/income. I can choose career X and career Y to pursue. Obviously if I'm purely logical from start to finish I won't get off the ground, so I follow whatever emotional drives I have until logic can be applied for some result. Career X appeals to my emotions because it excites me and has romantic appeal and has a small possibility of incredible success but is likely to result in having poor financial stability, the excitement will usually wears off among people in that field. Career Y doesn't appeal emotionally (at the time of making the choice) because it seems boring but usually people in that field have good job satisfaction, it has steady and moderate advancement but will never be lucrative. *Given my goal of maximizing happiness and balancing it with maximizing income/financial stability* then it seems clear that job Y is a better choice. If the choice is made a zillion times, in the end I'll be happier and more stable with Y more often than not.

If job Y happened to appeal to me emotionally, then there is no conflict and you can go with your gut. If my goal is not happiness/stability but excitement and having a chance to become crazy rich, then X is the logical choice and again there is no conflict. 

I'm not saying emotion is bad. I'm saying emotion should lose to logic if it ever conflicts with it, because it's less reliable.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28156015629.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't include your emotions in your logical decisions, you will never be happy.

But if you *do* include your emotions in your logical calculations, then it's logically impossible for your logic and your emotions to ever "clash", as emotions are always a premise in your logic. 

Basically, if your logic (minus emotions) says no, but your emotions say yes, then what does your more encompassing logic (that includes emotions) have to say about that? If you would have chosen your emotions over "logic", but you choose your emotions instead, then the only logical conclusion is that the emotional value you are responding to is of higher value to you than whatever negative value your logic calculated. In that case, logically, you should choose your emotions.

Basically, it's impossible to *ever* "choose logic over emotions" using logic. It's only ever possible to do that using emotions... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156156981.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>That's only if you plan to include all emotions you experience anytime in the logic. If I feel like I'd be happy spending $5000 from savings to buy a piano and teach myself with youtube, and my objective is to be happy, when in the process of deciding I might have warm-fuzzy feelings about the piano option and sad "life is a bitch" type feelings about giving up on my piano idea, but I might logically conclude that I'd be happier long-term with the other benefits of keeping the $5000 in savings than I would be with the piano. So basically emotions say yes get the piano, logic says no save your money. Trust your logic. You might still be wrong, but the majority of people the majority of the time will be wrong less often than if they'd gone with the emotional side.

Note: Of course, it's possible, you logically conclude that it's a good idea to spend $5000 savings on a piano.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156233262.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>My point is this:

Logic (excluding emotions) says: value of action = -100. Your emotions say you want to take that action. Let's suppose you actually decide to "follow your emotions". 

That *logically* implies that the emotional value that you place on the action is &amp;gt;+100, otherwise you wouldn't choose to "follow your emotions" over your logic.

And therefore logic would *also* tell you to take the action. 

I don't think that there is any possible way to conclude "logically" that one shouldn't "follow ones emotions" in any case where one would actually do so, if one considered logic at all (i.e. when they "clash").

The only way to follow your emotions in a way that conflicts with logic would be if you don't consider the logical view at all. I.e. in cases where the 2 don't conflict. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156285365.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That logically implies that the emotional value that you place on the action is &amp;gt;+100, otherwise you wouldn't choose to "follow your emotions" over your logic.

Why does it logically imply this? If logic tells me an action will result in -100 'value points', and my emotions tell me it's +500 'value points' but emotion has a mess of stuff mixed in that throw off the accuracy of my value ([hormones](https://womensinternational.com/pdf/moods.pdf), [priming](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)), [weather](http://psychcentral.com/blog/archives/2014/08/29/can-weather-affect-your-mood/), etc) then the emotion result would be inaccurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156302507.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>So how *would* you assess the emotional value of the action, if not by consulting your emotions?

Logically, you must consider this value, because emotions are by definition exactly what makes you "happy". 

If you fail to consider the emotional value of the action, you are not being logical. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156386060.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>I think we are talking at cross purposes. My emotions *now* regarding the potential outcome of a decision in the *future* are unreliable. That outcome might be an emotional one and I have to take that into account when I'm deciding between the two, however I'm not talking about my *"now" logic* is conflicting with my *"future" emotion*, but rather when my *"now" logic* is conflicting with my *"now" emotion*. It's possible that they conflict about a the outcome of a *"future" emotion* but they can conflict about stuff whose goal is not emotional. Placing a bet at roulette wheel can have conflicting emotion and logic. Your goal might be to have fun, in which case your logic might tell you to do what feels like fun, in this case they don't conflict. If instead your goal is to win money, your logic might tell you to bet on black but you might have a feeling that betting on double-zero will be better, in this case they conflict and logic should win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156560733.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really an "emotion", that's a "gut instinct". Clearly gut instincts and logic can conflict.

But unless you have a giant emotional attachment to your gut instincts (in which case, you will gain an emotional advantage from following them that you can't discount), that doesn't mean that emotions and logic conflict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28157229699.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's not instinct but intuition. You have a feeling about something without evidence to support it (a feeling that throw at the craps table will be 7 this time), instinct is a pattern of behavior that isn't based on prior experience (sea turtles wandering in to the ocean after birth). I'm don't mean to be anal about this, but I think it's important to distinguish because when we call it instinct in a casual way we're talking about a different idea than when we say instinct is separate from emotions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
