<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="234217718.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3vg3jq/cmv_when_logic_and_emotion_clash_logic_should/">
    <title>CMV: When logic and emotion clash, logic should always win.</title>
    <original_poster>renaissanceman975</original_poster>
    <original_post>Whenever a decision is made, a conclusion drawn, an idea perused or any other circumstance that might result in logic clashing with emotions I believe people should accept the logical side over the emotional side 100% of the time.

Now when I say a logical point in contrast to emotion I mean a point of view or course of action or what have you that, based on all the information you have available and can have logic applied to it, is different than what your feelings/gut/instinct/intuition/conventional wisdom/etc leads you to.

I know that you can't get off the ground without emotion, and that logic depends on values and life is meaningless if logic is all we use and so on. I don't think we should disregard emotion entirely, plently of situations don't need to employ logic (do I like ice cream or cake better?) and others may coincide with logic (when deciding whether to get married, maybe all the logical aspects agree with your emotions). However, in situations where we have an objective, take all the information we have available to us and apply logic, yet the way we feel about it leads us to a different conclusion, we should go with the logical side.

Sometimes, if there is a logical and emotional course of action and you didn't know how it would turn out the logical course turns out to have been worse in retrospect. But if you follow the logical course 100% of the time you'll maximize the amount of 'optimal choices'.

Let's I want to go to college and pursue a career, and my goals are to maximize my happiness and balance that with financial stability/income. I can choose career X and career Y to pursue. Obviously if I'm purely logical from start to finish I won't get off the ground, so I follow whatever emotional drives I have until logic can be applied for some result. Career X appeals to my emotions because it excites me and has romantic appeal and has a small possibility of incredible success but is likely to result in having poor financial stability, the excitement will usually wears off among people in that field. Career Y doesn't appeal emotionally (at the time of making the choice) because it seems boring but usually people in that field have good job satisfaction, it has steady and moderate advancement but will never be lucrative. *Given my goal of maximizing happiness and balancing it with maximizing income/financial stability* then it seems clear that job Y is a better choice. If the choice is made a zillion times, in the end I'll be happier and more stable with Y more often than not.

If job Y happened to appeal to me emotionally, then there is no conflict and you can go with your gut. If my goal is not happiness/stability but excitement and having a chance to become crazy rich, then X is the logical choice and again there is no conflict. 

I'm not saying emotion is bad. I'm saying emotion should lose to logic if it ever conflicts with it, because it's less reliable.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28155803381.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>As a blank rule this is bad for several reasons.

1. What if you're smarter emotionally than you are logically? If you have dumb logic why should you rely on thinking things through? If from your history thinking things through in a logical fashion leads to worse outcomes why do it?

2. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_fallacies What if your logic is reliant on lots of fallacies and stupid human reasoning things? Logic is a part of the brain, it is flawed.

3. What if your time is limited? Logic doesn't function well when used quickly, in those situations emotion, which is a faster response is often superior. If you follow the logical course of action 100% of the time when someone punches you then you're not going to be very effective, as you don't have time to think stuff through when being punched.

4. Emotion tends to be able to draw on a wider array of information. People have often noted that gut instincts have shown them factual issues before logic presented them. If emotions are faster why say no to them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155907349.0" user="fuccboi_intensifies" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of your points revolve around people having flawed logic. Flawed logic is flawed precisely because it's illogical.

If your main argument against logic is human error, that's fine and i agree with that. However far as i know there's no solid proof that human emotion is any less prone to error than logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155925024.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Thanks. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28155973157.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Are you arguing flawed emotion is worse than perfect logic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156116379.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite. I'm saying when properly employed, logic will get you what you want more often. I think, as a method for judging and deciding things, emotion is inherently flawed for many reasons. We wouldn't say perfect emotion vs perfect logic, because logic is a structured system that can be used to essentially (and literally) compute solutions. Also imperfect logic doesn't really work either because if it isn't "perfect logic" then it isn't logic. 

If I say 13+18=43, I was mistaken but it isn't logic that failed, I didn't employ logic correctly and thus got the wrong answer. Let's say I have an absolutely perfect understanding of my emotions and a flawed understanding of logic, I'll get more stuff wrong than if I utilize logic correctly but don't have a perfect grasp on my feelings.

I'd like to emphasize here, the use of logic doesn't necessarily mean we have to disregard emotions. Indeed, if something I want is an emotion dependent thing, then that emotion needs to be a factor in whatever conclusion I draw. If I have a bad day at work on Friday and am unhappy and my goal is to stop feeling unhappy, I can apply logic to the situation just like any other. My argument isn't that we should ignore our feelings and be like robots for a utopia, my argument is that when some logical conclusion is *in opposition* to something your emotions are pushing you towards, that is when logic should always win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156186612.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Also imperfect logic doesn't really work either because if it isn't "perfect logic" then it isn't logic. 

So to rephrase your view, when doing the perfect thing and emotion clash you should do the perfect thing?

If you use logic as a synonym for perfect, yes, using logic will appear perfect.

And so, even if the majority of the time logic lead you wrong and led to worse results, by your reasoning, the problem is that whatever logic is bad. So, regardless of what actually happens in the real world logic is always good?

Logic is something that runs on our brains. Emotion is something that runs in our brain. Both are subject to flaws and imperfections in our brain. In real life people have noted that at times logic is worse at solving problems.

We're slightly smarter evolved apes. For most of human existence we failed to invent much significant science. We stand on the shoulders of giants. You hold doing correct maths as logic- it's not for most, it's rote memorization of the work of others. We can augment logic and emotions via rote memorization of the work of others. 

&amp;gt;If I say 13+18=43, I was mistaken but it isn't logic that failed, I didn't employ logic correctly and thus got the wrong answer.

No, the problem was more likely that you failed to memorize the answer, or similar questions that could point you to the answer. Much of logic and philosophy comes from people spending months or years or decades studying a subject and coming up with conclusions that you can memorize and then apply to solve problems. You can do that with emotion or logic.

In some situations, emotion is better at applying memorized rules. Even assuming logic is functioning right, emotion is much faster.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156232473.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So to rephrase your view, when doing the perfect thing and emotion clash you should do the perfect thing?

Why are you saying using perfect logic is the same thing as doing the perfect thing? If I don't have all the facts it's possible for me to be wrong even though the logic I used was flawless. However emotion doesn't magically take these unknowns into account either, so despite neither guaranteeing a perfect outcome, you're more likely to get the outcome you seek when going for the logical path than the emotional one.

Imagine a detective is investigating a crime, had a dozen suspects, and had a bad feeling about one despite not having any evidence, and a good feeling about another despite having a small amount of evidence. Modern investigations go with the evidence rather than the 'hunch' because it statistically gets more/better results more often.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156243005.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I don't have all the facts it's possible for me to be wrong even though the logic I used was flawless.

The general assumption that logic is flawless is why I was noting it was wrong to do assume it was perfect. Logic isn't flawless. People often use logic in stupid ways, likewise with emotion.

&amp;gt;However emotion doesn't magically take these unknowns into account either, so despite neither guaranteeing a perfect outcome, you're more likely to get the outcome you seek when going for the logical path than the emotional one.

Emotion can take extra information into account.

Suppose you are with some people and get a sudden sense of fear about one person you can't work out a logical reason for. Your emotions could have tied certain types of body language to imminent violence, while your logical mind hasn't worked out what the general signs of violent body language are. Emotion has it's own separate memory banks.

The logical person might stay and die. The emotional person might flee and live. And if the logical person notes that trusting in logic leads to being beaten up, surely it would be logical to trust their emotions?

&amp;gt;Modern investigations go with the evidence rather than the 'hunch' because it statistically gets more/better results more often.

Could you demonstrate this to me with a logical scientific study? Or is this just a gut feeling of yours that this is true?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156276289.0" user="renaissanceman975" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The general assumption that logic is flawless is why I was noting it was wrong to do assume it was perfect. Logic isn't flawless. People often use logic in stupid ways, likewise with emotion.

I think the issue here is just a confusion about the way we are using the terms. Your logic, my logic, Obama's logic, Napoleon's logic and Rasputin's logic would be identical. Our abilities to employ it properly might vary. 10+10 = 20 no matter what, but I might make a mistake and get a result of 30, the logic isn't flawed, I messed up the use of logic. Our situations are different too, so my results might be different than your results because my equation might be 4+8=12, and yours might be 5+2=7, we have different stuff to input and get a different result. The mechanism itself doesn't change.

&amp;gt;Emotion can take extra information into account.

I'm not sure I'd count that as emotions taking it into account, but for the sake of argument let's say that's true. What's to say trusting your gut will lead you to the right conclusion. Con artists depend on this to take advantage of us, we trust a con artist because our emotions tell us they are trustworthy. These emotions aren't useless, but they're unreliable.

&amp;gt;Could you demonstrate this to me with a logical scientific study? Or is this just a gut feeling of yours that this is true?

[A](https://books.google.com/books?id=cP32PsHXYY8C&amp;amp;pg=PA29&amp;amp;lpg=PA29&amp;amp;dq=police+use+forensic+evidence+instead+of+hunch&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=t6i0JfcYOx&amp;amp;sig=9Vl_VKr1esV4T_Z7jiXzdBoBL1U&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi3n_ntq8PJAhUL3mMKHcCRA9oQ6AEIJDAB#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=police%20use%20forensic%20evidence%20instead%20of%20hunch&amp;amp;f=false) [cursory](http://cebcp.org/evidence-based-policing/what-works-in-policing/research-evidence-review/) [google](https://prezi.com/9cw6jhrpha09/forensic-science-vs-eyewitness-testimony/) [search](https://books.google.com/books?id=-I1zVIt41xsC&amp;amp;pg=PA51&amp;amp;lpg=PA51&amp;amp;dq=police+use+forensic+evidence+instead+of+hunch&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=6GdhJsTL_t&amp;amp;sig=ce29oBZ04nSTln_ru8xKu0HQdYg&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi3n_ntq8PJAhUL3mMKHcCRA9oQ6AEITjAJ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=police%20use%20forensic%20evidence%20instead%20of%20hunch&amp;amp;f=false).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28156298877.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Logic is often similar across people and its application if fuzzy. 10+10 is twenty and seven experts say that 20 is enough to solve some problem, two say its not and you have to decide which to trust. Real life is too complicated to be solved by one persons logic and is fuzzy enough to cause confusion.

Plus, logic is about assumptions. Lots of people have dumb assumptions so their logic varies.

You can test what proportion of times emotion is right about a situation vs logic. Con artists use logic to convince people to buy snake oil too, con artists use everything.

None of your cited studies say gut feelings are less accurate than small amounts of evidence. Of course, DNA evidence is valid whether you use emotions or logic. You can have a gut feeling evidence is good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
