<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442796892.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>STEM doesn’t exist in a vacuum. You don’t want to teach any history? Good luck being able to contextualize Galileo’s work with zero understanding of the culture at the time — students would have no knowledge of religion, the Roman inquisition or Italy at all. 

A lot of time in science classes would be spent not exploring and applying scientific principles, but instead explaining what the hell certain basic concepts are. Imagine explaining evolutionary biology to a group of students who have never learned history. 

It’s just impossible to untangle STEM from its social contexts. Why did we seek to learn these concepts in the first place? What was their application? What could we use them for in the future? That’s what you’re missing when you extract social sciences, history, literature.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442920805.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>People would still learn all those things.

But just like they learn about the meaning of life and morality outside school - also important context - so too can they learn these other things outside school</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442943755.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People would still learn all those things.

How?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442970990.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re being far too optimistic about parents teaching history and literature to their children. Most wouldn’t. And since you’re proposing that only public schools teach exclusively STEM, tons of parents would be trying to get their kids into private schools. Public schools would be drained of a lot of their students, and new private schools would spring up everywhere. It would be a major economic shift that we aren’t prepared for. Privately educated students would become the elites at an even greater pace, because they’d be the only ones with a holistic education. 

I’d also argue that students learn about the meaning of life and morality in English classes. They debate Iago’s motivations in Shakespeare, read about children without society in Lord of the Flies, think about justice and authority in To Kill a Mockingbird. 

Are you also suggesting no more civics classes? So no one would learn how their government works? Or make informed voting decisions? That’s a dangerous idea. The powers that be benefit greatly from an uneducated or undereducated population, which is basically what you’re suggesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443000754.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like everything here is simply a matter of differing intuitions (e.g. optimism versus pessimism). What objective, substantive point should I focus on ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443058776.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>By “optimistic” I didn’t mean intuition, but rather that you thought it was likely that a vast majority of parents would give their children comprehensive education of the 50% of course material you’re proposing to eliminate. 

Currently in the US, about 5.56% of all students are homeschooled. That population would probably continue to learn about social sciences. But it’s unlikely that most other students would. Many parents work full-time and don’t have the time or the knowledge to teach. And many parents don’t have the financial resources to send their children to the myriad social science tutoring centers that would spring up as a result of your new policy. 

What percent of children do you think would realistically be able to access the resources to learn social sciences?

Also, I think my point about the danger of a lack of education around government stands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444855632.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The point that even *you* can’t support Your View without adding an laughable caveat that students still learn all the subjects you had removed from school… somehow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443173753.0" user="htiafon" delta="False">
    <text>Why wouldn't they magically learn stem subjects outside of school?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444842011.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; People would still learn all those things.

In what setting? From who?

UPDATE: Instead of answering, OP blocked me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42488380826.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42488380864.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MikeMutethia – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42448152526.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People would still learn all those things.

Can't you say the exact same thing about STEM subjects? Those who want a career in STEM field would study these subjects anyway. Why bother to teach them to everyone? 

I think the main question is that what is the purpose of public education. Many people think it's job is to train workers for the economy. There might be some of that but for that there are only a few subjects that make sense to teach to everyone (reading, writing, basic arithmetic) as they are needed in pretty much everything people do. STEM subjects are definitely not such (and this from a person who works in a STEM field himself). 

However, there are other roles for the public education. I think in a democratic society it's absolutely crucial that people have certain skills (history, politics, ability to critical thinking). And these are things that people are unlikely to study on their own as their benefit comes through the fact that they make enlightened choices in elections that produces a good society, but for any single individual the benefit from their own educated election decision is minimal compared to the cost of obtaining all the education needed for it. It only makes sense on the level of society.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
