<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442669577.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles.

If the last 10 years has illustrated *anything* its that the "marketplace of ideas" does anything but correct itself. 

It just leads to people being more stubborn, more close minded, more self assured in their own viewpoints, and less receptive to other perspectives.

&gt;TLDR: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive. I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

This is such an "enlightened centrist" perspective.  *conservatives* have an issue with teaching the historical realities of slavery, the Civil War, and racism in schools, or really teaching anything bad about US history in general. 

Your solution is essentially "give conservatives what they want, and everyone will be happy."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442746060.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;conservatives  
&gt;  
&gt; have an issue with teaching the historical realities of slavery, the Civil War, and racism in schools, or really teaching anything bad about US history in general.

I often see this point made. But where does this actually happen?

I went to high school in the late 1990s. We spent I dunno maybe several semesters discussing slavery. At no point were we told that it was a fun affair and that people did not suffer. It was also no secret who was enslaved. In fact it was kind of hammered in our heads "the black people in your classroom are descendants of slaves". Nobody really gave a shit because they were being factual and there was no "US is bad" undertone to it. 

What we really see with CRT and all that other disgusting shit is that it is based on "US IS BAD HORRIBLE". We completely gloss over all the good US has done. We completely gloss over the fact that US is probably the least racist country on earth. That it has the most tolerance of any large country. Instead we focus on shit that we already learn except now with an emphasis on "US BAD MMMMMMMKAY'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442785888.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Nobody really gave a shit because they were being factual and there was no "US is bad" undertone to it. 

I guarantee that behind the scenes, there was at least one parent who was harassing the school board about it. 

But yeah, parents were generally less involved in school stuff back then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442814139.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What we really see with CRT and all that other disgusting shit is that it is based on "US IS BAD HORRIBLE". 

CRT is not and has never been taught in schools.  This whole narrarive has been fabricated and perpetuated by conservative ideologues as a means to undermine the public school system and remove any acknowledgement of racism in the US curriculum.

Parents are angry now because foxnews and the conservative media tell them there's something to be angry about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442832942.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't really address what I was saying.

We have been and continue to teach about slavery. We don't allow it to be framed as some pro-socialist rhetoric for good reason. Because educated people understand how cancerous socialist ideas are. But besides that there is plenty of information on slavery being taught in factual based curriculum that nobody opposes. Same thing with civil war. Same thing with civil rights. We spent a whole semester learning about Martin Luther king in AP history. This was in 2000.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442882262.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>You're illustrating my point.   Nothing substantial has changed in the last 2-3 decades in the school system regarding the history of race/slavery.  The only thing that has changed is conservatives stances on the subject matter, which has taken a far right turn in the last 10 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443016037.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>They have attempted to introduce new pro-socialist classes into the curriculum. Which we very wisely shot down to hell. 

That is really what people talk about when they say this "they don't want to teach about slavery" nonsense. It's not slavery we don't want to teach about, we don't want our kids to think US is evil and that socialism is the answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443161083.0" user="MontiBurns" delta="False">
    <text>Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42457327814.0" user="Paterno_Ster" delta="False">
    <text>Pro-socialist in what way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42458369953.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>Socialists have figured out that they will never get anywhere in USA using their normal economic based rhetoric. Because on average the US economy is very friendly to the population. Yes there are some people who are poor but most of them realize they fucked the dog one way or another (being lazy in school, being criminals etc).

What they found is that it's much easier to spread socialism using things like sexism and racism. Because people don't think about those things logically. A lot of white people have "white guilt" and will agree with whatever they hear. Only because they don't want to seem racist. This is a much easier vector to attack from.

This is why when you hear BLM messages they all have socialist undertones. They want to destroy the current system. They want wealth redistribution. Capitalism is evil. Blah blah. Same old message just a different delivery strategy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442840584.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Lately, euphemisms are being used for words like slavery, racial contexts are being removed from history lessons. In Florida, there was just a report of a textbook having any mentions of segregation removed from the story of Rosa Parks, now she's just some lady who refused to move... opting out of lessons or altering things because they make someone feel uncomfortable about race isn't helping. 

I do not remember being taught about many of the horrible things America has done. Glossing over things and teaching American exceptionalism isn't helping anyone understand how we got here. I can't remember learning about the CIA sponsoring violent coups, the aftermaths and the human costs that were often failures even by the standard of those who championed them. Nothing was ever put in that context. 

Simply learning about horrible shit the US has done isn't an agenda. You're allowed to come to any conclusion about the topic. I don't remember being told how to feel about a subject often in school, however if you don't teach the entire story you're shaping a glossed over, and sanitized curriculum. Which itself feels a lot more like an agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442926862.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Glossing over things and teaching American exceptionalism isn't helping anyone understand how we got here. I can't remember learning about the CIA sponsoring violent coups, the aftermaths and the human costs that were often failures even by the standard of those who championed them. 

Because often those are not properly communicated on social media.

For example the standard line is something like "US sponsored a coup". Which makes it sound like the country had this wonderful leadership that US decided to get rid of. But the reality is often very different. Take Ukraine in 2014. That is supposedly a "US orchestrated coup" according to Russian propaganda. Just the source of that information should raise an eyebrow yet people repeat it at nauseam. But what really happened? The guy who was legit elected chose to go back on an election promise. Some university kids came out in Maidan to protest. This was not a very big protest at first. Yanukovich used Putin style ruthless tactics to disperse with the protesters. Something the Ukrainians were not happy about. So this minor protest turned into a giant 2 million man protest. Where it was no longer about airing a grievance but removing Yanukovich from post. This is supposedly a "US sponsored coup".

If you look closely at nearly every situation. You find that at best US was choosing between 2 evil options. Where they would usually side with the anti-socialist side for obvious reasons. When the pro-capitalist evil side won. The people nit picking had an easy criticism of US.

See if it was taught this way. Most people wouldn't have a problem with it. Because it is factual. But that's not how they want it to be taught. They just want "CIA is bad" to be taught.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442859696.0" user="pfundie" delta="False">
    <text>Children aren't taught about the single largest advance in women's rights, when wifebeating became illegal sometime around the mid-20th century. Prior to that, it was socially encouraged for a man to beat his wife if she "disobeyed" him, and you don't have rights if your husband is legally empowered to physically hurt you at home for exercising them; domestic violence wasn't even grounds for divorce. Half of this is just because it's horrible and we like to shelter children, but the other half is that it makes conservative claims about the history of women's rights look bad, and makes the concept of "traditional marriage" seem either not very traditional or pretty disturbing. As a result, though, most people are completely ignorant of how society actually treated and thought about women for most of history, and that the historical legal arrangement of marriage was startlingly close to slavery.

There's various and numerous examples of confederate apologism as well, and discussions of the Japanese internment camps or the treatment of Native Americans are frequently glossed over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442882961.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>I grew up in the 1990s. It was never a secret that spousal abuse was far more common in the past. I don't remember exactly how or where I learned that. But spousal abuse being more common historically is not exactly some conservative secret. 

Traditional marriage has a ton of beneficial aspects. It keeps parents together. Children who are raised by 2 parents fair MUCHHHHHHHHH better than children raised in single parent households. There is a mountain of data that supports that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442873973.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Nobody really gave a shit because they were being factual and there was no "US is bad" undertone to it. 

I don't know how anyone could devise a factual course on the history of slavery that wouldn't have "US is bad" undertones to it, to be quite honest. Slavery was absolutely terrible. Slavery was state endorsed and enforced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442996973.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>Very simple. Every country has bad acts associated with it. You can teach about World War 2 in a German classroom without telling everyone that their ancestors were evil cunts and that they too are evil cunts because of that. No country that has been around for a while has nothing to be ashamed of. People are the same way. We've all done things that we regret.

Telling a bunch of young Americans that their country is shit over something that happened 150 years ago is not particularly productive. 

In fact you can frame it that the Western World were pioneers of abolition. The Northern US states were a big part of that. In reality US is also partially responsible for slavery being a thing of the past in most of the world. The only places that still have slavery are not Western. 

See you don't need to frame it with anti US undertones. They choose to do that because ultimately their entire rhetoric is "we don't like US, we want it to change, we want socialism". You can't sell socialism and be supportive of US at the same time. Which is their real goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443052393.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>You're pretty much proving the overall point here. First, your examples are hyperbolic and nowhere near representative of "an undertone". Kids don't go in class learning the US is shit. They go into class an learn pretty terrible thing the country has been involved in, a factual retelling of which will not be conductive to prideful sentiments (and they shouldn't...). 

Secondly your framing of the slavery issue isn't really factual, it's more of a tortured attempt to turn a gaping historical wound into a win. Like, yeah, nobody disagrees *it's possible* to frame the United-States history with slavery positively to save your feelings, they argue it's not factual to do so. Yeah, I did things I'm not proud of, that's true, but the solution to that shame isn't to construct a whole narrative where I was actually justified and nothing I did was wrong. The solution is to learn and do better. That's the whole point. 

If what you want is a curriculum where we excise anything that might possibly lead one to conclude change might be needed, you're not looking for education I'm sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443105612.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but US has learned and has done better. That's the whole point. Not only did US make slavery illegal. They made sure that the entire Western world followed that model as well. We have atoned. That's what they should teach in those classrooms. 

US is the leader of the western world. Which western country is cool with having slaves in 2023? None. 

It's funny because the same people who refuse to let go of something US did 150 years ago. Are the same type of people that tell us we should forgive violent criminals and focus on rehabilitation. 

Yes you can both teach that US had slavery and teach people that US is a great place to live that has done a ton of good for planet earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443612899.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Yes you can both teach that US had slavery and teach people that US is a great place to live that has done a ton of good for planet earth.

Our issue is that one of those things is a historical fact we should feel comfortable sharing we our youth, while the other is shameless editorializing I'd rather we leave at the discretion of parents if they so please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443638447.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>Which one? Both are historical facts.

"Shameless editorializing". Do you think people living in South Korea think it's shameless editorializing that they don't have to live under the Kim regime in utter destitute like fucking prisoners. How about people in Japan and Germany who have a country to be proud of that United Stats helped rebuild. How about Europe who withstood USSR aggression because United States had their back militarily. I'm sure I could come up with 1000 examples like this. But of course we only focus on the one we want to focus on which fits our "US is bad" narrative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444270614.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>The fact I prefer not living in North Korea is an opinion of mine. A lot of people would agree with it, but it's still an opinion of mine. It's an opinion we don't need to teach children as a matter of course. 

Similarly, you thinking "the United States is a great place to live" is an opinion of yours, not something we need to teach children. I'm not going to stop you from having that opinion - I might agree with it at time - but a curriculum that doesn't include it isn't lacking in any real sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444340770.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>You're not addressing the point.

It's all in the framing. You can teach slavery in a "yeah we were bad but we stopped doing that 150 years ago" frame. Or you can teach with your "US is irremediably bad for all eternity no matter what they do because 150 years ago they had slaves" frame.

And I'm using your own words here. You said I don't know how you can teach about slavery without saying that US is bad. 

Think about teaching German kids born in the 2000s that they are all bad and that Germany is bad. Because of what their country did in 1940s. Who does that benefit? Certainly not the German kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444398512.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; You said I don't know how you can teach about slavery without saying that US is bad. 

I did not. It's pretty easy to see too. I said: *I don't know how anyone could devise a factual course on the history of slavery that wouldn't have "US is bad" undertones*. Which is just the truth. Slavery was absolutely terrible. Slavery was state sanctioned and enforced. Slavery was practice by many figures prominent in the country's creation. US was indeed bad in sanctioning and enforcing slavery. I don't know how anyone with a soul and a conscience can go trough any sort of factual retelling of slavery without getting some "US is bad" undertones. 

If you want to argue we could also run some kind of apologia campaign parallel to that history, to mitigate that undertone, I'd argue it would no longer be factual. 

&gt; Think about teaching German kids born in the 2000s that they are all bad and that Germany is bad. Because of what their country did in 1940s. Who does that benefit? Certainly not the German kids.

It's the same thing? A factual retelling of German history 1920-1945 is going to have a "Germany is bad undertones", because Germany was up to absolutely terrible crap in that period. Yeah, Germany was indeed bad in starting a World War and conducting large scale genocide. These are easy conclusions to make based on a straight readings of the events.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444467869.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you should say "US was bad". Just like with Nazi Germany it's a totally different place now. Germany was very bad in 1940 but it is a very good country in 2023 in a very objective sense.

You can both teach the atrocities of Nazi Germany and acknowledge that Germany turned the page on that chapter. Which is precisely what they do btw. And precisely what we were doing for the longest with slavery. Before the socialists realized that this was a great way to paint US as a bad country that needs radical change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444511264.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>Granted I've never been to school in Germany, but I very much doubt "Germany is a very good country today is a very objective sense" makes part of any serious school curriculum. That's, again, pointless editorializing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444559689.0" user="Enzo-Fernandez" delta="False">
    <text>It's how you frame it. You don't have to outwardly say "Germany is a good place".

You can teach 1940 Nazi Germany as a shameful past that we overcame.

Or you can teach 1860 slavery as a "Systemic Oppression" that continues today. Without acknowledging the massive amount of progress that has been made. 

All about how you frame it. 

I'm sure there are things that happened in 1940s Germany that still affect life today. But they are not talking about going batshit crazy and destroying their economy through socialism in order to fix it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442925507.0" user="Normal-Flower4437" delta="False">
    <text>That’s isn’t really what’s been happening at all. Plenty of black thinkers in particular have outlined what they think is wrong with a lot of current progressive curriculum, how it’s ahistorical and/or reductive or inaccurate, and how the opposition is being mischaracterized. 

Slavery, Jim Crow, Housing Discrimination, and the Triangle Trade remain standard curriculum items and there exists no major conservative movement to remove it. Almost every famous instance has actually been a progressive mischaracterization.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
