<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42444220667.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Some individuals arguing LGBT students should be protexted from discrimination, while others belief school should not be promoting LGBT ideology in conflict with your personal beliefs

The ONLY personal beliefs a person can have that would conflict with the "ideology" of 'dont discriminate' is the belief that you should discriminate against gay people. Which makes you a bigot.

LGBT students being free from slurs shouted at them and teachers reporting them to CPS because all gay kids must be abused (or wirse, forcibly outing them even into a hostile home towards a gay kid) is not 'promoting ideology'. The only ideology that not doing those promotes is an ideology of not hating gay people for fucking existing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444302804.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're proving my point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444319781.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If an openly gay stusent is bullied by another student, what should the school do? Lookcthe other way because stopping discrimination is apparently 'ideology' according to you? Im genuinely asking. Do you believe bullying should be ignored.

If I 'proved your point', then your point is one of extreme privilege that would simply make life hell for anyone outside the norm of society's expectations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444328525.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I've said nothing of the sort. You're projecting some issue on me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444335152.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Then please answer my question.

Should students being called words like 'f*ggot' in hallways have any hope of their school protecting them. Yes or no, its very easy to type instead of dodging the question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444349695.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>You're hijacking the CMV. 

I haven't said schools should allow slurs based on sexual orientation any more than I've said schools should allow slurs based on religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444353942.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Your refusal to type a simple 2 or 3 letter word tells me my answer anyways.

Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444415571.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, let you speak for yourself. How would this: 

&gt;LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

Be changed/improved by a school only teaching STEM subjects?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444435733.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>There would be neither persecution of LGBTQ+ kids nor religious kids. They would go to math class and not worry about it. Just like Protestants and Jews and Muslims go to math class and don't worry about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444498837.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>... And what if there is?

Unless you plan to also prevent kids from ever having any social interactions, theres gonna be bullies.

So. If a bully decides to pick on a gay student for being gay. Should the school be allowed to punish the bully?

Because according to your ideal school, no they cant. And if that isnt true, you sure are being REALLY obtuse about it in this thread. So just give a straight answer:

Is. Discrimination. Against gay kids. Bad. And should. Schools. Be allowed. To intervene.

Its a very simple question where a one word answer will suffice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444508550.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If a bully decides to pick on a gay student for being gay. Should the school be allowed to punish the bully?

&gt;Because according to your ideal school, no they cant.

Where is this coming from ?

That isn't how it works if a Jew bullies a Muslim. Bullying is bullying, regardless of the reason. 

I honestly don't know what you're talking about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444516666.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>You atill refuse to actually answer the question.

Is bullying against gay kids bad? Should schools intervene if it happens? Or would that be 'lgbt ideology' to do so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444531081.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Bullying is bad. Schools should stop bullying. Stopping bullying does not advance ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444540474.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>So, we agreeing that discriminating against gay kids is bad and schools should be in their interest to not allow it.

In that case, why does your very CMV call out teaching to not discriminate as being something schools shouldnt do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444546330.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;why does your very CMV call out teaching to not discriminate as being something schools shouldnt do?

. . . . . . . . . . .  

What are you talking about ?

It doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444562695.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; LGBT rights: The rights of LGBT students have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing **these students should be protected from discrimination**

It does, my friend. You literally,in your own words, argue that even protecting students from discrimination would be a bad thing for a school to do.

If this is wrong, then why word it thay way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444622797.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I'm suggesting we should protect LGBTQ+ students from discrimination ***in the same way that*** we protect students from discrimination on the basis of religion.

So I am solving that problem.

I am also solving the corresponding problem of people being opposed to ***ideology*** \- IN THE SAME WAY we protect against religious ideology: by excluding it from the school.

I am SOLVING both problems. I am not taking a side *in favor* of a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444636254.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>"Both" problems?

Wanting kids to not be hated for existing as they are is not a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444517223.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Schools should protect all kids from bullying. 

What are you talking about ???</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444525545.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>Im talking about how much you sre beating around the bush to even refuse to just openly say 'bullying gay kids is bad'.

The fact a sentence thay simple takes this much effort for you to even approximate agreeing with it says alot about how you view people like me for just existing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444539649.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I have said it, repeatedly. And that it takes this much effort to appease you says a lot about how divisive this issue is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444546777.0" user="maxestets" delta="False">
    <text>You havent though. Youve beat around the bush when asked and also, I notice, refuse to actually specifically type 'gay' even when thays the specific thing your being asked about. Do you think even typing it would be a sin or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444558572.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>This is a filibuster. You're hijacking the CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444563433.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I don't want to be accused of excluding L_BTQ+</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444505385.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>That's. . .not how things have historically worked. 

&gt;Just like Protestants and Jews and Muslims go to math class and don't worry about it.

Lol.

This is something every school MUST deal with. 

How do you think schools should deal with it?

Edit: is this a hard question?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
