<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442780658.0" user="obert-wan-kenobert" delta="False">
    <text>This like this like two friends arguing over what to eat for lunch, so they compromise on soggy cardboard and mayonnaise.

Yes, it technically stops the arguing, but it’s an awful idea and makes everyone miserable.

Do you really want to ruin education for *all*  children because a few adults can’t stop arguing about culture war nonsense?

It’s also not even that big of a problem. You hear about it on the news all the time (because it’s clickbait) but 99% of English and History classes are regular, boring, and non-controversial. 

Finally, a lot of the education culture war is about sex ed, gender, biology, etc. So do you want to ban teaching science too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442885882.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>It's more like "instead of splitting a meal, let's get takeout from two different places and eat in the park"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442968423.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's more like "instead of splitting a meal, let's get takeout from two different places and eat in the park"

No, it's not, because this leads to worse outcomes for everybody.  Kids need to be at school practically speaking a certain amount of time while parents work.  Where will the extracurricular time to learn literature and cultures and the like practically come from?  What will the kids and parents have to sacrifice to teach it to them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442989339.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Establishing those private institutions will create jobs, where parents can be employed, funded from vouches that redirect funds currently being spent on that same education in public schools.

Seems feasible to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443034683.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>You are talking money.  I am talking about time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443058199.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>The kids will spend time they currently spend in Social Studies in public school

... at Social Studies at a private institution of their parents' choosing

... funded by vouchers

... equivalent to the cost of running a social studies classroom (for example)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443108152.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Wait...but what about all the science and engineering courses and financial literacy, reading, writing, woodshop, metalshop, cooking, and music?  How do those fit into the time?  It sounded like you went "here are the things schools should teach instead"?

Also...you never mentioned vouchers before here...they weren't mentioned in your post.  Where did they come from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443144538.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it.

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it.

\^ I took it for granted in this section. I'll revise to clarify, above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443162639.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>What?  you wrote what you quoted?  You literally aren't making sense there.

Let me ask this: why even have public school to teach science, tech engineering and math at that point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443171515.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>So they can work in industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443182059.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Oh!  so you view schools as a pipeline to a job, not a way to get an education?

Do you agree an educated population is better than an uneducated population?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443209925.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I think both the individual and society are served by having well-rounded education.

I don't think public school is the only way to deliver that well-rounded education.

Just as people learn about philosophy / morality / the purpose of life by way of their religious institutions (but we don't try to deliver that education via public schools), so too can we shift how we deliver education on other divisive issues.

So goes my CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443235178.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Cool, so what stops people who want the different curriculums from doing home schooling or private schools now that the ONLY solution is to completely upend the public school system?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443274594.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>What's so special about industry that the entire school system should be based on it? What about being able to function in society?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443366845.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Why not just spend time watching Amazon Warehouse training videos? The idea that public education just exists to create employees for megacorps is fucking baffling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444798931.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What percentage of parents know enough about history and literature to competently teach it to someone who doesn’t? Your View is completely unrealistic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443731101.0" user="breckenridgeback" delta="False">
    <text>This really just boils down to the conservative argument "don't teach my kids the facts if they conflict with my religious beliefs".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443748224.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't accurate.

Because the same argument applies in the other direction, as I indicated in the edit to my OP: 

&gt;(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.  
&gt;  
&gt;  
(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

Those are two examples where non-religious people argue "don't teach my kids your religious beliefs"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444811504.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>ha you had to change the quote because otherwise you couldn’t prove the commenter inaccurate. Did you think we wouldnt notice?

There’s a big difference between  "don't teach my kids the facts if they conflict with my religious beliefs"  and "don't teach my kids your religious beliefs"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443303056.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>What is the point of that? Vouchers are also based on public funds, so students would still be using public funds to get their social sciences education, with the added inconvenience of having to go to a different location for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442991847.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What will the kids and parents have to sacrifice to teach it to them?

I sincerely don't know what this means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443021973.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>There is only 24 hours in a day.

Part of that the kids are at school, and the parents are at work.

Part of that the kids and parents are sleeping.

Part of that, the kids are getting ready for school/eating/etc.

The remaining amount of time is the time that kids do all their other things.  They participate in sports/clubs/etc.  They get to play with friends.  They learn to be people.  They relax.  They spend quality time with the family.

So, what should parents sacrifice in order to teach kids geography, and other cultures and literature?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443036824.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying this is a bad idea because it will require parents to spend more time and energy and thoughtfulness on their children ?

Because I don't feel bad about that.  That would be good for children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443061669.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think that parents trying to indoctrinate their kids into their particular version of history will be in any way pleasant or meaningful interaction time for those children? 

I'm imagining that instead of watching a movie with my parents they were telling me about how the Civil War wasn't about slavery and black people were just entitled. I don't think that would improve anything at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443111108.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I think that is the purview of the parents. That's the whole point. If someone else wants to mis-educate their children, that's their business. I don't want them mis-educating my children. So let's agree to disagree and coexist in peace instead of have knock-down drag-out fights at every school board meeting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443148658.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>I'm simply disagreeing with your point that this change would be good for children. It would indeed give more freedom to the parents, but it would be a downgrade in the education of most children and also not provide any additional quality time as you suggested. We can see in the stats the kids who go through homeschool struggle in a lot of academic subjects, and that's with parents that signed up to teach their kids. I would hate to see the results with parents that are reluctantly forced to try and teach in their free time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443150792.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So let's agree to disagree and coexist in peace instead of have knock-down drag-out fights at every school board meeting.

Sure, send your kids to private school then.  That is an option, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444216613.0" user="Durthu_Oakheart" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I think that is the purview of the parents. That's the whole point. If someone else wants to mis-educate their children, that's their business.

Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444295986.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>It is outside the scope of this CMV to defend parents rights and responsibilities regarding education of their children</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444301635.0" user="Durthu_Oakheart" delta="False">
    <text>No it isn't. Justify your position, or just admit you're not posting in good faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444319510.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's how CMV works
 
If it were, I'd have to begin every CMV with an argument for Philosophical Realism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444786715.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>There will be no peace as long as conservatives like you are trying to prevent students from learning about history</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444815117.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>How can you say I'm trying to prevent students from learning about history.

My proposal is for every parent to get a voucher that they can use to send their kid to learn about history from whoever they want using whatever textbook and historic narrative they want.

I'm not preventing anyone from learning anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444909970.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; send their kid

In what vehicle?

UPDATE: Instead of answering, OP blocked me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443068604.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Please tell me, from the above list of things, what would you remove to make time for "teaching kids about literature"?

Would it be sports and clubs?  Would it be "interacting with other children?"  Would it be "time to relax" so children will be burning out?  Would it be "quality time with the family?  Would it be sleep?

What SPECIFICALLY would you want parents to go "dear child, you no longer have the time to do X, so I can teach you literature/geography" instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443373372.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Then why not end all schooling and mandate 100% homeschooling? Why does this argument not work for math or engineering?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444775021.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Are you saying

No, they asked you a question. Answer it. What should parents sacrifice in order to teach kids geography, and other cultures and literature?

UPDATE: Instead of answering, OP blocked me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42447562968.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>It'd take up the time and energy and thoughtfulness with them having to teach every subject that doesn't almost-exclusively rely on transmission of quantitative data to the left brain (even if they don't have a background in it/perhaps only learned it from their parents under this system) instead of, idk, doing things that'd legitimately help them bond with their children. Also abusive parents exist and this isn't going to make them be nice, imagine the worst teacher you've ever had was teaching at least half your curriculum themselves and you were legally bound to live under their roof</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443047738.0" user="dangerdee92" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;99% of English and History classes are regular, boring, and non-controversial. 

I'm from the UK and see alot of people today saying that schools are/were teaching history from a biased viewpoint (from the viewpoint that Britain was great) and ignoring the atrocities they committed.

Meanwhile when I was a school 15 or so years ago 99% of my history lessons was learning about farming practices in the 15th century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443789645.0" user="Jammy_get" delta="False">
    <text>This immediately triggered the words "crop rotation"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
