<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442890637.0" user="CheesecakeMedium8500" delta="False">
    <text>Teaching ABOUT a religion is not the same thing as partaking in that religion. It’s a horrible idea to suggest that people be less informed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442952575.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not suggesting that.

I'm saying people can learn things outside public schools</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442997574.0" user="CheesecakeMedium8500" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you are suggesting that. The entire point of public schooling is to set the baseline level of education for society. Saying “oh people can just learn it on their own” is a total cop out. They won’t. 

Walk down the street and poll how many people know about the Holocaust. Now ask those same people if they know about the indigenous genocide here in the US. Do you think they’ll know about it? Let alone that 10 times as many people were killed? 

No. The fact that Columbus Day only just had it’s named changed in federal observances demonstrates this perfectly. Public schools across the country taught that he was an explorer. They did not teach that he was a brutal slaver and a murderer. People largely didn’t “learn that on their own.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443021283.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>(1) People did learn things on their own *before* our modern public education system.

&amp;#x200B;

(2) The fact that people don't know things *today* is evidence *against our current system*; not an argument in favor of it.

&amp;#x200B;

What am I misunderstanding ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443094522.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The fact that people don't know things today is evidence against our current system; not an argument in favor of it.


It's an argument to teach MORE history, not less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443128000.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>This seems like a perpetual motion machine for doubling-down on failed programs, policies, and practices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443140289.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This seems like a perpetual motion machine for doubling-down on failed programs, policies, and practices.

Can you be more specific? 

&gt;People did learn things on their own before our modern public education system.


Do you know what the illiteracy rate was back then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443143305.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>Explain how, the point of history is to learn from it after all, if people are making the same mistakes as those made in history than perhaps we aren't teaching it well enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443160286.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Right. And doing more of what we're doing poorly won't make it better. Rather, we should do something different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443171120.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, so why isn't your solution to simply improve the class curriculums we currently have? We agree they aren't doing as good a job as they should be so lets make them better. Why have you instead jumped to a more costly, worse system that guarantees worse outcomes and is a logistical nightmare?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443193392.0" user="CheesecakeMedium8500" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; People did learn things on their own before our modern public education system.

Largely no. The general education level of society was abysmal compared to what it is now. Are you kidding me?

&gt; The fact that people don't know things today is evidence against our current system

Except your solution is to make that system **less robust and comprehensive**. That makes zero sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443009757.0" user="AlaDouche" delta="False">
    <text>And what about the people that can't? Public schools exist for everybody, from all walks of life, including those who may not have the time, money, or opportunity to do extra curricular learning. Don't assume your life is what everyone else experiences too.

Public schools teach what is generally accepted as the basic tools needed to have an opportunity to be successful. There's a wide range of subjects for two reasons: 1. Because not everyone has an affinity for the same things, and 2. Because we (as a people) *need* a diverse set of skills, even if it's involving something that you're not personally interested in.

Saying people can just learn whatever doesn't interest you outside of school is profoundly dismissive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443024090.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Vouchers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443040712.0" user="AlaDouche" delta="False">
    <text>What does that even mean? The government handing out free money for kids to learn things? Why go through all the extra loopholes and extra money to provide what could be provided in a public school?

The idea that the government should be spending more money to educate people outside of public schools so public schools can concentrate on specific things seems asinine. You're just talking about public schools with extra steps and more money from the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443220910.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'm not suggesting that.
&gt; 
&gt; 
&gt; 
&gt; I'm saying people can learn things outside public schools

You objectively are suggesting people be less informed.  By the nature of your proposal, you are suggesting that parents can choose to teach their children to be less informed or even misinformed.  This means that the general group of people will be less informed as a designed outcome of your policy change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443235513.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Our current education system has been in place for 60 years.

Do you think the population is well-educated *now ?*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443241472.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>More so than 60 years ago?  Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443311781.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I'm aware of no evidence for that conclusion. I suspect that is just a background assumption or belief. 

Can you propose some objective means of evaluating this claim ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443324088.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'm aware of no evidence for that conclusion. 

But you have evidence for the population is not well-educated?  I suspect that is just a background assumption or belief.

Can you propose some objective means of evaluating this claim ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443386656.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Touche. 

But this is "Change *My* View" - not "Share Your View and Invite Me to Change It". 

:-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443807840.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>So, you agree you don't have evidence the population is not well-educated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443836382.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>The view in my CMV is not dependent on whether or not (or how we measure whether or not) the population is "well-educated." 

I was merely responding to a premise underlying an argument put to me - but my original view in this CMV is not dependent upon this at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443854634.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Ok.  Cool, if it's not relevant to your view, I will raise the comment you responded to again, and hope for a relevant argument then.

&gt;You objectively are suggesting people be less informed. By the nature of your proposal, you are suggesting that parents can choose to teach their children to be less informed or even misinformed. This means that the general group of people will be less informed as a designed outcome of your policy change.

Does that mean you don't care how educated our kids are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443860323.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me this comment is intended to criticize rather than persuade. Am I misunderstanding your intent or missing some substance ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443903487.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, I literally am trying to find out your view.  You above said:

&gt;The view in my CMV is not dependent on whether or not (or how we measure whether or not) the population is "well-educated." 

So, I rewound our conversastion back to before YOU brought up how well-educated people are.  So I quoted the comment you replied to and asked a clarifying question in light of what you just said:

Do you care how educated our children are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443934510.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I do care.

But that would only be relevant to this CMV if I believed that (a) the current system of education is the only / best way to educate children; and/or (b) there is good reason to believe my proposed system would result in worse-educated children \~and\~ (c) that it would be so much worse that the gains in civility and domestic tranquility would not be worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443993392.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>OK.

&gt;You objectively are suggesting people be less informed. By the nature of your proposal, you are suggesting that parents can choose to teach their children to be less informed or even misinformed. This means that the general group of people will be less informed as a designed outcome of your policy change.

That settles B.

And for C) why do you think it would gain civility and domestic tranquility rather than protests by trying to implement your ideals with the stated goal to not allow kids to learn about LGBTQ+ stuff?  Isn't it more likely that you would be kicking a hornets nest?  Similarly, if you think it will solve the arguments about religion in school, why do you think the right won't rise up against it?

You said "science" is ok.  But evolution is a divisive concept.  Sex and gender are science.  Human biology is science.  Health is science.  You would still have these same debates, but under the label of "science" rather than "math".

Your solution results in worse outcomes for students by design (because nothing prevents parents from teaching extra information already) and doesn't actually even solve the part you want it to.  It just changes the the "subject name" the divisiveness is taught under.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443401934.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t know what metric you’re using, but 91.1% of Americans in 2021 had a high school degree. In 1960, only 41.1% did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443425006.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>That's just painting a bullseye around an arrow in the wall.

Making something legally required doesn't mean it's effective; it just means it's imposed by the state.

So I don't think that's a good metric.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443451023.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>Respectfully, no one can change your view if you want a certain metric to define “better-educated” but you refuse to say what that metric is. We can’t read your mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42445041315.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I don’t think that’s a good metric.

Because it proves you wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42445012138.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I suspect that is just a background assumption or belief.

*BZZZT!*  [Wrong again.](https://www.statista.com/statistics/184260/educational-attainment-in-the-us/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443294328.0" user="Holiday-Key3206" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry for the second response, but I just realized something:

This also is a different argument than your origional post.  You started with "the goal of this is to stop the divisiveness/fracture".  But now when people point out a flaw in the system is people will be less educated, you are arguing "people can learn things outside public schools"  And I "can" run a marathon.  With tons of effort and training.  That doesn't mean I will do so.  Essentially, this "do you think the population is well-educated *now*? argument is a call to "anything else is better" but really, you are proposing a system that specifically DOESN'T educate people and hope the parents will choose to teach them accurate information (or send them to a place where they will be taught accurate information).

You system, by it's design, causes kids to be less well-educated.  Because you explicitly said elsewhere, you don't care if others choose to teach their kids bad information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444992923.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>In what setting? From who?

UPDATE: Instead of answering, OP blocked me</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
