<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442743117.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s very practical for students to at the minimum take a government class so they know how the government functions. That’s an important part of having a politically literate voting base</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442835507.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Mmmm... but how can we do that without a culture war ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442882991.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Culture war is inevitable. There’s culture war about evolution and climate change. The goal is to have better informed voters</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442896554.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Why is that preferable to people understanding how laws, regulation and control of their daily lives are developed? You can discuss the functions of government without "culture wars".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442963048.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>But you can't have that discussion without getting into how they *should* be developed. So now we're into political theories and ideologies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443050638.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you can? Describing the literal functions of branches, their make up and roles is apolitical in the sense of that is how it is and how it works. Whether or not something should be that way isn't what the class is. 

I think those things SHOULD be discussed but that isn't what a government/civics class is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443085551.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Uhhmm ... I'm not sure. I gotta think about this more before I'm into delta territory; but I'm on the fence about it ...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442950066.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Why is avoiding a "culture war" desirable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442979145.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>Because I'd rather live in a society with (a) domestic tranquility; and (b) I'd rather not have to battle my ideological opponents over which of our mutually-exclusive paradigms will serve as the framework for the education of my own children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443022991.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Parents can homeschool or find a ideologically compatible private school if they want their kids to only learn certain things. I don't recommend trying to keep kids from learning things but it's definitely an option. 

Otherwise they can, y'know, let the school teach what they teach and then actually talk to their kids and tell them what they believe and not believe and what they think the school gets wrong. Let the kid learn critical thinking skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443044934.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Parents can homeschool or find a ideologically compatible private school if they want their kids to only learn certain things.

This is exactly what I'm proposing *with regard to culturally divisive subject matters*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443057708.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>But people can already do that. Why would your idea be an improvement?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443100368.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>No - right now, it's all or nothing. Either go to public school with all the idealogical baggage; or go to private school / homeschool.

I DO think public schools should provide a basic education - just not on divisive ideological issues.

But I also want my kids to learn about philosophy, history, culture, etc.

So that has to happen somewhere. I should get to pick where / how based on my criteria. The government is already taking my money to do that now; I just want that money back (e.g. a voucher) so I can spend it how I want to spend it to get the services I want - without someone else's religion / philosophy / view on history to be taught to my children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443131272.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;just not on divisive ideological issues.

Why not? I mean it isn't as if they're getting super deep into philosophy but I don't see the issue here, also what are some examples of "divisive ideological issues" to you, I imagine what falls under that category will differ person to person (for example for some, evolution would fall under this).

&gt;But I also want my kids to learn about philosophy, history, culture, etc.

So wait where do you want these taught?

&gt;So that has to happen somewhere. I should get to pick where / how based on my criteria.

So where do you propose?

&gt;I just want that money back (e.g. a voucher) so I can spend it how I want to spend it to get the services I want - without someone else's religion / philosophy / view on history to be taught to my children.

Do you think there is no way to teach these subjects in an objective way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443166982.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>If you are a middle-class parent, you probably don't pay anything in taxes (effectively) after all the child tax credits and stuff. 

So actually I'm paying more for your kid's education than you are. 

Also, again, science is THE most divisive subject. How should that be handled?

&gt;without someone else's religion / philosophy / view on history to be taught to my children.

Can't you just teach your kids what you believe and tell them you think their teacher is wrong, instead of trying to keep them from being exposed to other ideas?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443187267.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you are a middle-class parent, you probably don't pay anything in taxes (effectively) after all the child tax credits and stuff.

Schools are funded from property taxes. I'm a homeowner. My taxes fund the school.

&gt;Can't you just teach your kids what you believe and tell them you think their teacher is wrong, instead of trying to keep them from being exposed to other ideas?

I'm very proactive about exposing my children to the existence of bad ideas in the world. It seems awfully inefficient for those bad ideas to be put forth as good ideas by publicly-funded teachers, however.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443280273.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Schools are funded from property taxes. I'm a homeowner. My taxes fund the school.

And you probably get enough federal refunds/credits to offset some of that at least. 

&gt;I'm very proactive about exposing my children to the existence of bad ideas in the world. It seems awfully inefficient for those bad ideas to be put forth as good ideas by publicly-funded teachers, however.

Good, sounds like your kids are getting a well-rounded education. 

That is generally considered the best way to teach a large number of people at once. And clearly at least some parents agree with what the schools teach, or don't disagree enough to teach their kids otherwise. 

Why do you think necessitating the creation of dozens of little supplemental programs would be more efficient?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443328723.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That is generally considered the best way to teach a large number of people at once. And clearly at least some parents agree with what the schools teach, or don't disagree enough to teach their kids otherwise.

I think parents are painted into a corner - partially in reality and partially in their minds. They are trapped in a two-income / single-parent mindset and situation that makes it exceedingly difficult to exercise their options outside of public schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443358030.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. . .do you think having the option of possibly dozens of unaccredited out-of-school programs would make them pay more attention to that, or would they just pick the one closest to their house?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443048249.0" user="Independent_Sea_836" delta="False">
    <text>Teaching kids the difference between the House and Senate isn't going to cause a culture war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443343516.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn’t your argument also apply to evolution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443450739.0" user="Regular-Chapter-7101" delta="False">
    <text>You cant because one side (the conservative republicans who now want to raise the voting age) doesn't want the younger generations to know a lot about politics or voting so they'll create controversy around it. 

Just like how simple education on the facts segregation are now being attacked by conservatives because knowing that segregation existed 50 years ago leads to a greater likelihood that people believe systemic racism is still a modern day issue.

You know the field of history isn't just opinions. Saying gay people exist and can live happy functioning lives isn't an opinion. Sex education isn't an opinion, purity culture and teaching abstinence objectively leads to more teen pregnancies, STDs, rapes, etc. 

Lack of education is taking a political side, its taking the conservative political side. If people really think that racism ended after slavery or when martin luther king said "I had a dream" then you are prepping a young population to be more hostile to civil rights. If you take away education about gay people in our heteronormative society, younger generations are more likely to view gay people as strange and outsiders and are more likely to be hostile to them. 

The culture war over education exists SPECIFICALLY because conservative politicians want to sway more people onto their side of the culture war.

Your opinion isn't centrist or moderate infact it lines up exactly with what conservatives. 

Also supressing education in an attempt to decrease misinformation has to be the most contradictory thing i've heard all day. 

And also if your going to use the term "marketplace of ideas" know its termed that way because it will act like a marketplace. With less regulation, there is a higher chance you'll have monopolies that do well not because they are inherently better but because they have other things that give them an advantage. And those monopolies stop other ideas from spreading. Especially if you have an uneducated population who can't use history to think critically about society today.

Your theory of better ideas winning out would only work if we weren't a deeply irrational, emotional, and bias species. But sadly we aren't robots thinking entirely rationally.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
