<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2359291511.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/130nszb/cmv_public_schools_should_only_teach_science/">
    <title>CMV: Public Schools should ONLY teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) { USA }</title>
    <original_poster>Mr-Homemaker</original_poster>
    <original_post>**BACKGROUND - SEPARATION OF CHURCH AND STATE**: 

Public schools cannot endorse or promote any particular religious belief or practice, and must remain neutral on matters of religion.

In practical terms, this means that public schools cannot require or lead students in prayer, display religious symbols or materials, or promote any particular religious belief in the classroom. While public schools may teach about religion as part of a secular education, they must do so in an objective and neutral manner that does not endorse or promote any particular religious belief.

The rationale behind this is to protect religious freedom and prevent the government from imposing or favoring any particular religious belief or practice over others. It also recognizes that religion is a deeply personal and individual choice that should not be influenced or coerced by the government.

Overall, the separation of church and state is an important principle in the United States, and the Establishment Clause ensures that public schools remain neutral on matters of religion and respect the diverse beliefs and backgrounds of all students.

**APPLYING LOGIC TO HISTORY, CULTURAL STUDIES, AND LITERATURE:**

Given the increasing divisiveness in American society around history, cultural studies, and literature, it would be much cleaner and less contentious if we just agreed to pull those issues out of public curriculum as well.  

Parents - and whatever private institutions they want for their children - can teach children about history, culture, and literature with the time and money that public schools don't have to take up on it. (e.g. via vouchers)

Sure, there would be echo chambers and disinformation; but, the marketplace of ideas would eventually iron-out those wrinkles. Just as we can't legislate morality, neither can we legislate open-mindedness or critical thinking.  But that doesn't mean we can't have those things in society - it just means legislation and battles over curriculum isn't the place for it.

All the culture wars in the classroom are simply distracting from educational outcomes we actually want. And they aren't resulting in greater empathy or civil discourse - if anything, quite the opposite.

Certainly, there will be some equity issues (e.g. not all families or communities will have as much time or money to educate their children as others), but that isn't a sufficient reason to support the status quo, because *the system we have now suffers from those problems, too.*

&amp;#x200B;

**TLDR**: It seems that our society is becoming increasingly fractured and divisive.  I have a growing suspicion that the actual friction that results isn't because we don't see the world the same way - it's that we are fighting over whose view of the world will be taught in schools. So let's stop arguing about it and get on with our lives.

!delta

Ok. We'll teach spelling, grammar, etc.

But not literature

!delta

OH - good one - financial literacy deserves an honorable mention under the heading of math

....

Also OK: woodshop/metalshop/autoshop, cooking, music.....?

...

!delta
You're right - music is back OUT

//

Edit - examples of problems my proposed solution would make irrelevant: 

(1) LGBTQ+ Rights: The rights of LGBTQ+ students in public schools have been a controversial topic for years, with some individuals arguing that these students should be protected from discrimination, while others believe that promoting LGBTQ+ ideology in schools conflicts with their personal beliefs.

(2) Prayer in School: The debate over prayer in public schools has been ongoing for decades, with some individuals arguing that prayer is a fundamental part of their religious beliefs and should be allowed in schools, while others believe that public schools should be a secular space that is free from any religious influence or coercion.

(3) Texas Ten Commandments Law: The Texas legislature passed a law that allowed the Ten Commandments to be displayed in public schools and government buildings. This law sparked controversy, with some arguing that it violated the separation of church and state and was therefore unconstitutional, while others believed that it was an appropriate way to recognize the role of religion in American history and culture.

(4) Critical Race Theory: The teaching of Critical Race Theory in public schools has sparked controversy, with some individuals arguing that it promotes a divisive narrative regarding race and racism, while others argue that it is essential for understanding systemic oppression.

(5) Sex Education: Sex education in schools has been a controversial topic for years, with some parents arguing that it is not appropriate for schools to teach such material, while others believe that it is essential for students to receive comprehensive sex education.

//

Several people have argued that although my position is neutral, it would benefit their ideological opponents; and,
(1) they don't want an ideologically-neutral outcome;
(2) that they want to win the culture war; and
(3) therefore they don't want to end (avoid) the culture war

While I recognize people may hold beliefs that it is a good thing to win the culture war and for their ideology to be imposed on others, I just want to be honest that this is not a persuasive approach to "Change My View" - as I am against using the state to impose ideology on others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42442922555.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I certainly understand your view, but I don't think the solution needs to be as drastic as all that.  

I believe that we can teach everything as long as we're calling it what it is, without an imposed bias of teaching any particular theory as fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42442972324.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>But it is increasingly common for people to believe that the theory they subscribe to ***is*** fact. Or, at least, they want to impose their theory on others whether it is fact or not. Naturally, other people feel symmetrically convicted and intransigent. Hence culture wars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443014808.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.  What I'm saying is that, if we're transforming education in a meaningful way, let's transform it in a way that allows ideas to be presented *without* allowing only one idea to be presented as fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443030036.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if that is even theoretically possible, much less feasible. 

Do you have any idea how that could be achieved ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443210366.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I'm an older redditor, but I honestly never knew how any teacher of mine felt on any particular topic.  They checked their biases at the door.  This continued on into college.  A common theme was "I'm not here to teach you what to think.  I'm here to teach you how to think." 

Information was just presented in an impartial way.  For instance, "this is generally accepted within the scientific community, but it's not without criticism.  Some notable arguments against this are xyz..."  Or "there are many schools of thought.  This is what each major view presents on the matter."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443222359.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>That's not how it's done anymore.

Somebody back me up, here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443245789.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I know it's not.  I'm saying it *should* be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443315123.0" user="Mr-Homemaker" delta="False">
    <text>I think the horse is out-the-barn.

Don't know how to get him back in here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443417512.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I think we need to define education.  If you're not willing to present an opposing view, you're not educating.  You're indoctrinating.  We need indoctrinators out of the classroom.  This has to happen at either the local level, or from the very top with the Dept of Education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443617818.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>To what point, though? Should they have to seriously consider Flat Earth as a legitimate opposing view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443781001.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I dont know that it actually needs to be presented, but if it came up as a question, there's no harm in acknowledging that, yes, there are people who believe that.  

In fact, acknowledging opposing views can encourage more research and discussion.  

Keep in mind that this would be in a science class, yes?  Presenting science as what it is, including the limitations, and presenting all science as *the scientific view*  would eliminate most of the problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443824930.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Schools ARE teaching the scientific view. But you said they should present all views.

Briefly discussing and dismissing Flat Earth as unscientific would not satisfy Flat Earthers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42443956065.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you're saying, but a science class is going to be based in science.  There's room for dissent in science.  There absolutely *must* be dissent.  

I never said that flat earth would have to be dismissed.  Flat earthers believe xyz.  Scientists believe xyz.  Imagine the classroom that allows these competing ideas to be explored! Who is going to learn more?  The classroom who is told that flat earth is just bullshit, or the class who gets to learn why they believe what they do, and why scientific consensus disagrees?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444005011.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I never said that flat earth would have to be dismissed.

And if the class comes to the conclusion that Flat Earth is correct, the teacher should be like "ok then, the textbooks are wrong, all future lessons will be based on Flat Earth beliefs"?

(Which, btw, includes the belief that space (and all associated things like stars and planets) does not exist)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444066769.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>Is science really concerned that it would play out that way?  

Again, science class would be teaching the scientific view.  There would be no throwing out of textbooks because the scientific view still exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444118674.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;science class would be teaching the scientific view. There would be no throwing out of textbooks because the scientific view still exists.

That's what they do now.

That does not satisfy the people who want their opposing view to be seriously considered. 

When you say that opposing views should be considered, that means they have to be treated as equals. Not considered then dismissed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444335127.0" user="ReindeerNegative4180" delta="False">
    <text>OP was specifically talking about keeping STEM and getting rid of everything else.  Im not sure how this devolved into specifically science, which OP already wanted to keep.  Anyway...

A science class teaches science.  There's no requirement to believe the science, or there shouldn't be, anyway. You simply learn what science presents.  You learn what scientists believe to be true.  You learn what has been observed and how they came to the conclusions they did.  You learn why these things have been accepted as fact.  If a question arises about flat earth, then fine.  Consider it.  What does science have to say on the matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42444367121.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>OP is saying all controversial subjects should be privatized, and many have pointed out that science is really more controversial than any other subject. 

&gt;Consider it. What does science have to say on the matter?

Ok, but you should know that's not what people mean when they say that opposing viewpoints should be presented.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
