<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2363991100.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/133gj7g/cmv_the_government_should_tax_companies_that/">
    <title>CMV: The government should tax companies that replace human employees with AI and AI-controlled production and service more, to subsidize people who suffered from that.</title>
    <original_poster>OutcastZD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was inspired by a scenario prevalent in much sci-fi literature: people are subjugated by an artificial-super intelligence system and don’t have any opportunity but to waste their lives. I think it’s Jordan Peterson who said: if there’s no way out of a dilemma, we have to prevent it from happening in the first place. So maybe we should start regulating AI in a general manner and gradually establish a system where humans are the priority and take the initiative before it’s out of reach. If it’s somewhat irrelevant to reality, consider its mild form as huge tech companies are invading privacy to feed the algorithms databases, and the government is already incompetent at this. As a whole, the development of technology will be slowed,(but not too much as top companies have the incentive and funds to innovate, and will have more as inequality in society increases), but we will be better off in the long run.

And in recent days, the economy and unemployment rate is quite bad, and the redistribution may do some good to it. The taxation may somehow hurt the companies and the economy, but it’s mainly the large corporations that will pay the taxes(there should be a tiered taxation policy; small companies will have to pay little taxes), yet the benefits to the economy(employment and better market) may outweigh the costs.

It will require multinational cooperation to ensure its enforcement; still, there may be a practicality problem. But I hope you can provide some other convincing reasons to CMV. Many initiatives to protect the environment are not carried out, but we should still believe in and devote ourselves to environmental protection.

This may seem to be some anti-science stuff, but trust me, I’m the opposite of that kind of person. Been thinking about the Skynet type of thing since I was 7 or 8, and finally came out with some solution 

Edit: I forgot to edit this but I have changed my view. It’s so basically impossible to define what company uses AI and what don’t as it’s so prevalent in today. And AI is far from self-aware that kind of stuff nowadays, so it’s still a tool. Thanks for discussing and supplying information</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42464021002.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
