<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2363991100.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/133gj7g/cmv_the_government_should_tax_companies_that/">
    <title>CMV: The government should tax companies that replace human employees with AI and AI-controlled production and service more, to subsidize people who suffered from that.</title>
    <original_poster>OutcastZD</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was inspired by a scenario prevalent in much sci-fi literature: people are subjugated by an artificial-super intelligence system and don’t have any opportunity but to waste their lives. I think it’s Jordan Peterson who said: if there’s no way out of a dilemma, we have to prevent it from happening in the first place. So maybe we should start regulating AI in a general manner and gradually establish a system where humans are the priority and take the initiative before it’s out of reach. If it’s somewhat irrelevant to reality, consider its mild form as huge tech companies are invading privacy to feed the algorithms databases, and the government is already incompetent at this. As a whole, the development of technology will be slowed,(but not too much as top companies have the incentive and funds to innovate, and will have more as inequality in society increases), but we will be better off in the long run.

And in recent days, the economy and unemployment rate is quite bad, and the redistribution may do some good to it. The taxation may somehow hurt the companies and the economy, but it’s mainly the large corporations that will pay the taxes(there should be a tiered taxation policy; small companies will have to pay little taxes), yet the benefits to the economy(employment and better market) may outweigh the costs.

It will require multinational cooperation to ensure its enforcement; still, there may be a practicality problem. But I hope you can provide some other convincing reasons to CMV. Many initiatives to protect the environment are not carried out, but we should still believe in and devote ourselves to environmental protection.

This may seem to be some anti-science stuff, but trust me, I’m the opposite of that kind of person. Been thinking about the Skynet type of thing since I was 7 or 8, and finally came out with some solution 

Edit: I forgot to edit this but I have changed my view. It’s so basically impossible to define what company uses AI and what don’t as it’s so prevalent in today. And AI is far from self-aware that kind of stuff nowadays, so it’s still a tool. Thanks for discussing and supplying information</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477553448.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>Government should not interfere with any company because it usually generates negative effects in the short term and long terms.

Think this like Charlie and the Chocolate Factory, the father of Charlie worked in a tooth paste factory, he was replaced by a machine but at the end he was hired back to do the maintenance of the machine.

The AI is just like the machines from the Industrial Revolution, some jobs will end up being obsolete and new positions will be created, that's how the evolution of the society works. 

Back then, there were jobs that nowadays doesnt exists, when the light bulb was distributed in the society to illuminate cities, the lamp lighters lost their jobs. When the alarm clock was invented and popularized, the knocker-upper (the guy who knocked at your window at a certain time every day) also lost their jobs. When supermarkets grew, some door-to-door salesman like the milkman also lost their job. With the invention of fridges with freezers, the ice cutter lost his job. When the telephone appeared, the telegraphist was obsolete. The elevator operators lost their jobs when the elevators started to have buttons. And i can metions more jobs that today are obsolete.

And the society created new jobs, new positions, new challenges were created and the society didnt collapsed. We have light bulbs, fridges with ice machines, alarm clocks, smartphones and automatic elevators

But, if a government applies a tax for using a resource the company will shut down in that country and will move to another country that gives them better conditions and everybody working there will lose their jobs and no new positions were created so the unemployment raises, lowering the average wages because you can be replaced more easily because there are more people looking for a job(This is actually what is happening here in Argentina, the government is raising taxes to some businesses because of "solidarity" and the result was ending operations here and moving to somewhere else, these were Walmart, Nike, Adidas, Asics UnderArmor, MetLife, Dow, Axalta, 3M, HB Fuller, LATAM, Air New Zealand, Lactalis, Edding among other less know brands.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42479324665.0" user="OutcastZD" delta="False">
    <text>You made a quite a good point here, about the some jobs will be “obsolete” due to new technologies and the company will just move to elsewhere, causing mass unemployment. (I googled and didn’t find the “solidarity” in Argentina, maybe you can somehow elaborate that:)

But I wonder it’s too absolute to say the government shouldn’t intervene the market as it will prosper on its own. Some companies just became monopoly and prevented everyone from  developing and researching. It happened back then, it happens now. I think there is a lesson in game theory about this 

And in terms of obsolete, in the movie terminator, as the technology develops to a point, all humans became obsolete and were massacred by AI. In fact my intention of this post was to try to deal with this(before it’s too late), instead of addressing some social/economic issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42480927151.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But I wonder it’s too absolute to say the government shouldn’t intervene the market as it will prosper on its own.

That's basically the definition of Free Market, the spontaneous order of the society and markets, also known as "the invisible hand", a metaphore used by Adam Smith.

Countries that apply Free market policies are usually more richer and have better life conditions than the countries that apply more regulations and taxes or apply protectionism policies.



&gt;maybe you can somehow elaborate that

In the last 2 decades, governments here in Argentina tended to protectionist policies. They raised the taxes for any imported product but they also restricted some goods in order to protect the "national industries" and protect jobs from the competition, the results were terrible, most of the products here are more expensive than in the rest of the world with a questionable quality.

Not only that, when the actual government of Alberto Fernández won the elections, they created a new tax called "impuesto PAIS" (PAIS it stands for "for a more inclusive and solidary Argentina" in spanish)

It applied a tax and restrictions to the adquisition of any international currency (argentinian protect their savings in dollar generally because of the inestability of the Argentinian Peso, which has an anmual inflation rate around 100%)

That led to a parallel market of US dollars that costs 104% more than the official one, which is called Dollar Blue. And, due to the restrictions, it generated a shortage in absolutely everything, including raw materials that affected severily every production chain, leading to a shortage of even more stuff including the national manufacture and because of that it provoked a raise of the price in absolutely everything

Now, the average argentinian cant have any savings, the wages are crappy, small and medium business are going broke, big industries are leaving the country, the real unemployment is raising and we are in the middle of the biggest economic colapse of the argentinian history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481150444.0" user="OutcastZD" delta="False">
    <text>It reminds me of whenever I purchase video games, its always extremely cheap in Argentina region. I always wonder why. Thanks for the information</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481160742.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>Well... that's basically the reason, steam offers lowers prices there because, if they offered games with the real prices, they would loose a ton of potential buyer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481183880.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>And for foreign players, it's a really big discount. But because of them, steam is contemplating raising prices of games for Argentina, making it harder to buy a game if you use argentinian currency :/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481252198.0" user="OutcastZD" delta="False">
    <text>I hope they don’t, cuz that will be quite unfair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481272920.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>But, because of the "impuesto pais" as i explained it earlier, the real prices are even higher because of that tax and the VAT and other taxes, you basically pay 2 games for 1 game you actually get. So it's always something unfair...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481340456.0" user="OutcastZD" delta="False">
    <text>If the restrictions were so high and reasonable, won’t they have any election to change that? It’s a democracy I suppose? Or won’t there be any black market to bypass the rules? After hearing your case, it’s so shitty to have the country control everything. Maybe you can consider an immigration? Life isn’t about being taxed by the government. Anyway best of luck out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42481436342.0" user="PabloZocchi" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;won’t they have any election to change that? It’s a democracy I suppose?

We have, but we also have populism, socialism, adoctrination (so the people fear any other options), and  the government gives money (in subsidies) to the people and they say that "if you dont vote them, they will stop giving that money", and because of that, most of people are actually fanatics of a political party

&gt;Or won’t there be any black market to bypass the rules? 

It’s hard because of the equivant of the IRS, the AFIP and ARBA (yeah... we have 2 "IRS" here...) are very powerful and it controls any operation in international currencies or any transaction over the equivalent of 25USD in pesos

&gt;it’s so shitty to have the country control everything

That why i said that the government should not interfere at any level with the private market because it leads exacty to this. You don't want this

&gt;Maybe you can consider an immigration?

If i consider? I really want to get the fuck out of here as soon as possible, but resources are limited and i'm kinda stuck here for now

&gt;Life isn’t about being taxed by the government

I know... and it's fucking frustating</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42479346871.0" user="OutcastZD" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/134g9zp/one_of_the_creators_of_chatgpt_said_that_the/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;utm_name=ioscss&amp;utm_content=2&amp;utm_term=1</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
