<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43062730385.0" user="Alternative-Bid5540" delta="False">
    <text>I had this idea that lesbians look and act similarity when I was younger. Now I commonly meet lesbians and most of them are feminine looking. I only know a few that are masculine presenting. When feminine individuals tell me they are lesbian it doesn’t really surprise me or seem like a big deal to me. This same view led to me not realizing that I am actually bisexual despite looking feminine. I thought I had to look masculine to be attracted to women but then realized that sexuality is on a spectrum. 

I don’t have to have masculine traits to be attracted to women, and I can be attracted to both sexes. Sexuality is not always linked to gender expression. Some lesbians are nonbinary and do not have a clear gender expression. I have a friend that doesn’t shave or wear make up but also has feminine characteristics of wanting to dress girly, have long hair, and wear jewelry. She is a cisgender women that identifies as lesbian. I have been hit on by people numerous times that were feminine presenting. 

You may have assumed feminine individuals or lesbians could not be LGBTQ+ community by assuming they were straight, cis gendered, and binary. I am not sure what generation or area you are from. As someone in Gen Z being LGBTQ is not as uncommon, and I do not hold stereotypical views of lesbians or others a part of the queer community.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
