<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477845063.0" user="ScarySuit" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a lesbian. I was very femme when I was younger (long blonde hair, makeup, dresses, etc). Now I present fairly butch. I've always been a lesbian, my personal preferences changed. Maybe I'll swing back around to femme again in the future. 

When I presented as femme, almost no one thought I was a lesbian. I always got asked about my bf/husband. I think a mild part of why I'm leaning more butch now is to just try and stop people from asking if my wife and I are sisters...omg, I wish people would stop asking that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477895434.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry to hear that. You should speak to a therapist. Everyone deserves to be happy and present themselves as either masculine or feminine regardless of gender identity or sexual orientation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477962890.0" user="ScarySuit" delta="False">
    <text>Haha, there are way more pressing issues on the therapy list starting with a whole dossier on my conservative family's reaction to me being gay. 

Presenting as outwardly queer via dressing butch feels very validating actually. I hated feeling like no one saw me. I'm much happier now.

But my point is really that not even all butch presenting lesbians are always butch. And I was still a lesbian when I was femme. I know other femme lesbians. They are just harder to spot in the wild.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
