<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477033396.0" user="Rhundan" delta="False">
    <text>[https://ksassets.timeincuk.net/wp/uploads/sites/46/2017/07/femme-lesbian-relationship-5.jpg](https://ksassets.timeincuk.net/wp/uploads/sites/46/2017/07/femme-lesbian-relationship-5.jpg)

Feminine enough for you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477072702.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Who are the people in the photo? I need to know because if its from a movie, it wouldn't count.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477106671.0" user="ItIsICoachCal" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying the existence of one real life example of a conventially-attractive-to-hetero-men lesbian is enough to change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477147725.0" user="Rhundan" delta="False">
    <text>The picture is apparently from this article: [https://www.marieclaire.co.uk/life/sex-and-relationships/femme-lesbian-526255](https://www.marieclaire.co.uk/life/sex-and-relationships/femme-lesbian-526255)

So not from a movie, no.

This was from literally *5 seconds* of searching "femme lesbian" and going to the image section, btw.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
