<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477038799.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>The stereotypical lesbian couple is one butch lesbian and one femme lesbian. Most stereotypes are wrong in general but you don't even have the right stereotype. 

Anyway, yes, femme lesbians, or lipstick lesbians, or whatever term you want to use, definitely exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477673675.0" user="Lepany" delta="False">
    <text>How would you know a woman is gay if she isn't butch?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477712437.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>What if I told you that can be butch...and straight?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42478551118.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Examples? (No pressure. You don't have to link one if you feel pressured and don't want to.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42536189374.0" user="Mizo1987" delta="False">
    <text>Pink</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42539267698.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Pink isn't butch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42539815812.0" user="Mizo1987" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting to know what you consider butch.

Between the shaved hair, suit jackets, muscles and motorbikes, she's more butch than all of the women I know that actually date women. However, she does sometimes femme it up more than some women I know ever would. 

Do you think butch is more about the vibe than the appearance?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42539902706.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Its mainly appearance and some vibes too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42495883510.0" user="anakinmcfly" delta="False">
    <text>Usually because she has a wife or girlfriend

or because she says “I’m a lesbian”</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
