<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2374784829.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/139vvp9/cmv_it_shouldnt_be_illegal_to_speed_it_should_be/">
    <title>CMv: It shouldn't be illegal to speed; it should be impossible.</title>
    <original_poster>CaptainFunktastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I'll assume this is for the US only.

To wit. There is no reason for "speeding" to be a finable, or jailable offense, when through the use of common, cheap tech, it could be impossible. Every car with a function on board computer gets a gps tracker installed which connects directly to the tranny, throttle, and speedometer. When the legal speed limit is reached, it cuts fuel, engages a rev limiter, or prevents the tranny from allowing an increase in speed.

A counter to any possible arguments:

* "No one said you have to speed!" I don't have to be punished either.

* "It's not the roll of the government to control my vehicle!" It's not it's roll to punish you either.

* "What if there's an emergency!" Please, any law enforcement or judges in the comments correct me if I'm wrong, but no jurisdiction in the country recognizes "an emergency" as an excuse to speed.

* "What if I'm being chased by a *bad guy*?" Well, if neither of you can go faster than the other, than so what. Also, refer to my previous statement.

* "It's my car!" Sure, but that doesn't matter on public roads.

* "What if I want to take it on the track?" Than you have it classified as a race car, and can never drive it on the road.

* "People will tamper with and disable it!* Sure. If caught, they'll spend a few years in prison for destruction of government property.

* "Speed and horsepower are only marketing gimmicks." So, it's legal to market something I'm not legally allowed to use?

* There are a lot of smaller towns that simply can't survive without ticket revenue". If your city, town, village, community, or municipality can't survive without fucking with it's drivers, maybe it's destined to fail.

* What if I have a [insert classic car here] which doesn't have a computer?" Let's face it, the only time it ever leaves the garage is to go to car shows because you're too afraid of injuring it's potential resale value. Load it on a truck and tow it.

* "I paid half a million for this car!" Well, congrats, you paid half a mil to do 40 mph.

* "My car drives like shit below [X]mph" Well, good job on your shoddy maintenance or your piss poor tune.

* "We should be trusted to operate a motor vehicle responsibly at all times, that what testing and licensing are for." Okay. We're hairless monkies with the the same brains we've had for millennia. Trusting us to operate two tons of explosion powered steel, filled with toxic chemicals, at speeds no living organism was ever meant to travel is a terrible idea.

Please. Change my view.

Edit: View changed. Congrats all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42514411671.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"What if there's an emergency!" Please, any law enforcement or judges in the comments correct me if I'm wrong, but no jurisdiction in the country recognizes "an emergency" as an excuse to speed.

Maybe if you look beyond r/USdefaultism you would know it is actually legal in many countries to speed in case of emergency. It's rare and easily determined case for police and saves lives.

Personally I have driven over speed limit twice in my life and both cases destination was a hospital.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514469936.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>You've honestly ever spead twice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514478140.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Only twice (unless you count going maybe few miles over limit when taking over a car).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514493195.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>So twice intentionally, with some casual exceptions, are you American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514502341.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>No but why does that matter? I have lived in US for few years and even then I didn't speed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514518381.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>Speeding a bit on interstates, is kind of an American tradition/expectation.

Doesn't really matter just informs the perspective some.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514547932.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>It's expected everywhere I have lived/driven which is a lot. Lot of people have commented on that when I strictly refuse to speed. Or jaywalk. Or break any laws that people casually break.

I just feel that when breaking the law is expected there is either something terrible wrong with the law or with people's own morality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514618958.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I think that perspective is pretty fair.
I smoke pot, and through that my relationship with the state has always been iffy at best.
Since it's become recreational legal in my state, I've had a weird response where I'm now ridiculously law abiding.
It's fun, not having my existence be illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514760668.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>"Rules are meant for other not me"

Doesn't it suck when others break laws but you know when you can break them because you know better than others, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42515347254.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>The government dictating how I'm allowed to alter my own brain chemistry in a way that harms no one directly.
Seems like a needlessly intrusive invasion of privacy to me.

I try not to break laws, but live in America. Blowjobs are technically illegal in half of US states.

I like Bjs regardless of legal status.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517796868.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Doesn't it suck when others break laws but you know when you can break them because you know better than others, right?

There are laws that are categorically *not* enforced. In the state of Vermont, for example, it is illegal for a woman to get false teeth without permission from her husband. However, the law is explicitly not enforced, because it is obviously ridiculous.

Driving 20mph below the speed at which heavy traffic is moving is dangerous. Yes it is technically abiding by the law, but reasonable speeding (typically up to ~10mph above the limit if not more in some places) is generally not enforced in most places, unless you're doing it dangerously (i.e., not with the flow of traffic). 

It is perfectly fine, *safer* in fact, to just speed a little to avoid potentially *dying* or who knows, maybe even causing a pileup and killing many, many more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517762655.0" user="TheLandOfConfusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;No but why does that matter? I have lived in US for few years and even then I didn't speed.

Have you ever driven on a highway near a major US city? Like Chicago for example. The speed limit on I-90 is 60 if I'm not mistaken. Nevertheless every single lane is back-to-back traffic moving at 75+. A car going sub-60 would legitimately be a safety hazard</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
