<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2374784829.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/139vvp9/cmv_it_shouldnt_be_illegal_to_speed_it_should_be/">
    <title>CMv: It shouldn't be illegal to speed; it should be impossible.</title>
    <original_poster>CaptainFunktastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I'll assume this is for the US only.

To wit. There is no reason for "speeding" to be a finable, or jailable offense, when through the use of common, cheap tech, it could be impossible. Every car with a function on board computer gets a gps tracker installed which connects directly to the tranny, throttle, and speedometer. When the legal speed limit is reached, it cuts fuel, engages a rev limiter, or prevents the tranny from allowing an increase in speed.

A counter to any possible arguments:

* "No one said you have to speed!" I don't have to be punished either.

* "It's not the roll of the government to control my vehicle!" It's not it's roll to punish you either.

* "What if there's an emergency!" Please, any law enforcement or judges in the comments correct me if I'm wrong, but no jurisdiction in the country recognizes "an emergency" as an excuse to speed.

* "What if I'm being chased by a *bad guy*?" Well, if neither of you can go faster than the other, than so what. Also, refer to my previous statement.

* "It's my car!" Sure, but that doesn't matter on public roads.

* "What if I want to take it on the track?" Than you have it classified as a race car, and can never drive it on the road.

* "People will tamper with and disable it!* Sure. If caught, they'll spend a few years in prison for destruction of government property.

* "Speed and horsepower are only marketing gimmicks." So, it's legal to market something I'm not legally allowed to use?

* There are a lot of smaller towns that simply can't survive without ticket revenue". If your city, town, village, community, or municipality can't survive without fucking with it's drivers, maybe it's destined to fail.

* What if I have a [insert classic car here] which doesn't have a computer?" Let's face it, the only time it ever leaves the garage is to go to car shows because you're too afraid of injuring it's potential resale value. Load it on a truck and tow it.

* "I paid half a million for this car!" Well, congrats, you paid half a mil to do 40 mph.

* "My car drives like shit below [X]mph" Well, good job on your shoddy maintenance or your piss poor tune.

* "We should be trusted to operate a motor vehicle responsibly at all times, that what testing and licensing are for." Okay. We're hairless monkies with the the same brains we've had for millennia. Trusting us to operate two tons of explosion powered steel, filled with toxic chemicals, at speeds no living organism was ever meant to travel is a terrible idea.

Please. Change my view.

Edit: View changed. Congrats all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42514402406.0" user="cbdqs" delta="False">
    <text>When its hot out my GPS becomes less accurate and often times it shows I'm on the frontage road running parallel to the highway and not the highway itself this could very easily glitch between allowing me to go 30 mph when I'm supposed to go 70 and vice versa.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514441810.0" user="Kirstemis" delta="False">
    <text>Where would you be *supposed to* go 70? Speed limits aren't targets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514460970.0" user="CaptainFunktastic" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. Speed limits are the maximum speed you *can* go, not the minimum you *should* go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42515060739.0" user="Iceykitsune2" delta="False">
    <text>US highways also have a minimum speed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516222968.0" user="PM_ME_YOUR_NICE_EYES" delta="False">
    <text>From a design perspective that's incorrect. Typically roads are designed with the assumption that cars will be going the posted speed limit with the actual top safe speed of the road being a good 20-30mph over on highways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514471216.0" user="Rhundan" delta="False">
    <text>Uh, highways. Going too slow on the highway *is* a serious problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514475171.0" user="cbdqs" delta="False">
    <text>Speed limits are posted up to 85mph in the United States.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514496751.0" user="Kirstemis" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't mean you have to go that fast.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514504032.0" user="cbdqs" delta="False">
    <text>It's not illegal and OPs view is just to make it impossible to do what's illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516588062.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That doesn't mean you have to go that fast.

Honestly, if you want to be safe, you need to go with the flow of traffic. 

Speed differentials are really dangerous. The bigger the differential, the less reaction time people have to deal with it.

You should NOT be going 45mph on an interstate where traffic is flowing at 75mph. 

In my state, you can be ticketed for going *to slow* on some roads.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514483937.0" user="NaturalCarob5611" delta="False">
    <text>There are many highways with minimum speed limits around 45 and adjacent access roads at 25 - 30. It's not hard to imagine that your GPS mistakenly decides you're on the access road and slows you to a level that is not safe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514477480.0" user="Candid_Dream4110" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. And it would also struggle in rural areas where the GPS doesn't know what the speed limit is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
