<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2374784829.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/139vvp9/cmv_it_shouldnt_be_illegal_to_speed_it_should_be/">
    <title>CMv: It shouldn't be illegal to speed; it should be impossible.</title>
    <original_poster>CaptainFunktastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I'll assume this is for the US only.

To wit. There is no reason for "speeding" to be a finable, or jailable offense, when through the use of common, cheap tech, it could be impossible. Every car with a function on board computer gets a gps tracker installed which connects directly to the tranny, throttle, and speedometer. When the legal speed limit is reached, it cuts fuel, engages a rev limiter, or prevents the tranny from allowing an increase in speed.

A counter to any possible arguments:

* "No one said you have to speed!" I don't have to be punished either.

* "It's not the roll of the government to control my vehicle!" It's not it's roll to punish you either.

* "What if there's an emergency!" Please, any law enforcement or judges in the comments correct me if I'm wrong, but no jurisdiction in the country recognizes "an emergency" as an excuse to speed.

* "What if I'm being chased by a *bad guy*?" Well, if neither of you can go faster than the other, than so what. Also, refer to my previous statement.

* "It's my car!" Sure, but that doesn't matter on public roads.

* "What if I want to take it on the track?" Than you have it classified as a race car, and can never drive it on the road.

* "People will tamper with and disable it!* Sure. If caught, they'll spend a few years in prison for destruction of government property.

* "Speed and horsepower are only marketing gimmicks." So, it's legal to market something I'm not legally allowed to use?

* There are a lot of smaller towns that simply can't survive without ticket revenue". If your city, town, village, community, or municipality can't survive without fucking with it's drivers, maybe it's destined to fail.

* What if I have a [insert classic car here] which doesn't have a computer?" Let's face it, the only time it ever leaves the garage is to go to car shows because you're too afraid of injuring it's potential resale value. Load it on a truck and tow it.

* "I paid half a million for this car!" Well, congrats, you paid half a mil to do 40 mph.

* "My car drives like shit below [X]mph" Well, good job on your shoddy maintenance or your piss poor tune.

* "We should be trusted to operate a motor vehicle responsibly at all times, that what testing and licensing are for." Okay. We're hairless monkies with the the same brains we've had for millennia. Trusting us to operate two tons of explosion powered steel, filled with toxic chemicals, at speeds no living organism was ever meant to travel is a terrible idea.

Please. Change my view.

Edit: View changed. Congrats all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42515192013.0" user="Okinawapizzaparty" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with the premise that it should be impossible to speed, but I disagree with speed limiters idea.

It's a bandaid for the REAL issue: poor design.

It's OK to go 75 mph on a straight highway between cities. On the other hand in heavy residential neighborhood 20mph may be too much.

What we need to do is design roads that physically limits speeds WHERE appropriate.

No one would go over 15mph on this road:

https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5b/Crop_of_chicane.png/200px-Crop_of_chicane.png

This is exactly what we need. Chicanes, curb extensions. Narrowed lanes, continues sidewalks etc - to PHYSICALLY limit speeds as appropriate for purpose of the street/road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516168188.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think turning every road into a Mario Kart racetrack would improve safety, if you're willing to go that far, why not remove cars and roads entirely and replace them with Trains, Trams and Subways?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516226819.0" user="Okinawapizzaparty" delta="False">
    <text>Not every road.

Most streets in RESIDENTIAL neighborhoods.

And yes - it would 100% increase safety.

And yes, we should prioritize public transit (and biking), and close off many streets to car traffic.

However we should not get rid of car traffic entirely as there are still use cases where it's a valuable option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516384104.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>Case 1:  
Someone speeds down a straight road, they have good visibility, No one dies. Poor design.  


Case 2:  
Someone speeds down a slalom course, bashes a tree and the people crossing behind it, ramps off a series of speed bumps killing 12. Good design.

"No one would go over 15 mph on this obstacle course." Becomes "If someone goes over 15 mph on this obstacle course people will die.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516553742.0" user="Okinawapizzaparty" delta="False">
    <text>Basic statistics disagree with you. 

Overly straight roads in residential neighborhoods are super deadly while traffic calmed streets are not. 

https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.3141/1578-01

A contrived story that is unlikely to happen does not overrule statistics.

Fact remains - that 99.99999% of people will not go over 15mph on that road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517075795.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>Unfortunately, your source is behind a paywall, those must be pretty advanced statistics.  


I'm not saying straight roads are always better, I'm saying they're better then the picture you posted above, I don't need statistics to show that a downward sloped, unnaturally windy road with trees blocking visibility is a stupid idea. I'd honestly rather have OP's speed limiter then have roads purposefully made to be that ridiculous to drive on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517175733.0" user="Okinawapizzaparty" delta="False">
    <text>It's actually a great idea.

Low visibility, tree-lined, windy streets naturally cause drivers to drive super slowly 

Which is the point and works way better than some contrived speed limit.

Straight and wide highways that enourage fast driving should have no place in area where people actually live and hang out.

Again. Absolutely NO ONE is going over 15 mph there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517967859.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>People drive slower in fog,rain and snow too, that doesn't make the roads safer with those conditions. Add fog, rain and snow to your slalom course and it'll be worse.

All of this is costly and time consuming, it's like putting a brick on your toothbrush so you don't brush too fast, it's self defeating, If your toothbrush is causing damage then you need a new way to clean your teeth, tearing apart and rebuilding most residential areas is a large task especially considering some states barely maintain the roads they have.  


We'd save for more lives and resources by tearing up most of the parking lots and roads and focusing on public transport.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42516606858.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP - but to be fair, that is an extreme example of his point.

Engineers design roads for specific speeds. They know what features will cause people to speed up or slow down. 

Design the road for the speed you want and let human nature do the rest. 

Most of the time, when you try to ignore human nature - you fail miserably. Hence the fact 90+ percent of people driving on highways in my state exceed the posted speed limit by 5-15mph. There is no respect for something set arbitrarily wrong for what people actually do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42517143148.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with the premise, but, I think we're better off designing cities around people rather than around cars, If a road is so dangerous to pedestrians that an engineer has to fill it with obstacles then it might as well not be drivable. I'd rather the funding for tearing up and rebuilding roads to be safer go towards public transportation instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42519799741.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I agree with the premise, but, I think we're better off designing cities around people rather than around cars,

Except that ship sailed. Unless you plan to bulldoze significant parts of cities and start over - you work with what you have.

&gt; If a road is so dangerous to pedestrians that an engineer has to fill it with obstacles then it might as well not be drivable.

These are called STROADS. A 'Road' but being used as a 'STREET' and they are big problem.  

https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2018/3/1/whats-a-stroad-and-why-does-it-matter


&gt;I'd rather the funding for tearing up and rebuilding roads to be safer go towards public transportation instead.

Except public transit isn't viable in the overwhelming majority of the US by area. 

You are taking an exceptionally *urban centric* view and demanding it be forced on all of the *non-urban* areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42522141557.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Except that ship sailed. Unless you plan to bulldoze significant parts of cities and start over - you work with what you have.

It is a bit idealistic, but I think having so much of the land dedicated to massive parking lots and roads is wasteful.

&gt;These are called STROADS. A 'Road' but being used as a 'STREET' and they are big problem.

What I described looks nothing like a Stroad, you can clearly drive on a stroad.

&gt;Except public transit isn't viable in the overwhelming majority of the US by area.

I'm not suggesting every town have a subway system, I'd consider buses public transit.

&gt;You are taking an exceptionally urban centric view and demanding it be forced on all of the non-urban areas.

I'm not "demanding" anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42522575872.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It is a bit idealistic, but I think having so much of the land dedicated to massive parking lots and roads is wasteful.

And I think burning coal was a mistake. But that does not change reality of where we are today. 

You must work within reality if you actually want to change anything. 

&gt;What I described looks nothing like a Stroad, you can clearly drive on a stroad.

You are mixing messages here. What was shown (chicane styled street) was a direct response to the issue of STROADS. The goal to create streets that serve local traffic and don't evolve into arteries. 

&gt;I'm not suggesting every town have a subway system, I'd consider buses public transit.

You are ignoring **EVERY BIT OF THE COUNTRY THAT ISN'T A CITY** with this proposal. That is the point. Nowhere in this post did it say 'only in cities'.

Even many parts of cities lack the density to support public transit. 

&gt;I'm not "demanding" anything.

The CMV very much *is*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42523641005.0" user="00darkfox00" delta="False">
    <text>  
&gt;And I think burning coal was a mistake. But that does not change reality of where we are today.

Redesigning every residential road when most states can't even maintain the poorly designed ones they have is just as idealistic.

&gt;You are mixing messages here. What was shown (chicane styled street) was a direct response to the issue of STROADS. The goal to create streets that serve local traffic and don't evolve into arteries.  

A stroad from the video you posted looks massive, there's no way to transform something that massive into the chicane street while maintaining traffic throughput, you'd be turning a 3-4 lane road into a one lane, why not just divert traffic elsewhere?

&gt;You are ignoring EVERY BIT OF THE COUNTRY THAT ISN'T A CITY with this proposal. That is the point. Nowhere in this post did it say 'only in cities'.

How is this a response to what I said? You don't consider buses a form of public transit?

&gt;The CMV very much is.

And I disagree with it too, having less cars on the road is an alternate solution to redesigning our road system or putting speed limiters in every car.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
