<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42576615596.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty.

Any lawyer who defends someone without knowing if their client is innocent or guilty is terrible at their job and will lose the case. You can't successfully argue if you have no idea what's going on.

As far as your larger point, it's pretty weird to *just* blame lawyers. All major corporations are corrupt. There's not really a difference between the lawyers they retain and their receptionists. It's all dirty money. That's what capitalism is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576648068.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I don't only blame the lawyers. I also blame the corrupt corporations. I blame both</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576755543.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>A corporation is made of people. Unless you have this attitude for every single person who works there regardless of job, you're being inconsistent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576859905.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>No I'm not being inconsistent. The people who make decisions at a company are the people to blame. Not the assistants, receptionists, or janitors. They have no say in who the company sues</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577210824.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Lawyers are not all partners. They don't all get to make major law firm decisions like which cases to refuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577281399.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>But they do get to decide which law firm to work for. A lawyer should be more knowledgeable on the morality of a law firm they work for than the janitor.

Some janitors don't even speak English. Low level employees have less knowledge about a law firm than the lawyers themselves.

Janitors don't actively participate in suing innocent people. Lawyers do</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579011571.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>You're acting like law firms are like Krispy Kremes. There aren't *that* many to choose from. It's a skilled occupation. It's like you're upset at lawyers without actually understanding how their jobs work. The vast majority of what they do isn't these lawsuits you're upset about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576661284.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting point about receptionists. I don't blame receptionists for working for corrupt corporations because they aren't directly involved in suing innocent people. Lawyers are directly involved though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576775469.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>The argument that lawyers are evil for literally just doing their jobs is weird. Especially because I doubt you also blame the doctors of CEOs at these corporations for keeping them alive. Professionals do not spend hundreds of thousands of dollars on school and all that time training to just...refuse to work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576828267.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>But the lawyer's job is to sue innocent people. Lawyers are actively hurting innocent people for financial gain. 

I don't blame the doctors of CEOs because doctors aren't actively hurting innocent people.

People shouldn't become lawyers if they aren't willing to refuse cases they know will directly hurt innocent people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577201001.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Corporations don't hire different individual lawyers for every case. They keep a firm on retainer for all their cases and litigation issues. Plenty of which don't involve suing small businesses or individuals. An individual lawyer at a firm doesn't get to turn down cases without getting fired. A lawyer's job is to argue and win cases. Only lawyers who own their own firms get to decide which cases to take and refuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577249114.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>So some of the cases a lawyer works on are legitimate, fair cases and some are unfair cases.

If a lawyer is forced to take an unfair case, they should quit that law firm. There are law firms that don't bully innocent people, they just don't pay as much</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579002205.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Law school is *expensive*. It doesn't make good financial sense to run around quitting jobs and hoping another firm will hire despite the poor employment history. Lawyers need food and shelter just like everyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579288849.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579636325.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>*Anybody* can ruin an innocent person's life. Nobody knows what it's really like to be a lawyer until after they've already spent all that time and money getting qualified to be one. It's unreasonable to hold them to completely different standards than everyone else with a job. They're not lawmakers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579659816.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?

Or what about doctors or pilots?

Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42579698819.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Cops literally murder people everyday with no consequences. They're a terrible example. 

Lawyers *are* held to a code of ethics unlike other jobs. Anything with a license you can lose is like that in one way or another.

You're blaming lawyers for what judges actually do. All lawyers do is argue; judges (and sometimes juries) decide guilt or innocence and sentencing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
