<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42576510417.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you blaming the lawyers and not the companies? Those seem to be who you're actually mad at.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576551556.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I blame both. I blame the lawyers because they are helping these companies sue innocent people.

The lawyers could choose to work at a law firm that doesn't take cases from immoral companies. Those jobs pay less but wanting money isn't an excuse for suing innocent people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576723737.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>Even if this is true, your CMV is that "lawyers are immoral." The implication being that the profession is immoral. You say nothing about anyone who works in criminal law, for instance.

If your actual argument is that "some lawyers are immoral" well then good luck finding more than a couple of professions where that isn't the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576735587.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Good point, I'll change it to "some lawyers are immoral"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576765098.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>RIght, but again: How many professions do you think have zero immoral actors?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576784952.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't just say, "some lawyers are immoral" because that might imply I'm talking about individual bad lawyers that use scummy tactics

When I say, "lawyers are immoral" I'm referring to groups of lawyers that work for immoral law firms. Their whole profession is immoral cause it's entirely based on suing innocent people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577752546.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>What is "innocent" in this context? If there's no case, or if its a frivolous lawsuit it will be thrown out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576965143.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>It is not a lawyers job to decide who is and isn't innocent, nor should it be, unless you want lawyers to refuse to defend people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577088680.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you. I don't want lawyers to refuse to defend people. I guess what I want is for lawyers to sometimes refuse to prosecute people.

Rich people sue poor people over bogus claims. The rich person can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to win because poor people can't afford to go to court. Rich people force poor people to settle because poor people don't have the resources to defend themselves

So I consider it the lawyer's job to not accept cases with bogus claims. The lawyers don't even have to make a moral decision, they just have to make a decision based on the law and refuse cases with bogus claims</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577203166.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe that anyone working for such a company is immoral? Even the janitorial staff?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577254700.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>No because they aren't directly involved in suing an innocent person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577355410.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>They're contributing to the business. What has suing got to do with anything? The lawyer and janitor are both cogs in the same machine. Why is one cog more immoral than any other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577379132.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Because if the janitor quits, the lawyers are still available so the law firm is still able to sue innocent people.

If the lawyer quits, the law firm can no longer sue innocent people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577396260.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't answer my question.

They both contribute to the same machine. As does any of the office workers, retail workers, miner etc depending on what company you're talking about. What makes any of them moral or immoral to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577402931.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>They both contribute, but the contribution is vastly different</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577409706.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, I'm not arguing they are contributing the same thing, but they are contributing TO the same thing, the company they work for.

So what makes one moral and the other immoral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577412399.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I'm done with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577430911.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>If you aren't able to answer the question I think that identifies a flaw in your thinking.

This is the wrong sub to "just be done with someone" as its not me you need to be concerned with, it's my argument. Either respond to the argument or don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577448981.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I responded to many of your comments and you weren't saying anything new</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577504887.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>I'm asking a simple question which you don't seem to be able to answer.

What makes the lawyer of Shell any more or less moral than their Oil Driller? The CEOs Secretary?

The roles are different but they are all contributing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577552823.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure about my opinions about oil. But to your point about a secretary. It depends on the secretary. If the secretary isn't directly involved in hurting someone then they aren't immoral. 

Working for an immoral person is different than actually doing immoral things</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577610631.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Working for an immoral person is different than actually doing immoral things

Howso? Buying from some brands is immoral - and that's on the consumer end of things! How is working for an evil company not an evil act?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577670539.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that buying from some brands is immoral. I don't think the customer should be expected to know if the company is doing evil things.

That's a way of companies shifting blame to consumers and you are foolish to fall for that. 

I already answered your other question</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577731383.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Ignorance of evil doesn't absolve you of wrongdoing.

If you buy some cosmetic that was tested on animals for example you are directly contributing to animal cruelty.

&gt;That's a way of companies shifting blame to consumers and you are foolish to fall for that.

Perhaps I am taking responsibility for my role in the world, while you are avoiding yours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577782744.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>This is a common argument in recent years. Boycotts don't work very well. It's better to hold companies responsible.

Do you expect people to research the food they're buying before going to the grocery store?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577831859.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>One way to hold a company responsible is to not give them money.

&gt;Do you expect people to research the food they're buying before going to the grocery store?

You don't make a shopping list?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577857857.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I don't always make a shopping list. If I want lettuce and tomatoes, how would I know if the workers who picked the tomatoes are treated fairly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577865955.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Fair trade logo if it has a sticker, or place of origin if it's in a package. If buying locally you can talk to the tradesman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577944857.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>It's not the customer's responsibility. Why can't the grocery store research where their food comes from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42578005877.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>Why make the store responsible for the customer? Would you prefer for your shops to decide who they stock based on their personal morality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42578049019.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577410038.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>And I did answer your question. Wtf</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577436366.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't. I specifically asked about what it is that makes one contributor to immorality moral and another immoral. They are both contributing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
