<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42575875890.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>Your problem is with the law. The law states that if someone doesn’t aggressively defend their patent or trademark, they lose it. So they have to defend it.

Also, legal or moral advice from a TV show isn’t advisable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576113448.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>So you're on the side of patent trolls?

And I'm not taking legal or moral advice from a TV show. I just mentioned that TV show cause that's what got me thinking about this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576127094.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>There isn’t a “side”, there is an objective reality. Businesses protect their brand through patents and trademarks, and need to legally defend those claims to keep them active. 

For that matter, it’s absolutely necessary to have patents and trademarks. What’s the point of making something if it can get ripped off</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576147864.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>But patent trolls aren't suing people who are ripping them off. Monster Energy Drink was not being ripped off by the restaurant that used the word monster on their sign. Or the video game that used the word monster</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576163108.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not how the law works. If you allow another entity to use your name or branding, OTHER companies can and will then infringe on your trademark, and use the fact that you allowed “Mom and Pop Monster shop” to use your trademark, and therefore lost exclusivity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576210235.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think it's fair that a video game can't use the word monster?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576248283.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>Didn’t the proposed Monster settlement agreement allow them to keep the name, but it came with restrictions to their branding and design to prevent any crossover between the brands?

And honestly, yea I do, if the use of that word can be construed to infringe on their brands likeness. How would you like it if you were the owner of Burger King, and all of a sudden every restaurant could market their burger as “The Whopper”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576409927.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you about Burger King but I think that's different from Monster. The word monster is much more common than the word whopper. And whopper is specific to a burger.

I think it's ok for Monster to sue an energy drink that uses the word monster but not a video game</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576416839.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>And that’s fine, but it’s a lawsuit, not a foregone conclusion. Monster can sue and lose, which I honestly think they might do in this case</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42580998016.0" user="JustDoItPeople" delta="False">
    <text>Also, for what it’s worth, it’s better for Monster to sue and lose than to not aggressively defend the trademark under the current law</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576258196.0" user="Velocity_LP" delta="False">
    <text>They still can use the word monster. Anyone can sue for anything and demand anything to settle, doesn't mean they'll win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576423312.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Right, Monster won't win the lawsuit. But Monster doesn't need to win, they just need to use their greater resources to force the other side to settle</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576276668.0" user="Wolfaxe451" delta="False">
    <text>I think they'll likely lose because their trademark likely doesn't extend to video games. And the court can grant the fee shifting provisions to have Monster pay for the legal fees of both sides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42581999871.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>Dude has no idea what Monster actually sent the video game company because what they sent is completely enforceable. They said that they couldn't use the Monster "M" symbol, couldn't use the Monster font, they couldn't use the word Monster over a green and black background, and that they couldn't market non-video game merchandise with just the word Monster on it (though the entire title of the game is fine).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42581995267.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>Stop getting legal news from Kotaku. That's not at all what Monster said the indie company couldn't do. 

They said that they couldn't use the Monster "M" symbol, they couldn't use the word Monster over a green and black background, and that they couldn't market non-video game merchandise with just the word Monster on it (though the entire title of the game is fine).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577714117.0" user="twotime" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; That’s not how the law works. If you allow another entity to use your name or branding, OTHER companies can and will then infringe on your trademark, and use the fact that you allowed “Mom and Pop Monster shop” to use your trademark, and therefore lost exclusivity.

Totally wrong. It's well understood that identical English words can appear on different trademarks. At least when those are normal English words. 

"Monster Energy Drink" has no claim on either of the 3 words...

However, the core issue here is something else entirely: at least in US being right does not mean that much. Lawsuits are expensive and even when  a defendant win it almost certainly will not be compensated. That allows to use the legal system for extortion purposes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577739142.0" user="AULock1" delta="False">
    <text>And they’re not saying they have total control over those words. However if they can articulate that another brands usage of those words or their logo could in some way impact their own brand, they can sue for trademark violation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576425774.0" user="BIGFATLOAD6969" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have pictures of the restaurant/video game? I’d bet quite a lot that the similarities extend beyond the word “monster”. Because there’s “mini monster cafe” “snow monster cafe” and hundreds of other business that use the term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576551624.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So you're on the side of patent trolls?

What patent trolls?

You keep saying that but neither the OP nor any comment I've seen mentions anything at all to do with patents.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
