<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42577750592.0" user="twotime" delta="False">
    <text>No, the core issue is not the lawyers and not the corporation. The core issue is US legal system which is

A. INSANELY complicated and fairly unpredictable
B. crazily expensive
C. a defendant winning against a meritless lawsuit will not be compensated in most situations</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577813933.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>I agree the core issue is the legal system. But wow, you say, "not the corporation"

The corporation is the one making the decision to sue innocent people. Just because they are legally allowed doesn't mean they aren't immoral</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
