<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42576608496.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Lawyers and the concept of lawyers in general are the most ethical and moral things we do.

Everyone is entitled to the full protection of the law. It does not matter if it is civil or criminal law. We need professional, trained adovocates to ensure all parties are treated fairly under the law. 

Yea - lawyers get a scummy reputation, some of which is un-earned, because they are the advocates for the worst of society and their job is to literally advocate for the best interests of people/companies society may wish to condemn.

Why is this important. It is really very simple.

If our justice system is based on public opinion and we deny those most accused of being bad the resources, tools, expertise to defend themselves in the court of law, then we really don't have a fair judicial system at all. We have kangaroo courts masquerading as justice.

Are the US courts perfect? Heavens no but the system around it is actually pretty sound.

I would also challenge you to understand TV shows are not reality. They are fiction. They don't represent the real world very well. I would also caution you to be so judgmental as a layperson on company behaivor as well. You wish to jump straight to the conclusion Monster is in the wrong. How do you know? Do you actually understand the legal nuances? Do you know the legal arguments and controlling statutes and regulations? Do you understand the hurdles in lawsuits to demonstrate standing and harm? Or are you buying into a popular narrative that 'sounds good'? 

It's popular fiction you can simply sue anyone for any reason. There are several barriers to this - from filing fees and requiring representation (which an attorney can be disbarred for frivolous lawsuits) to requirements for standing. You aren't going to walk into a law firm and have them file a lawsuit without having cause.

If a court finds your claims frivolous, not only the plaintiff but also plaintiff's counsel can be held to pay costs, damages etc. Exact rules vary from jurisdiction to jurisdiction.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
