<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2387429574.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/13hewg6/cmv_lawyers_are_immoral/">
    <title>CMV: Lawyers are immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Distinct-Yogurt9276</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit3: Some lawyers are immoral

Lawyers that represent corrupt corporations are immoral. These lawyers work for big companies and help them sue innocent smaller companies. The most obvious example of this are patent trolls. Another example, Monster Energy Drink is a trademark troll. Lawyers who work for Monster Energy Drink are immoral. Monster Energy Drink has sued a restaurant for using the word monster on their signs. They also sued a video game titled Dark Deception: Monsters &amp; Mortals.

I consider these types of lawyers different from lawyers who defend violent criminals. It's not immoral to defend a violent criminal because you can't be sure if the defendant is innocent or guilty. It IS immoral to work for a company like Monster Energy Drink because everyone knows Monster Energy Drink is in the wrong, they shouldn't be allowed to sue people just for using the word monster.

I've been watching How I Met Your Mother. In season 3 Marshall is deciding between working for the NRDC (Natural Resources Defense Council) or working for a law firm that represents corrupt companies that pollute the environment. The NRDC pays much less money than the other law firm. I don't judge people who choose money over saving the environment, but I do judge people who actively help to destroy the environment. It's ok if Marshall chooses a higher paying job than the NRDC, but not if that higher paying job involves working for corrupt companies.


Edit: Another example of immoral lawyers:

Wealthy companies will sue poor companies with a bogus claim. The wealthy company can't win the lawsuit, but they don't need to. They just need to force the poor companies to pay for lawyers until they're bankrupt


Edit2: I blame both the corrupt corporations and the lawyers. I'm not only blaming lawyers


Edit4: Imagine you are a poor person being sued by a rich person over a bogus claim. You're forced to settle because you can't afford to go to court. Are you upset with the lawyers who are suing you? Or just upset with the rich person who hired the lawyers?


Edit5: Lawyers should not blindly work for the highest bidder. Lawyers can ruin innocent people's lives. Needing money is not an excuse to hurt an innocent person.

Someone said that's it's unreasonable to hold lawyers to completely different standards than everyone else with a job.

Is it unreasonable to hold cops to completely different standards than everyone else with a job?
Or what about doctors or pilots?
Lawyers have the power to ruin lives.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42575841513.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>If we replace the term "corrupt companies" with "companies that do things I personally disagree with" do you think it seems reasonable? Because other than companies doing things you don't like you haven't said anything that makes them corrupt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42575906305.0" user="NameUnavail" delta="False">
    <text>I mean the "things I don't like" stuff that companies do tend to be things like "use slave labour" or "sue people who give them bad publicity". It's not exactly a moral grey area</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42575961210.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>You've just said some stuff you don't like, suing people who slander you seems fine to me so I guess we just disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576002751.0" user="NameUnavail" delta="False">
    <text>Google SLAPP suits. 

Companies really don't tend to care if the bad PR is slander, or just truthful reporting. They'll just sue regardless, because you probably don't have the money to fight it, so you'll just settle even is you weren't actually doing anything wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576074434.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>Sure the rules and enforcement around SLAPPs should be increased but most lawyers for companies are never involved in anything like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42575971127.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Or we could use the examples OP provided of lawsuits over patents and trademarks. That is the view actually being addressed here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576016375.0" user="NameUnavail" delta="False">
    <text>Trying to sue someone for using the word "Monster" isn't exactly ethical either.


It's ridiculous to believe you can copyright a common word, and monster energy is clearly just trying to bully others by using what effectively amounts to a flavour of SLAPP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576077351.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576132109.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>They are playing by the rules. But if we agree that those rules are wrong, then it is immoral for lawyers to use those rules to sue innocent people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576158113.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>If we agreed that protecting trademarks was immoral, then we would agree that protecting trademarks was immoral. I agree with that. I don't agree that protecting trademarks marks is immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576196569.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>In this case protecting trade marks is immoral. Do you think it's fair that a video game can't use the word monster?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576267630.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>I already responded to basically the same question in this specific thread of comments. It is the one where I said it was worthy of ridicule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42612800610.0" user="Medianmodeactivate" delta="False">
    <text>Not if we agree we need some rules, and rules cannot be replaced easily. An immoral system is sometimes far better than the alternative of anarchy. In the meantime the need for lawyers means lawyers are not immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42580739836.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42581005746.0" user="JustDoItPeople" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not a copyright, it’s a trademark! They have to be defended aggressively or they risk losing it. Copyright is something that you can assert at any point over its life, trademarks have to be actively defended but are indefinite.

In many cases it's better to sue something tenuously related to your trademark and lose than to not defend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576087662.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Right. Good examples. Any case that isn't a moral grey area</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42576074782.0" user="Distinct-Yogurt9276" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe corrupt was the wrong word to use. But I did mention patent trolls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42577121791.0" user="Presentalbion" delta="False">
    <text>If you want a lawyer to advocate for you at any point you would want them to give 100% even if they personally don't like you or agree with you on something. Lawyers ought to not to become personal crusaders but should advocate for all of their clients equally and regardless of personal preference.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
