<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="239105883.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ycva3/cmv_marriage_is_not_hard_work/">
    <title>CMV: Marriage is not hard work</title>
    <original_poster>Lorenzo_Brandy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have been married for five years. We have one child together. We rarely argue and never fight. I don't feel like this is the result of the kind of concerted effort that certain people state is necessary for maintaining a marriage. Rather, we were very much in love from the outset and have therefore cultivated habits of being together easily. We also have put our marriage at the center of our lives (as opposed to, say, careers), which we were more than happy to do. We of course have had hard times, but neither of us have had rhe sense that these threatened the marriage in any way. It seems like a popular trope that marriage is hard, sometimes unpleasant endeavor and I get a little bent out of shape about it because it's not descriptive of my experience and I feel like it doesn't have to be that way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28198045691.0" user="ryancarp3" delta="False">
    <text>So how could I change your view, which is entirely based on your own marriage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198060665.0" user="Lorenzo_Brandy" delta="False">
    <text>It's hard to get an insight into someone else's experience, but I'm willing to try. I realize that I'm giving a pretty insular jumping off point, but I'm not close-minded. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198066767.0" user="ryancarp3" delta="False">
    <text>OK. When you say "marriage is not hard work," do you mean that having a happy marriage is easy, or do you mean that the work required to get a happy marriage is not unpleasant or especially difficult? Because I'm fairly sure forming a good relationship took work, even if you don't think that work was unpleasant or hard to do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198069394.0" user="Lorenzo_Brandy" delta="False">
    <text>The latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198089153.0" user="ryancarp3" delta="False">
    <text>OK, that's what I thought. In that case, I think I understand why it was easy for you but is often difficult for others: priorities.

&amp;gt; We also have put our marriage at the center of our lives (as opposed to, say, careers), which we were more than happy to do.

For me, this is a big reason as to why it wasn't hard for you to cultivate a strong relationship: you made it your #1 priority. Lots of people don't, and that's when things can go south quickly. For example, if you put your job ahead of your relationship on the priority totem pole, it would likely be difficult for you to take time to, say, put aside time at night to spend time with her instead of working on your next big project. She would then get upset with you for caring about work more than her, which would likely start a fight and lead to both of you going to bed angry. Eventually, she may resent your devotion to your job and may break up with you over it. Since y'all put your relationship first, other things didn't get in the way.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198096540.0" user="Lorenzo_Brandy" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with all if this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198833841.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>There are more sympathetic (and frankly "treacherous") reasons than "putting your career first" (which sounds selfish).

Let's say you have children.  Let's say one of those children has medical or psychological issues.  It's *incredibly* easy to slightly reprioritize things to indirectly put that child first (both parents), and before long the relationship seems tense and broken, and it doesn't *feel* like anybody did anything wrong.  Before long resentments are appearing that seem to have nothing to do with the child, or are only indirectly related.  

1. Why didn't she pick up the house this afternoon?  She **knows** I had to take the kid to the doctor today and wouldn't have time.  

2. Why doesn't she ever initiate sex?  (She's thinking she's dead tired from dealing with the kid's problems, so sleep sounds more important than sex).

3. Why doesn't she help with homework?  She **knows** that I get frustrated with this kid (maybe it's ADHD), and she always leaves it to me to help.  (She's thinking:  I don't know how to handle this kid's outbursts and inability to stay focused on school work, and hubby always seems to manage to get through it.)

And of course this is where the trope that "communication is key" comes in, but once you've got those kinds of external pressures on a marriage, it doesn't take much of a miscommunication to turn into a fight, and it doesn't take much of a fight to start thinking about leaving.

You can also substitute parents for children in the above situation.  Maybe a parent is elderly and becoming progressively more dependent on one of the people in the marriage.  This is in theory easier to identify, but still no less problematic.

Likewise you can have issues with family members putting external pressure on an otherwise healthy marriage.  The trope about a manipulative/terrible mother-in-law has a basis in reality for many couples.

I think there are many other examples like the ones above that contribute to the idea that "marriage is hard", and if the OP hasn't yet experienced at least one or two of these "life lessons" in five years, she's extremely lucky (many, if not most of them are somewhat outside of the couple's control).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
