<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="239105883.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ycva3/cmv_marriage_is_not_hard_work/">
    <title>CMV: Marriage is not hard work</title>
    <original_poster>Lorenzo_Brandy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have been married for five years. We have one child together. We rarely argue and never fight. I don't feel like this is the result of the kind of concerted effort that certain people state is necessary for maintaining a marriage. Rather, we were very much in love from the outset and have therefore cultivated habits of being together easily. We also have put our marriage at the center of our lives (as opposed to, say, careers), which we were more than happy to do. We of course have had hard times, but neither of us have had rhe sense that these threatened the marriage in any way. It seems like a popular trope that marriage is hard, sometimes unpleasant endeavor and I get a little bent out of shape about it because it's not descriptive of my experience and I feel like it doesn't have to be that way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28198102620.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>To help you try to make sense of what folks mean when they say "marriage is hard work", I'd like to dispel the notion that hard work is necessary bad or unpleasant. Because I would say the things you describe which enable your successful marriage (putting it ahead of your careers, cultivating habits, etc...) *are* hard work. But you love each other, so you enjoy doing it. Imagine anyone that has a difficult job, but still enjoys doing it. Of course it's hard work, but that never causes them to doubt their path or regret their choices. That's how I would imagine your marriage. It's like a hard job that seems easy because you both love it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198112883.0" user="Lorenzo_Brandy" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. Delta-worthy, but /u/oversoul00 beat you to the punch!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198117404.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>I saw that! So close :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28198332714.0" user="phcullen" delta="False">
    <text>You can award multiple deltas,  deltas are awards for well made arguments. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
