<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901804871.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Equality means everybody has the opportunity to use the stairs. Equity means we build ramps and elevators so everybody can get to where they need to go. 

So you're going to have to explain why equity is bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901821606.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Ramps and elevators are equality of opportunity. Not equality of outcomes.

Equity doesn't care about opportunity or how people got there. They look at any discrepancy in outcomes as evidence that there is no equality of opportunity. Which glosses past the fact that some people are more talented and harder working than others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901850351.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Ramps and elevators are equality of opportunity. Not equality of outcomes.

Not according to Libertarians.

And not by the technical definition either. 

&gt;They look at any discrepancy in outcomes as evidence that there is no equality of opportunity

That's a pretty good assumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901929998.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;&gt;Ramps and elevators are equality of opportunity. Not equality of outcomes.

&gt;Not according to Libertarians.

Libertarians oppose the concept of elevators and ramps? I think your confusing them with anarcho-primitivists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901937372.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, they oppose requiring them. 

If a business owner, out of the kindness of their heart, wishes to provide one, that's fine with them.

I figure most Libertarians would prefer the business owner charge to use them, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901973002.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are conflating their YIMBYism with being against any building codes. Libertarians tend to be strongly against the kind of regulations that are used to constrain building supply to keep housing prices up, like parking minimums, banning non single family homes, and spending three years studying the impact of the shadow of the house, etc. but I'm yet to hear one IRL be against the ADA or fire codes. I'm sure there are lots of crazy people on the internet, but I'd lump in views that bizarre and extreme with anarchism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902077357.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>I think opposing the ADA is a fundamental tenet of Libertarianism. 

https://ca.lp.org/issue/discrimination/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902115354.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>The website of the Californian libertarian party? So like ten guys? The internet is not a good place to go to find political takes that reflect real life, it’s dominated by niche interests and hyperbole. If it wasn’t, Bernie would have won in a landslide in 2016.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902141263.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Well I'm not going to scour the entire site for mentions of the ADA, but the Libertarian Party's actual platform says "We believe that government’s only responsibility, if any, should be protecting people from force and fraud." Hard for it to be any clearer than that.


https://www.lp.org/about/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903438159.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to separate libertarianism as a philosophy from Libertarianism the political party.

There are reasonable reasons to oppose portions of the ADA. 

https://www.dol.gov/agencies/odep/program-areas/employers/accommodations

I see many of these as reasonable. I can readily see the arguments for some of them such as providing interpreters or printing things in Braille as significant burdens and not actually 'reasonable accommodations'. 

I also see barriers to these in older existing structures. For instance, a business located in an older 'main street' building without an elevator. The costs to allow wheelchair access are not insignificant. These are the issues where the real world meets the idealistic concepts. 

I also have yet to meet a person who associates with the libertarian philosophy being against building and fire codes. They may be against closed scheme licensing programs (common in trades) but are not opposed the standards themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901940373.0" user="wynterin" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve usually heard equity described as equality of opportunity. Giving people the same opportunities they would otherwise be denied. It doesn’t mean you don’t have to work for it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901988571.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah the wording here is a bit ambigous.

I'm arguing for equality of opportunity.

Equity can sometimes mean that. But it can also mean "let's shoot for the same outcomes". Which to some people may seem as the same thing. But they are actually polar opposites of each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902076535.0" user="Thelmara" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Ramps and elevators are equality of opportunity. Not equality of outcomes.

Not at all.  They're absolutely equality of outcome - everybody gets up to the top of the stairs.  Stairs are equality of opportunity - everybody has the option to go up them however they can, some people are just more talented or harder working than others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902153960.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>If the goal is to just get up the stairs sure.

But usually those things exist in places like schools. Where people can have the opportunity to get educated. 

Or places like government offices. So that people have access to government benefits and other government functions. 

If getting up the stairs was part of the merit. Then perhaps those ramps would be inappropriate. I don't want a physically handicapped fire fighter. We sort of need those guys to move around.

But if the stairs are just an obstacle and have little to do with their actual merit. Then of course ramps and all that is a good idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901851290.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>You’re going to have to d a slightly better job with your analogies.

Equality means equal access to the means to better oneself. 

Equity means equal outcomes, independent of merit or work put in.

Your analogy is suggestive of mental handicaps that cannot be overcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901869952.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>This is an actual example used by Libertarians to explain the difference between equality and equity.

&gt;Equality means equal access to the means to better oneself. 

Yes. That means everybody has the opportunity to climb the stairs. It doesn't matter that some people can't do it---they have the opportunity to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902012349.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>I have not heard that analogy from libertarians, only from liberals.

Libertarian philosophy tends to believe people are fundamentally not equal in merit even if every conceivable obstacle was removed.

Some people are not the sharpest knives in the drawer and will not be rocket scientists no matter how much education you offer them.

Some of the wheelchair bound will not start in the NBA, no matter how many ramps you build.

Liberals tend to have a more optimistic view of people’s aptitude and think of them as much closer in merit if only the obstacles were removed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
