<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902044777.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>I think there's a bit of a strawman here, in that OP says that those advocating equity want something like "Everyone makes 100k a year no matter what they do or how hard they work." Outside of extreme communistic groups I've never heard anything like that.

What people want equity for is reasonably priced healthcare, education, housing, and a social safety net that protects citizens from having their lives ruined by situations in which they had no control (getting sick, being born poor, being born a minority, and so on).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902101352.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>My bad I didn’t really flesh out what I was trying to say as well as I should have. I know it’s not something with a super simple answer there’s much more nuance. I wasn’t meaning to say it’s horrible across the board in every instance I was mostly talking about situations where qualifications or abilities are a big factor and ignoring those for diversity and representation rather than the actual quality of the person. I’d argue however that in our society today being born a minority is actually an advantage rather than a disadvantage because of all the affirmative action and diversity quotas companies have to reach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902139047.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>"in our society today being born a minority is actually an advantage rather than a disadvantage because of all the affirmative action and diversity quotas companies have to reach."

That is an incredibly bad take my friend. Oh my goodness.

You're imaging a world where a middle class white kid and a poor minority kid are both looking for the same jobs, applying to the same schools, and the minority is so "lucky" because they can get in due to diversity hiring practices.

This conception isn't reality though. The truth is the minority student is much more likely to have a life in which the basic opportunities never come in the way the white middle class kid gets them. The poor minority has a razor thin margin of error in their life, they don't have relatives who can help them out if something goes wrong, and they grow up in communities that are dealing with huge socioeconomic issues that essentially make it like they're playing life on hard mode.

You might think this is bleeding heart liberal talk, but I've lived in those kinds of places and it just grinds you down.

To extend the video game analogy, let's say there's a prize for the first person to beat Doom. One player is set to casual mode, one to ultra hard. What's the big deal? They both have equal opportunities to play, right?

Would you be cool playing on ultra hard against someone on casual? Does that seem like a good way to run a video game championship?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902250300.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>You’re assuming that the minority is poor and the white person is not what if you flipped it and a wealthy Asian kid vs a poor white is the Asian kid still dealing with a razor thin margin of error? 

There’s a real problem though that’s holding these communities back and until it’s solved no amount of programs, resources or government assistance will solve and that’s the destruction of the family unit. For whatever reason we don’t talk about this enough and as a society we don’t treat it as important as it is and it’s absolutely crucial to help people grow up and become successful. We need to promote family and healthy relationships try and reduce divorce and stop thinking about everything so selfishly and strengthen the family unit. 2 dads 2 moms 1 mom 1 dad it doesn’t really matter the difference in numbers from a family with both parents compared to single parents is crazy. I’d argue though that for boys specifically that 2 dads or 1 mom and 1 dad may be better than 2 moms just for the strong male influence I think it’s critical for young boys/men to have. That’s a whole different topic though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902339970.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;There’s a real problem though that’s holding these communities back . . .

I have a couple of friends who are bankers. They happen to be black.   


Both have had guns pulled on them by cops. That has never happened to me.   


Both are pulled over probably once a year on average. I'm nearly 60 and have never been pulled over.   


We live in similar neighborhoods. I've ridden with them, they drive similarly to me. I know them well, and how they interact with people, there's nothing I can imagine them doing that would warrant having a gun being pointed at them.   


Whatever communal problems these demographics may or may not have, they are compounded massively by a system that makes people in these demographics live a very stressed life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902744790.0" user="ulsterloyalistfurry" delta="False">
    <text>60 years old and you've never been pulled over once?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902777858.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>Nearly 60, and not once.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42926562247.0" user="ulsterloyalistfurry" delta="False">
    <text>So in around 40 or so years of driving you have never sped, had a light out, or had a vehicle out of registration?

In 20 years of driving I've been pulled at least five times and I'm white.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42927528004.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>Never once. And I drive a great deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42927752418.0" user="ulsterloyalistfurry" delta="False">
    <text>Then you have the world's best fortune.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42930097481.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. I know lots of people who have never been pulled over, or the last time they were pulled over they were much younger and were actually breaking  law when it happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905576740.0" user="OfTheAtom" delta="False">
    <text>There are some bad situations but I've managed to live my 26 years as a black man without much trouble. Being short is probably more stressful than bring black.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905762365.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>There are people who are black who never have a bad run in with the cops. They likely live in a less segregated and less racially charged city than I do. However, plenty of both academic and anecdotal evidence suggests that being in a couple of specific minority groups in the USA places one at a much higher risk of having a negative interaction with the police. As well as more likely to have a host of other negative interactions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906090276.0" user="OfTheAtom" delta="False">
    <text>So it's about where we grow up that seems to matter a lot? Perhaps having it ingrained that the cops are a danger and will hurt you causes issues. I grew up like white people are taught, just stay calm and do what they say. 

Not to mention right now as a black man The social consequences for harassing me are worse for a cop than harassing white people. 

I'm not saying I have not heard a story or two of racist cops in the last 20 years. It happens. Cops should be held to a higher standard and met with critique. 

But the narrative of the left is overblown to be based around this monolith of being black. 

As we have covered, the neighborhood seems to be doing a lot of the necessary conditions for police harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902354000.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>It's not the obligation of others to protect you from the pitfalls of life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902394684.0" user="AllYouPeopleAre" delta="False">
    <text>I bet those same “others” would appreciate basic health needs if they encountered the pit falls of life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902431775.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care what they would appreciate. It's not my responsibility to provide for those I do not know or willingly wish to help. Exactly like I do not expect anyone else to assist me for anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902439041.0" user="AllYouPeopleAre" delta="False">
    <text>Do people deserve basic human rights? Should people have the bare minimum to survive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902458531.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>Health care isn't a human right. Social safety nets are not a human right. If something requires the labor of another person, it's not a right. If something requires another person's resources, it's not a right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902468532.0" user="AllYouPeopleAre" delta="False">
    <text>So anyone who can’t provide for themself doesn’t deserve to live?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902730137.0" user="dkinmn" delta="False">
    <text>That's their argument. Pretty gross!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902763438.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>That's what family and friends and charity are for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902960552.0" user="AllYouPeopleAre" delta="False">
    <text>So someone who can’t provide for themself and doesn’t have a support network deserves to die?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903760928.0" user="ChillingBaseDogs" delta="False">
    <text>Please go find a comment here that says they "deserve" to die.  Please do so.

*No one* has said that.  Now, they may die because they cannot care for themselves, or feed themselves - that's certainly true...  But that doesn't mean people are saying you deserve this or that this is good.  But it can still happen.

You have to *work* to survive.  If it's not in an office, it's doing something.  If that labor, or some other way to get paid to get food.

If you *dont* want to do that, fine.  Go live in the wild, but then you are *still* going to have to work to grow food, kill animals, store water and keep it fresh etc.

If you want to do that yourself instead of a typical job, then go right ahead - but the long and short of it is that you need to provide for yourself or expect to not make it in this world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905522827.0" user="AllYouPeopleAre" delta="False">
    <text>Both you and the other user are blatantly saying people who are unable to contribute shouldn’t be helped. What would happen in this world you are both advocating for to people who are physically or mentally unable to contribute?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902473630.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Health care isn't a human right. Social safety nets are not a human right.

Without them, you die. 

What DO you consider human rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902642246.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>The ability to acquire things that are required by every human as a biological matter in order to survive regardless of individual health circumstances.  In other words, food, water, and breathable air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902722770.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Often, social safety nets are necessary to acquire those things, at least in developed nations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902739727.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>Then they’re not natural rights.  They’re incidentally required things in the modern context in order to guarantee actual rights.  

But if a homeless person is capable of leaving a city and growing or even scavenging/hunting food, they are not being deprived of a natural right.  To be clear, I’m not saying that we should content ourselves with bare subsistence.  But that should be accurately framed as a desire to offer more than basic natural rights rather than an improper and inaccurate expansion of natural rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902789043.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>You just said that food and water are natural rights, make up your mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903703184.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>I did. There’s no inconsistency in my comments.  If you feel there is one, please quote the contradictory statements and explain how they are contradictory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903727262.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>All land belongs to someone. They aren't going to let some homeless person hunt or grow food on that land, or give them access to the water on their land.

So how would this homeless person obtain food and water?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903761838.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>That's right. ☝️ The rugged individualism thing might have worked in hunter gatherer days, but as soon as people live in a society your wants and needs will soon butt up against someone else's wants and needs. You could just kill the person but humans figure out pretty quick we get further when we share resources, knowledge, and expertise across many people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903762432.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment is a series of incidental assumptions that were already entirely addressed in my prior comments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903770280.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not do anything for other people unless it directly benefits you and your family /u/OpeningChipmunk1700 ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906583101.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>The answer to that question is completely irrelevant to any point I made.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902743176.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Health care isn't a human right. Social safety nets are not a human right.

&gt;Without them, you die. 

Really? So people just up and died before the 1950s because these things didn't exist? You are ridiculous. People lived for hundreds of thousands of years without  social security or Medicare. 

&gt;What DO you consider human rights?

On a high level, these are basically the only things that are actual rights:

-Pursuing what you find meaningful or expedient without interference from outside forces to the extent those actions do not cause direct and immediate harm to others

-Ownership of yourself and the fruits of your labor.

-the ability to use my property and resources as I see fit

-the ability to freely enter into contracts with others

-the ability to associate with those I wish and the ability to not associate with those I don't

-Defending myself, my name/reputation, and my family by whatever means necessary from those that would do us harm. 

-Similarly, defending my property from those that would wish to steal or damage it. 

Anything else, like expecting a social security check, is an entitlement. It's not a right. Government cannot give rights because rights don't come from governments. Rights are natural and inherent to the human condition. 

Said another way, if you were off in the wilderness by yourself, you wouldn't expect to have a doctor. You wouldn't expect anyone to just mail you a check because you are old or don't have a job. Because those things aren't rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902770178.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Really? So people just up and died before the 1950s because these things didn't exist?

Yes. What do YOU think happened to people who didn't get the health care or food they needed?

&gt;if you were off in the wilderness by yourself, you wouldn't expect to have a doctor

The wilderness does not recognize any of your rights. That's why we invented civilization and human rights.

Also, you have no rights if you're dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902803902.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That's why we invented civilization and human rights.

You missed the point completely, but I suppose I shouldn't expect anything less from a typical redditor. People didn't "invent" rights. Governments didn't invent them or create them or give them to you. They exist naturally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902881631.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>They don't. The wilderness does not afford you any rights at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902896176.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>You are fundamentally misunderstanding what a right is. Can I defend myself in a state of nature? Yes. Can I do whatever I find meaningful in a state of nature? Yes. Can I use my property/land as I see fit in a state of nature? Yes. Your rights are natural. They exist because humans exist and predate even the concept of government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902916917.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Can I use my property/land as I see fit in a state of nature?

If a herd of bison decided it was theirs, there wouldn't be anything you could do about it (unless you had a lot of other humans helping you, but that's not a natural thing). 

&gt;They exist because humans exist

Yeah that's what I'm saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903814329.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>By your logic, if all the land is owned by others, it's completely fine for someone to murder you and your family in your sleep as they strive for their own right to property and land. This kind of society is a mess for everyone. That's why over thousands of bloody years humans figured out we do a lot better when we work together and create social structures.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905312954.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, that doesn't follow from my logic AT ALL but you keep telling yourself that if it helps you sleep better at night</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902745539.0" user="jtrom1010" delta="False">
    <text>This is a sound argument absent private enterprise that's incentivized to do the opposite, particularly when it's not a function of a free market reality and it's a product of a complex corporate web that's made healthcare behave differently from other industries.

We can debate what's right on a blank slate forever but the reality is we have to solve for problems that exist already, that aren't favorable to free or highly regulated markets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902876208.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is people act as if markets that are intensely regulated are "free markets" and then beg for more regulation to solve the problem caused by being overregulated to begin with. Markets solve things far better than almost anyone today gives credit for. Case and point: laser eye surgery. This medical intervention became intensely cheap and affordable as a result of the entire industry being almost completely unregulated. Those running these operations had to advertise their costs up front, they had to compete with others, and they had to innovate to improve their product to differentiate. 

Markets are better than centrally planned "solutions" 100% of the time because centrally planned decisions have 1 single failure point. Markets allow for constant evolution to improve and arrive at an actual optimal place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902992742.0" user="jtrom1010" delta="False">
    <text>The crux of your argument is actually besides the point though, and given the lack of objective data either of us could use it's also a conjecture, if not an opinion.

My larger point is that healthcare exists outside the realm of typical industry, and there's a complex system that behaves uniquely that makes a usually simple approach moot.

There's a completely different kind of nuance to the lobbying, the interplay of insurance and government subsidies, all of it.  There's also the self evident importance of healthcare's crucial role over other forms of service based commerce.

All that is to say, I think the original CMV is flawed on the basis of reductive reasoning, as is approaching it wholly from the side of regulation vs deregulation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903828833.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Fly in the ointment is laser eye surgery is a nice "extra" to have. Completely optional, and able to be done at a time of your choosing. If you have a fast growing brain tumor that will kill you or are bleeding out from an accident, or are having a heart attack, you're in no position to shop around, and the health care provider has no incentive to reduce costs, because you either pay up or die.

Laser eye surgery is a really bad example for the point you're trying to make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903002876.0" user="Coooo8" delta="False">
    <text>Hope you don't ever get old and need social security or Medicare. Hope you don't use public roads or highways or water or sewage system. Hope your kids don't rely on public schools or public libraries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902658301.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It's not the obligation of others to protect you from the pitfalls of life.

Wouldn't this exact argument apply to removing property rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902704697.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>So, you wouldn't go to a hospital, then?

You want to abolish police?

You are against the rule of law itself?

"No man is an island entire of itself"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902741954.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>Thats literally what society exists to do. Its just that certain people have convinced themselves that theyre radical individualists as they drive down state maintained roads in cars that had mandatory safety tests to the store where someone else has made things they themselves aren't capable of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902991141.0" user="eloel-" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it is, that is the whole point of a social contract</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902997869.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>No, that is not part of what you typically call the social contract despite you progressives acting as if it is so you can justify the little tyrant inside you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903003026.0" user="eloel-" delta="False">
    <text>You regressives need to read better if tyranny is what you got from it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42912931571.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42912932476.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
