<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901978280.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Why is meritocratic distribution or resources inherently better than a more equal distribution? From a utilitarian POV, doesn't the more equal distribution raise average happiness more than the meritocratic distribution (since wealth has diminishing returns on happiness past a certain level)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902560056.0" user="CornSyrupMan" delta="False">
    <text>Utilitarianism is a sophomoric and dysfunctional philosophical framework</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902581468.0" user="Home--Builder" delta="False">
    <text>This is why you redistribute your paycheck every week to random people to spread the "happiness" ,right? Or are you one of the people advocating the happiness come from someone else's check?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902601681.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This is why you redistribute your paycheck every week to random people to spread the "happiness" ,right?

I call it taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903895133.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>I know right!? I thought that's what the person was actually trying to say at first. These libertarians are a wild bunch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913895757.0" user="Home--Builder" delta="False">
    <text>Not as wild as some lazy sack of shit that just wants to lay around all day but still expecting to have the same lifestyle as someone who busts their ass to EARN their way in life. This type of attitude the most entitled shit that people have ever come up with, but in your head you are still the victim, right? Just wait till the wheels really fall off society and you will see just how much tolerance people really have for putting up with you "victims".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914005580.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Like I said, you guys are wild! Just look at the vitriol and pent-up frustration in your post. Why are all you guys like this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914229575.0" user="Home--Builder" delta="False">
    <text>No, let's not turn this around onto me with middle school tactics . I'm not fooled by your attempt at playing the Uno reverse card. I am going to keep the focus on the parasite rhetoric.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914767378.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Wanting a functioning society with healthcare, education, and science based policy that helps the most people isn’t parasitic. I work, I pay taxes, but I can see it’s not just about how hard you work, and those at the top don’t work any harder than anyone else (and many who come from familial wealth don’t work at all).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903010431.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>Wealth does not have diminishing returns on life satisfaction. Read the whole study and not the headline pushed by progressives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903119807.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>[https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2016976118](https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2016976118)

Fig 1 shows that doubling money correlates with happiness by a similar proportion at all income levels, about 1.5 stnd dev. This means each individual dollar in income has diminishing returns on happiness. So the extra 240k of someone who is at the 480k+ bracket could be redistributed to take 5ish people from the 15k bracket to the 60k bracket. This would improve average wellbeing, if the happiness aligns with the typical happiness for that new income bracket.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903322815.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>There's two possible answers, I guess. One is that fairness is itself good. The other is that the incentive structure of meritocracy leads to more human flourishing than the incentive structure of redistribution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903377433.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;One is that fairness is itself good

Why do you consider fairness itself good?

&gt;The other is that the incentive structure of meritocracy leads to more human flourishing than the incentive structure of redistribution.

These arent binary things. You can have both structures in an economy. Meritocracy to create excess wealth, redistribution to ensure the whole of society benefits from that wealth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903409567.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why do you consider fairness itself good?

Cause I'm a great ape. I'm sure you've seen the chimp studies. We hate unfairness.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;These arent binary things. You can have both structures in an economy. Meritocracy to create excess wealth, redistribution to ensure the whole of society benefits from that wealth."

If you have both then they are in tension. If you do more of one you do less of the other. Equity people think we need more redistribution because we have the generate wealth portion more than taken care of. Equality people think we need more wealth because we don't have enough yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903528462.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Cause I'm a great ape. I'm sure you've seen the chimp studies. We hate unfairness.

I was hoping for an argument, not an appeal to nature. Chimps throw poop at each other, i think we are a little beyond that

&gt;If you have both then they are in tension. If you do more of one you do less of the other. Equity people think we need more redistribution because we have the generate wealth portion more than taken care of. Equality people think we need more wealth because we don't have enough yet.  


This doesn't sound like a bad thing. This just sounds like a reasonable discussion to have</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903577525.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I was hoping for an argument, not an appeal to nature. Chimps throw poop at each other, i think we are a little beyond that

Okay, would you be happier if my answer was "Because God says it was?"

I'm afraid there just aren't many answers to the question "Why is x good?" that don't boil down to "Because nature" or "because God," ya know? Ultimately it's one or the other.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;This doesn't sound like a bad thing. This just sounds like a reasonable discussion to have

So then you agree that society becoming more meritocratic might be better than it becoming more equitable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903616080.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I'm afraid there just aren't many answers to the question "Why is x good?" that don't boil down to "Because nature" or "because God," ya know? Ultimately it's one or the other.

Are you unfamiliar with the whole field of ethics? They definitely put a lot more thought into that. Aristotle for example argues that happiness is the ultimate good because it is the only thing we do for itself, as all other things can be reduced to "i do this to make myself happy" or "i do this to make others happy". This is a different type of argument whether or not you agree with the argument itself

&gt;So then you agree that society becoming more meritocratic might be better than it becoming more equitable?  


Sure, at least in the current economic system.  Do you agree to the reverse?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903638346.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Aristotle for example argues that happiness is the ultimate good because it is the only thing we do for itself,

Why is this good?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Sure, at least in the current economic system. Do you agree to the reverse?

Not only do I agree that the reverse *could* be true I think the reverse *is* true. But your rhetorical question of "Why is a meritocratic distribution better than an equitable one" has a **real answer**! As society trended more meritocratic out of the age of feudalism, it got ridiculously more wealthy, which was good!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903694734.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why is this good?

I dont feel like i can sufficently discribe this for you. Maybe go talk to a philosopher

&gt;Not only do I agree that the reverse could be true I think the reverse is true. But your rhetorical question of "Why is a meritocratic distribution better than an equitable one" has a real answer! As society trended more meritocratic out of the age of feudalism, it got ridiculously more wealthy, which was good!  


This is an answer to the actual question, not the reverse. I was asking if you thought more equity could ever be better than more meritocracy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903704954.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>Yes! I said yes! Not only that, I think more equity is *likely* to be better than more meritocracy right now!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903739254.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Oh i misunderstood, my bad. So you disagree with OP?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903769364.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>Relevantly to our discussion, I disagree with your argument that redistribution is good because of the diminishing marginal utility of money. More redistribution is, I believe, in fact good. But in other circumstances it might be bad. It would have been bad for the kings and lords of Europe to break up the major merchant estates of the 17th century in service of redistribution, for instance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903811661.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>I was assuming current contexts, considering that is what context the studies and discussion are in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903705851.0" user="TwirlySocrates" delta="False">
    <text>Because we need incentives to make resources/services available in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903747868.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Its a balancing game of course, but I am confident US could shift slightly more equitable without an economic collapse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42907265352.0" user="TwirlySocrates" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I agree. That's been proven repeatedly in many other countries. I believe in meritocracy - but it obviously cannot stand on its own. A capable worker who gets in a car accident no longer has economic merit because they can't work; but they obviously shouldn't be denied resources once they need it. Meritocracy also doesn't create equal opportunities for people of merit that are also impoverished. Etc etc.

Public heathcare and education, for example, should be a no-brainer for the US.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
