<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902400307.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices?

Because the latter group is extremely rare. Most people do well in life because they have good and/or well off educated parents and racial/gender privilege. That sucks for society as a whole because people who were born with less are usually much more resourceful. We consistently are led by the absolute worst people simply because of their privilege. Equity is the only thing that can get us out of this race to the bottom.

&gt;Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?

Hard work has literally never been the standard. There's zero motivation for anyone to work hard unless they're fighting to better a bad situation. That's why you see this generation job hopping and not giving a fck about company or career loyalty. 

Hell, some of the hardest jobs are the most poorly paid, for example teachers and firefighters. The more important a job is the worse those who do it are treated. I don't think anyone who was an 'essential' worker during covid (and survived to tell the story) is going to forget how they were expected to catch, work with and die from covid without a second thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903770033.0" user="Comfortable_Tart_297" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most people do well in life because they have good and/or well off educated parents and racial/gender privilege.

no they don't, they just acquire scarce skills

&gt;Hard work has literally never been the standard.

obviously, the standard is value relative to demand.

&gt;some of the hardest jobs are the most poorly paid, for example teachers and firefighters. 

they're paid above average, and a lot more people can be a teacher than a heart surgeon.

&gt;I don't think anyone who was an 'essential' worker during covid (and survived to tell the story) is going to forget how they were expected to catch, work with and die from covid without a second thought.

the alternative is letting the economy shut down and then everyone dies, so...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904159187.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;no they don't, they just acquire scarce skills

Such as...what exactly?

&gt;obviously, the standard is value relative to demand.

...which is why hard work isn't the standard. If you say hard work pays but only if you have a 'scarce' skill, that won't apply to most people and therefore most people have no incentive to work hard.

&gt;they're paid above average, and a lot more people can be a teacher than a heart surgeon

Neither one should be paid average. An education degree is specialized and requires quite a bit of training before you can actually be certified to teach. They're also expected to do quite a bit of work outside the classroom in terms of grading and lesson planning. Not to mention essentially parenting and buying classroom supplies out of their own pockets. All of this is why there is and will continue to be a massive teaching shortage. Our kids are years behind children in other nations at this point. It's embarrassing.

Firefighters are expected to be willing to *die* to save others. Average pay is insulting.

&gt;the alternative is letting the economy shut down and then everyone dies, so...

This is cute unless it's *you* being expected to die without proper consideration and hazard pay. In which case you say fck the economy and go into a new line of work. That's why we have shortages in every field that was treated this way from food service to nurses. It's a very stupid longterm strategy to treat people you literally need as disposable.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
