<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42905289577.0" user="AdroitTheorist" delta="False">
    <text>What a surprise this opinion was removed for "rule breaking". This is the 7th post in a row that has been recommended to me that was deleted before I could even read it. What good is this subreddit if every discussion is removed by mods?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906340519.0" user="Hammitch" delta="False">
    <text>They wish to keep it an echo chamber. They believe they’re on the right side of history, even though every piece of evidence suggests otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906568864.0" user="AdroitTheorist" delta="False">
    <text>It's a shame, I would've enjoyed reading some well written dissenting opinions but I'm not particularly inclined towards piecing together the discussion from only the side I disagree with. Not that this topic tends to inspire well written commentary when it's so embroiled with several obnoxious political ideologies hell bent on stifling any disagreement. From what I've seen the idea of equity over equality is that sometimes hard work *isn't* rewarded and that makes people very angry. It's an odd sense of entitlement from reality which, being an inanimate force, owes you absolutely nothing; neither society nor individuals owe anyone anything. Thankfully, we do have safeguards against the sea of troubles, for those that legitimately require help, but at some point (never to be determined at this rate⸮) we're treating a symptom of a problem rather than the problem itself by throwing 'aid' at it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906581172.0" user="Hammitch" delta="False">
    <text>Couldn’t agree more .</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
