<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901998745.0" user="Annual_Ad_1536" delta="False">
    <text>You have misunderstood what equity means. equity is synonymous with fairness:

&gt;equity noun (fairness): the situation in which everyone is treated fairly according to their needs and no group of people is given special treatment.

[https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/equity](https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/equity) 

Equality is a more general non normative term that refers to something being the same as something else. The purpose of equity is to achieve equality of opportunity, and hopefully equality of outcome. Making things as fair as possible by having mechanisms whereby people in wheelchairs can go places besides the bathroom, their house, and the hospital will go a long way towards that, much further than some "pull yourself up by your bootstraps" policy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
