<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901867068.0" user="Brainjacker" delta="False">
    <text>“Equality is giving everyone the same pair of shoes. Equity is giving everyone a pair of shoes that fits.”

In a neighborhood with most people living under the poverty line, equity might be subsidizing internet for students who otherwise wouldn’t have it. Should the same money be allocated to every neighborhood, everywhere (equality) when other students already have the access they need?

There are ways of attempting equity-based solutions that do not work, but ultimately the goal is to strategically address imbalanced social systems in an effort to give everyone a similar chance at success.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903689773.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>if you're talking about "equality of outcome" as "equality" then it sounds like you're just finding a way to say the same thing twice

equality either means equality or it doesn't.  "equality of opportunity" is a nonsense concept, it always has been.  you can't have equality of opportunity without equality of outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903967827.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think all people should be able to play in the NBA?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905239945.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>is that what we're talking about here, the requirements for extremely specific physical activities?  or are we talking about power in society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905812981.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>So you agree people can be different and we can see inequality of outcome even with equality of opportunity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42909643622.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>i think that equality of opportunity and outcome only refers to socioeconomic conditions and the hierarchy of our society, and bringing up basketball implies that the people on top got there because they "earned" it and are "skilled" like a basketball player is skilled, and haven't just been born into a higher class.   therefore, its completely irrelevant to what we're actually talking about here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914129899.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>But when you see stats like white people in the lowest income quintile are about 2x as likely to get out of it than black people, does that strike you as inequality of opportunity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42917952999.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>it isn't really disproving what i'm saying, just because there are other kinds of inequality of opportunity doesn't mean that there will ever be real equality of opportunity in a class based society  


its unrelated but i'd also question a lot of other things about that statistic, like who are the people leaving poverty both white and black, what is their class background, who are the people staying in poverty in both instances and where are both groups located, i mean there's potentially a whole lot going on there besides just "people are being prejudiced" which would be the typical liberal/progressive answer to why that is occurring</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905384681.0" user="Brainjacker" delta="False">
    <text>“you can't have equality of opportunity without equality of outcome.”

Uh, no. Everyone can have the same opportunities with varying results. You’re welcome to your opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905575483.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>equality of opportunity means that you're starting from the same place as everyone else  


that's impossible if people are starting far richer or poorer than others, and it always will be  


"equality of opportunity" without genuine equality has never made any sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905580383.0" user="Brainjacker" delta="False">
    <text>Then it sounds like that’s how you feel. Good times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905584267.0" user="Ill-Swimmer-4490" delta="False">
    <text>not seeing an argument against it</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
