<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42903403762.0" user="The_Confirminator" delta="False">
    <text>Equity recognizes that each person has different circumstances and allocates resources and opportunities needed to reach an equal outcome.

In the US, the reason why equity has gained steam is due to certain groups experiencing systemic factors that can't be fixed by providing equality. Banks, for example, have historically avoided loans towards minorities. On paper, they receive equal treatment, but not equitable treatment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906357894.0" user="Hammitch" delta="False">
    <text>Equality of outcome will never be attainable and is objectively destructive in a society that is no where near equipped for it , like ours . Indeed , equality of outcome ; or the pursuit therein could unintentionally destroy any nation(s) that attempt it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
