<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902051825.0" user="VStarffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc.

People say stuff like this but I don't think anyone really believes it. I don't think you believe it.

You say everyone should have the same opportnities to further their education. Ok - do you believe that all children should therefore go to public schools which should all be equally funded? Or should parent shave the opportunity to choose what schools their kids go to - and to pay extra for it?

If you believe parents should be allowed to bestow benefits on their own children, then you don't really believe in equality of opportunity for the kids, right?

My point her is that I don't think you actually know what you mean by "equality", much less "equity". To be fair to you, almost no one does of course.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902128012.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>I’m referring to situations where skills or qualifications are ignored for the sake of representation or diversity. Ideally I would like for the school system to allow people who are not as financially stable to be able to attend them with some sort of program to give them then same opportunity if they chose but I think based on that choice the outcomes should be different. I didn’t really explain my point as well as I should have but your school example is really good I like it and that kind of helps me explain better what I was getting at with equal opportunities but based on the decision to utilize those opportunities the results should be different</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902367832.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>To clarify, you think it’s not right that some kids have parents that can afford to send them to private school, while other kids have to go to public school even if they’re just as academically gifted, and someone should compensate for that gap?

If that’s where you stand, you may need to define a lot of your argument more clearly because that’s more in line with most people’s understanding of equity rather than equality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902485125.0" user="courtd93" delta="False">
    <text>You’re missing the first step-as someone else mentioned above, the being born on 3rd base thinking they hit a triple. If you live in an inner city with failing schools and have to babysit your younger siblings because mom and dad have to work 2 jobs each to get by and eventually a job the second I turn 14, the outcomes you get on your work gets you a b+ average. I, living in a rich suburb with top schools in the country and/or private school with my after school being a sport twice a week and otherwise I can devote to my work does the same work and gets an A+. Did I work harder than you? Nope. I did the same or less work because I wasn’t needing to compensate for stressors that you do. If you were in my spot, you would have had A+s because you could have studied and gotten 8 hours sleep still instead of the 5 you did staying up to study after, or having the time to write and edit your essay over days instead of the one night you could schedule it in, and because the teacher was able to explain things in a way you could understand and could ask questions that your actual teacher can’t because she’s too busy breaking up fights to do more than highlight the one way to teach. You don’t have the A+s because you had additional things weighing the impact of your efforts. Now, when the two of us are up for the same college admission slot, I’m going to look better on paper than you do because I had the opportunities that led me to high potential of positive outcomes. You look worse even though you can do all the same work, and worked harder because you did not have the same potential of positive outcomes I did.

This is why we need equity. Equity is about equal access to the potential positive outcomes. Not a guarantee of the outcome, just the actual access to it. A quadriplegic who uses a wheelchair doesn’t have equal access to positive outcomes if all you have is stairs. Doesn’t matter that some can walk it fine and even some who can’t walk could crawl or scoot up. They are paralyzed, and don’t even have access to the potential. That’s why it matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902132417.0" user="Rwandrall" delta="False">
    <text>tons of people totally believe it. they'll say that there's no such thing as merit because your ability to work hard and succeed is defined entirely by nature and nurture, both of which are down to luck, so even if someone works really hard and is smart with money, they shouldn't get more, because it's luck that gave them those attributes.

It's a very common viewpoint in left wing circles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902495494.0" user="Admirable_Ad1947" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a Progressive and I believe that's a misrepresentation of our view. We DO believe that that hard work and merit exist, it's just that luck and happenstance also play a big part and that nobody is truly 100% self sufficient. Let's take Bill Gates for example, he's no doubt worked his ass off and showed a ton of ambition and drive when building Microsoft. But he also had the good fortune of being born into a well off family in a safe, stable country. 



Do you really think Gates would be a billionaire if he were born black in Alabama pre civil rights? Or if he were born in rural India? He also benefitted greatly from the public services and infastructure in this country. His software engineers were mostly educated in public schools, his products were shipped out on public roads and the taxpayers helped enforce his contracts through the courts. Thus I believe it's only fair he pay it forward and give a portion of his profits to the public to help those less fortunate then him and to maintain the same conditions his business thrived in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903685183.0" user="Rwandrall" delta="False">
    <text>Again, plenty of progressives have the same view as you, but go further with it, and say that the "luck and happenstance" play an even bigger part. It's just a quesiton of how big. The view you express here is basically one that pretty much anyone in the world except the craziest libertarians would believe in. "I believe the rich should pay taxes" is not a particularly progressive position, and it's not what equity means.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
