<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902348982.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with arguing that we’ve “blurred the lines” between equality and equity in my opinion is that the two have never really been as distinct as people say. The typical distinction people make is equality = equal opportunity and equity = equal outcomes, but I think this can fall apart quick. 

Let’s take a simple example; you have a person born to a rich family and a poor family, and each has the goal to get a good job and not have to worry about being able to support their family. Do those two truly have an equal opportunity at doing that? *Technically*, *legally* there’s no reason that can’t be a reachable goal for both of them. But we know that’s not how things work. These are not equal starting grounds, and the same can be said for other social issues outside of wealth alone.

So something like wealth redistribution from the rich to the poor, is that equality or equity? The more conservative economic side might say that’s a desire for equality of outcome. But that assumes the game is not already slanted, it presumes the existing state of things was based on merit and hard work when it simply wasn’t. Is it not equality to attempt to level that playing field for all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903023493.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; it presumes the existing state of things was based on merit and hard work when it simply wasn’t

Are you saying there is absolutely ZERO merit and hard work involved in earning more money? Like I just walked into my $400k income? That people just get handed 6 figure jobs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903123701.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>No it’s not that there’s *zero* merit involved with getting a good job; the idea that your economic success is *purely* a product of hard work and merit is just heavily overstated. 

Like I got into a good college and will hopefully end up in decent paying STEM job, and I absolutely worked hard leading up to that, but it would also be silly to attribute that solely to my effort and ignore the advantages I’ve had, not being poor, nice neighborhood, good parents, etc. Don’t take it as like a slight against your hard work or whatever, but obviously getting a 400K income is going to be significantly more difficult if you start poor lol, and if that’s true that’s fundamentally not really a meritocracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903371853.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Let’s take a simple example; you have a person born to a rich family and a poor family, and each has the goal to get a good job and not have to worry about being able to support their family. Do those two truly have an equal opportunity at doing that? Technically, legally there’s no reason that can’t be a reachable goal for both of them. But we know that’s not how things work. These are not equal starting grounds, and the same can be said for other social issues outside of wealth alone.

To be blunt, they actually *do* have equal opportunities. There is blurring of this by people who want to include other factors. The reality is, one person is not actually being prevented from achieving - which is what equality of opportunity is about. There is nothing in this about how easy it is to capitalize on opportunity. The fact they have different 'starting points' really does not matter. 

In my mind, people advocating for considering this are really looking at *outcome* here and trying to pigeon hole this into 'opportunity' concepts instead. And yea - I really do mean that when you look at outcomes, unequal outcomes are actually to be expected here - even with equality of opportunity. 

Equity is framed around different concepts generally. Equity is about giving what is needed to whom needs it. An accident site is the best example. You don't give band-aids to people who aren't bleeding. Equity really isn't about equality opportunity or outcome. It is a claim that there is a specific need by a specific group of people that should be filled.

That being said, there are many who use equity arguments to justify the desire for equality of outcome while claiming to be 'balancing opportunity' instead. The most common is 'people didn't start from the same place'. It is really an argument for equality of outcome, not equality of opportunity.   

And to be clear - this is not always good or bad. Many times, when considering social programs under the 'equity' justifications, you must look to outcome to see if it actually worked. For instance, a program to improve employability of blind people. To see if the program actually worked, you likely would look at employment rates of blind people before and after the program - which is entirely an outcome based assessment. 

Equity tends to get a bad rap when it is used to justify specific and contentious social justice type polices. It is again using the 'equity' concept to correct a 'need' that is not universally accepted as existing and attempting to change the distribution of the outcome to match those goals. This conflict is rooted in the facts humans are inherently unequal and at the same time, people expect equal outcomes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903675982.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;To be blunt they actually do have equal opportunities…

I mean you can argue that but I think that’s a pretty vacuous definition of equal opportunity and not in line with how it’s generally used. The term doesn’t exclusively refer to like anti-discrimination laws in hiring, and wealth obviously has an impact on economic opportunity. And poverty + your circumstances can absolutely prevent you from doing things, why does said prevention have to be an explicit restriction to constitute equal opportunity?

People also heavily associate equal opportunity with work ethic and a meritocracy. An playing field with one kid born to a poor family competing against one born to a rich one is just fundamentally not a meritocracy. People born poor are significantly more likely to die poor, [stickiness at the ends yada yada](https://www.pewtrusts.org/~/media/legacy/uploadedfiles/pcs_assets/2012/pursuingamericandreampdf.pdf). We’re not measuring merit if we ignore systemic biases.

I don’t fundamentally have a problem with equity either, like some of the things you mentioned. But I disagree that these things would qualify as equality of outcome and I think the term is largely a straw man. What does equality of outcome mean to you, like giving everyone the same exact amount of money? Wealth redistribution doesn’t do this. There are also lots of factors that just can’t be controlled for, like where you’re born and the family you’re born into. I don’t think many people expect everyone to have exactly the same economic outcomes lol, just a much more flattened hierarchy in outcomes then there is now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905698941.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I mean you can argue that but I think that’s a pretty vacuous definition of equal opportunity

I disagree here. Equal opportunity laws came about because people were literally *denied* the ability to apply to jobs. They could have met the requirements of a job but because they were the wrong race or sex, they never were even considered. 

&gt; wealth obviously has an impact on economic opportunity. 

But this is not the subject of the equal opportunity laws. This is a more modern idea based around 'equity'. 

If you go to the Equal Opportunity Commission website, you will not find support from them about discrimination based on this. 

https://www.eeoc.gov/overview

&gt;People also heavily associate equal opportunity with work ethic and a meritocracy

I would argue people associate opportunity with the literally, the chance to apply and to not be denied merely because of an inherent characteristic independent of the role in play. You likely are conflating the 'meritocracy' with the consequence that the better qualified get selected over the lesser qualified. 

&gt;But I disagree that these things would qualify as equality of outcome and I think the term is largely a straw man. What does equality of outcome mean to you,

This is actually very simple. The 'equality of outcome' is deciding a policy needs to be put in place to specifically change the 'outcome' seen for a given item. For instance, deciding there is not enough women in STEM so you create programs exclusively to recruit women into STEM. That is an equality of outcome proposal. Deciding not enough low income people go to college so you create a program for low income people to be able to go to college. That is an outcome based idea.

Conversely, the equality of opportunity corrections would be things like removing red-lining. Preventing people from making a hiring decision based on race. There is no guarantee of any given outcome, but systematic prevention of a specific outcome has been removed.

Not all 'outcome' based proposals are bad. 

In a philosophical sense, people who are more concerned with equality of opportunity don't expect to see outcome's match the demographics of the population. Unequal outcomes are normal and to be expected because humans are inherently unequal as individuals. 

But - people who are more concerned with equality of outcome do expect to see outcomes match the demographics of the population. Unequal outcomes are a sign of problems that require actions to make it more 'equitable'. 

When you look at real people, this is not a binary. Real people see opportunity and outcome and use their values and ethics to determine what, if any, equity type solutions are needed. People exist on a spectrum. There is a real conflict though people who are at different points of the spectrum debate policy. 

For instance, many who don't see being born poor as a justification to create strong equity programs for instance. There are people who reject 'historic injustice' as a justification for equity programs. Essentially, it is a very contentious arena. Even those on the heavily 'equity' side don't universally demand it. The best examples are sports teams. There is no push by anyone to address the significant unequal outcome seem in the demographics of many sports - though you do see some push for 'diversity'. Complaints about the PGA and the 'Rooney' rule in Football come to mind. 

Personally, I think a lot of this for individuals boils down to the line of individual vs collective responsibility and where people fit on that spectrum. Those who lean very individualistic see the solution to be the responsibility of the individual. There are legitimate comments to be made that programs exist if people would simple take advantage of them. The leading horse to water and making them drink problem. Others lean more collectivist and remove the individual responsibility in many cases. Again, this is not binary and it is a spectrum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906465315.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But this is not the subject of equal opportunity laws…

Equal opportunity laws are obviously important, but the term equal opportunity or *equality of opportunity* — if you make a distinction, they’re generally interchangeable — is a broader sociological concept that refers to more than just those laws. 

The issue here is that you’re limiting your view of “opportunity” to explicit discrimination alone when there are tons of ways social factors can limit not  just your outcomes, but your *access* to jobs and opportunities. Poor people on average are not going to get the same education, limiting job opportunities. If you’re homeless and don’t have an address, many jobs won’t even consider your application. And this doesn’t even get started on how bias can slip through equal opportunity laws, like the fact that “black-sounding” names are [significantly more likely to be discriminated against in hiring](https://www.nber.org/papers/w29053).

&gt;You likely are conflating the meritocracy with the consequence that the better qualified get selected over the lesser qualified.

No, my point is that we’re not judging “merit” if people come from vastly different backgrounds. Should the goal of equal opportunity not be to reward one’s efforts on a level playing field not overwhelmingly dictated by the social status they were born into?

&gt;Deciding not enough low income people go to college so you create a program for low income people to be able to go to college. That is an outcome based idea.

Nope, not if you recognize that there are systemic forces *like not having the money* preventing qualified students from attending those colleges, and are creating a program to address that fact, thus providing a more equal opportunity for people of all economic backgrounds to attend. Same idea with women in STEM. Women have often been discriminated against in STEM fields, through unconscious bias in applications, societal expectations for what women can be, or harassment and such driving them out, so programs attempt to counteract an existing bias to make a more level playing field. But if you blind yourself to all these forces and purely focus on legal restrictions, you will never see it or stop it. 

&gt;Unequal outcomes are normal and to be expected because people are inherently unequal as individuals.

The progressive argument is generally that if you give people true equal opportunity, they will have much *more* equal outcomes. Obviously there will still be variations in wealth under a capitalist economic system. 

I’ll ask though, what do you mean by inherently unequal? Do you think some people just work super duper hard or that’s why they’ve succeeded? Or do we mean that the social circumstances people are born into will necessarily affect one’s achievable outcomes? Because the latter I agree with, and I don’t think that’s fundamentally an equal system, but I feel like that’s not what you mean. 

&gt;Even those on the side of equity don’t universally demand it… sport example

Presumably because they don’t really consider disproportionate racial demographics in some high level athletics to be a big social issue, whereas people do see the economic opportunities of poor people and minority groups to be much more worthy of addressing because it affects millions of people’s well-being.

I agree that all of this is a spectrum; the lines between collectivist/individualist or equality/equity can be blurred. What I caution against primarily is “responsibilization,” [a term used by theorist Wendy Brown](https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/1467-8675.12166?saml_referrer) to describe how the moral responsibility of self-investment and entrepreneurship are thrust solely on the individual, displacing any structural critique of the lack of social protections or public goods that led people to their respective positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906982206.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The issue here is that you’re limiting your view of “opportunity” to explicit discrimination alone when there are tons of ways social factors can limit not just your outcomes, but your access to jobs and opportunities.

This is actually quite contentious. There is not a physical barrier here and there examples to be pointed to where poverty is overcome. 

That is my point. There is a divide in defining what equal opportunity means. There is a strong push to put equity items in this and claim if equity is not present, than equal opportunity is not present. 

&gt;No, my point is that we’re not judging “merit” if people come from vastly different backgrounds.

Sure you are. There is explicitly a merit difference in the factors that matter. It may be far more difficult to be judged qualified for some backgrounds but that does not invalid the merit aspect at all.  All of this is equity ideas focused on changing outcome distributions. 

This is more of the desire to include or incorporate equity ideas into the equal opportunity concept. Equal opportunity does not mean equal ability to capitalize on said opportunity.

&gt;Nope, not if you recognize that there are systemic forces like not having the money preventing qualified students from attending those colleges, and are creating a program to address that fact, thus providing a more equal opportunity for people of all economic backgrounds to attend. Same idea with women in STEM. Women have often been discriminated against in STEM fields, through unconscious bias in applications, societal expectations for what women can be, or harassment and such driving them out, so programs attempt to counteract an existing bias to make a more level playing field. But if you blind yourself to all these forces and purely focus on legal restrictions, you will never see it or stop it. 

Hard disagree. All of these are Outcome based ideas. There is no law preventing low income students from going to school. It may be more difficult because of funding, but there is no barrier stating no - you cannot go even if you can pay for it. That *has* existed in the past. 

There is a massive push to include equity and outcome into the claims of equal opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42907481744.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;There is not a physical barrier here and there are examples to be pointed to where poverty is overcome. 

Poverty *can* be overcome, but as an aggregate, being poor is absolutely a barrier toward economic opportunity. What do you mean physical, do you mean legal? I don’t think we’re going to agree on this part, but if you’re saying a poor and rich person have complete equality of opportunity, I think this is pretty asinine. By nature of the status they are born into and nothing else they have different access to economic opportunities.

&gt;There is explicitly a merit difference in the factors that matter. It may be far more difficult to be judged qualified but that does not invalidate the merit…

Keep in mind I’m not critiquing people doing job hiring — they’ll select the qualified people available to them — I’m saying the *society* isn’t meritocratic. To say otherwise is to make your definition of merit post hoc, to assume those with wealth earned it through merit and those millions of poor people who disproportionately remain poor their entire lives lacked the merit, completely ignoring the fact that they lacked the same access to those opportunities.

&gt;Equal opportunity does not mean equal ability to capitalize on said opportunity.

Then your conceptualization of equal opportunity is meaningless and incomplete. This would be like you’re running a race but right before it the starter shoots you in the leg and says “What? You have a completely equal opportunity to run the race, no one’s stopping you. It’s just gonna be harder for you.” People aren’t being given an equal opportunity to succeed if they’re handicapped by poverty from the start. 

You keep bringing up law in the next part and repeating your argument without elaborating. Why do you think explicit legal restriction is the sole arbiter of equality? Like do you think all inequality against women ended with the Equal Pay Act? You mentioned redlining, the results of which still exist today (it still has a massive impact on the racial demographics of certain areas). Is this an equal playing field, or do we disregard everything that isn’t written down on paper?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42907791521.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Poverty can be overcome, but as an aggregate, being poor is absolutely a barrier toward economic opportunity.

But this is contradictory for the question of opportunity. How difficult it is to overcome is not he question. The question is whether there is a clear prevention. Remember, in the not too distant past we had clear barriers where people, no matter how qualified, were prevented from getting opportunists. 

This is devolving again into 'equity'. Where it being difficult is somehow now equated to being not equal in opportunity.  

&gt;I don’t think we’re going to agree on this part, but if you’re saying a poor and rich person have complete equality of opportunity, I think this is pretty asinine.

THis is exactly what I am stating because I do not consider the hardship required to capitalize on oppertunity being relevant.

Lets make a stupid simple example. We have two people, one in a wheelchair and one able bodied. THey are seeking employment as a receptionist. (where the wheelchair is not relevant).  In this case, the business has steps leading into/out of the building.

I would state that both parties do NOT have equal opportunity here. The steps are physical barrier forming a hard no to the candidate in the wheelchair completely independent of the qualifications/merit of the position. No person in a wheelchair could get that job. 

Now, we have a different set of people. This time we are talking about transportation. One is more affluent and has a car. The 2nd person has a very unrelaible form of transportation and cannot afford better.

In this case, the ability to get work is a factor that 2nd person must work harder to overcome to convince an employer of thier suitability. There is no problems with equal opportunity here. The difference is meaningful to the opportunity and merely being more difficult does not matter. 

&gt;Keep in mind I’m not critiquing people doing job hiring — they’ll select the qualified people available to them — I’m saying the society isn’t meritocratic. To say otherwise is to make your definition of merit post hoc, to assume those with wealth earned it through merit and those millions of poor people who disproportionately remain poor their entire lives lacked the merit, completely ignoring the fact that they lacked the same access to those opportunities.

This is far to complicated a topic to distill to one factor. The fact is, society is imperfectly meritocratic. In general, in broad terms, merit is rewarded. Patterns of good decisions are rewarded. Patterns of bad decisions are punished. 

&gt;Then your conceptualization of equal opportunity is meaningless and incomplete

No. I am merely stating the starting points don't have to be the same. There is nothing in equal opportunity that demands fairness or equal starting points or even equal ability to compete. The equal opportunity merely means that a person, if they wish, could enter that race. They are free to compete against others to be the best choice. There is not a physical barrier in place preventing them from even being considered. 

&gt;You keep bringing up law in the next part and repeating your argument without elaborating. Why do you think explicit legal restriction is the sole arbiter of equality?

I bring up law because this form a shared concept of what terms mean and what standards are in play. This is especially important with the repeated desire by many to include 'equity' type considerations in the concept of equal opportunity. The law serves are a good basis to refer to.

The common theme in your comments is the merging of 'equity' into 'equal opportunity'. I flatly reject this. These are two different concepts. They may be related, but they are not bound the way you are presenting them.

Also - to be clear. 'equity' issues are not inherently bad. They are questions that should stand on thier own merits though.  

If you would like the 'test' I use to differentiate, it is actually fairly simple. It is an equal opportunity issue if the best qualified example from a group is unable to be considered for an opportunity. A person who could otherwise take advantage of an opportunity is prevented from doing so while other, less qualified people are free to take advantage. Again, take an African American Sailor in WW2 would was not allowed to be anything other than a cook in the Navy. 

If the best qualified/motivated individuals can take advantage of the opportunity, even if it is quite difficult, then there is no equal opportunity issue here. It is instead pushed into a question of equity where different groups face different challenges to take advantage of opportunities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908332910.0" user="teaisjustgaycoffee" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We have two people, one in a wheel chair and one able bodied… the building has steps leading into/out of the building… I would state that the two parties do NOT have equal opportunity here…

I agree! And similarly, if you are locked out of being able to attend a great university or are unable to move to an area with better job opportunities because you’re in poverty, I would say you do not have an equal opportunity there. Those steps are an economic barrier toward your ability to accept that position, even if you’re qualified, which you’re less likely to be to begin with if you were born to bad circumstances. 

&gt;this time we are talking about transportation… one is more affluent and has a car. The 2nd person has a very unreliable form of transportation and cannot afford better… there is no problem if equal opportunity here.

There *absolutely* is. The only difference is that we legally require all commercial facilities to have wheelchair access under the ADA, and we don’t mandate good public transit or access to cars because that’s obviously a lot more difficult. The fundamental argument you’re making is the same. That person in a wheelchair can do the job, they just have to work harder and convince their employer they can get up those steps man. I think expanding public transit would go a long way to make ensure equal access to job opportunity.

&gt;This is far too complicated to distill to one factor. The fact is society is imperfectly meritocratic.

I don’t disagree. I think you’re oversimplifying society down to merit and ignoring other factors under an incomplete definition of equality. 

&gt;No. I am merely stating the starting points don’t have to be the same. There is nothing in equal opportunity that demands fairness or equal starting points or even equal ability to compete. 

Yes there is, it’s in the words “equal” and “opportunity.” I’m not trying to be rude or anything, but go up to a poor person and say they have an equal opportunity to be a CEO as a wealthy person born into a family with a business lol. Like “oh overwhelmingly people of your social status won’t make it or even have the chance to get there but it’s equal! You have a right to compete… kind of!” To use my analogy, no one would say that runner who was shot in the leg actually had an equal opportunity to compete, even if they technically could.

We’re repeating ourselves a bit at this point, but I think what I’ve said is perfectly in line with ensuring equality of opportunity. I think equity and equality, while not the same, often overlap and that whether an action qualifies as one or the other can sometimes depend on your motivations for that thing. 

&gt;It is an equal opportunity issue if the best qualified example from a group is unable to be considered for an opportunity. A person who could otherwise take advantage of the opportunity is prevented from doing so while other less qualified people are free to take advantage. 

Disregarding the fact that this isn’t even the legal definition, how do you determine this? What if the otherwise qualified person for the job is prevented from that opportunity because of a lack of transportation, or a qualified student can’t afford college? This seems indistinguishable to me but I have no doubt you would exclude them from the term “unable.” Explicit and legal hiring discrimination is obviously a part of equal opportunity, but ensuring equality broadly necessitates far more.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
