<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42915125838.0" user="JohnWasElwood" delta="False">
    <text>But as long as you have "people" involved in the system there will nearly always be bias.  A black HR guy might try to help black people work at his company, an Asian lady... a Hispanic lady... a white guy... The list goes on.  

If a trans HR person sees 2 nearly identical resumes for a position and one of them shows up to the interview with a rainbow flag decal or a COEXIST bumper sticker, which of the 2 do you think has a better chance of getting hired?  What if the person who DOESN'T have any of these public indicators on their car has a more impressive resume than the rainbow flag decal person?  What are their odds?  

Just look at the current celebrity worship culture.  People are always going to be attracted to wealth and power and they're going to try, in their meager ways, to emulate their celebrity heroes.  Why do high school kids (and a LOT of adults) wear their sports team shirts with the name and number of their sports hero on them?  

"People" are always going to be prejudiced and will nearly always try to surround themselves with people who think and look just like them.  You can spout all of the high minded ideals all day long, but at the end of the day when it comes time to pick your employees, co-workers, friends, sports team members, etc. you're going to surround yourself with people just like you.  If you're a rich snob in a high class neighborhood, guess who is coming to dinner, and guess who ISN'T.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
