<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901762829.0" user="mcmullankevin" delta="False">
    <text>The notion that the harder you work brings greater benefit is a myth. Hardest working people I know doing 3 jobs are trapped in poverty.  The link between hard work and reward does not exist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901797696.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>"working hard" implies a combination of work ethic, talent and good decision making.

If a person works really hard at flipping burgers. They are either very low talent or they are making terrible life choices.

So no it's not a myth. It's just a very condensed way of saying that you need to maximize your ability. Which usually means investing in learning a skill that you have aptitude for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902121550.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>If your argument is that hard work is not hard work then I feel like your conclusion doesn't follow by definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902167214.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>That is what people mean by hard work.

It also implies that they are being very productive. The hardest working grill guy at McDonalds isn't particularly productive relative to a doctor or something.

It's a semantic thing.

We don't really mean "hard work" in a physical sense. There is a lot of things that are very hard to do but serve no purpose. I can pick up a big ass rock and carry that thing around all day long. What benefit was that to anyone? besides perhaps better health for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902509393.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That is what people mean by hard work.

Which people? You're arguing with people who don't mean that. 


&gt;It's a semantic thing.

Right. The semantic issue is that people who say "hard work is rewarded" have a made up definition of the word "hard work" such that it doesn't mean working hard. The whole thing becomes nonsense in a way that the saying "hard work is rewarded" isn't true. 

&gt;We don't really mean "hard work" in a physical sense. There is a lot of things that are very hard to do but serve no purpose.

A lot of this "purposeless work" that doesn't get rewarded is the exact work we need for our society to function. If doctors stopped existing tomorrow it would not change my day to day would not change until I needed one. If the grocery store shelves stopped being stocked because the people who do that job stopped existing, we would literally have society-wide chaos within a week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902749225.0" user="dkinmn" delta="False">
    <text>It's shocking to me that anyone disagrees with this argument. Our economy is not a meritocracy. It doesn't reward hard work. It's been rewarding in groups with opportunities to make money.

Why do we pay software engineers many times more than we pay the teachers who MAKE software engineers?

There is no succinct and good answer for that. We just do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902793636.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>We pay software engineers because they are scarce. It is much easier to be a teacher then a software engineer.

IQ requirement for software engineer about 115.

IQ requirement to be a teacher 95-105 depending on the subject. We have way more people capable of being teachers than software engineers. Which is why we pay software engineers more. 

That is how meritocracies work. They reward scarce skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903300581.0" user="thomasale2" delta="False">
    <text>TQ isnt real, and teacher is more important anyways and much more difficult</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903459144.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>IQ is very real. Some people are just smarter.

Perhaps our testing models are not as accurate as they should be. 

Most people have the mental acuity to teach. But they don't have it for software engineering. It's a well known secret for why some people get paid more than others. Some jobs most people simply can't do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903458505.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That is how meritocracies work. They reward scarce skills.

That's not a meritocracy. That isn't even what merit means. A meritocracy would reward useful skills, not scarce skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903477298.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Scarce and useful often go hand in hand. When we think of scarce skills the fact that it's useful is sort of implied. If you're the best in the world at some sport you made up that nobody watches or even know exists. That's not the same as being a pro level basketball player. There's no demand for your skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908417144.0" user="Notachance326426" delta="False">
    <text>IQ is completely meaningless</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902787332.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but the whole point of an economy is to figure out how to combat scarcity.

If we have scarce food. We need to get enough resources and labor to food production. That sort of thing.

Although the grocery store shelves need to be stock. We have an abundance of people who can do it. Because pretty much anyone with feet and arms that work can do it. Meanwhile it takes 16 years of grueling education and loads of talent to become a doctor. Doctors are scarce. People who load up shelves are not. You can find people who are capable of doing that job anywhere where there are humans. 

So yes when we say "hard work is rewarded". What we really mean is scarce skills are rewarded. Perhaps people should say it that way. But what they are inferring is that getting those skills often requires a lot of hard work. Like the case with a doctor who spent 16 years doing pre-med, med school, residency and fellowship. Those are all very difficult tasks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903444715.0" user="ghotier" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So yes when we say "hard work is rewarded". What we really mean is scarce skills are rewarded.

Right  we lie and say we value hard work when in reality we value scarce skills up to a point. Which is exactly what I said but somehow you think restating what I said somehow makes me wrong. It doesn't.  The thing we reward the most is wealth. Then scare skills. But we don't reward hard work. 

You're seeing a disparity between what we say we value and reality and you're papering over your cognitive dissonance by saying the two things are synonymous. They aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903469917.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>No we actually reward scarce skills. People with those skills tend to amass wealth. The relationship is backwards from what you're stating.

I don't know what you value. But the economy values scarce skills for obvious reasons. Because we need more people in those fields. That is a model that gets more people in the correct careers. We don't need an army of janitors. Anyone can do that job. We need doctors, engineers, lawyers etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902285585.0" user="Constellation-88" delta="False">
    <text>This completely removes the fact that circumstances happen that are beyond your control. You can work as hard as you want, but some AH can come in and steal all of your money, leaving you penniless. You can graduate from high school as valedictorian and be unable to attend college because your mom dies and you have to stay home to help the family. You can be highly intelligent and not able to afford college. You can go to college and graduate just as the economy crashes and be unable to find a job in your field. You can be in a car wreck and lose your ability to work or study full time. So many things happen beyond "work hard= success." 

In reality, your choices don't guarantee anything. They can only put you in certain positions. For example, person A doesn't study, gets crap grades, barely graduates, and has no chance at college without massive debt and years of remedial classes. Person B does study, gets great grades, gets scholarships, has a good ACT/SAT score. 

Both Person A and Person B are equally subject to the possibility of someone stealing their college funding, their family members dying, or a car wreck happening because their choices cannot change those things. Their choices only put them in certain positions when circumstances beyond their control happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902310453.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think anybody who believes in meritocracy thinks that car crashes and all those other things you described don't happen. It doesn't guarantee anything. But it does set you up for success provided some catastrophe doesn't take place. You can't live your entire life waiting for something awful to happen and being inactive as a result. 

When you look at a person who is 40 years old and working at McDonalds. And then you look at a 40 year old doctor who makes $200,000 a year. Maybe that McDonalds worker had 10 car crashes happen to them in a row. But chances are if you looked at their decision making process you would see gigantic differences between the McDonalds worker and the doctor. Lots of time wasting, lazyness, partying, etc etc etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902345322.0" user="Constellation-88" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that you can't live your life making poor choices because tragedies might happen. But I think that a meritocracy is a mythological perspective held by people who either have not had anything happen to them or have had a couple bad things happen and have been able to overcome those things due to positive circumstances combined with their hard work. I think that everyone who is living in poverty, depression, sickness, etc. has had circumstances beyond their control that make it harder for them to be successful. It may not be a car wreck. It may have been having an addict for a parent or a sick sibling or being assaulted in high school. But whatever it is, most people in our society endures some sort of trauma. 

When a flower doesn't grow, we don't think it wasn't working hard enough. We assume the balance of water, soil, and sunlight were suboptimal for the flower. Positive circumstances (support systems, good luck, etc), negative circumstances, and hard work go together in a combination to determine how much a human grows. If we gave people more support, took away the negative circumstances we can, and then people chose to work hard, everyone would be happy. But instead our society ignores entirely the need for support and the negative circumstances and just sits back and says "Well ya didn't work hard enough" and expects people to make something of their lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902410079.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>But is that really true? 

When I was a junky. I was able to get food stamps. About $267 a month adjusted for inflation. It was enough to eat off for $130 a month and I used the other $130 to get drugs. 

I had housing assistance. Which made my rent much cheaper. And the apartment came with internet and electricity. It was a very small apartment with 3 other roommates. But a lot better than living on the road. 

We do have loads of safety nets in our society. It's not like we have 0. 

Had I never stopped using drugs. I'd probably be sleeping on the side of the road right now. Or more likely dead or in prison. That was a decision I had to make. 

The decisions we make are far more important than our circumstances. In most cases anyway. Obviously if you got into a serious accident that does not apply. But most people thankfully never get into horrific accidents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902519244.0" user="Constellation-88" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that, to be healthy, you have to stop choosing drugs. And your story proves my point because you had those safety nets (support/positive circumstances) to help you make that choice. Not everyone can access those safety nets. 

And I want to be clear: healthy choices are important. I’m not saying they’re not. But it’s 1 of many things that have to happen for people to be okay. You could’ve chosen to get off drugs and then had a bunch of other things happen or those safety nets you could access could’ve been inaccessible to you and then it would be different. The reason people make unhealthy choices in the first place is only because they don’t see another option. Addicts choose to use drugs because they think the only way out of their pain is to numb it given that they can’t change the circumstances that cause it. 

My point is that it’s the confluence of choices and circumstances. The things within your control and the things outside of your control. Meritocracy just ignores the things outside of your control. A better perspective would be to see it all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902803847.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I became an addict because I liked being high. It feels good. Many addicts refuse to admit that about themselves.

I used to make all sorts of excuses. It helps me with anxiety and depression. It certainly did that. It helped me sleep and talk to girls. Definitely did all that. But the real reason was I just liked being high. It feels good to feel good.

Also I would argue that I did not choose to improve until people stopped enabling me. My father kept giving me $. Which in turn just led to more drug use. It wasn't until he decided to cut me off. That I sobered up. Because my choices were either start stealing shit or go to rehab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908448948.0" user="Notachance326426" delta="False">
    <text>How is the air up there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902740377.0" user="dkinmn" delta="False">
    <text>And luck, friend. It's a myth. Period. I was born into an upper middle class family, and despite not being a particularly gifted student or employee in my younger days, that's what I am now.

Opportunity is not equally distributed. I think you'd admit as much. So, a person born to a poor and broken family doesn't even get nearly the opportunity I did. That's just a fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902835873.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>If you live in USA. Yes you had the luck of being born in a meritocratic and highly prosperous society.

If you want middle class in America. You need to do 3 things:

1) Get an education or get a scarce skill

2) Don't commit crime

3) Don't have children too early.

And even if you do #2 or #3 you will likely be able to make it. Your road just becomes a lot tougher.

I assure you go to any McDonalds, Wendys, Burger king or the like. Go talk to the 35+ year old employees. You will see that they did not follow those 3 simple rules. Sometimes because they were toxic shitheads who lived a life of crime. Sometimes they had a bunch of kids as teenagers and permanently affected their ability to build skills. Sometimes good ol lazyness and lack of ambition. And occasionally they just had a low IQ and simply weren't capable of #1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902863658.0" user="dkinmn" delta="False">
    <text>When you're already at the bottom, those things are more difficult, which means they take more effort, which means that effort is not equally rewarded.

You're not actually basing this on any actual academic research on economic mobility. You're just repeating lazy Nixon and Reagan era talking points that were designed to make the haves feel superior to the have nots.

An upper middle class family member can literally do the opposite of all of these and still end up better off than a poor person who follows that plan.

And you know it. You just have some weird attachment to the myth of meritocracy.

You can INCREASE you're chances of success, but there is no way you can look at piles of data and truly believe what you've written here. You simply can't. It's a comfortable myth for people who want to believe that poverty is easily explained by poor character and poor choices.

In a country where it's been proven that "black sounding names" are less likely to get interviews, jobs, home loans, etc, your argument is plainly silly. But, that's okay. I'm not expecting you to take my arguments seriously. You've made your choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902904347.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen many upper class kids end up in prison. So the #2 rule definitely applies to everyone.

I've also seen a bunch of people who started in poverty making really good $ as highly educated professionals. So the #1 rule definitely applied to them. 

\#3 is sort of common sense. 

I spent 6 years working at Wendy's. 3 years as a crew member and 3 years as a manager. I've seen the behavioral patterns of poor people and college kids that worked in our store. So yes I say this with a lot of experience behind it. People who are poor usually make a ton of really shitty life choices to become that way. Usually a general lack of respect for institutions. Usage of drugs. No will to take accountability for their own behavior. Having loads of unprotected sex at a young age. etc etc etc. You get the point. 

I wasn't even around for Nixon or Reagan. Sounds like they were just telling the truth. 

Also...

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List\_of\_ethnic\_groups\_in\_the\_United\_States\_by\_household\_income](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ethnic_groups_in_the_United_States_by_household_income)

This is the best evidence I know of American meritocracy. When brown skin Indian immigrants are out earning the local whites 2 to 1. You know that the people who are getting paid are the ones with skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903870485.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, but the question is, WHY do poor people make "a ton of really shitty life choices" as you say? Is it just how their DNA is structured? Because they're just stupid? Or could it be that the circumstances of a person's birth and upbringing will determine the likelihood of good and bad decision making?

Of course some poor kids will get out and live successful lives. And some rich and middle class kids will screw up and have shitty lives. But those will be on the small ends of the normal distribution curve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905308414.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>It's a combination of both. Intelligence, impulsivity and aggression level are all heritable. But obviously your upbringing has an enormous impact on you as well. 

If you have families who are heritably low IQ and high aggression. Is it really surprising you find a lot more of them in the poor communities? There's only so many jobs they can do. Maybe the military and other such functions. They served a purpose back in the day, but don't have a place in our "you can be anything you put your mind to" society cause that is just horseshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906779340.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>So, in a nutshell, poor communities' core problem is that they're full of genetically inferior people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906828669.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>It's a part of it yes. 

And I would use the term "genetically inferior". If apocalypse happened those same so called genetically inferior people would find that their muscles and their aggressive demeanor is suddenly very advantageous. Remember we didn't evolve in this environment. We evolved in a much more dangerous and hostile place. 

It's more about how you frame it. You have some 125 IQ guy who genuinely believes that white people will never give him a chance. He might just use that talent to sell drugs. On the other hand you tell him the truth that he can do anything he wants if he just applies himself. He may go work at an Emergency Room or something. The problem is we say the same thing to people with an IQ of 90. And eventually they figure out that we are full of shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902981184.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a myth. If it was, no one would ever move up or down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903886521.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>Demographically, no one is moving from up to down or down to up. The rich are moving up up up, and the rest are moving down down down. A few anecdotes don't change the data.

https://assets.motherjones.com/politics/2011/inequality-p25_averagehouseholdincom.png</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904003198.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socioeconomic_mobility_in_the_United_States

The distribution of income has nothing to do with mobility. If you look at the intragenerational mobility section, within 9 years nearly half of the US population changed income quintiles.

Your graphs are also purposefully misleading considering the absolute income one is pre tax. They definitely played with that so you wouldn't be able to see everyone's income was rising.

Edit: I found the graph that isn't exceedingly misleading: https://www.cbo.gov/publication/58781

Towards the middle of the document you can see rich are outpacing others but everyone is growing pretty well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914299398.0" user="Scrappy_101" delta="False">
    <text>No, not "everyone is growing pretty well."

And did you seriously just link Wikipedia and point out a section where they mention a study, but then completely ignore the next few paragraphs where they present the opposite? Talk about misleading...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914813325.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>That next few paragraphs cite this CBO report: https://www.cbo.gov/publication/42729?index=12485

The CBO's description of that report is quite literally:

&gt;CBO finds that, between 1979 and 2007, income grew by: 275 percent for the top 1 percent of households; 65 percent for the next 19 percent; just under 40 percent for the next 60 percent; and 18 percent for the bottom 20 percent.

So yes even the bottom 20% grew by about 18%. And that report is cited as talking about economic mobility, but doesn't actually mention it in the report. Whoever cited it misunderstood. At a static period in time, multi-year income is only marginally more equal than single year income. But it isn't talking about people's incomes over a period of time.

The other paper which is cited (http://www.columbia.edu/~wk2110/bin/mobility-short.pdf) that actually deals with income mobility has this to state:

&gt;Figure 4A reports the probability of staying in the bottom two quintiles P0-40 or top two quintiles P60-100 after 1 year (again conditional on remaining in the core sample after 1 year). Two basic findings should be noted from those graphs. First, the probability of staying in the top quintiles is higher than the probability of staying in the bottom quintiles, showing that being in the bottom of the distribution in any one year is more a transitory state (on average) than being in the upper part of the distribution.

And if you look at page 42 of the document, only 80% of the bottom quintile remain in the bottom quintile the following year. And page 43 of the document, roughly 8% of people in the very bottom quintile make it to the top of the quintile within 11 years (compared to 20% if it were completely random). That's a pretty sizeable group for you to call it "anecdotes" that there is the possibility for people to dramatically improve their own situations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914915436.0" user="Scrappy_101" delta="False">
    <text>Growing doesn't mean growing pretty good. Seems you've moved the goalposts to make your point. 

As for your study, you're really overstate how great the movement is. You even said "80% of the bottom stay in the bottom in a year."

Either way, I'm not the one that said anything about anecdotes. That was the other person.  I merely pointed out how silly it was for you to talk about misleading when you did the very same thing. Besides, they were clearly being exaggerative anyway. The overarching point they were making, that economic mobility and inequality is bad, holds true and you;ve not refuted it. I do agree the MotherJones graph is a weird one though and doesn't really tell us much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914963198.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>8% of the bottom quintile manages to make it to the top quintile within 11 years? You consider that equivalent to "no one is moving up or down"? 8% moved from the bottom to the top! That's millions of people!

As I've shown multiple times, everyone is growing. I like my first CBO report better since means tested transfers have increased over the period, therefore actual income after transfers has grown much more strongly for the lowest income quintile than income pre transfers (80% increase vs 18%). But even 18% is a very sizeable income increase. You think that's negligible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42915239410.0" user="Scrappy_101" delta="False">
    <text>"Either way, I'm not the one that said anything about anecdotes. That was the other person." Seems you missed that part oof my last comment.

As for income, did you even read your first source? Income has gone up IN RAW NUMBERS, but the share of income for all but the top quintile has gone down. When examining this topic, you can't just look at raw income and ignore everything else, such as the distribution of the income, inflation, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42915297554.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; When examining this topic, you can't just look at raw income and ignore everything else, such as the distribution of the income, inflation, etc.

Those numbers are already adjusted for inflation. The CBO was reporting real increases, not nominal. Why would distribution matter if you've already incorporated changes in cost of living? If you incorporate transfers, the lowest quintile is 80% better off than they were in 1979.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42915469230.0" user="Scrappy_101" delta="False">
    <text>Ok great, but you, of course, completely ignored the graph lmao. Just further proving how dishonest you are. Your ego is too fragile too be wrong about something, which is why you constantly move the goalposts, ignore things that don't fit your narrative as if they didn't exist, etc. 

"If you incorporate transfers, the lowest quintile is 80% better off than they were in 1979."

The graph literally shows the opposite, but go off lmao.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908558666.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>False. 

Distribution of income is not tracking the same individuals across time. But typical from Mother Jones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903542633.0" user="HealthMeRhonda" delta="False">
    <text>"investing in learning a skill that you have aptitude for"

This is much harder work for someone who has no time because they are working full-time just to keep a roof over their head,

No role models to show them how going into debt actually helped them in the long run, and talk them through applying to schools

Poor literacy and, again, no time to teach themselves things that others take for granted by watching videos - because they're either working, sleeping or too exhausted from working to actually learn.

This is before you even introduce an illness.

This is before you introduce parents who are addicts or growing up in environments where you weren't physically safe or taught the basics like how to cook nutritious foods.

Some people are dropped off by their Mom, a short walk from the "start" line of the race with well fitting running shoes on and a good breakfast in their belly.

Other people have a long walk to the bus stop, having to come up with the money before they can arrive at the place where the race starts and they couldn't afford breakfast and they didn't sleep well because they were worried about missing the race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901814693.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>When people say "hard work" they mean work hard at getting a promotion and advancing up the company as high as you can, then using that experience to get a higher paying job at a different company and move up the ranks there.

It doesn't mean mean do a minimum wage job for 20 years.

And it doesn't mean it'll work for everyone, it can't by definition. It's for the people who improve and work up the ladder. The ones who show that and advance work hard to then keep improving and advancing, not everyone does the same job really well and they'll be rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901861784.0" user="cbdqs" delta="False">
    <text>O ya thats exactly what Mark Zuckerberg, Elon Musk and Bill Gates did. That's exactly how they got to be some of the richest people in the world</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901938893.0" user="Natural-Arugula" delta="False">
    <text>If hard work = makes more money, than whoever has the most money therefore worked the hardest.

For example, in the above using your experience to gain trust isn't work because it's not something that you do, it's something that someone does. It's their trust in you that is doing the work. But it doesn't matter, because money = work.

If Instead of your experience it's your inheritance that gains you trust, well that is also hard work in this paradigm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902073129.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>They invented stuff and started their own companies. Worked hard doing it too. 

Didn't do the same minimum wage for 20 years and expected to be rich from it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902102939.0" user="Huffmanstinks" delta="False">
    <text>Elon Musk didnt invent jack shit, he bought existing companies with emerald slave money daddy gave him</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902155595.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah not working in a warehouse for 20 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902433634.0" user="YuenglingsDingaling" delta="False">
    <text>And was way better at it that other people who started rich. The dudes is an absolute ass don't get me wrong. But you can't chalk up his success just to daddy's money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908496508.0" user="Notachance326426" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah cause people that have a ton of money, can’t fail over and over and over and over until they get lucky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908621266.0" user="YuenglingsDingaling" delta="False">
    <text>No they can't really. Rich people stay rich by making wise business choices. Ruthless and amoral? Sure, but they work. Musk, despite his recent headlines, has made a series of great business decisions. I don't believe you luck into being one of the richest dudes alive. Same thing with Bill Gates. He made a great product sure. His success was through his brilliant and ruthless business choices. I'm not trying to hold these guy on a pedestal, please don't jump my ass. I'm just trying to point out, they weren't just lucky and rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902175822.0" user="9yr_old_lake" delta="False">
    <text>You are not very smart if you think Elon musk invented ANYTHING. bro is the Thomas Edison of our generation. Not a great inventor just a rich hack.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902193983.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>Okay? He got his cash differently from that list you provided, woop-te-doo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902259567.0" user="9yr_old_lake" delta="False">
    <text>So he didn't work for it lmao. He has had everything handed to him his entire life. Bill gates and mark Zuckerberg did actually have to put some work in, but not like an insane amount. Most of their wealth came from having really good connections through their parents. The point is that no one is rich because THEY worked hard. They are rich because of the culmination of the level of multiple generations, and usually the ones that actually get the insane wealth did the least amount of work. Wealth is built in multiple generations not just one. And if someone does go from poor as fuck to rich as fuck it's because they hit the lottery eaither literally or figuratively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902414519.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>What about people who do work hard and become rich though?

Footballers are a prime example of people from Poor backgrounds working hard and becoming Millionaires. Actors and Musicians too, there are plenty of stories of people becoming rich in life through hard work, including in business. By working hard, advancing their career and getting promotions then moving to other places. It happens all the time. The person flipping a burger at McDonalds, never applying for a promotion or higher paying job elsewhere and just working isn't gonna be rich. And even if they go work hard to advance, someone else might come along with more talent and take the promotion instead. 

My whole point was that "hard work" doesn't mean go to the same minimum wage job for 20 years and expect to be rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902498762.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Footballers are a prime example of people from Poor backgrounds working hard and becoming Millionaires. Actors and Musicians too, 

Almost always because of some unimaginable luck. Do you think that every kid who's that good at football/acting/music is going to become famous, making millions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904775630.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>No, I said they worked hard for it and got it, not that everyone does and should get it. That was part of my very first point as well, even if you do work hard, sometimes someone else with talent or skill or luck or personality or charisma or looks or whatever else will come and get it instead. That's just life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904791427.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>But that doesn't mean that someone who didn't get that luck is lazy or stupid or lesser in any way than the person who did get that lucky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904803845.0" user="Swing-Full" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I never said they were.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902464694.0" user="YuenglingsDingaling" delta="False">
    <text>Bill and Mark came from upper middle class. Like, their parents where not even millionaires.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902569457.0" user="9yr_old_lake" delta="False">
    <text>Yea and they had REALLY fucking good connections plus plenty of luck and a little hard work made them millionaires, but the point is hard work is the least contributing factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903116830.0" user="TwirlySocrates" delta="False">
    <text>That's not true. Doctors are paid better than most jobs, but it's not because there's a consiparacy of corrupt doctors to bleed the people of their money. It's partly because training to be a doctor is hard work.

The game isn't always fair to be sure. There's a lot of people who don't have the money or opportunity to undergo medical training (or other well-paying jobs).  But that doesn't mean there is no link between hard work and reward.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903540333.0" user="6InchAssholeWidth" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Hardest working people I know doing 3 jobs are trapped in poverty. 

This is a perfect example of someone not understanding correlation and causation.

People with 3 jobs are obviously poor people because rich people only work 1 job max. People with 3 jobs are also going to be hard workers.

There is a correlation between poverty and hard work but it only exists because poor people have to work hard to survive.

This does not mean that hard work being a benefit is a myth. A hard working person is obviously more likely to achieve high rates of success in the workplace because their employer can make more money off them than a lazy person.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
