<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902318242.0" user="-paperbrain-" delta="False">
    <text>How do you feel about handicap parking spaces? Or disability SSI?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902370929.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>Fuck ‘‘em they should walk! Nah I’m just kidding lol I replied to a few people’s comments and I didn’t explain exactly what I meant and it seems like I was talking about equity in every instance that’s my mistake I should have been more clear. 

I mostly meant in situations where ability or skills snd qualifications are ignored to favor others who are less qualified or aren’t the best candidate but for the sake of inclusion everyone gets the same end result regardless of anything else</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902407508.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>Then you need to be more clear if you think equality and equity are good/bad only sometimes. You need to organize your thoughts better.

Nowhere is ability ignored. Even the closest and most controversial one, affirmative action, is about selecting between various all able and all qualified people. 

This is done a) because school isn't viewed as the end result, just a step towards career and wealth, so giving an equitable leg up to disenfranchised groups isn't equal outcome but equal opportunity. Whatever your end result is still up to you. b) Nobody who's able is ignored. The #1 SAT whatever is still going to the top schools and careers. Just with more diversity in each school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902677239.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; talking about equity in every instance that’s my mistake I should have been more clear.

You should make a new post or atleast add an edit because these views are widely different to the point you are going to have a lot of "non-applicable" comments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903908058.0" user="Patarokun" delta="False">
    <text>What you're not taking into account is that maybe a college or a company finds value in a diverse student body/work force that can bring a variety of life experience to the table.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
