<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902030598.0" user="ParagoonTheFoon" delta="False">
    <text>It's not as simple as equality good, equity bad. They're not unrelated. Often, providing equality in one regard is only to provide equity in another regard, or vice versa. 

 Equity can be used to promote equality of opportunity for example - you might have someone who grew up poor and received a poor education, and someone who grew up rich with tutors. In this case, you might give the poor student advantages to make up for their lack of education when applying for college, since this upholds a meritocracy based on intelligence rather than privilege - you treat them differently to give them the same shot at getting into college. What you did was give equitable treatment (not equal), in order to provide equality of opportunity. Or when it comes to helping survivors of an earthquake. You don't want to give them equal treatment, all the same amount of time. You want equity - you want those who have the most severe injuries given the most treatment and time. 

I think that it is more so the sort of equity or 'equality of outcome' that disrupts desirable meritocracies (like ones based on intelligence, ability, qualification) which are debatably bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902056898.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I get you I didn’t flesh out my point well enough I didn’t mean in all situations like your earthquake example but I mean more for jobs or areas where ability and qualifications are a factor and rather than chose the best ones there’s a representation % they are trying to achieve</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902170055.0" user="The_FriendliestGiant" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is, you cannot take an unequal starting position and just announce at an arbitrary point that from now there's going to be equal opportunity without enforcing some kind of equity system. Without an external force to actually level the playing field, you're left claiming that it's now completely equal for the children of generational wealth and privilege to compete with the children of generational poverty and discrimination, as though they're both starting from anything like an equal position.

If a society has had an extended period of unequal wealth distribution or racial, gender, sexual, or religious discrimination, you first need to ensure a period in which equity is enforced in order to eventually be able to claim that equality is meaningfully in effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903148940.0" user="crumblingcloud" delta="False">
    <text>What about other traits that people are born with, are there equity for that? Such as height and looks. There are countless studies about taller people making more money and very high paying jobs reserved for good looking people. You cant have selective equity for certain groups but not others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903913294.0" user="Quaysan" delta="False">
    <text>It's harder to crack down on those things, but it's not like people AREN'T working on it.

The body positivity movement, though focused on a few specific areas, is still inclusive. The push to become inclusive of trans people has ripples and waves, removing the expectation for what a person of a specific gender looks like removes the stigma of not matching that expectation. Social movements dedicated to fair pay and unionization will also help make sure that people who contribute specific skills over time are paid well.

It's not really enough to point out where things aren't going well, you have to follow up and push through with the thought. "What about other traits?" Well, what's the next logical conclusion after arguing that equity should exist? 

If Equity doesn't exist for everyone, that doesn't mean it's a bad idea, it just means that we still have work to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904321778.0" user="crumblingcloud" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with provide bare basic needs but you cant make unequal people equal. No matter how hard i practice basketball i cant be the next lebron james, 


Forcing quotas on schools and companies is not victimless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42906629270.0" user="Quaysan" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody expects everyone to achieve the same results as the best or greatest. We just don't want people to miss out on potentially becoming the next lebron james because their parents couldn't afford to give them dinner every day.

The idea of equality and equity isn't to make the end goal the same for everyone, it's to make the starting line the same for everyone.

Nobody is going to make Lebron dunk on a 6 foot high hoop. I feel like you fundamentally don't understand what people are trying to do when they initiate things like affirmative action.

If a person gets into a school or hired for a job because of affirmative action, it's not because they don't have the ability to succeed at that school or job. Affirmative action is just a policy put into place so that bias against people who aren't commonly accepted goes away. 

Forcing quotas is sometimes necessary because people may have biases they don't recognize. Remember the name bias study? [People with less western/european names were less likely to receive a response from employers despite having similar/equal accreditation.](https://www.nber.org/papers/w9873)

There's a myth that affirmative action gives jobs to people who don't deserve it, I believe that you may either consciously or subconsciously believe that.

Affirmative action just makes it more possible for the next Michio Kaku to become the next Michio Kaku.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905436970.0" user="The_FriendliestGiant" delta="False">
    <text>That the world cannot be made perfect is not a valid reason not to work to improve it as much as possible. Especially when comparing the effect of unconscious individual bias (height and looks) with persistent generational institutional discrimination. 

It's not a matter of having selective equity, as though people are deliberately setting out to reserve privileges for the good looking. It's simply a matter of not every issue having a solution, but not letting that prevent work towards solutions that do exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902978189.0" user="Eagle_Chick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I didn’t flesh out my point well enough 

That should be a delta- not oh, I'd like to add something..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902120594.0" user="grantcoolguy" delta="False">
    <text>Great point, well written.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42912935946.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902853741.0" user="Comfortable_Tart_297" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes of course that meritocracy based exclusively on intelligence or innate potential is most desirable. Usually there is also a component of aptitude and virtue in addition; otherwise we should just admit people based on iq.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903141253.0" user="crumblingcloud" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you on socio-economic equity but i cant get behind the race version. There can be wealthy and privileged people of color who do not need the privilege</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
