<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901922386.0" user="team-tree-syndicate" delta="False">
    <text>The idea of meritocracy sounds great on paper but is quite delicate to make a reality. Obviously if someone is a genius and works hard and makes the right moves they should be rewarded as such, but not everyone can do that. Not everyone can function in a meritocracy. A counterargument to this is that people who don't provide a large merit to society shouldn't be super rich or get big benefits. The problem is that *most* people can't be CEO's or astronauts or shareholders, most people are stuck working normal jobs.

Not that this is a huge problem by itself, but when the rewards for doing these jobs now is the ability to barely afford food or a roof over your head it becomes a big problem. Not to mention the generational handicap minorities face, the ever increasing barrier to education or home ownership, the barrier to entry for living in a city rapidly rising etc. A meritocracy can work but the people who are at the bottom still need to be able to.. live.. and eat and stuff. If that isn't the case things will fall apart really fast.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902030953.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>I get where you’re coming from and you made some really great points but I don’t fully agree with your point of “Most people are stuck working normal jobs… the rewards for doing so are barely affording food or a roof” What jobs are you referring to? If you’re referring to minimum wage jobs of course they struggle to get by minimum wage jobs aren’t meant to support a family or to be there long term. They are for kids and students to get some experience and money until they can pursue a career. 

While there’s definitely a generational handicap I think the greater issue is to allow it to be a handicap hear me out for a second. One of the most highly educated and successful groups of people in the US are Nigerian immigrants these people aren’t coming to the US with very much they would essentially be in a very similar situation to someone coming from an impoverished community a victim of the generational handicap but the difference is they aren’t using that as an excuse to not try they are coming over and working very very hard to get to a successful position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902223298.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What jobs are you referring to? If you’re referring to minimum wage jobs of course they struggle to get by minimum wage jobs aren’t meant to support a family or to be there long term.

There are very few minimum wage jobs. 

But can you seriously tell me that someone making $12.50 an hour can afford a decent quality of life, even though that's an entire $5 an hour more than minimum?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902348622.0" user="TrenbolognaSammies" delta="False">
    <text>     Nobody is forcing them to work a shitty paying job we all have the opportunity to get a better job and leave the low paying ones for retired people wanting to do something or students and teenagers. Alot of people give up and make excuses for themselves. They don’t try for anything better that put absolutely zero effort into their lives, make poor decisions like having multiple children too young with multiple people and expect to have the world given to them. Have success fall right into their lap but they don’t do anything other than complain about it not being fair or making it about race or gender instead of their own lack of effort. These days we absolutely love making excuses and not taking accountability it’s always someone else’s fault, so many people just don’t try. 

    I hear some people say that they don’t have the money to go to school or they don’t have time but you really don’t need school to get a well paying job. I think for a lot of people post secondary education is actually counterproductive,a waste of time and a fantastic way to put yourself into a lot of debt. A good group of people don’t think about the demand for jobs in the field they wish to study. They complain they can’t find work because they got a degree in gender studies or something that may have interested them but you gotta think of the demand.

   I dropped out of university and I now work a union construction job I got an apprenticeship and have great benefits make 40+ an hour will eventually be at 50-50+ I make way more money than most of my friends that went to these big name universities to study something that has no demand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902380739.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>Why does your post look like that? 

Do you have any tips for helping people in small towns find better-paying jobs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902309422.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>Nigerian people who are in extreme poverty have no means of traveling to the U.S., even to live here as undocumented immigrants. They can’t get the funds together due to the fact that they don’t have much extra money and the exchange rate is terrible. On top of that, they can’t get tourist visas because in order to do that, you need to prove that you have a good job to return to in Nigeria. I’m having trouble finding statistics because everything I can find groups together first and second generation Nigerians in the US, but I believe even first generation Nigerian immigrants tend to come to the US with higher education levels than average. So their kids then have a leg up on the competition. It really isn’t the same as people coming here from Honduras or even the same as people who have lived in the US for many generations but impoverished. 

Another thing to consider is that when a Nigerian immigrant to the U.S. helps out his family members financially, the amount of money he gives them is very small, in US dollars, compared to what someone born in the US would need to give their impoverished family members to help them out. This is because of exchange rates. This makes it easier, in many cases, for immigrants to to save money than for poor people born here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902417635.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What jobs are you referring to? If you’re referring to minimum wage jobs of course they struggle to get by minimum wage jobs aren’t meant to support a family or to be there long term.

I have a kid who graduated with a 3.2 GPA from a moderately well-regarded business school. He's been sending out 20+ job applications a day for any opening anywhere in the country that he qualifies for. He has had 2 interviews in the last 3 months.   


I'm a hiring manager, his resume is well done. But just to check we had a 3rd party expert look it over for us.   


And it's not like he has nothing on his resume. He's been a manager for a set of 6 Subway franchises, he's been a sous chef on a passenger train.   


He can not find a job that pays him enough to rent an apartment of his own.    


So, I'm thinking you have no idea what you're talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903003212.0" user="team-tree-syndicate" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you’re referring to minimum wage jobs of course they struggle to get by minimum wage jobs aren’t meant to support a family or to be there long term. They are for kids and students to get some experience and money until they can pursue a career. 

This is just wrong though. Minimum wage jobs used to actually be really good and support a whole family easily.

Minimum wage jobs aren't also just temporary school kid jobs anymore, you will now find even higher position jobs in management or ASGM jobs paying close to minimum wage. I was barely making above minimum as a manager which required a college bachelor's.

Also, how are you supposed to buy a house when they have increased like 10x to 20x in price yet even good jobs still have the same wage? Even if you are educated and have a good job you can't afford a house now. Compare this to my grandparents buying a house off of 1 income on minimum wage. Things are very different now.

"Minimum wage shouldn't support a family and house" is just rich people rhetoric to excuse the fact that they've jacked up the prices sky high by paying politicians to screw over the public. Minimum wage used to be able to do this.

Also, if minimum wage jobs are just for school kids to gain experience then how are they supposed to be able to afford college which has also increased like 10x to 20x in price?

You can say all you want that there are ways to get past all of these barriers, and yes there are ways, but my point is that these are new barriers propped up that didn't exist before, created by greed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
