<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42902161090.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Equity is not the guarantee of equal outcomes. Equity is equality in the context of variable reality. Everyone isn't given the same chances. That just doesn't happen. Nature gives some people a hard disadvantage. Privilege gives other advantages few will ever experience. Equity is not equality of outcomes, but an equalization of inherent inequalities. 

Equality is sharing evening equally with no regard for who has more and who has less. Equity isn't taking and redistributing everything equally. Equity is most simply a reconsideration of who gets how much when sharing. 

The dictionary definition or rather the first result I got from Googling which was on a dictionary website is to be fair and impartial. Treating people equally is often a way to be fair and to be impartial. However when people themselves are unequal in their situations being equally giving or equally punishing to them has unequal results. 

It's certainly unreasonable to expect an equality of outcome over everything and everyone but perhaps its considerably less unreasonable even reasonable to consider the expectation of a righting force toward inequality away from inequality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903294899.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The dictionary definition or rather the first result I got from Googling which was on a dictionary website is to be fair and impartial. Treating people equally is often a way to be fair and to be impartial. However when people themselves are unequal in their situations being equally giving or equally punishing to them has unequal results.

Okay, well, let's look at what the US government says about equity:

&amp;#x200B;

[https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/](https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/)

&amp;#x200B;

"By advancing equity across the Federal Government, we can create opportunities for the improvement of communities that have been historically underserved, which benefits everyone.  For example, an analysis shows that closing racial gaps in wages, housing credit, lending opportunities, and access to higher education would amount to an additional $5 trillion in gross domestic product in the American economy over the next 5 years.  The Federal Government’s goal in advancing equity is to provide everyone with the opportunity to reach their full potential.  Consistent with these aims, each agency must assess whether, and to what extent, its programs and policies perpetuate systemic barriers to opportunities and benefits for people of color and other underserved groups.  Such assessments will better equip agencies to develop policies and programs that deliver resources and benefits equitably to all.  "

&amp;#x200B;

This does not actually sound like treating people fairly and impartially. It looks like it's about treating them *partially* in order to *redress historical inequalities*.

This may or may not be good. I am not going to argue about that. But it is just not the case that in the 21st century political context "equity" means "treating people fairly and impartially."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903813462.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Partially in order to redress history, or just in acknowledgement that without some additional effort that history has taught we won't be fair? 

Honestly even partially to redress history the way that says works pretty well. It's to give and give back opportunity that has been historically denied or taken away.

Like I'm reading the same thing you are and between the lines I'm reading '...and paying special attention to actually be fair to all the people we've been woefully unfair to in the past.'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42904270615.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Honestly even partially to redress history the way that says works pretty well. It's to give and give back opportunity that has been historically denied or taken away.

Right, again, I am not going to argue whether doing this is good or bad. I am just saying that it is not *treating everyone impartially* to give back a historically denied opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42905738172.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Sure it is. It's pretty much by definition. Impartiality is the fair and just treatment of parties that don't treat each other fairly. The first Google result I got is the fair and just treatment of rivals. I think we can just abstract "rival" to something less adversarial and say people just don't treat each other fairly or impartially. Without an extra step in effort to be fair and impartial people aren't fair and impartial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42908586478.0" user="DouglerK" delta="False">
    <text>Huh OP was removed. Go figure. Not to project that onto you but if you're stepping in to argue the same thing as the OP then I just hope you've got a little more intellectual honesty there. 

Ill repeat that pushing for an equality of outcome is unreasonable. There will always be inequality. Expecting otherwise is childish and naive.

I will also repeat however it is as I argued pretty much the definition of impartiality to be taking action to ensure fairness and equality are upheld where it is not or has not been. If we have data that says things aren't impartial, fair or just then it is absolutely impartial, fair and just to address that

Redressing historical wrongs isn't just about doing something special for or apologizing to descendents because their grandparents or ancestors got the shaft. It's showing consideration for how their grandparents' situation affects their current opportunities today. As well it is considering how their grandparents situation, although arguably much worse in the past, is still their situation. Racism has changed and evolved and arguably lessened greatly since the mid-20th century but its not like it just magically went away.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
