<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901780735.0" user="caveman44_" delta="False">
    <text>Equity isn’t a bad idea in the short-term as it allows the creation of a more *permanent* equality of opportunity. Oppression is generational and doesn’t disappear just because everyone technically has the same opportunities. We should be trying to maximize fairness by reversing a lot of historical damage to marginalized groups so that one day there will be only tests of merit. But forcing equity forever is not sustainable and will do more harm than good, I agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901809009.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Equity is a terrible idea. It requires you to shit on people who are productive at the expensive of people who are not. It's literally the exact opposite of the incentive structure that you want. 

You're telling all the people who are hard working and who invest their time in learning their skill that they are suckers.

You're telling all the people who do fuck all with their lives that they made the right decisions. 

Equality of opportunity is a very good standard. Equality of outcomes can only exist in the most ineptly run societies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901849288.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Equality of opportunity is a very good standard.

Okay, well creating equality of opportunity will require us to favour equity, as people are born in unequal circumstances and will require different levels of support to achieve equality of opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901858998.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>No equality of opportunity doesn't care a bout that.

It means everyone has a path they can take. That doesn't mean that the path is the same level of difficulty. 

I had the same path that Lebron James had to the NBA. But he is wayyyyyy more talented than me. The path being there is the key. If I had the same merit as Lebron I'd be playing in the NBA too. But I don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901870192.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>You'd think "equality of opportunity" means have equal opportunities. What you're describing here isn't equality of opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901899298.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I had the same exact opportunities as Lebron James. The problem is he is way more talented than me. Had I shown up to High School and scored 60 points a game every single game. Because I am a monster physically. I too would be playing in the NBA. Regardless of where I came from, what my skin color was etc etc etc.

That is the key to equality of opportunity. That everyone who has merit. Has a path to develop themselves into something.

That is why we have public schools. That is why we have scholarships, grants, financial aid etc. So people can develop their talent regardless of their origin. 

Equality of opportunity does not mean "shit on others at the expense of those who don't want to help themselves".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901932769.0" user="caveman44_" delta="False">
    <text>Merit is genetics. In order to truly see merit, you have to reverse historical oppression that negatively affects generations of upbringings. Because both nature and nurture are important. What we are concerned with is advancing the species and that means giving those with potential a better chance. As I said, equity is not something that should be permanent and ubiquitous. It is useful temporarily to reverse unfairness due to the past.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901949295.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Merit is not just genetics.

If I have an IQ of 160. But I play video games all day long and show no earthly interest in learning any productive skill. I don't have any merit.

Merit is both nature and nurture. 

If the same IQ 160 guy uses his talents to sell drugs. He doesn't have any merit either. 

The best thing to do is make sure everyone has a path they can take. Which is why we have things like scholarships, grants, financial aid, food stamps etc. 

Some degree of support for the sake of developing talent is a good idea. But the equity people take it way too far. They don't want to hear that some people are more talented and certain populations tend to make very poor life choices which explains why they don't take advantage of the mountains of opportunities they have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901950633.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>Equality of opportunity would mean people have an equal shot at succes, which is obviously not the case here. I was born to wealthy parents, in a rich part of town, in the richest nation on earth. I spawned on third base. All I needed to do to end up in like the 10% of earners is to not fuck up massively. The idea this massive leg up did not change anything in my final circumstances - or my relative merit - is a bit ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901974970.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Your parents behavior is part of your merit. You are their child after all. 

Whether we like it or not. The decisions our parents make. Have a huge effect on our lives.

Going back to my Lebron James analogy. It's not time to change the rules of basketball just to make sure barbodelli has the same shot at being in the NBA. Which I'm not even sure what those rule changes would be. Maybe Lebron can only make 1/3 pointers because of his height or something. Because that will not make NBA a better league. By having a bunch of low talent people playing there. 

In your profession. Did everyone have wealthy or well off parents? Cause that's certainly not the case in mine. Many people came from the lower class. 

And what exactly are you suggesting? That we take away kids from their parents and raise them in some Soviet camps? That would be horrific for everyone. But hey it would definitely go a long way towards equity. Funny thing is even in that scenario there would be a few winners and a whole bunch of losers just like now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902472231.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>My parents behaviour cannot be part of my merit. They're not me. That's not how merit works. That's my whole point. 

&gt; In your profession. Did everyone have wealthy or well off parents? Cause that's certainly not the case in mine. Many people came from the lower class.

A very large majority of my colleagues - that's true in my workplace now, but it was true in college as well - come from very similar backgrounds. Very few of them could be qualified as coming from lower classes. 

&gt; And what exactly are you suggesting?

I'm suggesting that a society that sees some being born on third base and others having to start from less than scratch - then treat these two groups the same - isn't a society of "equality of opportunity".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902516370.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>They are you. You are them. 25% of your genes come from each grandparent. You are the amalgamation of your grandparents genetically speaking.

&gt;I'm suggesting that a society that sees some being born on third base and others having to start from less than scratch - then treat these two groups the same - isn't a society of "equality of opportunity".

As long as they have the same path to build and show their ability. They are.

I keep going back to my Lebron James example. Me and him went to the same public schools. Had access to the same High School basketball teams. My high school basketball team has produced a couple of NBA players. The most notable of which is Vernon Maxwell. If I played like those guys I would be in the NBA.

Equality of opportunity means you have a path. But it doesn't mean you have what it takes to walk it. It merely makes sure that those that do have what it takes to walk it. Are able to do it. Does that make sense? 

The high school basketball team is the equal opportunity me, Maxwell and Lebron James had.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901962710.0" user="Natural-Arugula" delta="False">
    <text>Equality under the law means both the rich and the poor are banned from sleeping under bridges.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901854657.0" user="caveman44_" delta="False">
    <text>The people who are harmed by equity practices are not harmed near as much as those who have been affected by historical inequality. And those people are benefited greatly by equity, as their success will potentially be generational, ending the need for equity in the future. 

So you didn’t get accepted to the top university because of equity…so what? There are still plenty of opportunities for you. This is like saying the rich shouldn’t be taxed more heavily than the poor. They will be fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901875632.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Equality of opportunity needs to be the standard. 

Not making things easier for people who don't work as hard or who are not as talented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901898601.0" user="caveman44_" delta="False">
    <text>As I said, just because everyone *seems* to have the same opportunity doesn’t mean they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901922508.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>The way it's measured is fucked up.

Let's compare me and Lebron James. I too played basketball a lot as a kid. But I'm not 6 foot 9 of pure athletic muscle.

One of these equity guys. Who completely disregard the concept of natural talent. Will look at the fact that I never earned a brown penny playing basketball meanwhile Lebron is earning more in a year than I do in a lifetime. And conclude that we had different opportunities. Even though our opportunities were identical. 

You can't point at discrepancies in outcomes and use that as evidence that the opportunities are different. The merit might be different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901946589.0" user="caveman44_" delta="False">
    <text>Being poor and living in a poor community and being raised by parents carrying generational trauma is not equality of opportunity, especially in academic affairs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901984015.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>If they have the same paths available to them it is. 

Equality of opportunity doesn't mean that we make it easy. And that certain people won't find it easier.

Lebron James and me had the same exact path to the NBA. But he was talented and I wasn't. The fact that I didn't make it doesn't mean that the path was somehow different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
