<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2450483461.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14iyd51/cmv_as_a_society_we_have_started_to_blur_the/">
    <title>CMV: As a society we have started to blur the lines between equity and equality, although equality is good equity is not.</title>
    <original_poster>TrenbolognaSammies</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve noticed that a large number of people have confused the meanings of equity and equality and have been pushing more towards equity. Obviously equality is ideal because everyone deserves to have the same opportunities to work or further their education to eventually reach the same end goal regardless of race or gender etc. I’m not saying they should be guaranteed the same goal as equity would suggest but they should have the possibility so long as they work hard and check all the boxes on the way. I’ve noticed however this is no longer enough and many people think that equity is the way to go and that we shouldn’t only have equal opportunities but also we should have equal outcomes and this is not fair or a good thing to implement in society. 
    Everyone should have the same opportunities available if they chose to work hard and take all the necessary steps to achieve the same results but guaranteeing the same outcome or results for all is not only not fair but is counter productive and shouldn’t be the case. If someone doesn’t work as hard or makes poor decisions how is it fair that they achieve the same outcome as someone who worked very hard and made great choices? It’s important to understand the difference between the two concepts and make sure that we value equality and fairness rather than to strive for equity. Hard work should be the standard and should be rewarded if everyone achieves the same results regardless of how much they put into it what’s the motivation for anyone to work really hard?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42901746733.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>Quick question:

How do you feel about wheelchair ramps on government buildings?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901834924.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>I’m curious where you are going with this line of questioning.

Are you suggesting that being black is equivalent to a permanent physical handicap that bounds them entirely outside their control?

If it were the case that all physical ailments were treatable by physical therapy, would you still advocate for the same level of enforcement of the ADA or would you be comfortable with a less absolutist approach to disabilities (like Europe with their older buildings)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42901936019.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>Where I'm aiming is that ramps are an example of equity, not equality. It's not just that everyone gets the same things provided for them, but rather that we make sure that the things we provide are sufficient for *everyone* to be able to realistically achieve the goal (in this case, entering the building).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902095044.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite the same. I don’t have to be handicapped to take the ramp. Anyone can use it. The kind of equity the left push via redistribution is zero sum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902187765.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The kind of equity the left push via redistribution is zero sum.

I don't think that's true at all. I'm pretty far left, and I see talk of equity in my workplace all the time because I'm a teacher. I always have a few students with IEPs and similar plans that require that I give certain acommodations to those students. You know who complains if I make the same accommodations to all students? Nobody. Nobody complains. And I do that on a fairly regular basis. If I have a student who has an acommodation that I make completed notes available to them, I'll post them for the whole class. I've given additional test time to students who give me reason to believe that they're taking longer than expected for any reason other than lack of understanding of the material.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902327199.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>The kind of equity the left push for includes wheelchair ramps. There’s no way to claim that wheelchair ramps are not an example of leftist efforts toward greater equity</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902901553.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>You are still not getting it. 

The wheelchair ramp is for everyone. You do not have to be in an wheelchair to use it. It is providing greater equity without picking winners and losers. 

On the other hand, leftist policy like UBI absolutely has winners and losers. Namely, the people who pay the taxes are the losers since they are net negative and people who pay nothing in taxes are winners.

That is why no one raises a fuss about wheelchair ramps and no one in position of significance talks about UBI.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903097828.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t have to be in a wheelchair to use a ramp, but almost everywhere with ramps will have stairs as well. And able bodied people tend to prefer stairs. It doesn’t really matter at all though. If a place has a wheelchair lift, which can only be used by people in wheelchairs, I don’t think able bodied people would care. The fact that anyone can use a ramp is irrelevant to any point any of us might be trying to make here. Able bodied people have stairs— they’re able to get to the top whether or not someone adds a mechanism to enable wheelchair users (and/or other disabled people) to get to the top as well. 

I’m not sure where UBI entered the conversation. We’re talking about equity and equality. OP didn’t say anything about UBI and we have no reason to think that’s on topic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902382595.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;the left push via redistribution is zero sum

I strongly suggest you read "[Utopia for Realists](https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40876575-utopia-for-realists)" for a look at some real-world experiments done in numerous countries showing that redistribution is not zero sum.

Simply saying something is true doesn't really stand up to actual experiments that showed the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902827850.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;redistribution is not zero sum.

For the people actually doing the paying, yes it is zero sum. And your book is exact proof of it.

Where do you think the resources for eradicating poverty comes from? Or UBI? Not from the poor that don't pay taxes to begin with. Thanks for proving my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902837378.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For the people actually doing the paying, yes it is zero sum

Except it isn't.

But hey, thanks for proving you're interested in saying "nuh uh" instead of having an informed discussion.

People spend money when they have money to spend. That increases the amount of money in circulation, which has a multiplicative effect. It also increases the velocity of money in circulation due to some other add-on effects. Both of these are overtly beneficial to those who aren't poor.

Further, doing things like basic income can reduce or eliminate vast swaths of bureaucracy, and the associated costs that go with that. Which can be quite significant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902994896.0" user="movingtobay2019" delta="False">
    <text>Except it is. Because when I get taxed $50k a year by the fed and my UBI is $9k, I am net negative. 

Versus someone who pays $0 in federal income tax and gets $9k in UBI. 

It's very simple math. Are you actually denying I lose money in this scenario? Yes or no? 

&gt;But hey, thanks for proving you're interested in saying "nuh uh" instead of having an informed discussion.

Your idea of an informed discussion was to point me to a book written by someone with zero economic or financial background?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903141309.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>Playing 0 sum games with economics demonstrates either a lack of seriousness or familiarity or both.  


&gt;Your idea of an informed discussion was to point me to a book written by someone with zero economic or financial background? 

Who fairly reported the results of several experiments on various methods from the available documents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902336165.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>If all physical ailments were treatable with physical therapy, we would live in a completely different world. The one we live in works differently, so why would we need to make up a fake world in order to talk about issues of equality and equity in the real world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902658150.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>The point of analogies &amp; hypotheticals is to test the principals behind a structure and see if they continue to hold. 

If they do not, it suggests their might be a flaw in the rationale.

The person above led with analogies about wheelchairs rather than directly addressing the real world scenario at hand. Does that bother you too? It’s interesting your replying to me and not them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902672022.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>Oh buddy. You’re so stuck in your own way of thinking that you can’t see the obvious. They weren’t making an analogy. It was an example. Wheelchair ramps are a real life example of when we all generally agree on choosing equity over equality. There’s no analogy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902897178.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>Citing an example of physical access equity as evidence we should apply equity principals to other scenarios *is the analogy*. 

People are not aligned on race base equity.

So the poster asked a rhetorical question that basically translates to “*because you are implicitly in favor of physical access equity, you should therefore be for job-employment equity*”.

For that assertion to work, they are implicitly stating being black is *like* being handicapped (as an immutable physical characteristic) and education-job opportunities are *like* a building without wheelchair access because you cannot access them (ostensibly due to no fault of your own).

That is an analogy. And I reject it that analogy on multiple dimensions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42902961379.0" user="g11235p" delta="False">
    <text>OP made a post about equity versus equality. The only specifics in the post are about “race, gender, etc.” It’s completely normal, in all discussions of equity and equality, to discuss disability. It can reasonably be assumed that in conversations about this subject, the people talking are considering disability. Again, there’s no analogy. 

It’s possible that OP just wasn’t considering disability when they condemned the entire concept of equity, but they certainly never said that in their statement of their view that they want to see changed, so it’s fair game</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903501431.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; like being handicapped (as an immutable physical characteristic

Not at all correct. Handicaps aided by these measures are *frequently* temporary and caused by circumstances. 

Wheelchair ramps are equitable to *both* paraplegics *and* people in a wheelchair for 3 months because a pig shot them in the knee. 

Whether you want to admit it or not, blacks in the US suffer under numerous challenges that are not "permanent characteristics" but are, instead, caused by external biases and disadvantages that can be alleviated so they can improve their situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903660934.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; that are, instead, caused by external biases and disadvantages that can be alleviated

What external biases specifically? The first priority is to identify and remove the barriers.

Alleviation of circumstance should be secondary. If you cannot clearly identify the barriers, we risk ghost hunting.

If a person had a broken leg, we would generally prioritize getting the leg healed over building ramps. If someone kept getting a fracture in the same place we would ask *why* instead of going “well, guess we need more wheelchair ramps”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903887677.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If a person had a broken leg, we would generally prioritize getting the leg healed over building ramps. 

No, the person with the broken leg would prioritize healing. 

"We" as in society, would both make healthcare available and build ramps to prepare for the inevitable people that will break their legs, and also of course the permanently disabled. 

But as for circumstance... there's no equal opportunity without alleviating that, so... might be a "secondary" priority, but really "we" are many, and can work on many things at once.

Also, there's a whole stream of people coming along all the time... best to be prepared.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42903343185.0" user="The_Confirminator" delta="False">
    <text>Does he have to go anywhere? If the wheelchair example is sufficient, then OP should in theory have his mind changed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
