<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2452685301.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14k9k39/cmv_alpha_males_are_actually_95_percent_beta/">
    <title>CMV: Alpha males are actually 95 percent beta</title>
    <original_poster>chosenmadao</original_poster>
    <original_post>The others are human traffickers internet celebrities.  
I really don't believe this bullshit. I made a lot of observations in the military and people don't fit these patterns. The reason I'm writing this is because they contradict what they made up. they're all going after a few "alphas". but speaking by their rules, one alpha never follows another alpha. For example, andrew tat. This guy has millions of followers. most of them are men. others are probably female simps. now, if they are all alpha then what are all these alphas doing together? Why are alphas praising or defending andrew tate on the internet? All I see is adolescents who have not become individuals, have chosen a "male" role model for themselves from the internet. or, in their language, the alpha male gathered all betas around him.  
 just it. speaking by the book, an alpha never follows another alpha, when an alpha sees another alpha, he prepares for a fight. there is only one alpha in a group, there is no such thing as an assistant alpha. There are only loyal betas who take advantage of alpha. But, as far as I can see, these aren't even beta. fanboys only.  
Another contradiction (paradox?) "sigmas". I'll cut it short. why would a sigma have discussions with anonymous people on the internet about being sigma?   
Imagine that: Kai, the most famous sigma (who is a beyblade character, not kpop) is watching videos of the his sigma brothers to be cool (or make a girl). do you think this makes sense?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42913078108.0" user="Jebofkerbin" delta="False">
    <text>It's almost as if human behavior doesn't neatly map onto observations of how captive wolf populations organize themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913256072.0" user="NoVaFlipFlops" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We hate to break it to you, but wolf packs don’t actually have alpha males and females. The researcher who introduced this term tried to clear up what had happened many years ago, but thanks to pop culture and some money-hungry publishers the confusion still persists.

[Easy-to-read-article](https://www.iflscience.com/the-term-alpha-male-is-all-a-lie-66483) explains why the science behind wolf (and supposedly human) hierarchy is crap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913266283.0" user="Jebofkerbin" delta="False">
    <text>It was my understanding that wolves do form the alpha-beta structure, but only when you get a bunch that don't know each other and force them to live in an enclosure together.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913485610.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Which makes it like trying to map all of human psychology onto like, the cast interactions on Big Brother, yes. To what little extent alpha-beta structure in wolves exists, it's entirely artificial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914535011.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>This is an incredible analogy that I will now steal and use later</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913660017.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>It's not an "alpha-beta" structure. It's just a family structure with the older male and female taking on the mother/father role and the rest taking on the children role. The researcher who wrote the original, flawed paper has spent most of his professional career trying to correct that mistake and demonstrate how the captive wolves behaved very similarly to wild wolves with the exception that the wild ones tend to stay in family packs where they're all related by blood and the captives ones didn't because they couldn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913815071.0" user="nanotree" delta="False">
    <text>Completely. The people who think they are "alpha" have domination fantasies, and the only way they feel superior is to shit on others and make them feel bad for not having the things they have. The one thing I find interesting is how well it works. Ultimately it comes down to our competitive nature, which we have well documented and pretty well understood at this point. It's one reason why social media is such a problem, because everyone is showing off this superficial version of themselves and their lives. People see that and think they are missing out on something and it can turn into a depressive cycle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914154909.0" user="cbdqs" delta="False">
    <text>Ya, but since lobsters are way more similar to humans than wolves their brain chemistry is definitely analogous./s&gt;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914204870.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Don't fuck with me man, I'm the alpha lobster... I'm blue</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914496824.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
