<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2452685301.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14k9k39/cmv_alpha_males_are_actually_95_percent_beta/">
    <title>CMV: Alpha males are actually 95 percent beta</title>
    <original_poster>chosenmadao</original_poster>
    <original_post>The others are human traffickers internet celebrities.  
I really don't believe this bullshit. I made a lot of observations in the military and people don't fit these patterns. The reason I'm writing this is because they contradict what they made up. they're all going after a few "alphas". but speaking by their rules, one alpha never follows another alpha. For example, andrew tat. This guy has millions of followers. most of them are men. others are probably female simps. now, if they are all alpha then what are all these alphas doing together? Why are alphas praising or defending andrew tate on the internet? All I see is adolescents who have not become individuals, have chosen a "male" role model for themselves from the internet. or, in their language, the alpha male gathered all betas around him.  
 just it. speaking by the book, an alpha never follows another alpha, when an alpha sees another alpha, he prepares for a fight. there is only one alpha in a group, there is no such thing as an assistant alpha. There are only loyal betas who take advantage of alpha. But, as far as I can see, these aren't even beta. fanboys only.  
Another contradiction (paradox?) "sigmas". I'll cut it short. why would a sigma have discussions with anonymous people on the internet about being sigma?   
Imagine that: Kai, the most famous sigma (who is a beyblade character, not kpop) is watching videos of the his sigma brothers to be cool (or make a girl). do you think this makes sense?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42913110242.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe the alpha beta, etc ranking of human males makess any sense in the real world. But for the sake of arguement:

Andrew Tate can't possibly be sleeping with all the women in the world. So in theory it is possible for more than 5% of Tate fans to create their own human wolf packs, as long as Tate fans are a minority of the worlds male population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913225815.0" user="Kudgocracy" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it doesn't make sense because it's not actually a thing with any scientific grounding and it never has been.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913259089.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>Even in animals?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913263296.0" user="Kudgocracy" delta="False">
    <text>We're not talking about animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913280521.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>Where does the scientific grounding come from if not studying animals?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913285440.0" user="Kudgocracy" delta="False">
    <text>Scientific grounding for what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913299620.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yeah, it doesn't make sense because it's not actually a thing with any scientific grounding and it never has been.

Whatever you were refering to. I am interested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913367518.0" user="Kudgocracy" delta="False">
    <text>What you said, the dividing human males into alphas and betas, not making any sense in the real world.  Which of course it doesn't because it's based on any kind of scientific evidence whatsoever.  It's based on ONE small study of wolves in captivity (wolves are not humans, and thus this is irrelevant), the study couldn't be replicated, doesn't apply to wolves in the wild, and was eventually disbunked by the very author himself of the original study.  Not only is it a bad bunk study, but it's about wolves.  WOLVES ARE NOT HUMANS.  Boy, did it capture a lot of boring imaginations, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913404684.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's based on ONE small study of wolves in captivity (wolves are not humans, and thus this is irrelevant), the study couldn't be replicated, doesn't apply to wolves in the wild, and was eventually disbunked by the very author himself of the original study.

Well I'm glad wolves don't have to deal with that either. Re humans it seems like common sense to me, no need to get science involved.
When you said there was scientific grounding I imagined an experiment that resembled the show Love Island.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913586311.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I think it really depends on how you define alpha male.

If Alpha male is someone who has high status for no other reason than he is big and aggressive and thus the males around him don't challenge him as much. Then yeah that is definitely a thing in some environments. Particularly places like military basic training, jails and prisons. 

To a smaller extent it happens in many other places.

If you try to make someone like Putin or Biden the alpha male. Then yeah it sort of falls flat on its face. Most average young males could take those on in a fight no problem. There's far more nuance there in the hierarchy that has little to do with fighting prowess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913286630.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Not in the way that pop culture understands it, at least.

Many different species have many different dominance hierarchies, so what "alpha" means can vary radically from one to the next.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42913531887.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>There is a small wolf that lives in my house. Despite him being a 'good boy', he is always taking orders from this giant alpha monkey, and he doesn't get any babes because the monkey castrated him.

That's pretty beta if you ask me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914217572.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>its weakened cause you castrated it... it's also a dumb animal trained by thousands of years of being bred to be a companion

I guess... the wolves that dogs were domesticated from were betas..

it's all a very stupid way to think about people though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914317678.0" user="fghhjhffjjhf" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;it's also a dumb animal

Don't insult my wolf. Only I can insult my wolf, because I feed it, and wash it, and pick up its poop.

Also I am considering that I am in fact the beta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914329506.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>call me when picks up your poops heh</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
