<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2452685301.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14k9k39/cmv_alpha_males_are_actually_95_percent_beta/">
    <title>CMV: Alpha males are actually 95 percent beta</title>
    <original_poster>chosenmadao</original_poster>
    <original_post>The others are human traffickers internet celebrities.  
I really don't believe this bullshit. I made a lot of observations in the military and people don't fit these patterns. The reason I'm writing this is because they contradict what they made up. they're all going after a few "alphas". but speaking by their rules, one alpha never follows another alpha. For example, andrew tat. This guy has millions of followers. most of them are men. others are probably female simps. now, if they are all alpha then what are all these alphas doing together? Why are alphas praising or defending andrew tate on the internet? All I see is adolescents who have not become individuals, have chosen a "male" role model for themselves from the internet. or, in their language, the alpha male gathered all betas around him.  
 just it. speaking by the book, an alpha never follows another alpha, when an alpha sees another alpha, he prepares for a fight. there is only one alpha in a group, there is no such thing as an assistant alpha. There are only loyal betas who take advantage of alpha. But, as far as I can see, these aren't even beta. fanboys only.  
Another contradiction (paradox?) "sigmas". I'll cut it short. why would a sigma have discussions with anonymous people on the internet about being sigma?   
Imagine that: Kai, the most famous sigma (who is a beyblade character, not kpop) is watching videos of the his sigma brothers to be cool (or make a girl). do you think this makes sense?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42913774885.0" user="Direct_Manner_3868" delta="False">
    <text>That's crazy talk! Next thing you know, they'll be telling us that dogs don't actually see in black and white.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42914517625.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
