<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2454551757.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14ldk99/cmv_most_communities_are_echo_chambers_its_not/">
    <title>CMV: Most communities are echo chambers. It's not echo chambers that are inherently harmful, it's echo chambers that echo world-shaping ideas that are.</title>
    <original_poster>ivyinthewait</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most communities are echo chambers in order to create a civil environment. Racism, homophobia, ableism etc. tend to be filtered out of communities in order to protect the mental health of community members who are apart of these marginalised groups while also upholding a civil and non-toxic environment. This is an echo chamber because it causes a lack of exposure to alternative viewpoints. This specific type of echo chamber is the most popular form of echo chamber we see on the internet today and can be seen in places like music communities, gaming communities, art communities etc. I classify this form of echo chamber as harmless. An etiquette is required to form a community which considers the mental health of the members within it.  


The actual issue we have with "echo chambers" are the ideas they are echoing. Political echo chambers, conspiracy echo chambers, hate groups, pseudo-science or anti-science echo chambers, etc. These echo chambers are harmful due to the inherent world-shaping views that come with them. There is a difference between an echo chamber with a focus on creating a civil environment and an echo chamber that tries to pull you into a specific way to view the world and how the world should work. Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.   


&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42923429985.0" user="Sir_Charles_Phantom" delta="False">
    <text>Is it possible that echo chambers that are designed to create a civil environment can fall prey to becoming echo chambers that pull you into a specific way to view the world because those echo chambers don't allow dissent?  

Certain echo chambers are specifically designed to trap you in a bubble and then lie to you.  But it's hard to know if the ones that aren't designed for that, become susceptible to that, because nefarious actors, or obsessive "believers" know they have a captive audience.  

In a sense, the actual issue with echo chambers are that they're echo chambers.  Not that they shouldn't exist, but, rather, people need to be responsible with them.  Know that you need exposure to dissent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42923489365.0" user="ivyinthewait" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Is it possible that echo chambers that are designed to create a civil environment can fall prey to becoming echo chambers that pull you into a specific way to view the world because those echo chambers don't allow dissent?

!delta Yes, to an extent. A place that moderates racism could coerce people into an anti-racism worldview. So I guess I concede here a bit.

&gt;Certain echo chambers are specifically designed to trap you in a bubble and then lie to you. But it's hard to know if the ones that aren't designed for that, become susceptible to that, because nefarious actors, or obsessive "believers" know they have a captive audience.

Could you explain/expand this concept for me a little more?

&gt;In a sense, the actual issue with echo chambers are that they're echo chambers. Not that they shouldn't exist, but, rather, people need to be responsible with them. Know that you need exposure to dissent.

So you're saying that echo chambers don't necessarily need to stop existing, the problem is that it leads people to forget about the importance of hearing out all perspectives?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42924026209.0" user="Sir_Charles_Phantom" delta="False">
    <text>An echo chamber designed to cultivate an anti-racist worldview will tell you what is racist and what isn't.  And if you can't talk about what that means within the echo chamber by offering dissent, among other things, it becomes susceptible to nefarious people who want you to think things are racist when they aren't.  

I do see your point though.  A cigar web forum, for example, might not allow talk of politics, and racist comments are not tolerated.  This keeps the sub civil.  Although that type of thing isn't an echo chamber, because you can disagree about which cigars are best.  

I think I go back to the point that all echo chambers are potentially problematic and should be used with caution.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
