<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2454551757.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14ldk99/cmv_most_communities_are_echo_chambers_its_not/">
    <title>CMV: Most communities are echo chambers. It's not echo chambers that are inherently harmful, it's echo chambers that echo world-shaping ideas that are.</title>
    <original_poster>ivyinthewait</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most communities are echo chambers in order to create a civil environment. Racism, homophobia, ableism etc. tend to be filtered out of communities in order to protect the mental health of community members who are apart of these marginalised groups while also upholding a civil and non-toxic environment. This is an echo chamber because it causes a lack of exposure to alternative viewpoints. This specific type of echo chamber is the most popular form of echo chamber we see on the internet today and can be seen in places like music communities, gaming communities, art communities etc. I classify this form of echo chamber as harmless. An etiquette is required to form a community which considers the mental health of the members within it.  


The actual issue we have with "echo chambers" are the ideas they are echoing. Political echo chambers, conspiracy echo chambers, hate groups, pseudo-science or anti-science echo chambers, etc. These echo chambers are harmful due to the inherent world-shaping views that come with them. There is a difference between an echo chamber with a focus on creating a civil environment and an echo chamber that tries to pull you into a specific way to view the world and how the world should work. Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.   


&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42925108471.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
