<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2458830303.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14nx9lr/cmv_the_bare_minimum_skill_a_politician_should/">
    <title>CMV: The bare minimum skill a politician should have is the ability to speak and form coherent sentences.</title>
    <original_poster>dancartopb</original_poster>
    <original_post>Politicians should be able to speak clearly and explain their ideas in a way that everyone can understand. It's important for them to communicate well so that people know what they're thinking and what they want to do.  
  
The best example is John Fetterman, anytime he speaks he makes no sense. A lot of arguments people have are that he just can't speak clearly but mentally he is the same. I'm not convinced of that but even if that were true I still don't think he should be in office. There have been multiple times when he tried to speak in Congress and nobody was able to understand him, that in turn wastes taxpayer money and time for other issues that can be hashed out and solved.  
  
Some people would say, well Joe Biden, or Donald Trump can't speak clearly, in my opinion thats a completely different thing, at the end of the day they can convey ideas, regurgitate a scripted speech, and talk and have regular conversations with people. Sometimes they both say things that make no sense but its not consistent and not all the time.  
  
John Fetterman on the otherhand has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences, and thats why I think he should resign from office, or be forced out somehow.  
  
Ive thought about Stephen Hawking and yes he was a genius and unable to speak and thats the only semi convincing argument I can think of, and if John Fetterman was able to speak through a robot and rebuttal arguments and have conversations as well as Stephen Hawking was able to through a computer then id have no problem with that.  
  
I feel like people today are way to accepting where they would even argue for people with mental disorders such as people with down syndrome being in political office. And thats where we are headed to at this point.  
  
I'm open to hearing why someone would be against my view but the arguments ive already heard aren't convincing enough...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42947261926.0" user="DK98004" delta="False">
    <text>Being a politician is about getting elected, that’s the job.  You need to be chosen, by YOUR people.  If you can’t communicate, and you get elected, it is because the people voting thought other factors (political party, viewpoints, race, gender, endorsements, look,…) were more important than your communications skills.

The problem you’re pointing out is that once you get elected, being effective at legislating requires different skills.  The sad part is that doing the legislating is really complicated and hard.  Being good at helping your people (and, at its best, all people) seems impossible without communication skills, but that fact is so far removed from the job of getting elected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947488432.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with what your saying, so Congress should impeach whoever cannot speak clearly thats in Congress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947811886.0" user="DK98004" delta="False">
    <text>How does that help them get re-elected?  What you’ve proposing is that their voters will value the impeachment more than other things and use that to drive their vote.  Some options are likely off the table.  You can’t bring up or vote to impeach your own party.  If it’s the other party, it will just be seen as a political attack. Even worse, an impeachment is saying that their constituents don’t get THEIR representative.  Remember, politicians don’t get to select their colleagues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
