<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2458830303.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14nx9lr/cmv_the_bare_minimum_skill_a_politician_should/">
    <title>CMV: The bare minimum skill a politician should have is the ability to speak and form coherent sentences.</title>
    <original_poster>dancartopb</original_poster>
    <original_post>Politicians should be able to speak clearly and explain their ideas in a way that everyone can understand. It's important for them to communicate well so that people know what they're thinking and what they want to do.  
  
The best example is John Fetterman, anytime he speaks he makes no sense. A lot of arguments people have are that he just can't speak clearly but mentally he is the same. I'm not convinced of that but even if that were true I still don't think he should be in office. There have been multiple times when he tried to speak in Congress and nobody was able to understand him, that in turn wastes taxpayer money and time for other issues that can be hashed out and solved.  
  
Some people would say, well Joe Biden, or Donald Trump can't speak clearly, in my opinion thats a completely different thing, at the end of the day they can convey ideas, regurgitate a scripted speech, and talk and have regular conversations with people. Sometimes they both say things that make no sense but its not consistent and not all the time.  
  
John Fetterman on the otherhand has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences, and thats why I think he should resign from office, or be forced out somehow.  
  
Ive thought about Stephen Hawking and yes he was a genius and unable to speak and thats the only semi convincing argument I can think of, and if John Fetterman was able to speak through a robot and rebuttal arguments and have conversations as well as Stephen Hawking was able to through a computer then id have no problem with that.  
  
I feel like people today are way to accepting where they would even argue for people with mental disorders such as people with down syndrome being in political office. And thats where we are headed to at this point.  
  
I'm open to hearing why someone would be against my view but the arguments ive already heard aren't convincing enough...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42947580316.0" user="GadgetGamer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure Fetterman has his bad moments, but the first match I found when I searched for "John Fetterman speaking" came back with [this footage of him on a committee](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nLpdu0_3-G0) and he sounds fine to me. I mean, he sounds like the usual boring way most politicians speak on committees.

So you are wrong that he has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947801525.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Stop lieing to yourself</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948260034.0" user="GadgetGamer" delta="False">
    <text>What are you talking about. I literally gave you the link to the video that proves you wrong. Everything that he said was understandable. The witness who he was questioning had no problems understanding him and was able to answer his question.

So what is the lie?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948388079.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
