<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2458830303.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14nx9lr/cmv_the_bare_minimum_skill_a_politician_should/">
    <title>CMV: The bare minimum skill a politician should have is the ability to speak and form coherent sentences.</title>
    <original_poster>dancartopb</original_poster>
    <original_post>Politicians should be able to speak clearly and explain their ideas in a way that everyone can understand. It's important for them to communicate well so that people know what they're thinking and what they want to do.  
  
The best example is John Fetterman, anytime he speaks he makes no sense. A lot of arguments people have are that he just can't speak clearly but mentally he is the same. I'm not convinced of that but even if that were true I still don't think he should be in office. There have been multiple times when he tried to speak in Congress and nobody was able to understand him, that in turn wastes taxpayer money and time for other issues that can be hashed out and solved.  
  
Some people would say, well Joe Biden, or Donald Trump can't speak clearly, in my opinion thats a completely different thing, at the end of the day they can convey ideas, regurgitate a scripted speech, and talk and have regular conversations with people. Sometimes they both say things that make no sense but its not consistent and not all the time.  
  
John Fetterman on the otherhand has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences, and thats why I think he should resign from office, or be forced out somehow.  
  
Ive thought about Stephen Hawking and yes he was a genius and unable to speak and thats the only semi convincing argument I can think of, and if John Fetterman was able to speak through a robot and rebuttal arguments and have conversations as well as Stephen Hawking was able to through a computer then id have no problem with that.  
  
I feel like people today are way to accepting where they would even argue for people with mental disorders such as people with down syndrome being in political office. And thats where we are headed to at this point.  
  
I'm open to hearing why someone would be against my view but the arguments ive already heard aren't convincing enough...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42947156497.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Can a mute person be a politician?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947166272.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Can a mute person be a politician?

No if the politicians job involve speaking at all then they shouldn't be a politican, but if they are able to use a computer or something else to speak then id have no issue with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947193794.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; No if the politicians job involve speaking at all then they shouldn't be a politican

Why is vocalization so important to you? I hardly ever listen to a politician speak. I read what they said later. A mute politician could just issue statements, and it would make no difference to me in how I receive their positions.

&gt; if they are able to use a computer or something else to speak then id have no issue with it.

Can [Fetterman](https://time.com/6251752/john-fetterman-stroke-recovery-assistive-technology/) not do this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947234624.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Well one argument I made was, he wastes valuable speaking time in Congress, which wastes taxpayer money and wastes time that can be used to solve other issues.

And thats different then the technology I was speaking about, he should be able to have it be his voice, and as far as im aware he hasn't attempted to use anything like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947257799.0" user="DodGamnBunofaSitch" delta="False">
    <text>if wasting valuable time is your bar, then you're gonna have to rescind your dismissal of trump not having these issues.

using a sharpie to change an official weather map?  saying maybe we should nuke the storm?

trump's many instances of 'word salad' would seem to fit neatly into your insistence that politicians must always make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947294518.0" user="Rugfiend" delta="False">
    <text>I wholeheartedly concur. One read of his 'I know nuclear' slurry ought to have been sufficient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947318973.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>And if every single time trump spoke he made no sense I would agree with you, like ive said this goes beyond a handful of times. This is every single time John Fetterman speaks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986167067.0" user="DodGamnBunofaSitch" delta="False">
    <text>the only time trump makes sense is when he's being racist, so now we know that about you, huh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947284323.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Well one argument I made was, he wastes valuable speaking time in Congress

So do all the grandstanding republicans investigating dick pics. He’s a senator, he’s entitled to his time. 

&gt; And thats different then the technology I was speaking about

&gt;&gt; if they are able to use a computer or something else to speak then id have no issue with it.

So, the point is that he can use it. You said that made it cool. If he *chooses* not to, and you don’t like it, vote against him if you are able. If you are not able, let his constituent decide if they want to keep him. That is the real way we handle such things. At the ballot box. Not by barring the disabled from public service because they can’t make mouth sounds in the way you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947382281.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Not by barring the disabled from public service because they can’t make mouth sounds in the way you want.

You are over simplifying the issue, he can't read a scripted speech, he can't get any of his ideas across to anyone. He is not effective compared to someone able to speak. And yes people like him should be voted out, but if a people are stupid enough to vote them in, the government should enact something to remove them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947421667.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; he can't read a scripted speech,

Out loud, after having a stroke. My dad is like this, his brain is still working properly, but the connection to the mouth has been damaged. 

&gt; he can't get any of his ideas across to anyone. 

Only when speaking. He can and does in other ways.

&gt;And yes people like him should be voted out, but if a people are stupid enough to vote them in, the government should enact something to remove them.

No it should not. The people possess the ultimate authority in this country, not the government. It is up to the people of his state, and them alone, to decide this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947478714.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>And if John Fetterman was my dad Id tell him to resign. 

And the 25th Amendment exists for a reason, im sure theres some version of that for Senators, it should be used in times like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947559365.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; And if John Fetterman was my dad Id tell him to resign.

If he were your dad you’d have a better understanding of his condition, and wouldn’t be basing your opinion on media clips and think pieces. 

&gt; im sure theres some version of that for Senators, it should be used in times like this.

The senate can expel people. It hasn’t happened since 1862, and wouldn’t be successful now. The voters are the only way unless he himself resigns. And, honestly, Feinstein is way better target for your ire. She may actually mentally incompetent, whereas Fetterman is only physically disabled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947450966.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>If the people of Pennsylvania prefer a stroke-crippled, mute, time-wasting Fetterman to his election opponent, why shouldn't they get what they want? Republicans who are mad about it should try running a better candidate next time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947506230.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Because we are headed towards idiocracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947531934.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the rise of "soundbite politics" may have something to do with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947611074.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>Who are you to judge that? For me, I think electing Oz over Fetterman just because Fetterman had a serious stroke would be the move toward idiocracy. Oz was a total joke of a candidate as well as a confidence trickster and a foreign agent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42949622523.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>And you'd prefer authoritarianism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42949618888.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  he can't read a scripted speech, he can't get any of his ideas across to anyone.

Do you not read political coverage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947170134.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>They shouldn’t be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947196724.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Why? They can still convey ideas via text or sign language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947236732.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Most people can’t understand sign language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947255489.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>That is why there [are interpreters.](https://youtu.be/a3RH1Lm5YBk)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947268744.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t want to listen to an interpreter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947288005.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? What difference does it make?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947298409.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Then the interpreter should be elected and not the politician.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947306772.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>What!? It’s the politician’s thoughts and words being repeated by another person verbatim. Do you think we should elect a text to speech app if a person used that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947317406.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>The person giving the speech should be the politician. Politicians shouldn’t be allowed text-to-speech apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947327782.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>What if they were putting a sexy beat under it? Wouldn't that be better than boring old bio-speaking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947336958.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>No</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947345796.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>That is nonsense. The person thinking the thoughts that inform the positions should be elected. Anyone should be able to use anything they want to convey their thoughts. Speech, application, writing, interpreter, whatever they want. Get your thoughts out there, that’s all that matters. The form is irrelevant in todays world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947373278.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>This is nonsense. The person saying the thoughts should be elected. If all you do is think thoughts, you can be on a politicians staff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947396486.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The person saying the thoughts should be elected

So, you are cool with a brainless puppet that can speak, but not a genius logician who cannot? Like, if some charismatic dummy with no opinions on anything was up there, and he just read whatever was handed to him out loud, Ron Burgundy style, you’d think, “that’s my guy, he’s way better than the deaf girl with a phd in public management that uses sign language and an interpreter.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947417739.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the job of a politician is not to come up with ideas but to communicate ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947433679.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>That is so far from my belief that I cannot see a way to continue this discussion. Take it easy out there, here’s some [Three Dog Night](https://youtu.be/OXWzt3lenUc) to play me out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947427837.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  The person saying the thoughts should be elected

Yeah - that's right. The thing that's creating those thoughts, we should elect - we should elect that thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947302351.0" user="Rugfiend" delta="False">
    <text>Just say you're an ableist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947513977.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42950572265.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>And I don't want to listen to Matt Gaetz. It doesn't seem like that's enough to prevent him from holding office.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
