<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2458830303.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14nx9lr/cmv_the_bare_minimum_skill_a_politician_should/">
    <title>CMV: The bare minimum skill a politician should have is the ability to speak and form coherent sentences.</title>
    <original_poster>dancartopb</original_poster>
    <original_post>Politicians should be able to speak clearly and explain their ideas in a way that everyone can understand. It's important for them to communicate well so that people know what they're thinking and what they want to do.  
  
The best example is John Fetterman, anytime he speaks he makes no sense. A lot of arguments people have are that he just can't speak clearly but mentally he is the same. I'm not convinced of that but even if that were true I still don't think he should be in office. There have been multiple times when he tried to speak in Congress and nobody was able to understand him, that in turn wastes taxpayer money and time for other issues that can be hashed out and solved.  
  
Some people would say, well Joe Biden, or Donald Trump can't speak clearly, in my opinion thats a completely different thing, at the end of the day they can convey ideas, regurgitate a scripted speech, and talk and have regular conversations with people. Sometimes they both say things that make no sense but its not consistent and not all the time.  
  
John Fetterman on the otherhand has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences, and thats why I think he should resign from office, or be forced out somehow.  
  
Ive thought about Stephen Hawking and yes he was a genius and unable to speak and thats the only semi convincing argument I can think of, and if John Fetterman was able to speak through a robot and rebuttal arguments and have conversations as well as Stephen Hawking was able to through a computer then id have no problem with that.  
  
I feel like people today are way to accepting where they would even argue for people with mental disorders such as people with down syndrome being in political office. And thats where we are headed to at this point.  
  
I'm open to hearing why someone would be against my view but the arguments ive already heard aren't convincing enough...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42947236240.0" user="No_Bad_197" delta="False">
    <text>Winston Churchill would beg to differ. He was always mumbling and stumbling but nevertheless a great orator and writer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947392538.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Completely different example, if John Fetterman was simply mumbling while speaking things of substance I wouldn't mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947402433.0" user="No_Bad_197" delta="False">
    <text>Ah so it isn’t just about forming coherent sentences but also about the content? Then that’s a different CMV title there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947463761.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think politicians when talking in Congress should talk about their favorite color? It should obviously be about whatever issue is at hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947498754.0" user="No_Bad_197" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not arguing about anything relating to Fetterman. Your CMV title was meant to be about ability to speak and coherence not substance and content of what is spoken so I’m just pointing that out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947634060.0" user="political_bot" delta="False">
    <text>Sticking to the issue at hand is a high bar that most politicians don't meet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42953621795.0" user="LucidLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>Can you provide a link to the speech to which you refer? I can't find it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
