<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2458830303.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14nx9lr/cmv_the_bare_minimum_skill_a_politician_should/">
    <title>CMV: The bare minimum skill a politician should have is the ability to speak and form coherent sentences.</title>
    <original_poster>dancartopb</original_poster>
    <original_post>Politicians should be able to speak clearly and explain their ideas in a way that everyone can understand. It's important for them to communicate well so that people know what they're thinking and what they want to do.  
  
The best example is John Fetterman, anytime he speaks he makes no sense. A lot of arguments people have are that he just can't speak clearly but mentally he is the same. I'm not convinced of that but even if that were true I still don't think he should be in office. There have been multiple times when he tried to speak in Congress and nobody was able to understand him, that in turn wastes taxpayer money and time for other issues that can be hashed out and solved.  
  
Some people would say, well Joe Biden, or Donald Trump can't speak clearly, in my opinion thats a completely different thing, at the end of the day they can convey ideas, regurgitate a scripted speech, and talk and have regular conversations with people. Sometimes they both say things that make no sense but its not consistent and not all the time.  
  
John Fetterman on the otherhand has no ability to speak, convey ideas, or form coherent sentences, and thats why I think he should resign from office, or be forced out somehow.  
  
Ive thought about Stephen Hawking and yes he was a genius and unable to speak and thats the only semi convincing argument I can think of, and if John Fetterman was able to speak through a robot and rebuttal arguments and have conversations as well as Stephen Hawking was able to through a computer then id have no problem with that.  
  
I feel like people today are way to accepting where they would even argue for people with mental disorders such as people with down syndrome being in political office. And thats where we are headed to at this point.  
  
I'm open to hearing why someone would be against my view but the arguments ive already heard aren't convincing enough...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42947157736.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>A counter-example would be a mute politician - physically unable to speak, but capable of writing concise, elegant, meaningful prose.

Why should this person be barred from office?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947174356.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Mute people shouldn’t be politicians. A large part of the job is speaking and debating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947213103.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>OP has already conceded text-to-speech, so would presumably concede someone reading a prepared (or extemporized) argument on behalf of the politican would be ok. 

If you had someone who demonstrated clear, lucid, powerful arguments and a full understanding of the issue *in print*, why would you not want them in office?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947244350.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Having someone else reading the speech is not okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947261304.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Why could that *possibly* matter to you?

Do you vote based on a candidate's timbre or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947273796.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>Delivery is very important for politicians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947319503.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Then they can use a text-to-speech using AI Barry White.

They'd have your vote, I presume?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947326325.0" user="Repulsive-Magazine57" delta="False">
    <text>It should be illegal for politicians to use text-to-speech apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947343770.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you're going far enough, tbh. Politicians shouldn't be able to write. Too much chance of them being tricked into using TTS.

The whole thing would be a disaster for a politically literate nation, if they could use TTS, you're right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947461581.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>I just thought of something else.

Why are you talking to me? You seem to want me to entertain your opinions, and - I think - adopt your view of things.

But you're using *writing* - so what do you hope to achieve, when I can't hear your dulcet delivery?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42977618178.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; A large part of the job is speaking and debating.

It shouldn't be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947209370.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>I would say the majority of the job of a politician is being able to speak, if he or she is able to write amazing prose then they can work for a politician as a script or policy writer, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947217112.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that kind of sad, though?

Why would they need to *speak* their words instead of you reading them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947276537.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Why would they need to speak their words instead of you reading them?

To communicate efficiently with other politicians, experts, aides, and bureaucrats. To efficiently answer questions posed by journalists.

"Couldn't this just be done in writing?" Not really. At least not with the current human condition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947286874.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think mute people can't make good managers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947297818.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>I think just about anyone can make "good" managers. Whether they can make **good** managers depends on whether the job caters to their needs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947314074.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>OK. And what's a politican's job?

Is it speaking to you, or is it working on policies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947340820.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>What do you believe goes into working on policies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947369477.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>A question to be answered. Synthesis of information, deliberation on options and a decision reached. 

Another question - do you think it's impossible to get international projects completed in multinational corporations, without the use of phones?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947382593.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; "Couldn't this just be done in writing?" Not really. At least not with the current human condition.

I preempted this line of thinking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947396884.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>No you didn't - you just asserted that people can't take a few minutes longer to read something.

It's honestly a depressing view of human potential.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947490222.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>A few minutes longer for everything in a day quickly becomes hours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947497989.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>How long did it take you to think of that response and type it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947654604.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you either are just disagreeing to disagree, or you've never had a job where spoken communication was necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947663995.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you've never communicated on a project with someone in a different timezone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947698713.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Do you really? What indicates that I haven't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947703031.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>That you've never had meaningful, concise communication through text.

That it seems to baffle and confound you that such a thing is possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947754535.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't baffle me at all. I know how efficient good written communication can be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947762082.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Well shit. Good thing we can do that then, because otherwise mute people could never be leaders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947769466.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, ignore everything I've said, that's the way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947788762.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I think just about anyone can make "good" managers.

including mute people.

I listened to *that* - where you shot your argument through the foot and put two more in the back of the head to make sure. The rest was just window dressing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948112280.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Perfect example of the massive limitations with written communication.

I'll be slightly charitable to your position here: I think this is mostly a case of you reading what I said with the least charitable interpretation possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948117837.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>How is that "charitable" on your end?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948354124.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>The alternative would be that you didn't understand what I said. What I said wasn't complex or difficult to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948357941.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Sure - yeah. That's the only possible alternative here.

Not that you're worse at this form of communication than you think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42948572519.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, I will give it one more go:

Do you think it's easier and faster to talk to an expert to understand a topic or to ask questions in written form?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42977616146.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I preempted this line of thinking.

You "preempted" it by saying "no, because human" without any actual information about what you meant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42977685846.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>"The human condition" does not mean "because human". The human condition changes all the time. It's how we live and behave in concurrent times. I also allowed for OP's situation if the structures allowing for the written word to be (if not the only way to communicate) the dominant way to communicate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42977697500.0" user="iglidante" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I also allowed for OP's situation if the structures allowing for the written word to be (if not the only way to communicate) the dominant way to communicate.

This, to me, posits that humans are the recipients of emergent preferences and norms, but should not be empowered to introduce variance counter to those things.

Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42977771959.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>I can only speculate as to why you think so. But this is not a correct reading. We introduce changes counter to the status quo all the time, that is part of the human condition.

OP's position that I disagreed with, and which was almost diametrically opposed to OOP's position, was that the written word is (if not more efficient), just as efficient as the spoken word, in every way. This is obviously not the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947278637.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I would say the majority of the job of a politician is being able to speak, if he or she is able to write amazing prose then they can work for a politician as a script or policy writer, etc.

It would make conversation and debate worse.

How can a politician engage in a debate, negotiation, or a public forum where immediate interaction and persuasion are key? To defend their positions and influence policy decisions in real time you would need to be able to speak, relying solely on just writing their words they wouldn't be able to actively participate in that.

By being physically unable to speak, the individual in question would be better suited for roles such as a script or policy writer, where their exceptional writing abilities can still contribute to the political process.

Life isn't fair and we shouldn't accommodate everyone for the sake of accommodating them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947307705.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; How can a politician engage in a debate, negotiation, or a public forum where immediate interaction and persuasion are key?

Do you think this fixation of the importance of immediacy might actually be a *bad* thing, generally speaking?

Basing policy on "immediate persuasion", say?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947365351.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>The way our government and Congress works, yes immediate persuasion is needed. Even if that's a bad thing overall its one of the skills you need to have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947375775.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Key phrase there is "that's a bad thing"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947517311.0" user="dancartopb" delta="False">
    <text>And its a bad thing if your 5 feet tall you will never be in the NBA, its just how it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947525525.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>[Mugsy Bogues](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muggsy_Bogues)  was 5'3, my man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947587771.0" user="ijustwantthequest" delta="False">
    <text>5’0 is a different animal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947600722.0" user="suspiciouslyfamiliar" delta="False">
    <text>Go on - explain the critical importance of three inches in the story of Mugsy Bogues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947503983.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>In that case should we maybe not let Deaf people vote at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42947235172.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I would say the majority of the job of a politician is being able to speak

I would say it is to communicate. [A mute person can still communicate.](https://www.afb.org/about-afb/history/helen-keller/books-essays-speeches)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42949630835.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>I elect a politician to represent my views in government, not read words off a teleprompter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42950700875.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I would say the majority of the job of a politician is being able to speak

I do not know how somebody could be so wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
