<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257568692.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>This is kinda the stereotypical response for this topic, but have you seen Magnolia?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257604067.0" user="NorbitGorbit" delta="False">
    <text>Tom Cruise is basically playing Tom Cruise in Magnolia; that is why he is so good in it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257612185.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>It has been some years so I may not be remembering it correctly I will revisit it but I don't remember particularly buying his performance then again I was much younger when I saw it so I won't pass lifetime judgement on Cruise although my main beef with him is how much praise he has gotten for the movies he has done in the past 10 years that his performance just feels so samey to me. I will recheckout magnolia and as someone else pointed out eyes wide shut. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257626159.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of people have your opinion because Cruise has such a distinctive face and voice and doesn't do accents.  It makes it easy to see all of his characters as the same guy.  That's why I recommend Magnolia, because he's playing so against type(and doing a fantastic job at it).

I also think Edge of Tomorrow is a good example for the opposite reason.  The movie starts with him as an almost cartoonish version of the smug smooth talker we've seen him play so many times.  It's kind of cool to see the subtle changes that take the same kind of mannerisms seem likably cocky in one character, and turn them totally hateable in another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257663919.0" user="NorbitGorbit" delta="False">
    <text>in magnolia he plays a charismatic jerk (as he did in rainman, and eyes wide shut), not against type at all.

tom cruise is not convincing as a hapless loser in edge of tomorrow, however.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257741672.0" user="AdmiralCrunch9" delta="False">
    <text>The charisma isn't why Magnolia is agaisnt type.  It's the sleaziness, and the bitter anger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257940538.0" user="NorbitGorbit" delta="False">
    <text>he is also sleazy and bitterly angry in Rainman, and in Eyes Wide Shut (though the bitterness is more under the surface in Eyes Wide Shut).

BTW I think these are Tom Cruise's best roles because they allow him to express elements of himself that he cannot in real life. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
