<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257568059.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>I used to think that but Tropic Thunder and Eyes Wide Shut changed how I felt about his acting. I wish he'd accept more roles that showed his abilities but that's up to him. Besides, at least he's good in those action movies - most "action" stars aren't even very good at starring in action movies. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257606769.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I havent seen Eyes wide shut so I definitely should, may make a difference. I didn't see anything in Thunder that I havent seen from Cruise before. Sure he was more over the top and he looked different but the first just felt like cruise trying to be over the top, and the latter has no bearing on his acting ability. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257640106.0" user="NorbitGorbit" delta="False">
    <text>Cruise is basically playing Cruise in Eyes Wide Shut. But no one else could play Cruise in Eyes Wide Shut.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257659346.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you *should* watch Eyes Wide Shut anyway. It's a weird movie and Cruise did a very good job with it. If you've only watched Cruise's action movies then it's easy to hold your current view of his abilities but it's simply inaccurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257703673.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I would disagree that expecting each role to feel unique to be a poor measure of skill. If the person does 50 actions movies he should have at least more than one role with 50 different backgrounds. Besides I have seen more than just his action and he has yet to pull off a convincing role to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257715096.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If the person does 50 actions movies he should have at least more than one role with 50 different backgrounds.

Is that up to the actor or the person who wrote the script? Cruise is only responsible for delivering the lines he's given in a way that the director approves. And he's quite good at *that*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257748691.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps but based off the script Valkyrie shouldn't have had a Tom Cruise character in it but that is the performance he gave. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257765576.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Valkyrie was just horribly written...I don't think anyone could have saved that script. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257898817.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>That is true but I did appreciate other actors in the movie in their roles where I was completely unable to with Cruise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257903909.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That is true but I did appreciate other actors in the movie in their roles where I was completely unable to with Cruise.

He was given the bulk of the lines and when the script is a bad one it's like giving someone more rope...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257908942.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>with some of the suggestions I have gotten I will check out a few of his other roles and if I am able to see more talent there I will definitely be able to not be as critical on some other movies hes been in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257934987.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's a good idea. Glad I could help. Now if we could only get Cruise to ditch Scientology...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
