<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257680105.0" user="entrodiibob" delta="False">
    <text>You judge an actor's role in a film by its own merit. Complaining that it was the same as the last movie has no bearing on the quality and context of the role. Your complaint would have no weight for someone who is about see their first Tom Cruise movie. He would be judged on whether or not he is able to convince the viewer that his role was a fit in the film. 

Besides, he may "look" similar but the motivations and conflict of his characters are completely unique. The devil is in the details. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257690860.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I judge an actor based upon their continued ability to keep me in the movie I am watching. If the actor cannot convince me that they are the character I am watching they have failed as an actor. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
