<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28258457270.0" user="Buzzk1LL" delta="False">
    <text>I'm probably not saying much that hasn't already been said, but let me give it a go. Just because someone isn't a chamelion method actor, doesn't make them bad or "dumb entertainment". What Cruise does, might actually be more challenging. Character actors have a gimmick or trait that they can latch on to as a crutch, Cruise doesn't do this.

In one sentence you are saying "Cruise just plays Cruise in every movie". The fact that you think that, means he is believable and convincing in every one of those movies. You even admit in one of your comments "it just Cruise with a different personality". How is that a negative? That's the testament to his ability. Different personalities are different *people* not just Cruise on a Monday afternoon instead of a Tuesday afternoon.

The Character he plays in Collateral, M:I, A Few Good Men, Magnolia, Rain Man, Vanilla Sky are all very different people/characters. The fact that Cruise can do them all while being completely recognisable is a credit to his ability.

As an aside. How do you feel about the likes of Morgan Freeman, Jessica Chastain, Denzel Washington, George Clooney?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
