<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257592529.0" user="lovesuprayme" delta="False">
    <text>This thread is unlikely to receive any answers other than "Have you seen his performance in [movie]?"

With that being said, he was great in PTA's Magnolia. He plays a rather minor character, a pickup artist and motivational speaker who isn't really connected to the other characters, but towards the end where he makes a monologue to his dying father and starts getting emotional, he just steals the whole movie. He even got an Oscar nomination for it. It's also arguably PTA's best so totally worth watching regardless of Tom Cruise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257651841.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I will need to rewatch that it has been probably 8 years I don't really remember thinking highly of Cruise at the time but I was much younger then. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
