<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257578904.0" user="SC803" delta="False">
    <text>Which movies of his have you seen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257648828.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I have seen a large portion of practically all of his films in the past 10 years and seen several of his larger name movies from before that frame. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
