<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257623983.0" user="whitepalms85" delta="False">
    <text>1. Just because someone is a one dimensional actor doesn't make the actor "awful". Actually, most actors are relatively one dimensional. There aren't too many actors that can play anything from ugly villain over funny hero to sad drama. It's also that Hollywood likes to hire actors that have shown success in a specific role. It's no different from work life of normal people (e.g. if you worked in marketing once then firms will always try to hire you for a similar role and you will struggle to find a role in IT or medical research or so).
2. As others pointed out, he really isn't that one dimensional. E.g. Rain Man, Interview with a Vampire, Mission Impossible, Eyes Wilde Shot, Magnolia, Collateral, Last Samurai and so on aren't really all the same roles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257669290.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>1) I exaggerated by saying awful but on the premise I disagree with you. If an actor can't act then they are not a good actor regardless of how enjoyable they are in certain roles. 

2) I would argue that in all the ones you mentioned (sans eyes wide shut[havent seen] and magnolia [been a long time people are telling me to rewatch]) the largest change in role is from somber to stoic to over the top yet are all the same person in different situations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257717891.0" user="whitepalms85" delta="False">
    <text>The issue with what you are doing here is basically that you are defining "good actor" in a way that fits your personal view. 

For example your definition is very narrow. Based on your definition even some high ranked actors on e.g. this [top actors list on IMDB](http://www.imdb.com/list/ls050274118/) wouldn't fit your criteria. Btw. Tom Cruise is 97 on the list, which makes him a good actor but not very top, which I think is fairly accurate.

And in your definition you seem to put all emphasis on how diverse the acting skills are. There is nothing wrong with that but that's not very objective. You could also define a good actor by how much money they are making, how many fans they have, how high the average critics ranking of their films is, how credible they are in their roles, how much they add to a movie... E.g. personally I care most about whether the actor gives me the impression that it is real and that he isn't acting. I don't mind too much that I don't see the actor in different roles.

However, if you define "good actors" by "only actors that have performed very well in very diverse roles in top movies" then you end up with only a hand full of actors. And I agree that by this definition Tom Cruse isn't part of it.

This obviously isn't science but in research there is always a point where you have to ask yourself the question whether the question you are asking is really that good / relevant. I mean there aren't that many people that claim that Tom Cruise is the greatest actor of all time. It's a bit like saying "CVM: It isn't actually cold on the North pole".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257747411.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>Basing acting ability on the ability to allow the viewer to believe they are the character they are portray seems pretty fair when that is literal definition of the term acting. 

The thing is that it isn't that Tom Cruise can't play but one role its that he has the same personality in real life as he does in his roles. It isn't just that Tom Cruise plays the same roles its that the portrayal of the rolls all feel like Tom Cruise. And besides his roll in Valkyrie was not written anything like any of his other rolls yet he made it feel entirely the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257788656.0" user="whitepalms85" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think we know enough about Tom Cruise to really be able to tell how close his real personality is to his roles. I mean if you see him in e.g. late night shows then he is probably still acting. I would argue that a lot of actors are basically acting during all their public appearances. It's basically all just one long image campaign and they have PR advisers and managers.

Anyway, as long as he is still credible in his roles  I don't really care too much whether he is playing himself or not. And it certainly involved some acting as he isn't e.g. an agent or a Samurai in his private life.

But then we are back to the point that you wrote a very negative statement about Tom Cruise but then apply a very strict definition for a "good actor". 

You could also look at it from a totally different point of view: pretty much everyone, from fans over directors to movie critics agree that Tom Cruise is at least a reasonably good actor. So either somehow you are the only person that is able to see that Tom is that bad or there is some massive conspiracy going. I don't think any of that is the case so your definition must be pretty far off from what everyone else uses.

Also isn't your view of him strong influenced by his negative off screen image?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257896528.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough on the persona thing but that doesn't affect the idea that it feels like one role. 


I didn't put in my prompt I didn't enjoy did his performances but that he does a poor job in convincing the audience that the role he is playing is a real person. 

I also don't see how using the literal definition of a word is being strict. Sure it can have other meanings but I am specifically talking about talent of acting ability I even addressed that in the OP. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257952641.0" user="NorbitGorbit" delta="False">
    <text>When the role is written to be essentially Tom Cruise, who can do a better job of acting as Tom Cruise than Tom Cruise? Here is an example: Christian Bale is essentially doing a bad Tom Cruise impression for American Psycho, and it comes off as quite comedic but he never really embodies the character the way, say, Chloe Sevigny does for her character in the same movie.

Now, you can ask, how can someone acting as themselves be considered acting? Imagine you are not an actor but suddenly thrust into a scene with lights and cameras and people staring at you expecting you to say your lines as yourself. Can you do a good job being yourself in that situation?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
