<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985847140.0" user="Divio42" delta="False">
    <text>Even if every point you made is valid, and that could be debated but I won't, you are still the only person who stands to be impacted by your hatred. So why cling to it with a burning passion?

What do you stand to gain other than adding even more stress to your life when you even said it yourself that everyone in your own country is already depressed and hates themselves/each other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985875407.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>That's why I'm trying to change my view on America, but for some reason I just can't help but dislike it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985935723.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>Think of Weezer. You love Weezer. They are American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985943235.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I love America now, damn</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985967696.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, you could structure your life to eliminate all American media and American products. But you might not enjoy that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985991059.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I couldn't live without weezer, no, but in all seriousness, that just makes me jealous that America has and makes so many things that we need in every day life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986004450.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>Are jealousy and hatred the same? I’m not sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986015898.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Part of my hatred is because of my jealousy towards America</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986115637.0" user="Basic_Antelope3837" delta="False">
    <text>Then maybe the main feeling is envy with an extra side of resentfulness. If you still like something about the US, like Weezer, then I don’t think that is complete hatred</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986144100.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah maybe, trust me there are deffinetly a lot of things I like about the US, mainly the products and things of yours that we can use, I also liked seeing the massive cities, but it would make sense if the feelings I have towords America come from envy, sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985992148.0" user="Divio42" delta="False">
    <text>You don't occupy any significant amount of space in the collective mind of that which you hate. That only leaves you with your own hatred against something that is, at best, entirely apathetic about you. 

I'd argue that changing your view on America is not as important as changing how you process hatred.

By all means, dislike America but don't let disliking become hatred. Instead, turn it into apathy. Don't let it occupy that space in your mind.

That extends beyond your opinion of the US as well. We're living in an age where people are refining the science of capitalizing off people's anger. Why do you think American politicians like Trump are always in the media? They create anger which generates clicks which turns into ad revenue. You don't combat that by feeding into the hatred. You combat it by not letting whatever red meat is being fed to you by the media to live rent free in your brain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986008457.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Great points honestly, I'll take these into consideration, thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986099479.0" user="Divio42" delta="False">
    <text>Also worth noting - a lot of the shit you don't like about the US? Well, we here in the US don't like it either but we're a big fucking country with a lot of people and a political system that gives more power to rural areas with fewer people.

Not all of us are fat and stupid, love guns, or bland shitty food. I probably have a higher opinion of the average person from your country than I do of the average person from at least half the states in my own country.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
