<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985949998.0" user="SpreadEmu127332" delta="False">
    <text>“American Food” is so vague you have no idea. We have Germans, Irish, English, Italians, French, Mexicans, Canadians, Native Americans and many many others. There are so many different types of foods that most people probably haven’t tried, it’s not very easy to group it all together.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985972404.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I mean all the food I've tried in America. I don't like ordering a side of fries and getting a massive bowl of bland fries, the best meal I had was a salad, but that might just be because it's hard to make a salad blander.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986585771.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Can you be a bit more specific about where you ate food? It sounds to me like you just went to a bunch of fast food places, which is a TERRIBLE way to try to experience American food culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986919895.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Never went to a fast food place, mostly diners and chains.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986938170.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Next time, try something less corporate. Chains are big corporate structures which are focused on eliminating financial waste and squeezing as much profit for shareholders as possible. Try local places that focus on quality food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986956641.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I did try a few local places, some were fine, some were bad, but I didin't have anything good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987025781.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>What did you eat?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987061753.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I can't really list everything off, this was a long time ago, but what I remember I had salads, pizza, burgers, pancakes, just fries (which they gave me like a massive bowl of) I think I had a burrito somewhere? anyways, the best food I had was a salad, but it's hard to fuck up a salad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987173780.0" user="InfidelZombie" delta="False">
    <text>Here are some great American foods based on those cultures:

German - Bratwurst with sauerkraut on a bun

Irish - Corned beef and cabbage

English - Popovers

Italian - Pizza (100x better in US than Italy)

French - Pot roast

Mexican - Burritos

Canadian - Ok, you stumped me on this one...

Native American - Beef Jerky</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987192953.0" user="SpreadEmu127332" delta="False">
    <text>Poutine is pretty good, but yeah, there’s so much variety that it’s impossible to try everything and make a generalised opinion like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987206711.0" user="InfidelZombie" delta="False">
    <text>Sure poutine is alright, I just don't think it's made the jump to being "American" food, and I can't think of anything from Canada that has.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
