<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42986872525.0" user="ILoveLampRon" delta="False">
    <text>Seems like you hate everywhere you go, so why don't you just go live under a rock?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986893272.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>So me hating America and admitting that my own country has flaws means I hate everywhere I go?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987416933.0" user="ILoveLampRon" delta="False">
    <text>Seems like it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
