<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="43" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42987222983.0" user="hadtodoit_69" delta="False">
    <text>Even Americans can feel that way, but about certain parts of America specifically. America is so diverse. About 50% of America is pretty divided. What I’m trying to say here is that a large portion of Americans agree with you. But you should see the areas of America that the folks live in who agree with you. Some portions of America are exactly like you say. Shit holes with nothing but fat, stupid, ignorant people. But man there are so many refined areas of America that are in the running for the most beautiful places in the world. Sounds to be like you’re talking about Florida, the Midwest, or the south. But even areas of those places can be beautiful and awesome to visit and see. But yo if you’re anywhere on the west coast or the east coast (Boston, New York, etc.) those places are pretty sweet, full of refined people with lots of different cultures. 

I’m born and raised here and there are parts of it that I hate, but there are times when I realize that it might actually be the greatest country in the world. 

What I’m trying to say here is: there are plenty of Americans who agree with you, but only about certain parts. There are other parts (many parts) that are among the most beautiful, refined, and civilized places in the entire world. That’s not to say these parts don’t exist anywhere else in the world either. But dude there’s a WHOLE CLASS of Americans that other Americans feel give us a bad name and ruin our reputation around the world. We hate them too. But there’s so much great stuff in the US. So much amazing stuff. Try going to New York, Monterey, Denver, Los Angeles, Austin, Miami, Santa Cruz, Santa Barbara, San Luis Obispo, San Diego, Portland, the list goes on and on and on. So many amazing places where you’ll see lots of really down to earth, healthy friendly people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
