<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985875534.0" user="Federal_Penalty5832" delta="False">
    <text>As a continent-sized country with over 300 million people from all walks of life, it would be an oversimplification to characterize all Americans, their habits, and culture under one umbrella. Much like Europe, where cultures can vastly differ from one country to another, America too has its cultural differences across its various states. You've mentioned visiting the East Coast, which is just one part of the vast American mosaic. Perhaps other parts like the Midwest, the South, or the West Coast might offer different experiences.

Also, it's important to remember that the Internet often amplifies the loudest voices, which may not always represent the majority. This is true not just for Americans but for any nationality. As for the notion of Americans being "fat and stupid," consider that America has been home to some of the greatest minds and innovators in modern history. From [Einstein](https://www.biography.com/scientists/albert-einstein) and [Tesla](https://www.biography.com/inventors/nikola-tesla) choosing to immigrate and work there, to homegrown talents like the [Wright brothers](https://www.history.com/topics/inventions/wright-brothers), [Steve Jobs](https://www.biography.com/business-leaders/steve-jobs), and countless others, America has made significant contributions to global scientific, technological, and cultural advancements.

When it comes to food, you're right that there is an abundance of fast food and convenience products in America. But there's also an incredible diversity of cuisine from all over the world, thanks to its multicultural populace. From New York's renowned culinary scene to the fusion cuisines of California, there's a richness in American food that extends far beyond fast food chains.

Regarding the metric system, it's a valid criticism, and you're not alone in it. Many Americans themselves find their system confusing and support the adoption of the metric system. It's largely a historical artifact at this point, and change, as we know, can sometimes be slow to come about.

Your point about guns is well taken. Gun control is a hotly debated topic within the United States itself, and many Americans share your concerns. It's a complex issue tied to their Constitution and cultural history, and it's something they are grappling with as a nation. In fact, this [Pew Research report](https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2019/10/16/share-of-americans-who-favor-stricter-gun-laws-has-increased-since-2017/) indicates that the majority of Americans favor stricter gun laws.

As an exercise in perspective, consider this: Every country, every culture has its quirks and idiosyncrasies. Imagine if someone from Asia, Africa, or even another European country were to characterize your country based on a brief visit, or what they see on the internet, or stereotypes. Would it be an accurate representation of your country and its people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985926508.0" user="neatokra" delta="False">
    <text>This is a great response - what are the chances OP actually takes the time to read the whole thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987921054.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
