<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985940604.0" user="sbennett21" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot.

I don't blame you, I hate them too. 

&gt;Also, I don't get their obsession with guns

Our national history is different. I don't get Germany's obsession with pacifism, even if I see the historical context. I don't understand Ukrainian corruption, UK obsession with monarchy, Hungary's pro-russian stances, European extreme rejection of migrants (and even the US's not quite as extreme rejection), etc. 

&gt;I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world,

America is sufficiently big that this makes sense to me. Sure, it's not the nicest, but it does make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985961422.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the actually kind comment, the thing with guns does make some sense when you put it like that, and while pacifism and guns aren't really interchangeable like that, I get the rest of your examples. The internet giving me results about America makes sense too, I just really don't like when it happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986012711.0" user="sbennett21" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;while pacifism and guns aren't really interchangeable like that, I get the rest of your examples.

The way that it makes sense to me at least is that part of the reason why Americans like guns is because of our history: breaking away from a tyrannical government, believing in individual rights, having it in our constitution, and being wary of excessive government force. 

I think German pacifism is very similar, in that it's a reaction to Nazism and WW2. 

&gt;The internet giving me results about America makes sense too, I just really don't like when it happens.

And I think that's fair. I kind of assume that the average person on Reddit for instance is male, American, upper middle class, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986115019.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, the guns thing deffinetly makes more sense to me now, and yeah, it's hard not to picture people as just what you're used to, I completely get it. Thanks for taking the time to be civilized, by the way!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
