<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985794865.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I hate all of the food in America

Suppose someone who lives in Australia visits Denmark. Upon returning, they say "I hate all the food in Europe". Do you think that person is likely to have a well-informed view of European food?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985830283.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Of Dannish food, yeah, every single meal I had in America tasted bland and was huge, and when I googled it I found that this isn't an uncommon opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985862963.0" user="parishilton2" delta="False">
    <text>If you went to TGI Friday’s and Olive Garden, yeah, that’ll happen. You have to choose restaurants carefully. Bad food exists everywhere in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986557919.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>Some of the biggest brands being the worst is kinda a red flag though. 

Let's see, applebee's, olive garden, Texas roadhouse, ihop, chilis 

How many of this those would you call healthy eating?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986591797.0" user="Altruistic_Advice886" delta="False">
    <text>You are conflating two kinds of "bad" here.  There is "bad food" as in "this food doesn't taste that good" and "bad food" as in "this food is not healthy".

Chain restaurants exist to serve as many people as possible while being as consistant as possible across locations, and as such, they are generally not that good.  Not bad, but not good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986661293.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>Op did say bland and fattening, so they're looking at both. 

But you choose what kinds of foods to be consistent on. Even fast food like Greggs even if it's heavy on pastries is leaner than McD, leaner AND more veg than a sit in like wafflehouse or ihop which are 90% starch. Still tasty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986680783.0" user="Altruistic_Advice886" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, OP did say that, but this was the complaint in the thread being responded to:

&gt;Of Dannish food, yeah, every single meal I had in America tasted bland and was huge, and when I googled it I found that this isn't an uncommon opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987418986.0" user="throwawayarmywaiver" delta="False">
    <text>Roadhouse is delicious, ive never heard of anyone actually eating at an applebees, olive garden is known forntrying to act fancy while being terribke, and ihop is for drunk people to load up on pancakes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42988777840.0" user="makelo06" delta="False">
    <text>Applebees depends on the location and dish. It's certainly nothing special, but still good for the price, speed, and availability. OG kinda sucks. IHOP is just a slightly fancier Waffle House.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986001807.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>Depends entirely on where you are. If you're going to some diner without a spit of ratings, not sure why you even went there.

Even in the east coast, that's a huge amount of territory to cover. Southeast has some good soul food if you look for it- but you won't find as good clam chowder/pizza as you would find in the Northeast- and even then it depends on where. 

Remember that one state in the US can be the same size as an EU country or even bigger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986603533.0" user="Altruistic_Advice886" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  but you won't find as good clam chowder/pizza as you would find in the Northeast- and even then it depends on where. 

Dear god, even in my town, the pizza depends on which place you go to.  The closest place to my house, is a style of pizza I don't like, but a 5 minute drive away is something I enjoy.  But people who grew up on New York Style will hate both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986612197.0" user="US_Dept_of_Defence" delta="False">
    <text>I lived in NYC for 10 years- I agree though, while every city has a better pizza joint, everywhere I've moved after I didn't like it as much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986011299.0" user="deadfeet3" delta="False">
    <text>Food is pretty varied in america. As examples: NY is known for their pizzas, Louisiana is known for their cajun food, Texas is known for texmex, and Hawaii has their own set of traditional foods you should try.

There is too much variety to say some random restaurant in Massachusetts is indicative of the entire US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986037402.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>To be blunt, with merely two weeks or so in the USA, there is absolutely no way you sampled representative samples of food available in the US. 

The comment about going to Denmark and then extrapolating to the entire comment is spot on. You are using a very limited experience to extrapolate to the entire country.

Your entire comment is critiquing essentially a stereotype. You have created a strawman in your mind for what the USA is and what an American is. You then argue against that strawman. 

You have not considered the USA is about the 3rd or 4th largest country in the world depending if you consider population or land mass. If you don't think defining Europe by an experience in Denmark is right, you should do the same thing for the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986084787.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is, if you visit like twenty different food places in Denmark and have the same experiene in every single one of them, it's not that crazy to think that the entire country's food is similair, same with me for the US, OBVIOUSLY, I don't know if that's the entire countries food, but I believe it's most of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986221615.0" user="denyjunctionfunction" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of places did you go? And could it be that those places just didn’t meet your expectations or even more simply, your tastes? The US is very varied in its food across the continent. Even in between cities/towns in the same general region. At best you maybe could say one state didn’t have good food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986337545.0" user="Corduroy_Sazerac" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it would certainly be crazier to extrapolate that view to cover the rest of the EU. Which is similar to what you have done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986475878.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>The US is closer to the size of Europe then Denmark. 

I wouldn't even expect a sample size of 20 to be reasonable for Denmark. This is so easy to bias with choices of *where* you choose to eat.

As I said, your post appears to try to create a stereotype/strawman to describe what you think the USA and Americans are without considering whether your stereotype is even accurate. 

I mean, you have seafood of the Northeast, Southern US cooking, Barbecue in Texas vs barbecue in the midwest. You have the tex-mex flavors. You can find any number of ethnic restaurants all over the US. 

If I compare this to Europe, it is the difference between France, Greece, Belgium, Italy, and Sweden. Do you think, being European, that you could generalize all European foods by visiting only one of those countries? Seriously, would eating in Belgium tell you anything about food in Italy?

The second part is the fact that the USA is a 'melting pot' of cultures. This means you can find just about every cuisines worldwide in the USA in any semi-large city. Whether you took advantage of any of this in your visit - I cannot say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987431283.0" user="throwawayarmywaiver" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but denmark is such a small country compared to the US, which is around the same size as all of europe (the US is only slightly smaller)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987175622.0" user="repster" delta="False">
    <text>Dane living in the US here

I can tell you that food varies hugely across the US. I consider Danish food boring and bland, and I look forward to returning to the richness of flavors available here if I visit Denmark for more than a week

Bread is about the only thing Denmark does better</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987406810.0" user="throwawayarmywaiver" delta="False">
    <text>You said you went to the east coast, which states did you travel to?

Most of our famous foods come more from the south/southwest and there is a tiny bit of overlap on the coast, so im curious to know where you visited?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987486963.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say Danish food, I said European food.

The United States is bigger than Europe (well, at least than the EU), and its food is just as varied. The food you can find in Atlanta, Georgia will be *dramatically* different from the food you can find in Berkeley, California. Sure, you'll be able to get a burger in both places, and there will be food chains that exist in both places. But there will be things in each place that you can't find in the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987814230.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>Their point was america is gigantic. The food in one city is different than the food in another. I grew up on one coast and moved to the other. My friends from India and Romania can find more of their favorite foods they loved from their homes than I can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987083873.0" user="InfidelZombie" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I've spent at least a week in almost every country in Europe. Poland was the first, and the food blew me away. Then I went to Italy and, let me tell you, if Italy was the only place I'd been I would think all European food sucks!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
