<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985892318.0" user="ulsterloyalistfurry" delta="False">
    <text>Which part of the US were you in? Even different regions of the same state can have vastly different cultures. What country are you from? I'm sure I could find something bad about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985907524.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I already mentioned how horrible my country is, Lithuania. It has the highest suicide rates in Europe and a lot of racists, homophobes and sexists, if that helps you with finding bad things about it. I'm sure different regions are different, but when every place has the same parts I dislike, I assume that about the rest of the country, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986849617.0" user="Additional-Charge593" delta="False">
    <text>People are people everywhere.

One thing to consider is that much of what is happening politically in the United States today is a continuation of the war between the states that started with the union of slaving and industrial colonies with battlelines redrawn as red and blue but remember that Europe went through the internecine religious wars for three centuries before mellowing out to what it is today. Lot's of killing and violence, pogroms. So, not defending, but calling for perspective. People are people everywhere through time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985928548.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>also if you're on the east coast (which op said somewhere) you may get the opposite feeling, tiny crowded states with little differences between them 

going to philly, boston and baltimore will feel more similar than going to billings, los angeles, des moines and dallas</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
