<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985814320.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Most Americans also hate all those things you mentioned about their country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985834083.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>fair enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985915735.0" user="neatokra" delta="False">
    <text>I love living here personally</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985939225.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Do you like that there is an obesity epidemic?  
Do you like that unhealthy, preservative/sugar/salt-ridden fast food is highly normalized, and fresh-healthy food is not, and is often unavailable for many people?   
Do you like the gun culture?   
  
  
You can still love your country and love living there, but dislike certain aspects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985956982.0" user="neatokra" delta="False">
    <text>You can always just…not eat unhealthy food? Weird reason to hate an entire country but do you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985967485.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_desert</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985981959.0" user="neatokra" delta="False">
    <text>The United States is the only country with food deserts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986028651.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying it is.  But I am saying that it's something that you might not love about your country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986816033.0" user="Altruistic_Advice886" delta="False">
    <text>You avoided answering the questions asked of you and responded with something irrelevant.  Do you enjoy those things?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986105022.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>So I see this a lot with left wing totalitarians.

Don't like obesity?  Eat less, move more.

Don't like "access to junkfood"?  Shop on the perimeter of your supermarket (supermarkets are an American thing) rather than in the aisles.  That's where all the healthy food is.

&gt; and is often unavailable for many people?

Fuck.  Them.  Sell me on why I should care about poor people or unhealthy people.  For a delta.  The whole point of America is "rugged individualism" and being the master of your own destiny.  It blows my mind to see 20-somethings whining about "minimum wage" when the real question should be "what did you waste your life doing that you're nearing 30 and your time has such little value that there had to be a law made about it?"

What is "gun culture"?  Why do you guys always side with Reagan on the gun issue but never anything else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986195191.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>So I see this a lot with right wing people.  This is a very individualist mindset rather than a collectivist mindset.   When they see a problem, the first thought is "How does this affect *me*?" rather than caring about how much of a problem it actually is, and what can be done about it.   
    
I can't sit here and tell you why you should care about other people and not just yourself.  That's a pretty fundamental view that most people learn before they enter kindergarten.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986218443.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>So I see this a lot with left wing people.

They can't answer a question so they always reply with some version of "educate yourself, shitlord".

Literally how is it my problem that you're 300lbs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986331383.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>1.  I'm not 300lbs. But in America, a lot of people are.      
2.  Society's problems are your problems.  If schools aren't providing healthy lunches to kids or giving them enough exercise or educating them on how to live healthy lives, then there's going to be a lot of 300lbs adults when these kids grow up.   And it's not just education - there are 100 reasons why there's an obesity epidemic.  But it IS your problem if it's your kid who is affected by this, or if you can't get an ambulance when you need one because there are too many obese people with health problems and they are getting priority over you because you're otherwise healthy,  or if you have to sit next to an obese person on a flight, or if healthy food is more expensive than junk food so you end up paying more for your lifestyle than the average obese person, and so on and so on.       
It's not hard to recognize that yes, this is a problem, and yes, it affects you.   Even if it didn't affect you, certainly there are (or will be) problems that *do* affect you.  At that point, would you want others to care about those problems?  Of course you would.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986439856.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying I get to police other people's bodies?

You just laid out a pretty convincing case against fat acceptance and I'm very nearly sold on normalizing fat shaming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986583400.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Not at all what I was saying, but okay.  
 
I'm saying that as a citizen and member of society, you have the power to influence and change society. If you recognize that obesity is a problem in society, then what can be done about it?  One thing that can be done is healthy lunches in schools. Your taxes pay for education, so you have a say in how they're spent. Elect leaders who will provide funding to schools to give them better school lunches.   There are hundreds more possible causes and solutions to the obesity epidemic, and along with them hundreds more ways you can help. Plus hundreds more problems out there that don't necessarily affect you directly, but which could be solved. Even if all you do to help is to not stand in the way of people who are actually trying to help.  
  

Fat acceptance is a bit of a different issue. For my opinion on it, see the next paragraph. Feel free to skip it if you'd like to focus on the argument at hand:     
  
Obesity is a disability. For many, it's somewhat self-imposed, but for many others it's not.  There are medical reasons (thyroid, diabetes, mobility issues, mental health, etc.) why someone might be obese.  Our society should be one that accommodates disabilities to a reasonable degree.  So the first half of "fat acceptance" for me is to just recognize that it's a disability, and to provide accommodation whenever possible.  And by that, I don't mean that you have to buy the extra plane ticket for an obese person who needs the extra space to sit next to you on a flight. I mean that - like wheel chair ramps, braille writing, or other disability accommodations - obese bodies should be considered when architects and engineers are designing spaces for people.       
The second half is recognizing that fat people are actually people. It doesn't make someone a bad person if they're fat - even if it's self-imposed choices that led them to becoming fat.  Fat people can still be nice, funny, attractive, etc.   You don't have to personally find fat people attractive, but you also don't have to go out of your way to make fat people feel like they're *not* attractive.  They're just a person.  They already know they're fat and don't need it pointed out at every opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986616933.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>But like your arguments were taken straight from FatPeopleHate:

You literally even used the "they're inconvenient to be around" one with the airlines.

If it's my problem, I have the right to fix my problem.  And you're saying it's my problem, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986637224.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Did you even read what I wrote?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986694041.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If it's my problem, I have the right to fix my problem. And you're saying it's my problem, right?

Is a direct response to 

&gt; I'm saying that as a citizen and member of society, you have the power to influence and change society. If you recognize that obesity is a problem in society, then what can be done about it?

My whole side is that you are free to eat yourself to death if you want and I won't stop you.  Your "fat people raise fat kids who grow up to be fat people" isn't really selling me on why that's my problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986844637.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>*All* problems are your problem, because you live in a society.   If you ignore every problem that you can somehow rationalize as "not your problem", then every problem gets worse.   
  
 
This is what I'm talking about when I say individualist versus collectivist society. We'd all be better off with more collectivist thinking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986884306.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If you ignore every problem that you can somehow rationalize as "not your problem", then every problem gets worse. 

Perfect example:  Philadelphia.  That place is a shit show and it's only ever getting worse.  H on Kensington, lead in the water, there was a transvestite mass shooter last week that didn't even make national news because gun crime is just atrocious there.  There was a terror attack that collapsed a highway there like a month ago.  It's bad and getting worse all the time.

I live in Texas.  Literally none of that is my problem.  That whole city can get blipped off the map and I wouldn't know it if I didn't have internet access.

The obesity epidemic can get worse and it still wouldn't be my problem.  Why are "your problems" my responsibility to fix?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986929495.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Why are "your problems" my responsibility to fix?

Because you live in a society.  The world is a better place if people help other people.  People who help others are generally more happy and fulfilled in life.   Plus, sooner or later, you're going to be the one who has a problem that you need help fixing. It might be a problem that is very easy to fix if you get help.  But if everyone had the same individualist mindset of "not my problem", then you will be screwed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
