<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42986739995.0" user="CP1870" delta="False">
    <text>1. If you just went to fastfood places and chain restaurants that's your fault not Americas, all the good food in America is at small independent places not the massive chains. 

2. Thats because America is the world power. Without American nukes Russia would have invaded tiny defenseless Lithuania a long time ago. Be thankful that our military is the only reason Lithuania is not apart of the Russian Federation

3. Why does it matter? Most Americans know both systems. I personally like some imperial measurements more than metric ones (for example miles and Fahrenheit, Celsius is a horrible scale that's just as arbitrary as Fahrenheit) 

4. Guns are important here because that's how the nation was founded. One of the big reasons for the American Revolution was the British taking away the colonists guns which is why we have the Second Amendment to prevent that. Also I can ask a similar question about why the Germans and Japanese love authoritarianism so much, they just seem to love having the government boot squishing their necks</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42986904262.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>I went to a variety of places, random family diners, chain restaurants, only thing I didin't have was fast food.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
