<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2466309142.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14sdkba/cmv_i_hate_america_with_a_burning_passion/">
    <title>CMV: I hate America with a burning passion</title>
    <original_poster>HoovyKitty</original_poster>
    <original_post> I am a European and I've visited America for a couple of weeks before (east coast) but I just hate America and a lot of American's for some reason. The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid, but I always took that joke with a grain of salt, but ever since I vistied, I've believed that statement and agreed with it fully. I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening, I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world, I also hate the stupid (to me) measurements like pounds (written lbs??) feet, inches, miles and whatnot. Also, I don't get their obsession with guns, I've never understood how they can have so many shootings, and I get that it's a massive country, but compared to the entirety of Europe it's still insane. The thing is, there are countries in Europe and elsewhere that have way more things that I dislike about them, hell, even my own country sucks, everyone here is depressed, hates themselves and hates eachother and we still suffer from Russian influence, but for some reason America just makes me want to make fun of it and hate it way more.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42985883616.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>* The joke here has always been that American's are fat and stupid

That's our poor people.  You have poor people too.  It's so crazy when you talk to a bigot and they rattle off a list of all the things they hate about whatever they hate and it always, always boils down to "Okay so you hate poor people.  Me too."

* I hate all of the food in America and how it's bland and fattening

This is kind of nebulous and I'm not sure specifically what you're talking about.  Like "American" food?  So like Texas Barbecue and Southern food or do you mean like "food that Americans cook" in which case the flex would be "we're a nation of immigrants and my immigrants who fled your country probably cook your dishes better than your grandma.

*  I hate Americans all over the internet treating America like the center of the world, 

America is the center of the world because we spent 5% of our defense budget last year on ruining your economy with our favorite passtime: a proxy war.  Imagine Russia v Ukraine without America's support.  lol

How many American military bases do we have in your country?  How much aid have we thrown at your government?  I bet you're a NATO member.  You're welcome for being the only country that actually pays their pledge and keeps that joke alive.

* I hate it when I google something and the results are about America instead of the world

Ooh self burn.  Your word for "search something on the Internet" is an American name brand.  Like Bandaid or Velcro. 

* Also, I don't get their obsession with guns

Our country started with a violent revolution and the first thing an actually-oppressive government does when turning to tyranny is trying to disarm civilians.  It makes a lot more sense when you realize that cops are part of the government.

*  I've never understood how they can have so many shootings

Gangs and a blind trust in pharmaceutical companies.  You take the bad with the good sometimes.

So here's what I'm reading between the lines:

You hate us for our diversity, you hate us for our success, and you hate us for our global cultural victory.  I mean I don't want to sound like a Congressman from NYC but I'm pretty sure you're just angry because you're jealous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985934372.0" user="HoovyKitty" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, jealousy is deffinetly part of it, but because your goverment helps ours doesn't make you the one country to rule all countries</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985969432.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>It's called "soft influence".

The reason we do it isn't because we like you (we don't).  The reason is because we can, on the **WHIM OF A MADMAN**, pull out our big dicks and say "Do this or the gravy train stops" and have [the King of Europe declare, "Oh shit, we're in serious trouble you guys."](https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/387067-merkel-europe-cant-count-on-us-to-protect-us-anymore/) and like 3 and a half years later you are, in fact, in serious trouble.

Here's the thing about being the top of the heap.  You basically get to pick between us and China, and China's pretty keen on genocides and slavery so it's probably in your best interest to watch our movies, enjoy our video games, and say thank you every once in a while.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987197026.0" user="dangerdee92" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree, I'm not American but I'm not stupid.

I'd rather live in a world where the USA is the top dog than a world where China is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42985990955.0" user="Tedstor" delta="False">
    <text>My young adult son still gets financial support from me. He lives in my house. He drives a car that I own. 

I make ‘some’ of his rules and have a ton of influence over what he does/doesn’t do. 

If he wants me to fuck off so he can do whatever he wants, he needs to become financially independent and move out. Until then…..I’m still his Daddy. 

Geopolitics is basically the same way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987465521.0" user="throwawayarmywaiver" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That's our poor people. You have poor people too. It's so crazy when you talk to a bigot and they rattle off a 

I dont know where OP is from exactly, but the obesity rate in the UK is around 25% so with the assumption that theyre from there (obviouslycould be very wrong), they dont actually have much room to talk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987504158.0" user="shadowbca" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;always boils down to "Okay so you hate poor people. Me too."

just to clarify here, are you saying both you and OP hate poor people? because that's how this reads to me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42987783189.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that OP is confused and he THINKS he hates Americans, but what he really hates is poor people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
