<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="247416961.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43b05d/cmv_ivory_confiscated_from_poachers_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Ivory confiscated from poachers should be destroyed, not sold to fund Elephant/Rhino conservation efforts.</title>
    <original_poster>patrickmurphyphoto</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello CMV,

A post popped up in /r/worldnews today about [how Kenya has confiscated and will burn $270million dollars worth of poached Elephant Ivory](https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/439fg2/kenya_to_destroy_largest_ever_ivory_stockpile_in/).  Many of the comments stated the opinion that this is a waste to burn it, and that the product should be sold at a very low price, to flood the market, and to raise money for conservation efforts.

I believe that destroying the Ivory is the best solution.  The sale of Ivory was banned in 1989, and the two legal sales that have happened since have [revived the demand in the markets that they were sold](http://www.economist.com/news/international/21595932-push-stop-poaching-and-save-elephants-extinction-up-smoke). 

Many people compared destroying the product to the ineffectiveness of similar practices in the drug war. Drug manufactures can afford to lose a large percentage of their shipments because the profit is so high, and most profitable drugs come from plants, or other resources that are renewable and not as scarce as Elephant Ivory.

I would love to hear your opinions, and will be taking them in to full consideration. Feel free to make suggestions about other potential solutions I haven't considered here.  I have an interest in (but limited knowledge of) economics, feel free to use macroeconomics to explain your view!

So, Change My View Reddit.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28266304956.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>you forget that the ones poaching the ivory are not the same as the ones selling it,  poachers generally do so because its one of the few ways for them to make a living. they don't care that they are hunting something to extinction or that the price that its sold after is more or less, they simply want their price regardless of how much profit others make on it. destroying it, selling it does nothing.

now markets may grow with additional ivory, but as long as you stop those that buy from poachers it does not matter.

essentially its a focus on the wrong part of the chain, at that point the elephant is already dead and everyone involved has already been paid.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
