<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="247416961.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43b05d/cmv_ivory_confiscated_from_poachers_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Ivory confiscated from poachers should be destroyed, not sold to fund Elephant/Rhino conservation efforts.</title>
    <original_poster>patrickmurphyphoto</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello CMV,

A post popped up in /r/worldnews today about [how Kenya has confiscated and will burn $270million dollars worth of poached Elephant Ivory](https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/439fg2/kenya_to_destroy_largest_ever_ivory_stockpile_in/).  Many of the comments stated the opinion that this is a waste to burn it, and that the product should be sold at a very low price, to flood the market, and to raise money for conservation efforts.

I believe that destroying the Ivory is the best solution.  The sale of Ivory was banned in 1989, and the two legal sales that have happened since have [revived the demand in the markets that they were sold](http://www.economist.com/news/international/21595932-push-stop-poaching-and-save-elephants-extinction-up-smoke). 

Many people compared destroying the product to the ineffectiveness of similar practices in the drug war. Drug manufactures can afford to lose a large percentage of their shipments because the profit is so high, and most profitable drugs come from plants, or other resources that are renewable and not as scarce as Elephant Ivory.

I would love to hear your opinions, and will be taking them in to full consideration. Feel free to make suggestions about other potential solutions I haven't considered here.  I have an interest in (but limited knowledge of) economics, feel free to use macroeconomics to explain your view!

So, Change My View Reddit.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28266123532.0" user="Blackheart595" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with the practice of not selling it. That would be hyprcratic.

However, I don't think they should be destroyed either. When the current situation is that you have a heap of ivory, destroying it would be a purely destructive action (obviously), and I don't want to encourage such a behaviour.

In my opinion, the ivroy should be stored, so it can be used on old art that uses real ivory for restoration purposes. That way, it doesn't get into the free market, and it isn't wasted either, but instead, it takes what is and makes the best use of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266156616.0" user="patrickmurphyphoto" delta="False">
    <text>These are good points, my response would be, do you feel that the pressures of corruption would allow some of the ivory to be sold to benefit government officials etc?

Also, in 2014, Ugandan armed army and police men were protecting a location with a safe full of 1.1 million dollars of ivory, they were over run and it was stolen, this was not reported for months until an audit exposed the incident. 

Who should the Kenyan's trust to keep the ivory worth 270 times as much safe?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266169366.0" user="Blackheart595" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's what I'd be unsure about as well. They probably should be handed over to a trusted organisation - maybe even an organization that supports conservation. As for how it's protected... well, I guess I lack the required knowledge in that regard. I'm just not really convinced that the ivory you talked about actually was 'stolen', since they kept so quiet about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266239668.0" user="jackfrostbyte" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose one method might be to offer it to any museum, university, archive, etc.  That way each can request an amount they can store, and after a set period of time they would destroy the remainder. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28267871904.0" user="DrWhiskeydick" delta="False">
    <text>Give it to the UN and distribute it throughout the member nations to various museums, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266667048.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>Who is doing this storing? Its not like you can just leave that much ivory sitting around, it will need to be guarded. Who decides which art it goes to?

It certainly sounds like an ideal solution from a conservation standpoint, but it's not a feasible option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28267875813.0" user="DrWhiskeydick" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand this argument.  It's not feasible because you don't know which art it would be used to restore?  Donate it to various museums or conservation organizations throughout the US and Europe, anywhere.  Let them decide what they use it for.  It's a valuable and useful resource and the harm that can come from it has already come.  This is like letting the holocaust happen, then destroying all of the brand new medical data from the horrific experiments because you didn't like where it came from.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28268019849.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>Who is going to transport it and store it until it's used to restore art?

Who will guard it from theft? It's like trying to store a pile of gold. 

And who is paying for all of this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28268472882.0" user="DrWhiskeydick" delta="False">
    <text>It's like trying to store a pile of gold, which is done constantly and perfectly well all the time.  When's the last time someone stole a pile of gold, like the 1880s?

The UN or whatever organizations receiving them would pay for them to be shipped.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
