<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="247416961.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43b05d/cmv_ivory_confiscated_from_poachers_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Ivory confiscated from poachers should be destroyed, not sold to fund Elephant/Rhino conservation efforts.</title>
    <original_poster>patrickmurphyphoto</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello CMV,

A post popped up in /r/worldnews today about [how Kenya has confiscated and will burn $270million dollars worth of poached Elephant Ivory](https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/439fg2/kenya_to_destroy_largest_ever_ivory_stockpile_in/).  Many of the comments stated the opinion that this is a waste to burn it, and that the product should be sold at a very low price, to flood the market, and to raise money for conservation efforts.

I believe that destroying the Ivory is the best solution.  The sale of Ivory was banned in 1989, and the two legal sales that have happened since have [revived the demand in the markets that they were sold](http://www.economist.com/news/international/21595932-push-stop-poaching-and-save-elephants-extinction-up-smoke). 

Many people compared destroying the product to the ineffectiveness of similar practices in the drug war. Drug manufactures can afford to lose a large percentage of their shipments because the profit is so high, and most profitable drugs come from plants, or other resources that are renewable and not as scarce as Elephant Ivory.

I would love to hear your opinions, and will be taking them in to full consideration. Feel free to make suggestions about other potential solutions I haven't considered here.  I have an interest in (but limited knowledge of) economics, feel free to use macroeconomics to explain your view!

So, Change My View Reddit.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28266149808.0" user="Trevor1680" delta="False">
    <text>Not selling the ivory leaves more demand to go and get more Ivory. 

Your best options for protecting the species that produce Ivory, is to make a good substitute or arguably better is to allow people to breed these species so that they can sell the Ivory. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266173545.0" user="patrickmurphyphoto" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; better is to allow people to breed these species so that they can sell the Ivory

Did you see the second link in my post, it discusses that the legal sale of ivory makes the illegal market flourish at a disproportionate rate.  Authorities have a hard time distinguishing illegal ivory vs the Legal ivory, I imagine you might be able to buy ivory cheaper if it is illegal than the very rare legal ivory, giving poachers the advantage.

The increase of people who you know who have ivory goods, legal or illegal in your area is likely to increase your desire for the product.

We would have to start producing ivory at a large rate, many many huge farms before I think that it would push out the illegal market, elephants take much longer to mature(live 60-70 years, but you could probably get fully developed tusks before that) than most animals which would make farming mean you would need to keep many many generations of elephants at a time to have a continued harvest.

A substitute would be pretty great though!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28266208727.0" user="Trevor1680" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine that demand increase comes more from a price change, there was probably that surge of demand due to the increase in total supply lowering the cost. Or if it is another reason your really covered because people are breeding these animals and matching that to demand. 

The problems with the substitutes is that people with an eye can still tell it is fake so maybe a more realistic one would help. Because if you cant tell the difference you can under cut real ivory and stop all financial reasons to kill these animals. 

The thing with breeding is we already did it with the Crocodile/Alligator i forget which and it was a huge success. It took about ten years for them to be near extinction to really abundant now. Really it is just making a financial incentive to have these animals around. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
