<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032493230.0" user="The-Last-Lion-Turtle" delta="False">
    <text>What's the difference between endorsing a candidate from a different party?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032646899.0" user="digbyforever" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine it solves for the subset of voters who both want to cast a vote, any vote, for President/Senator/Congressman and vote for a third party, but not be a spoiler.  Yes, this may not be a totally coherent view, but it doesn't seem crazy.

It would also solve for the party operatives who want their third party to keep getting votes (I think something about all the third parties in New York want to compete to be listed third on the ballot), so if you have the ability to nominate a popular figure like Biden or Trump, so to speak, you can more easily compete to be the "top" third party.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032706519.0" user="The-Last-Lion-Turtle" delta="False">
    <text>Someone voting for Biden is voting for democrats not 3rd party regardless of if the 3rd party nominates them.

It sounds like you are trying to optimize a metric for 3rd party participation without creating any real support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43351787737.0" user="Chorby-Short" delta="False">
    <text>Not really? For presidential elections, at least. In New York, each party can use different elector slates, in which case voting for one party or another does affect the outcome even if they have the same nominee for president. Doesn't happen often, but happened to Johnson in 2016.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
