<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032452473.0" user="mullrainee" delta="False">
    <text>Cross-endorsement causes more problems than it solves in NY. Republicans are more adherent to Conservative Party goers because the Conservative Party can bring their own candidates and have them appear in Republican Primaries. 

The Independence Party is hijacked by both parties to acquire a different line that most people believe is just them registering as “Independents.”

The Working Families Party is consistently taken over by activists who don’t align with their values because they have so few members outside of NYC (I believe Steve McLaughlin the Rensselaer County Executive once ran under their banner and he’s probably the most conservative County Executive in the state).

Angelo Santabarbra, an Upstate Democrat often carries the Conservative Party line because he’s an excellent retail politician.

The stark reality is that many of these smaller parties are easily hijacked by informed political operatives because they lack the funding, resources, and infrastructure of major parties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43033041825.0" user="PublicFurryAccount" delta="False">
    <text>This is the first visibility I’ve had into how these parties have been functioning. I felt like there must be something odd just from the news of wild swings in the WFP but had chalked it up to the whiplashing which was all the rage back then.

!delta</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
