<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032695105.0" user="markroth69" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that electoral fusion should be legal. It should be there simply because if enough people vote for a candidate on the third party line the candidate and maybe the big party will see that they should look more towards what the minor party is pushing. 

But....

I don't think this the best solution or will actually result in that. What we really need is elections for multiple people at once. Getting 50% of the vote in a district shouldn't give you the one seat that the district is given, It should get you half of the multiple seats the district has. 

Failing that we should have ranked ballots or runoff elections in every election to eliminate spoilers actually spoiling elections. 

Fusion creates the possibility that we can find room for more views in politics. Changing the way we elect candidates would do more.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
