<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032651777.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>It should be legal but even without it organizations can support candidates within the Democratic party. For example, unions do this all the time where they endorse candidates who might even be union members but are now running under the Dem ticket. Or consider another org that AOC has a connection with -- the DSA. You can still run "your candidates" without officially being part of the process. 

I'm not sure if it's going to ease political cynicism as the in the end the problem isn't with the name Democrats or Republicans but rather the fact that nothing ever seems to change for regular people and there are too many obstacles to being engaged in politics. What solves this apathy or cynicism is grassroots organizing like the type done by WFP or DSA and other political organizations and parties. People will vote Democrat if they understand it will be in their interest to do so. Remember, the majority of the population are not these political fanboys and fangirls but rather people who don't know or care about politics and don't vote. Those are the people you have to reach and they're the ones who can be shifted anyway. 

And doing that is actually upstream of legalizing something like political fusion or changing the way votes are counted. Those kinds of reforms are only possible if the work is done to organize people and build some power and influence among the voting base. Without it, as we saw in NY, Democrats and Republicans work hand in hand to basically preserve the decaying status quo for their benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
