<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43038056528.0" user="gslavik" delta="False">
    <text>Working Families Party in NY has no electoral power. I would vote for their candidates, especially if they cross-nominated someone from another party just to get them more votes so they could keep ballot access.

WFP nominated (often) Democratic candidates just to be able to keep ballot access. From some research I did long ago, around 1% of registered voters in NY are registered as anything except Democratic (just over 50%), Independent (around 30%), or Republican (around 20%) (that is, "other" parties are a rounding error among the three listed registrations).

&gt; With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

I can see this being true only if "straight ticket" voting was the only way you could vote. Since it is not the case, your argument is not entirely accurate.

&gt; Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.

Changing our voting/representational systems towards something like RCV or proportional representation would achieve that to a greater effect. Currently, if your party gets 5% (minimum number of vote portion needed to get into parliament in proportional representation systems) of the votes for a national seat (Congress, for example) evenly across the country, you get 0 seats. If your party can get 5% of the votes evenly across the country in a proportional representation system, you know have something like 20 seats (out of 435 if we use US House of Representatives).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
