<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032401345.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really see how this would help solve the problem of two parties in American politics holding 99% of the political power. The case is already basically "If you want to run for office in the US, then you must do it as either a Republican or a Democrat if you want a chance to win." 

You're allowed on the ticket in down-ballot races even if you don't have a candidate on the main election. 

We don't vote for politcal parties in the US, technically, we vote for candidates.

If a ballot has Joe Biden (Democrat) and Joe Biden (Same guy Different Party) are both on the ballot, that's just confusing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032478302.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I don't really see how this would help solve the problem of two parties in American politics holding 99% of the political power.

It doesn't, but that's not the issue the OP is trying to address. Rather, it simply lessens the issues associated with spoiler candidatea within the current political system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032540521.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>How? Either you share a candidate with one of the two parties, or you share a candidate with another 3rd party. 

If you share with a rep or dem, it's meaningless. 

If a bunch of 3rd parties band together, and run their own candidate it's still going to spoil for whichever candidate they are closer to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032571668.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you share with a rep or dem, it's meaningless...

It's not meaningless, because those votes then actually have an impact in avoiding "the alternative". That is, if you more closely align with the Democrat candidate, then there's a meaningful impact in helping avoid a Republican win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032591034.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>What is the difference between voting for Joe Biden (democrat) and voting for Joe Biden (Green).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032619528.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't one, but that's not the relevant difference.

The relevant difference is between voting Joe Biden (Green) vs. voting Sam Nobody (Green).

In the former case, your vote makes a difference (at least as much as one can). In the latter, it's meaningless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032667028.0" user="Dalexe10" delta="False">
    <text>See, you’re confused… we’re talking about this from a perspective where we want parties other than rd to have influence. In your scenario, lets say i’m the green party in a state… i could already accomplish your objective of giving all of my votes to a mainstream party by just not running a candidate and endorsing whichever rd candidate i like better</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032709072.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>That's fair in the short term, but per the OP you lose the attention your way.

The OPs idea is that they can still maintain the public image, their identity in the public's eyes. They can still influence people to vote for "them", thereby entrenching themselves in the public mind. In the future, this gives them future influence (either by allowing them to align with a different party, or if they become sufficiently significant, become the party who has a greater influence on the candidate being run).

With your approach, they just simply disappear into obscurity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032744946.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; their identity in the public's eyes

As an off-brand democratic party who just re-skin the same candidate? I don't see how this helps them. If they want prominence, run good candidates on their own platform in elections that have room for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032774433.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>You're doing most everything the same -- you engage people, spread your message, garner supporters, lists, etc. The only difference is that you direct them to the best available candidate ("available" defined as one for whom a vote would meaningfully make a difference given the political system), rather than a more closely ideologically aligned candidate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032790257.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>That's all completely allowed already. They don't need to have the same candidate listed twice on the ballot.

There's nothing stopping the Green Party from going out and campaigning for Joe Biden right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032800548.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That's all completely allowed already. They don't need to have the same candidate listed twice on the ballot...

Would they be listed twice? I'd imagine they be listed as both -- Joe Biden (Democrat/Green).

Either way, the point is to officially indicate they're your preferred candidate in this election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032820955.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>Another negative I just thought of.

Should I be allowed to form the Puppy Kicking Party then put my name on the ballot next to a candidate I don't like? 

Donald Trump (Republican/Libertarian/Puppy Kicking)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032844777.0" user="JustinRandoh" delta="False">
    <text>Presumably "fused" candidates would be able to consent to the fusion -- this seems like a non-issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43351757911.0" user="Chorby-Short" delta="False">
    <text>How it often works is as a threat. If the conservatives command 8% of the vote in a  district where the Republicans need that 8% share to win, then the conservstives can leverage that to win republican concessionsions in exchange for conservative support. The threat of having the election spoiled is what nominally helps keep the major parties in line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034614343.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>Down ballot voting which is what a huge percentage of people do.

I personally would like to see the ballots randomized with no distinction as to what party a person is representing. Get rid of down ballot voting and try and force people to research individual canidates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034634122.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>I think you'd just wind up with a lot of voting that is either random, or based entirely on names.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034897282.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. There is a lady in my state who has won primaries simply because her name is Twinkle ( it stands out and is easy to remember). 

Ideally, people would throw their votes away at an even pace and the informed voters would decide the election.

Of course in my state you can pretty easily tell what party a person is based on their name so maybe it's not the best idea. 

It could just be inviting problems. The majority black district would meltdown if a white woman changed her name to something ethnic like Shoquesha Freeman and won. Same if a black guy changed his name to gregory ( i think thats a white name) or something and won.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43035068197.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>Already is. 

[https://www.npr.org/2016/07/27/487577930/why-the-first-name-on-the-ballot-often-wins](https://www.npr.org/2016/07/27/487577930/why-the-first-name-on-the-ballot-often-wins)

TLDR: Being listed first on the ballot vs last makes about a 10% difference on down ballot votes. 

And worse, that's just people who vote the first option. If folks are truly voting randomly, that'd be in addition to that effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034928273.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You're allowed on the ticket in down-ballot races even if you don't have a candidate on the main election.

This is not generally the case long term. 

Ballot access laws will dissolve your party in most states if you fail to meet certain election thresholds for gubernatorial or presidential races. 

So, yes, you could do that for exactly one election. Then you cease being a party, can no longer run candidates, your voters are deregistered, and you have to reform from scratch. 

Not coincidentally, all surviving third parties run these candidates.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
