<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43034910924.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>Three objections: 

1. Party membership as identity will work against third party identities. If a third party supports the Democrat candidate for president, they will be viewed as Democrats. If they support Republicans, they will be viewed as Republicans. By associating a smaller brand very strongly with a more widely known brand, the larger brand is likely to dominate the smaller. 
2. A better solution is to simply remove ballot access laws that function solely as an obstacle to more options. Most states require that a third party field a presidential candidate that reaches a certain amount of electoral success(1% in my state) to remain a party. Fusionism is sort of a workaround for that, but it would be preferable to simply remove the bar altogether. Have some very minimal law to clean out only truly abandoned parties, not those running candidates and having thousands of supporters. 
3. This is a poor solution to the "throwing the election" myth, which rarely happens in practice, and is only possible due to the FPTP voting system. Approval or RCV solve this entirely while permitting more than two choices. Both have been used to good effect...with Australia using RCV nationally for over a hundred years. This is probably a far smaller effect than ballot access problems, but even if one wishes to fix it, the solution is obviously not fusionism, which does not provide a third presidential candidate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
