<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2475325074.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14xqt1u/cmv_electoral_fusion_should_be_legal_throughout/">
    <title>CMV: electoral fusion should be legal throughout the US.</title>
    <original_poster>PublicFurryAccount</original_poster>
    <original_post>Electoral fusion is when two or more parties agree to nominate the same candidate. This practice is only fully legal in New York and Connecticut, the former of which has been covered nationally somewhat because of the relationship between Rep. Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez and the Working Families Party.

I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote. With electoral fusion, a minor party can nominate a major-party candidate while still running their own in down ballot races they’re more likely to win. This allows the minor party to be a player without being a spoiler, garner attention, and provide a political home for its members (who no longer need to strategically split their ticket).

Further, I think this might help ease political cynicism. Many people treat party membership as an identity and some dissatisfaction with politics is no doubt linked to identity mismatch. People who are Democrats because they oppose Republicans, for example, might be happier in the Green or Purple Parties *if they can be assured that voting third party won’t throw the election.*

This isn’t a view I hold terribly strongly but I do hold it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43032400752.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I think electoral fusion solves a major dilemma in the American political system: minor political parties need to run candidates in prominent elections to gain attention but, for that same reason, the voters will be wasting their vote

[Ranked choice voting](https://fairvote.org/our-reforms/ranked-choice-voting/) solves this better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032428103.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Fun story. 

In my state, several years ago now, the legislature was considering online voting for active duty personnel using the DOD’s system. I don’t remember what it was called. They had numerous people come up to talk about how soldiers might be in remote places and unable to return a ballot. 

Admirable goal but internet voting is foolish, both as far as internet security but also the particular implementation had no apparent plan for recounts or double checking. 

Luckily it did not pass. Instead active duty voters are given a ranked choice ballot at the start of the primaries iirc. Such an obviously better idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032475583.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>So there's always *a little* fraud in every election, but either the person who suggested that doesn't know what the internet is or they knew exactly what was going to happen and hoped they could be in control of it.

Jesus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032842166.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Let’s not forget laziness as well :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032668412.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Ranked choice voting is fine. I have nothing against it. However, it's NEVER going to break the two-party system. It's NEVER going to make third parties viable national parties. It would probably help a few very charismatic third party candidates win some minor local elections, or maybe even a House race. It's not going to fundamentally change anything about the parties that govern us, though.

The big flaw in thinking with people who believe RCV would make any meaningful change is that they're imagining most people who say they'd prefer a third party want the *same* third party. This simply isn't true. Most Republicans who would vote third party would vote for the Libertarian Party or Constitution Party. Most Democrats would vote for the Green Party or maybe DSA. Some centrists would vote for the No Labels or Reform Party. People would vote for their preferred third party, then put their preferred major party as their second choice. And a hell of a lot of people would still vote for the major parties. When the votes are tallied the major parties would still have the largest shares of the votes. If neither had a majority they'd eliminate whichever third party got the least votes and reallocate those. If Libertarian got the least votes, most of those would go to the Republican. Or, if Green got the least, most would go to the Democrats. They'd retally and a major party would inevitably win.

What's more, the first time a major race was decided by RCV runoff there'd be even more claims that a third party "stole" votes from the losing major party than we got in 2016 (or 2000 or 1992).

If you really want to break the two party system then we need to eliminate single-member legislative districts and switch to proportional representation. Make districts up to 5 members (or so). If 20% of the people in that district want a Libertarian candidate, they get their Representative. If 40% want Democrats, they'd get 2 Representatives. Etc, etc. It's WAY more representative than single-member districts, and it allows minority political voices to be heard more than any other system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032690687.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If you really want to break the two party system then we need to eliminate single-member legislative districts and switch to proportional representation. 

Look, I don't disagree with anything you said in the abstract. But, RCV can be implemented without a constitutional amendment, whereas proportional representation cannot. It is primarily for that reason that I didn't bring it up. But yeah, I'd much rather that be the system, I just don't see it ever happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43032757403.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>I actually don't think proportional representation would require an Amendment. I think any state could pass it on a state-wide level on their own. Here's Article 1, Section 2 of the Constitution (the part that describes the structure of the House):

&gt;The House of Representatives shall be composed of Members chosen every second Year by the People of the several States, and the Electors in each State shall have the Qualifications requisite for Electors of the most numerous Branch of the State Legislature.

&gt;No Person shall be a Representative who shall not have attained to the Age of twenty five Years, and been seven Years a Citizen of the United States, and who shall not, when elected, be an Inhabitant of that State in which he shall be chosen.

&gt;Representatives and direct Taxes shall be apportioned among the several States which may be included within this Union, according to their respective Numbers, which shall be determined by adding to the whole Number of free Persons, including those bound to Service for a Term of Years, and excluding Indians not taxed, three fifths of all other Persons. The actual Enumeration shall be made within three Years after the first Meeting of the Congress of the United States, and within every subsequent Term of ten Years, in such Manner as they shall by Law direct. The Number of Representatives shall not exceed one for every thirty Thousand, but each State shall have at Least one Representative; and until such enumeration shall be made, the State of New Hampshire shall be entitled to chuse three, Massachusetts eight, Rhode-Island and Providence Plantations one, Connecticut five, New-York six, New Jersey four, Pennsylvania eight, Delaware one, Maryland six, Virginia ten, North Carolina five, South Carolina five, and Georgia three.

&gt;When vacancies happen in the Representation from any State, the Executive Authority thereof shall issue Writs of Election to fill such Vacancies.

&gt;The House of Representatives shall chuse their Speaker and other Officers; and shall have the sole Power of Impeachment.

It lays out how many Representatives each state gets, but the first part just says that the people of each state get to pick their Representatives. It doesn't say anything about single-member districts or multi-member districts. It's just always been the norm to have single-member districts. I'm not a constitutional lawyer, but I think a state could pass a law creating multi-member districts and using proportional representation with no problem.

Of course, this Supreme Court could very well just pull some BS out of their asses if they don't like it. They don't really seem to care what the law or Constitution says if it disagrees with their political agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034808013.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>Would also help get rid of gerrymandering if they did away with the districts and just appointed the people proportionately based on state elections.

The only issue is each current district wouldn't have their own personal representative that is loyal to them. It would not go over well with the public. 

Alabama is having to add a 2nd likely democrat/black district and people are already freaking out about how the Mobile metro won't have a representative that is loyal to them and how their rep would most likely come from the more inland areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43033089947.0" user="Familiar_Math2976" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; However, it's NEVER going to break the two-party system. It's NEVER going to make third parties viable national parties. It would probably help a few very charismatic third party candidates win some minor local elections, or maybe even a House race. It's not going to fundamentally change anything about the parties that govern us, though.

The fundamental benefit of RCV is not necessarily breaking the 2PS, but establishing the true intentions of the electorate. If a vote comes back 40% pink, 35% purple, 25% yellow, then all the yellow #2 votes push the Purple over the top, then it makes clearest that Yellow is a significant voice and should be given some credence.

&gt;What's more, the first time a major race was decided by RCV runoff there'd be even more claims that a third party "stole" votes from the losing major party than we got in 2016 (or 2000 or 1992).

Those people don't understand the system and we shouldn't design our system around appeasing their ignorance. The whole point of RCV is to mitigate the 3rd party spoiler effect. Consider that people have fabricated "They stole our election" claims out of literally nothing so there's no ironclad solution there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034728961.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>I like your idea.

Couple it with the issue that a Representative in the house represents over 700k people on average. Knocking that down to 50k or even 100k would be a large help. Your idea fixes that problem as well. 

The 50.01% winner take all setup should be reformed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43035145310.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>I also agree that the House should be massively expanded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43034882926.0" user="HappyChandler" delta="False">
    <text>You’re putting some of the effects FTPT on RCV. 

It wouldn’t necessarily require a charismatic candidate. For example, in NY, WFP could nominate a progressive for governor versus Hochul. They could endorse 1-2 WFP, Hochul. Hochul could either co-run with WFP, attempt to get moderate Republicans, or some other way. 

And it would get more options in the room. 

And, parties would build over years. Success begets success, and WFP can’t succeed too much because then they become spoilers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43035107310.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's NEVER going to make third parties viable national parties. It would probably help a few very charismatic third party candidates win some minor local elections, or maybe even a House race. 

Third parties have already done these things. The Libertarian Party routinely holds hundreds of local offices and gets the occasional state house race. They have had exactly one congressional seat, albeit for unusual circumstances. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;What's more, the first time a major race was decided by RCV runoff there'd be even more claims that a third party "stole" votes from the losing major party than we got in 2016 (or 2000 or 1992).

This has also already happened, in Alaska this past election cycle. Oddly enough, it was three GOP and a Democrat, but the Democrat ended up winning with a plurality, so a third party could not be blamed. RCV was blamed instead by the large GOP majority, and it faces a possible repeal. 

Approval is better than RCV for the reasons you list, and RCV is imperfect, but we don't really need to postulate this, we have experimental data illustrating it. 

Alternatively, one can look at Australia, which has had RCV for over a hundred years, but is still a de facto two party system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43038068731.0" user="gslavik" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; People would vote for their preferred third party, then put their preferred major party as their second choice

I think this is perfectly fine and a bonus in ranked choice. This would also give us information on initial choices for representation. This would also let the bigger parties know who to make alliances with and change their platform.

&gt; If you really want to break the two party system then we need to eliminate single-member legislative districts and switch to proportional representation. Make districts up to 5 members (or so). If 20% of the people in that district want a Libertarian candidate, they get their Representative. If 40% want Democrats, they'd get 2 Representatives. Etc, etc. It's WAY more representative than single-member districts, and it allows minority political voices to be heard more than any other system.

I agree with you on this point. However, I think the entire country should be voting in for Congress. Considering that people elect Senators, too, I think there should be an amendment turning Congress into a unicameral legislative branch.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
