<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43065928903.0" user="dale_glass" delta="False">
    <text>I'm having trouble understanding what's this supposed to look like.

You think somebody will invade, take over, and then start farming on Canada's former land?

Russia is a complete non-starter. They can't take Ukraine, and have shown they have extreme difficulty projecting power outside their borders. They've lost a huge chunk of their stuff already. They'll probably be weak for a long time to come, so the prospect of them invading Canada with any kind of success is a very far off one. There's no rush with dealing with that scenario.

For the US, why bother? War is expensive, wouldn't it be much cheaper to just pay for the food? Canada, as a huge and modern country would be a tough nut to crack and no doubt get support from other countries in such an event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065958990.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You think somebody will invade, take over, and then start farming on Canada's former land?

America proved that it can elect an external state puppet.  
I don't put it beyond them trying to invade Canada in the next 50 years.  


I don't say to build the nukes now. Canada has the reactors and the technical know-how to achieve atomic weapons in less than a year.   


But in a world of climate change where food and water insecurity is increasing across the board.  


No one can put aside the premise of being invade solely for food and water.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066155472.0" user="jadacuddle" delta="False">
    <text>When did America elect a puppet president????</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066158141.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text> 2017 to 2021</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066169087.0" user="jadacuddle" delta="False">
    <text>Trump was incompetent at best in almost every aspect, but was there any proof that he was that puppet of another country? Which country would he even be the puppet of?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066176681.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>[https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/09/biden-can-access-trump-putin-calls-468100](https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/09/biden-can-access-trump-putin-calls-468100)  


https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-trump-russia-contacts-idUSKCN18E106  


The guy was Sus at best</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066205931.0" user="jadacuddle" delta="False">
    <text>The first article you mentioned specifies that Trump did this with all foreign leaders calls during his presidency, and also says “But former senior Trump advisers said it was rare that Trump would say anything to the Russian leader that he had not already said publicly”

The second one just says that Trump distrusted the bureaucracy of the US National Security apparatus and considered it more productive to establish more direct channels to Russia in order to communicate better about fighting ISIS in Syria (probably the only time the US and Russia have agreed on something in the past decade). 

Not really sure what evidence you’ve seen to convince you that an America president was entirely puppeted by a foreign country but so far this isn’t very convincing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068186099.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>You mean 2021 to 2024.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068253720.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>Sure buddy. 90% of the world disagrees with you. But sure</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068371356.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>The Durham report showed the entire Trump-Russia thing was not only a hoax, but that Obama
and everyone else in charge knew that it was bogus in Crossfire Hurricane.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068441091.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>Yes buddy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068756270.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
