<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43065860750.0" user="No_Percentage_3921" delta="False">
    <text>but then, wouldn’t we all just have less water?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065866620.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it is basically a dead man trigger for the protection of the Canadian people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065903437.0" user="No_Percentage_3921" delta="False">
    <text>oh okay! i understand now! not sure if i really agree, but it wouldn’t be the worst last resort imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065923369.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with dead man triggers, is when do you trigger them

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o861Ka9TtT4

With a full scale invasion it's easy, but what if you get salami tactics?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066100599.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>I think the salami tactics would hit a wall if there was ever a point where water so was valuable they attempt to invade over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066123626.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is also if someone decides you're bluffing, you then either accept the invasion or destroy your own people's water supply</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066360889.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP is putting forth a situation where the water crisis is so desperate for some reason that a land invasion simply for that purpose would be justified. Like essentially a situation where let’s say Russia, can’t get enough water to prevent its citizens from dying en mass so they decide to invade Canada specifically for their lakes and water. Not saying it’s likely or anything, just what OP is presenting</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066394431.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but if you're the Canadian prime minister when that happens and you can't resist through a conventional army you either surrender or destroy your people's water supply. If Russia or whoever decides you won't kill your people then the deterrent is pointless</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066498064.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>What happens to your people if Russia claims the water though? Either way the people are doomed. It’s scorch earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066580633.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing happens, Russia can't teleport that water away</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066675544.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>So Russia invaded with no intent to use it themselves? They’re just gonna let the Canadians use it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066776331.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, Canadians are going to be able to use it no matter what. The difference will be to what extent and to how difficult it would be. It just isn't feasible for any political entity to make such enormous swathes of natural water completely inaccessible to the people who live near them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066800933.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>If Russians seize the territory, how will they use it? It’s also not feasible for any political entity to invade Canada for their water alone but here we are talking about such a scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066805463.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>Presumably by exporting as much as they can back to Russia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066836566.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>I was referring to the Canadians. I figure a nation willing to invade for water isn’t going to share said water.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066848911.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>Again, Russia just won't be able to stop them all the time. The bodies of water we are talking about are absolutely enormous, can't exactly post a guard every 10 feet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066863337.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>I figure they could set up a very effective exclusion zone, however this doesn’t exactly mean survival for the Canadians. What about the ones who don’t live immediately next to the lake who now have no import of water to water them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066870401.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>They're in trouble, for sure. Still better than the alternative proposed alternative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066881024.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>Is it? I think it would be better to actively deter the invasion in the first place with the threat of the nukes. 

Canada is fucked without the water so it’s better they ensure that so is Russia if they try and take it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066974284.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>Yep, it is without a doubt. Permanently (pretty much) soiling the water supply precludes the possibility of Canadians fighting for and regaining that water. That's the thing about nuclear deterrents, sure, they're good deterrents, but if they threats are actually carried out everyone loses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067061969.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>Thats kind of the point no? It’s why we haven’t waged war with Russia or pushed any country with nukes too far.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067076304.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, although I'd like to clarify that Canada loses far, far more than any invading force in this case as opposed to a traditional MAD scenario. If this were carried out, Canada would be permanently fucked, and the invading force would pretty much just be in the same position they were in before, minus some soldiers and money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067082487.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>It comes down to how desperate the situation truly is for water</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067978998.0" user="Cryonaut555" delta="False">
    <text>Russia has a single lake that has almost 1/4 of the Earth's surface fresh water. They're fine for water.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066172195.0" user="deadfeet3" delta="False">
    <text>So, say the Russia invades canada to overthrow the government and take control of the water reserves. Who suffers the most from your solution?

Is it the russians, who did not have access to those reserves in the first place? Or is it the canadian people who rely on those reserves? Say the real target is the USA. Would it not be smart to attack canada first, triggering the dead man trigger and contaminating the USA water supply? Is the USA, a long term ally and trade partner of Canada, really a threat at all?

All i can see are ways it can backfire</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066440579.0" user="Bad_Mood_Larry" delta="False">
    <text>The United States could easily cripple Canada with economic sanctions and would invade immediately before a nuclear threat could be on it borders. A nuclear dead man switch is a valid causa belli in eyes of most of the world as Canada would soon be deemed as rogue nuclear state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070989924.0" user="denyjunctionfunction" delta="False">
    <text>Considering a large portion of the population lives in the vicinity of these lakes, and most of the US’s doesn’t. Killing off Canada doing this and then just taking the rest of Canada would be a move desperate people would take. You’re just fucking the other parts of Canada.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43072550679.0" user="Maestro_Primus" delta="False">
    <text>No it isn't.  It guarantees the death of the canadian people.  At best, it is a dead man trigger for the canadian GOVERNMENT.  The people survive an invasion and go on to live their lives under a different flag.  Radiating all of the water is just killing yourselves out of spite.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
