<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43086225330.0" user="3superfrank" delta="False">
    <text>Why install atomic bombs in big lakes when Canada can just...
*exist*.

Canada's a pretty big country with very sparsed out population centers. Which means so long as it resists, invading and occupying it is going to be very, very painful for any adversary army who fancies it. Including the US. An invasion of Canada, even in current circumstances, would necessitate going through a grinding war of attrition so bad and so costly, that every potential adversary has a less expensive option to deal with their water/food shortage.

And that's under the assumption that you share a sizeable Land-Border with Canada (the only candidate being the US), and all of Canada's friends suddenly decide to ditch Canada. Which, if either don't happen, your invasion has gone from the realm of totally not worth it to utterly impossible.

If you're the US, the best (and really only) candidate to invade Canada, the US could also just...ask nicely for Canada's resources. Cus they're close buddies. And whatever mutually beneficial agreement they can reach will no doubt be better for the US than trying to invade and occupy Canada for those same resources.

And if you're anyone else...well I I don't need to go into that do I.

And this is leaving aside the other comments here talking about the exact usefulness of a body of water hundred of km away from a population center and so on.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
