<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43065968811.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>The climate change hooplah has reached "Mad Max" predictions?

Is this a common prediction or is this just something specific to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065979195.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>It is a common trend among young people to be aware that several climate targets have been breached and that most of how humanity function as a society will change in the next 100 years yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066004772.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really new though.

It's always been missed 10 year deadlines and consequences after our grandkids are dead.

But I've never heard that Canada is going to be at risk because of water wars before your post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066308841.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>God I wish we wouldn't get consequences until another 100 years go by</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066346881.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It is a common trend among young people to be aware that several climate targets have been breached and that most of how humanity function as a society will change in the next 100 years yes.

Is maxi wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066381937.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>No, that's correct you were wrong though when you said about things happening after our grandkids are dead.

&gt;It's always been missed 10 year deadlines and consequences after our grandkids are dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067105616.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>Again

&gt; It is a common trend among young people to be aware **that several climate targets have been breached** and that most of **how humanity function as a society will change in the next 100 years yes.**

The first bold part of his statement was "It's always been missed 10 year deadlines" and the second bolded part is "after our grandkids are dead."

Which part of my assessment of his comment do you feel is wrong?  Do you think I'm guessing he's older than he is and his grandkids will really be alive in 2123?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43069359815.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>The part where you're wrong is where you think within the next hundred years doesn't include the next 15, 40, 60 years. I certainly won't have any grandkids in the next 15 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070643655.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>So how far away, rounding to the nearest decade, is the invasion of Canada and the Mad Max Water Wars?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070668914.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>No idea, do you think consequences could include anything before that happens or is that the only possible consequence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070739473.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>But you're saying it's definitely sooner than a 2123 like OP is saying.  I won't set a reminder to say I told you so, just a ballpark guess- when is th invasion of Canada for their water going to happen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070749182.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>So you really think the only consequence that could possibly come from climate change is the Canadian invasion? No other consequences can happen only that one? Muppet</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070755893.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>I'm literally using OPs situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070770300.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>And I literally said "consequences" not "the exact scenario OP described", notice the difference there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070789459.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>Oh so you're not talking about what I'm talking about and you're mad at a strawman.

Pretty standard of you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070988543.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, apparently when you replied to a comment about general consequences it didn't mean the specific one you were thinking of, that's definitely my fault and not your lack of reading comprehension.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43071001570.0" user="Novemberists" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it's my fault I didn't fit the straw man you built me up to be.

So when's the soonest, biggest global warming consequence hitting?  Is it dire or is it one of those "global warming is when the weather happens" things?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43072644107.0" user="ZombieCupcake22" delta="False">
    <text>Right, you acted as if people were saying something different to what they did but other people made the strawman, whatever you say.

I suppose the biggest and soonest is hard to say, the increased frequency and intensity of droughts, foods and heatwaves and all the secondary impacts like worse wild fires are already happening and will continue to get worse. The increased acidity and decreasing oxygen availability in the oceans is pretty big. The increase in food and water borne diseases, drop in food production and security will affect everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
