<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43066108232.0" user="KarmicComic12334" delta="False">
    <text>No. What is the worst case scenario for an invasion of canada without a doctor strangelove device? Lotsa people die, the government changes hands, the surviving canadians blend with the invaders and life goes on. In a few generations whether it is chinada or the United states of north of mexico, it is just a country where people live full happy lives.

What is the worst case with the doomsday plan? All canadians die, either from the invasion or slow painful radiation poisoning. Most of the usa dies of radiation poisoning, water keeps flowing, the gulf of mexico dies. Cancer rates in the carribean skyrocket. The government of canada falls, then the usa. In a few generations north american is a wild wasteland with few humans livi g short brutal lives and animals walking around with open sores, tumors, mutations. 

How is the latter better for anyone, even the people of canada?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066131304.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most of the usa dies of radiation poisoning

There you go. This is the deterrent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066180285.0" user="KarmicComic12334" delta="False">
    <text>How does that deter china or russia? Two birds one stone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066368161.0" user="Enderules3" delta="False">
    <text>Unless America assumes Canada is bluffing and attacks anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
