<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43066985445.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>Desalinization costs between $0.50 to $1.5 per litre.  To desalinize all the freshwater the US uses per year would be $193 billion, and that includes irrigation, and power-plant cooling. 

Canada's GDP was $1.988 trillion in 2021. Poisoning all of our own water would bring the GDP down to $0. It would be cheaper for Canada to pay to desalinize all of the US's water than to actually poison our own water.

&amp;#x200B;

From an invader's perspective, the US spent around $110 billion a year for the 21 years of the invasion of Afghanistan, a country 6.5% the size of Canada, with 0.5% the GDP, and a similar population. It would only cost $80 billion a year more to just desalinize 100% their own water as an invasion would likely cost. 

In short, there is no world where someone invades Canada for water, because it would be way more expensive for everyone than even the most expensive alternatives.

The places that might be invaded for water are poor countries that cannot afford desalinization, fighting other poor countries that have low military budgets, or landlocked countries with no access to seawater.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
