<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43073324073.0" user="PlayingTheWrongGame" delta="False">
    <text>1) Being alive as member states of the United States is preferable to dying of radiation poisoning.

2) If the US were to substantially change to the point where it poses an existential risk to Canada, what makes you think such a deterrent would work?

3) Beginning construction of such a project would **trigger** a war with the United States, and there is a zero percent chance that Canada could keep such a secret from the US. There is no chance the U.S. would tolerate such a threat in North America. It would try diplomacy and covert means first, but it would resort to war if those weren’t working. 

4) Pissing off the United States precisely when Canada most needs international support from a powerful military neighbor to defend its territorial integrity in the arctic seems like a pretty ill-conceived idea. You’re basically presuming the US is the primary threat, but ignoring the fact that China and Russia would actively prefer removing both Canada and the US from the world stage so it’s hardly a deterrent.

5) Given that triggering such a thing amounts of collective suicide, what’s stopping the US or other more powerful countries from encroaching on Canadian sovereignty with salami tactics? Where each provocation causes Canada to lose something but none of them individually are enough to hit the suicide button.

6) Canada is completely incapable of defending itself from a hypothetical US intrusion into its airspace. These facilities would be destroyed before they could be triggered, likely before the Canadians even knew anything was intruding in their airspace. The only way to eliminate such a risk would be to make them true dead man switch type doomsday devices… which are too risky to keep around in peacetime due to the risk of accidents or mistakes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
