<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43065892794.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>That's not a huge deterrent though, it's hurting Canada itself and not the invaders. Worst case, the invasion fails, and the invaders are more or less in the same place as they were before minus a few soldiers and tech. Best case, they get colaborators to disarm/remove those bombs.

A deterrent would be installing dirty bombs in the lakes of other countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065896853.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>The only reason to invade Canada would be water at this point. The rest is forest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065905297.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but trying and failing to secure the water is still worth it if theres no other downside than not getting the water.

A deterrent is supposed to be worse than just failure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065995637.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>If the US were to invade us for water, this prerequisite that they need it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066447976.0" user="AlphaQueen3" delta="False">
    <text>The parts of the US that would likely need water are far enough from canada that it wouldn't make any sense.  The northern  half of the country is generally pretty water-rich, and also pretty cold so would remain farmable (with shifting crops).  The southwest might be in deep shit, but it makes a lot more sense for them to build desalination plants on the pacific, or ship water south from the Pacific northwest or the great lakes region, than to invade canada and try to ship enormous quantities of water all the way down to southern california or new mexico.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066850588.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>If they do nothing, they get no extra water. If they try and fail, they get no extra water and lose a few soldiers and tanks and stuff. If they try and succeed, they get the water.

"not getting water" is not a deterrent. Because it's not making anyone elses situation actually worse. While actually making the situation worse for your own citizens.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
