<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43066179828.0" user="pigeonshual" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think Canadian sovereignty is more important than not doing a total ecocide?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43068531509.0" user="LMFN" delta="False">
    <text>I would rather die than be part of the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070433750.0" user="Big-Ranger-4318" delta="False">
    <text>What? The US is much more prosperous than Canada. I understand why you'd not want to be part of a different country, but why would you rather die than be part of a more prosperous country than your own?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43073105194.0" user="LMFN" delta="False">
    <text>Are you really that more prosperous with the insane wealth gap?



Elon having a few hundred billion as a whole bumps up the average but y'all got outrageous healthcare fees, a mass shooting problem and one half of your government is openly a bunch of treasonous fascists.



I don't want to live in a country that still hasn't dealt with the Neo-Confederates running rampant in the Southern state governments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43070931986.0" user="pigeonshual" delta="False">
    <text>Not what I asked</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
