<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2481523944.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/151fo4o/cmv_canada_should_install_dirty_atomic_bombs_in/">
    <title>cmv: Canada should install dirty atomic bombs in each big lake as an invasion deterrent.</title>
    <original_poster>maxi1134</original_poster>
    <original_post>With the upcoming climate changes and the fact that Canada has 20% of the freshwater reserve in the world. Russia, America, and other states might have an interest in invading Canada to access the water reserves and the Canadian north that will taw out and become available for crops.    
  

With this information, I believe that rigging the water table to be radioactive for eons in case of invasion would be the perfect deterrent to prevent the invasion from any other state.   

  

Especially America, as their water table would then also be contaminated</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43065859095.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>And if it goes off by accident or due to a false-alarm?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065863582.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>The same can be said about American nuclear weapons</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065893434.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>But they're stored in protected facilities, not just there in actively traveled lakes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065907485.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>The nuke would not be directly in the lake. But in a facility near it. Something happen, you drop it in the lake in 30 minutes and activate it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065950478.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, who is invading wealthy countries for access to lakes? Nestle literally just buying up that shit and nobody is stopping them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065983086.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>You assume that the capitalist system, who is failing as we speak in various part of the world, will continue to work and that international exchange will remain the same</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066031199.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>you need to add in the OP that the context for this is assuming a total global transformation where nations are broken, north america is weak and somehow worse as a trading partner than a costly invasion target for fucking fresh water.

I still wouldn't nuke the lakes. There is no winning that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066192904.0" user="SouthDakota_Baseball" delta="False">
    <text>Nestle isnt using shit for water compared to agriculture. Their entire water use is equivalent of about 1500 acres of corn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065898828.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Correct. Is this a rebuff, or an agreement?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065910304.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>Because a bluff can be called.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065918647.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Can you elaborate, please?

A bluff about installing nukes in the waters can be called just the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43067333205.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Can you elaborate, please?

A bluff about the nukes in the water can be called just the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065955646.0" user="Mr_McFeelie" delta="False">
    <text>Yea the same can be said about nukes but pretty much everyone agrees that mutuality assured destruction sucks and is only in place because we can’t fix the situation anymore. People would probably sleep better if nukes were off the table so why add another one of those dead man triggers to the world ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43065964024.0" user="maxi1134" delta="False">
    <text>MAD only happens between nuke owners.  


This can be proved by Ukraine's invasion. Former nuke-owner who relinquished its nukes and got invaded</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43066993231.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it sure can. Not exactly a great defense of the idea though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43069920201.0" user="parlimentery" delta="False">
    <text>You say that as if the idea that the US should have nukes is some kind of self evident truth. I think most people are of the opinion that no one should have nukes, but that the path to that future isn't feasible because we can never guarantee unilateral disarmament or that previous non-nuclear powers won't start producing them.

Saying Canada should nuclear rearm would be, in my mind, a weird opinion, but maybe you could make a case that it would in some way stabilize the balance of power that has thus far prevented the use of any nuclear cruse missiles, but proposing that Canada should introduce an entirely new use for nuclear weapons in preparation for a hypothetical invasion? 

I was going to make a separate comment for more general counter arguments, but I think I will consolidate and transition into my other thoughts here.

1) This idea, no matter how much you over engineer the devices, can never be accident proof. These waterways freeze in the winter, there is a non-zero chance of earthquakes. Even under normal summer conditions there would be a strong downstream force on the structure. Sure, we have been counteracting the force of rivers for quite some time, but dams do fail, and so might this.

2) Canada would be opening itself up to a much more imminent and arguably more destructive force than climate change: terrorism. Even if these stations were 100% fool proof in terms of the structural engineering to prevent failure, they still have either a digital system that can be hacked or a physical system that can be infiltrated to detonate them.

3) Using this device would be tactically stupid and morally unfortunately and Canada's enemies would know this. Canada has much more fresh water than it needs for even its pre-devastating future invasion population. An army invading for the purpose of stealing water would probably not systematically kill every Canadian for multiple reasons: one, they are human beings who are probably anti-genocide. Two, the need people there to run the infrastructure needed to extract that water. They might subjugate Canadians to work in the water shipping industry, or they might handle that themselves and rely on Canadians to populate local communities that would make that extraction easier by providing things like access to food and services. These Canadians would probably not be well off, but lethal drinking water wouldn't exactly improve their circumstances. I would also contend that even if the invades were killing all Canadians, poisoning your own water to get revenge is still wrong. These are people who committed atrocities in the name of survival, which is surely more understandable than doing it in the name of an ideology. There also might be many dissenters forcibly relocated there to work.

4) This is maybe my weakest point, but I still think it is worth saying: this sends a God awful message to a world trying to unite to solve this problem. Building a contingency revenge plot at great cost and risk *might* look like Canada is declaring the problem unsolvable and giving up. As a large, developed nation this would undeniably have a ripple effect of countries concluding that it may be in their best interest to stop trying to prevent climate change and start preparing for world war 3.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
