<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28275499988.0" user="Kush_McNuggz" delta="False">
    <text>Just as saying not excepting change is narrow mindedness, so is making change for the sake of change. It comes down to what is the right solution, and most of the time we really don't know. So many aspects of life are so subjective, it really comes down to change, or the way things are. 

For example, I have a lot of foreign kids in my classes. They talk a lot between themselves and to the teacher much more than the American kids do. The traditionalist in me thinks they should shut up and let the teacher present the material. The other side of me thinks maybe it's better to be more verbally active in the lecture process. In the end, one really isn't right or wrong, they're just different. 

On a different note, things are the way they are for a reason. Everyone before us worked their lives to get to where we are now. For example, eating with friends/family is a tradition that most cultures have used for thousands of years, but we never really think about it or question it. I'd say the fact that this tradition has lasted so long with so many different people speaks for itself as to how good it is. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
