<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28274909666.0" user="Kirkaine" delta="False">
    <text>Well, yes and no. I'm by no means a conservative, but I at least respect the people I disagree with enough to make an effort to take them seriously.

You should read some Burke. It's easy to say that we should simply go with 'better' solutions when they come along. However, this is a difficult prescription given how naively ignorant we can be when it comes to trusting our own ability to tell which solution is 'better'. The conservative opposition to rash change isn't a whole lot different to the anti-GMO stance you see amongst some environmental groups. Not that change is inherently bad, but that society is really fucking complicated and interconnected, we're totally fucked if it breaks down, and we should exercise a hell of a lot of caution before proclaiming we're smart enough to go engineering it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28274922147.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>That makes sense for some policies and ideas but often we have an idea about what the (complicated and interconnected) impact will be  (i.e. a different state/country has already enacted a policy, or a similar one is already in place). 

The best example I can think of is gun laws in the states. Progressives have tonnes of examples that they can point to showing that banning guns massively reduces gun crime yet conservatives are often completely unwilling to consider this. 

I also think that they probably play up the argument that you're making i.e. Republicans keen to point out all the relatively small differences between Australia and the US in terms of conditions for gun reform, so therefore we wouldn't be fully aware of the far-reaching consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275029265.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, the argument that I often see from pro gun people isn't that there wouldn't be less gun crime, it's that the resulting drop in gun crime wouldn't be worth the loss of freedom. I think that the comparison to Australia is apt, but realize that while they had success,bit was at the expense of individual freedom, however little the right to own guns may be. In the US, there are even more guns, and the right to own them is enshrined in our Constitution, which logically means a larger loss of freedom (to me anyway). Is this greater loss of freedom worth it for us? I think so, but it doesn't make someone narrow-minded to come to a different conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275064088.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>Any loss of freedom argument is a principled one rather than practical though. So unless they're talking about 'slippery slope' of government control the argument is not relying on practical consequences. So ignoring what the principled role of the government is (i.e. protecting society vs. individual freedom), I think it's fair to say that a lot of Republicans think (or at least argue) that the country would practically be worse (i.e. more crime) if guns were banned. Which I think ignores the information from Australia etc. which gives an indication of the probable reality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275153012.0" user="Ifeellikeafatbaby" delta="False">
    <text>I just want to point out that in order to have a functioning society, we should stop saying people with differences in opinion from you are inherently stupid or bad.  There's a reason a lot of people are liberals and a lot of people are conservatives and it's not because either of them are stupid, regressive or intolerant as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275166956.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I've said that anywhere. The whole point of this post is to find reasons for alternative thinking beyond 'it's different from mine so must be wrong'. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275421830.0" user="Ifeellikeafatbaby" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying you said it, I'm just making the point that we shouldn't devolve to name calling or belittling of beliefs on either side.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275166583.0" user="FreeMarketFanatic" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that I think there would be more crime if guns were banned. It is indeed a principle. That principle is the right to self defense. 

Guns are important because of that adage "When seconds matter, the police are only minutes away."

You can not depend on the state to protect you. You have to take care of yourself sometimes. Guns help with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275180528.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>Just because you can link an argument to a principle, doesn't make it a principled argument. Principles are very often related to practical outcomes like in your example. Principles are about what's fair/right or more important (i.e. you think it's fair and right that individuals should have the ability to defend themselves). Practical arguments are about outcomes (e.g. rise or reduction in crime). These can also be linked to principles (i.e. I think lowering crime for the community is more important that an individual having the right to self defence). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275187924.0" user="FreeMarketFanatic" delta="False">
    <text>Right... our principles differ. I prefer to protect the rights of the individual, which is what the country was founded on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275383631.0" user="Taeyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Is "what the country was founded on" an argument in itself, in your opinion? In my opinion not, but this sub serves to see other views, so I'm curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275436796.0" user="FreeMarketFanatic" delta="False">
    <text>No, it isn't. However, I am invoking a plea to preserve something that was given to us and giving some insight into the conservative mindset. The preamble to the Constitution does say that the country was founded to "secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275417946.0" user="skybelt" delta="False">
    <text>Note that you have identified an important cleavage between conservatives and liberals, as discussed in [this article](http://www.vox.com/2016/1/13/10759874/republicans-democrats-different) among others - liberals prefer to strive for practical outcomes, conservatives for principled ones.  That's why these sorts of arguments often feel like you are bashing your head against a wall.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275933574.0" user="disinterestedMarmot" delta="False">
    <text>Haven't read the article, but I don't feel like Vox is a very reliable source for the differences between liberals and conservatives.

Besides that, from the conservative side, they'll always talk about idealistic liberals, trying to shoehorn in impractical and inefficient policies in an attempt to create their golden society. Republicans say liberals are idealistic for trying to elimimate poverty with welfare, for example. The liberal idealists think it will get people back on their feet, but a practical evaluation would reveal that people don't work as hard when they have a large social safety net (or something).

There are ideals and practicality on both sides. Both sides like to cast themselves as practical, and the other side as idealistic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275946402.0" user="skybelt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Haven't read the article, but

This is not a valuable contribution.

Vox is summarizing research conducted by political scientists.  Primary sources can be found and studied [here](http://matthewg.org/papers/ideologicalright.pdf), [here](http://matthewg.org/papers/policyredblue3.pdf), with another Vox article summarizing them [here](http://www.vox.com/2014/9/15/6131919/democrats-and-republicans-really-are-different).  [Jonathan Haidt](http://www.ted.com/talks/jonathan_haidt_on_the_moral_mind) has done some interesting, somewhat similar research as well.

I don't think it's intended as a critique of conservatives (or principle-driven thinking), but an explanation for why it often feels like the two political are talking past one another.  As was happening above - "I want to reduce gun deaths" versus "I want to protect individual liberty."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28276270866.0" user="disinterestedMarmot" delta="False">
    <text>I was pooping at work, so sue me. But Vox is undoubtedly liberally biased, and will go so far as cherrypicking data and relying on individual studies in order to make a stronger case. It's a step above most the conservative tripe, though. I'll read the article when I get home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275909880.0" user="cullen9" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think it's fair to say that a lot of Republicans think (or at least argue) that the country would practically be worse (i.e. more crime) if guns were banned.

This is why gun control will never pass, people forget that a lot of democrats are gun owners too. It's usually a city vs suburb/rural distinction, not a party one.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275729033.0" user="Waylander0719" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The best example I can think of is gun laws in the states. Progressives have tonnes of examples that they can point to showing that banning guns massively reduces gun crime yet conservatives are often completely unwilling to consider this.

In many cases they are not discounting those statistics or the effect of banning guns. But they consider the loss of liberty and (in their minds) opportunity for tyranny that stripping a population of its guns constitutes as a greater evil then the gun crimes. 

They will also point out that lower gun crime does not = lower crime overall. Many places with lower gun crimes will have much higher rates of things such as stabbings, you have simply replaced one (admittedly more effective) tool for another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28276249975.0" user="disinterestedMarmot" delta="False">
    <text>Liberals can point to how reducing guns reduces gun crime all they want, and the statistic still doesn't count for shit. For one thing, they often don't factor out suicide - while the increase in suicide is unfortunate, it constitutes a tiny minority of deaths, and isn't generally what we worry about when we think about gun violence.

The more egregious error, however, is that I don't give a shit if guns increase gun crime. Of course they will! What matters is if guns increase crime or murder in general - otherwise we just give up our right to arms in return for getting stabbed to death instead of shot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275287461.0" user="Dartimien" delta="False">
    <text>That anti-GMO example isn't really helping your argument</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275916144.0" user="disinterestedMarmot" delta="False">
    <text>Well they didn't say that conservatives were sensible - just that they were conservative (in the most literal meaning of the word).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
