<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28275636182.0" user="rend0ggy" delta="False">
    <text>Let's break down your characterization of conservatives:

1. Want things to stay the way they are (or revert back to how things were in some instances)

2. Therefore they are narrow minded and not willing to consider new ideas

"Narrow-mindedness" is essentially being intolerant to other perspectives - this isn't inherint in conservatism - they just favour the traditional way of doing things. One could easily argue that progressivism is a "narrow minded" perspective that seeks to move us towards an elusive utopia.

Neither progressivism or conservatism is necessarily *rational*, which we'll take as antithetical to "narrow-mindedness".

Some of your responses are:

* Conservatives don't acknowledge working models of progressive ideas like Scandinavia

The issue with this particular point is that conservatives acknowledge that many countries have severely fucked up by attempting to create a socialist paradise on earth. You need only look to south america, to countries that enact the SAME policies as Scandinavian countries, to see the disparities in outcome that result from key demographic and environmental factors. That's another thing conservatives acknowledge - that European socialist countries do well because they tend to have homogeneous populations that value 'the greater good' - German citizens are the best example this mentality (they have a welfare state but every person sees value in contributing to the society at large).

The US is fundamentally different to these countries - and fundementally better when seen through a conservative lens. Sweden didn't give us the iPhone, or the internet, or Google. Sweden aren't a cultural and economic powerhouse. Sweden doesn't have the strongest military in the world - Conservatives see America as exceptional and don't want to adopt Sweden's policies because they don't want to BE LIKE Sweden

* Facts in the gun control debate

There aren't any facts, there are correlations. And even if there were correlations, the gun debate isn't necessarily *solely* about which policy would reduce death the most - banning cars would save 3x as many lives as banning guns. It's about weight an essential and fundamental liberty against the social and individual costs of gun violence - there isn't a "rational" calculus here to make. You can't balance those two equations</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
