<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28274922283.0" user="heelspider" delta="False">
    <text>I think you should consider the Law of Unintended Consequences. Progressives (such as myself) are constantly pushing for changes that look very good on paper. But none of us knows for sure if those changes will actually play out the way we hope they will.

It may be fairly easy to point out places where our society can improve, but let's face it: in terms of human history, we already have pretty much the best society humanity has ever created. We have an awful lot to lose by experimenting or toying with things willy-nilly.

A functioning society needs a counter-balance to those who are willing to make a ton of major changes. Think of it not as narrow-mindedness, but as pragmatism. If you had a million dollars, would you gamble it all for another 500 grand? I'm not sure "narrow-mindedness" is a fair label to those who would say no to that question. Maybe "risk adverse"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28274926866.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say that this is why the wealthy tend to be conservative? Like for them, then sure the status quo might be great and worth protecting but does that not just show that they are narrow-minded (or perhaps just self-centred) as aren't considering anything outside their own lives?

Also, as a progressive, I would point to current examples (like Scandinavia) that's proved that a lot of changes progressives are rallying for haven't crumbled society.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28274979463.0" user="BrawndoTTM" delta="False">
    <text>Except Scandinavia is currently crumbling because of a really terrible idea progressives pushed for and conservatives warned against.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28274982174.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>which is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28274988856.0" user="BrawndoTTM" delta="False">
    <text>Flooding the country with refugees, which is both destroying the welfare system, and making a lot of places much more dangerous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275023703.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>Personally I think that's a problem that has no perfect solution (but tend to believe that that is the lesser of two evils when the alternative is the refugees stay in a war-torn country or are stateless) but that's not something I'm going to CMV on. 

Probably fair enough for people (conservatives) to be wary of the harms there. Better examples would be drug legalisation, same-sex marriage legalisation, banning guns, universal healthcare, education reform etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275585302.0" user="simsoy" delta="False">
    <text>Sources needed. People can say that, but if refugees are 1% and only 1% of crime then places haven't gotten more dangerous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275627714.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>According to this graph, 3/4 of the rapes in Sweden are commited by the 5% that is muslim https://themuslimissue.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/valdtakt_2011_stor_nyb.png?w=382&amp;amp;h=478

From wikipedia, muslims are 5.5x more likely to commit rape: 
https://www.bra.se/bra/publikationer/arkiv/publikationer/2005-12-14-brottslighet-bland-personer-fodda-i-sverige-och-i-utlandet.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275646176.0" user="simsoy" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I'm going to trust a clearly *unbiased* site like the muslim problem or Wikipedia. Those just aren't sources I think are trust worthy and pushing an agenda.

Edit: also, we're talking about welfare, not rape. It's clear you're pushing or parroting an agenda. A quick Google search revealed that Sweden has the highest rate of reported rapes in Europe, and rape is fairly under reported. For example, America and the U.K. Have far higher rates of rape than what Sweden reports since most aren't reported. Sweden it seems has the highest amount of rape cases going to court and putting people in prison, according to a BBC report. While Muslims might rape at a higher rate than the native population, the native population of Sweden reports rape at a higher rate than anywhere in the world. So while maybe only 1/3 rapes are reported in the USA, that number is far lower of Sweden.

A country like Japan reports around a 1/100,000 rape rate, but further studies shows women don't report it due to cultural reasons so really only about 1/50 rapes are reported if it is assumed they have similar rates to the USA which we can pretty much guarantee they do. Sweden appears to be on the other side of the coin being such a progressive nation where the police actually do more than in other countries. 

http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-19592372

http://www.japantimes.co.jp/community/2014/12/08/voices/foreign-students-account-treatment-rape-case-points-gaps-japans-safety-myth/

http://www.japantoday.com/category/lifestyle/view/victims-are-finally-learning-to-speak-out-against-japan’s-outdated-rape-laws

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275668726.0" user="Beelzebubs-Barrister" delta="False">
    <text>this is from the official study/report from the swedes themselves:
 (google translate, p35)
https://www.bra.se/download/18.cba82f7130f475a2f1800012697/1371914727881/2005_17_brottslighet_bland_personer_fodda_sverige_och_utlandet.pdf
The excess risk for those who themselves were born abroad have increased
slightly from 2.1 to 2.5.
Is the observed excess risk high?
How should we look at the different gruppern
as the risks to be registered
for crimes compared to those born in Sweden to two Swedish born
parents?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275699485.0" user="simsoy" delta="False">
    <text>Unfortunately I don't read Swedish. And going from 2.1 to 2.5 for what, crime, murder, money spent per person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275704014.0" user="simsoy" delta="False">
    <text>Also the rape numbers contradict each other. You said about 75% of rapes are committed by 5% of the population yet Muslims only rape at 5.5x the national average, statistically speaking then Muslims can only make up about 27% of all rapes which makes the entire validity of those statistics seems suspicious and possibly invalid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275766979.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sweden has the highest rate of reported rapes in Europe

This also has to do with the way Sweden's police report rape cases. In many countries, if a person is raped multiple times by the same person, it's counted as 1 case, whereas Sweden counts each individual act as a separate case. So the woman who's repeatedly raped by an abusive husband reports in the US as 1 case and in Sweden as 112. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275775022.0" user="simsoy" delta="False">
    <text>That too. I think a lot of conservatives in Europe are trying to pin crime on Muslims with the idea of, "us verse them" and trying to present a romanticized pure view of Europe not remembering that Europe is far from a perfect place with tons of crime and rape like the rest of the world. I'll hear some people saying "*they're* raping **our** women!" As if women are property and rape is bad because it's *them* damaging **our** property. And then when this is pointed out they say we're defending Islam and attacking white people when we're just calling them out on their agendas and bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28280917386.0" user="singlerider" delta="False">
    <text>That graph is an estimate, based on the rates of over representation found in the previous 1996 study, which used data from the 1985-1989 period.

That 1996 study looked at the number of people *registered* for crimes, based on nationality, as a proportion - ie as a per-thousand people rate.

It's important to note that the people registered for crimes were not those convicted, but those suspected - idiosyncracies within the Swedish legal system mean those suspected of crimes are recorded in more specific detail than those convicted (ie, one might be convicted of theft, but suspected of vehicular theft etc)

The headline rate from the study was that North Africans (Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco and Libya) were 23 times more likely to commit rape than indigenous Swedes. This was based on the rate of 4.6 per thousand people, compared to 0.2 per thousand people for Swedes born to Swedish parents.

However, this is partly due to the small sample size - that 4.6 per thousand figure was generated from 14 suspected rapists from a population of 3023 people. By contrast the indigenous Swedes were suspected of 584 rapes amongst a population of 2920700 people.

This means that although one interpretation is to say North Africans are 23 times more likely to commit rape (to be completely fair we should actually say "to be suspected of committing rape"), rape is 42 times more likely to be committed by an indigenous Swede.

In other words, the graph is at best a huge exaggeration and disingenuous extrapolation of the data being used to further a political agenda (which should be obvious - despite the well documented over-representation of certain ethnic groups, the belief that such a small minority could actually be responsible for the majority of such crimes suggests a lack of critical reasoning).

At worst you could describe the graph as outright lying.

The reports, though they do highlight the over-representation of certain groups, don't support the notion that immigrants, children of immigrants, or Muslims, are responsible for the majority of *any* crimes. It's not even certain (though it seems very probable) that these groups *are* over-represented, due to the Law of Large Numbers - small ethnic minority groups are always likely to have results that are somewhat anomalous, because there are so few of them. There were roughly 1000x more Swedes included in the study than North Africans, so each individual North African becomes 1000x more significant.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275007167.0" user="joncrtny" delta="False">
    <text>Source needed. That's a pretty huge claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275675710.0" user="Gabcab" delta="False">
    <text>I live right on the outskirts of Oslo, and I can tell you that this is greatly exaggerated</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275517928.0" user="MonkRome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Would you say that this is why the wealthy tend to be conservative?

It depends on where you draw the line of "wealthy".  If you're just taking any individual that makes above $100,000 a year then it is nearly evenly distributed.  But if your only taking the 10 richest people in the country then it is heavily republican.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
