<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28276046000.0" user="DisparateNoise" delta="False">
    <text>Emerson once described a person's politics as being one of four things: radical liberal conservative and reactionary. Sadly, most media labelled "conservative" now a days is reactionary, trying to restore some fictitious golden age where everything was perfect and nobody but evil liberals complained. This is partly the fault of Republican anti-obama rhetoric over the past eight years, but also the frustration of poor Republicans who've been fooled into thinking all their problems are because of outsiders instead of the shitty neo-liberal policies enacted by Republicans and "third way" Democrats. 
Most genuine conservatives are just as intelligent as liberals, if less responsive to change. Don't worry though, Emerson also said the Radicals and Liberals are always on the right side of history. #bernie2016
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
