<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248557201.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/43zfyp/cmvconservatism_is_just_narrowmindedness/">
    <title>CMV:conservatism is just narrow-mindedness</title>
    <original_poster>bridget-9</original_poster>
    <original_post>Conservatism in its most basic form is just wanting things to stay the way things are. This means that instead of thinking about and analysing a new idea or solution to a problem, conservatives prefer to stick with the current way of doing something. This to me seems like they are not very willing to even consider new ideas even if they may be better than the current system/ tradition which is essentially just narrow-mindedness. Traditions are held as sacred and are therefore not compared fairly and rationally to new alternatives. Conversely, I don't think it's true that progressives want change for change's sake, but at least embrace change when they see a problem with the current system.

Edit: Deltas awarded, thanks guys- this gave me plenty to think about and I'm more convinced than I thought I would be tbh (maybe I suffer from being a little narrow-minded too). 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28275067999.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>So you give the benefit of fhe doubt to progressives, but not to conservatives? There are plenty of conservatives who look at the issue and determine that the status quo is better than a change, or at least better than any change proposed. In fact, in my experience, it's more likely to see a progressive say "we've got to do something about x", without specifying we have to do something that is effective, our won't be worse in the long run. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275079284.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>A few people have said similar things, so I see where you're coming from, and I accept that I did kind of assert my reasons for claiming this. I just replied to Taldoable (above) as to why I maintain that progressiveness lends itself to open-mindedness in a more obvious way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28275087175.0" user="bridget-9" delta="False">
    <text>Progressives are also almost 'forced' to consider the SQ, because it's what's sparked the change, whereas conservatives aren't forced to think of new solutions to things. 
Obviously that doesn't mean progressives will necessarily compare the SQ fairly, but they've been aware of the SQ the whole time whereas conservatives are only aware of a new solution when it's been presented to them so aren't forced to be comparative in the same way. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
