<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248893922.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/446ns2/cmv_the_middle_east_will_be_consumed_by_chaos_for/">
    <title>CMV: The Middle East will be consumed by chaos for the rest of the 21st Century</title>
    <original_poster>AssFaceKillaaa</original_poster>
    <original_post>Change takes a long time. Things happen overnight, but we don't see true effects until removed by a generation or two. There have been myriad of conflicts in the middle east for the entirety of my life, as well as most of the last century. Over the course of the last Century, The Middle East was thrown into Chaos due to many factors: 

-The redrawing of borders which effectively isolated portions of ethnic or religious groups into minority/majority regions that would form the basis of targeted persecution for regimes at later times (disbanding the Ottoman Empire/reshaping political landscape of the region).

-The discovery of massive oil reserves across the region which would turn some states into the massive economic powers (Saudi Arabia/Iran/Qatar/UAE... and on and on) that would drastically effect their relation to the rest of the world.

 -The formation of the State of Israel, and subsequent dissimilation of Palestine (this one should be obvious..)

-The growth of what would become an endemic trend of militia groups backed by states foreign or otherwise for purposes of fighting Proxy-Wars or affecting regional influence. (i.e. Mujahideen turned into Taliban turned into Al-Qeadea turned into ISIS...)

Because of these and many other reasons, I believe that the region as a whole will continue to see failing Nation States, massive civilian casualties, continued violent confrontations between Nations, Rebel groups, and civilians, and systemic corruption for *at least* the next 85 years. **I don't believe through supporting Regime Change, or diplomatically informed policy decisions will affect meaningful change in the region in this century.**

 Or to put it another way: *The damage has been done.* 

PLEASE CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28277759573.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>A century is a very, very long time. A lot can change. 100 years ago, Europe was the most unstable part of the planet and in the throes of the deadliest war the world had seen to that point. Today, it's one of the most politically stable regions in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277837792.0" user="AssFaceKillaaa" delta="False">
    <text>I would agree that that is a great example of a counter-argument, but... 

Europe is very different culturally, politically, religiously. It's resources, history.. Europe was also at War with itself (and abroad) for the better part of the 400 years before the 20th century when it stabilized in the mid-century. 

So I would argue that perhaps we're seeing the *beginning* of that period of great conflict for the Middle East. I'm not saying it's a guarantee that they will be at war for the next 3 Centuries, but that because of compounding effects, there won't be stability for some time to come.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278156567.0" user="speedyjohn" delta="False">
    <text>There's as much of a history of conflict in the Middle East as there was in Europe. My point is that it's impossible to predict 100 years down the road. 

If you'd asked someone in 1916 (or heck, even in 1946) whether they though Europe would be the most politically stable region in the world in 100 years, most people would have said no. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278219565.0" user="AssFaceKillaaa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My point is that it's impossible to predict 100 years down the road. 

Yeah.. I get that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277867764.0" user="allkindsofjake" delta="False">
    <text>There are other places that have done this as well.  In the early days of the United States, the United States was a backwater with a struggling economy.  By the 1880's the country was a growing industrial power that spanned the continent. 

Also, the prosperous United States of 1965 is a very far cry from the 1865 us in the endgame of a ruinous civil war that devastated a third of the country.

IMO the Middle East is gonna be a clusterfuck for a few decades, but not a full century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278052690.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention that Europe has then instigated a SECOND, even larger war that have destabilized the entire world and plunged it into unrestrained bacchanal of violence an murder using commercial means to slaughter populations on industrial scale and total firebombing of entire cities.

And that was only 70 years ago.

What is happening in Middle East now is not even a pale shadow of the kind of instability that Europe unleashed, and have recovered from in less than 75 years.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
