<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248893922.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/446ns2/cmv_the_middle_east_will_be_consumed_by_chaos_for/">
    <title>CMV: The Middle East will be consumed by chaos for the rest of the 21st Century</title>
    <original_poster>AssFaceKillaaa</original_poster>
    <original_post>Change takes a long time. Things happen overnight, but we don't see true effects until removed by a generation or two. There have been myriad of conflicts in the middle east for the entirety of my life, as well as most of the last century. Over the course of the last Century, The Middle East was thrown into Chaos due to many factors: 

-The redrawing of borders which effectively isolated portions of ethnic or religious groups into minority/majority regions that would form the basis of targeted persecution for regimes at later times (disbanding the Ottoman Empire/reshaping political landscape of the region).

-The discovery of massive oil reserves across the region which would turn some states into the massive economic powers (Saudi Arabia/Iran/Qatar/UAE... and on and on) that would drastically effect their relation to the rest of the world.

 -The formation of the State of Israel, and subsequent dissimilation of Palestine (this one should be obvious..)

-The growth of what would become an endemic trend of militia groups backed by states foreign or otherwise for purposes of fighting Proxy-Wars or affecting regional influence. (i.e. Mujahideen turned into Taliban turned into Al-Qeadea turned into ISIS...)

Because of these and many other reasons, I believe that the region as a whole will continue to see failing Nation States, massive civilian casualties, continued violent confrontations between Nations, Rebel groups, and civilians, and systemic corruption for *at least* the next 85 years. **I don't believe through supporting Regime Change, or diplomatically informed policy decisions will affect meaningful change in the region in this century.**

 Or to put it another way: *The damage has been done.* 

PLEASE CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28277860258.0" user="SiliconDiver" delta="False">
    <text>Ironically, You say the middle east will be consumed in chaos for what upwards of 85+ years,

But all your cited "reasons" didn't even exist 100 years ago.  100 Years is a long long time.

That's a long long time...

&amp;gt;-The redrawing of borders which effectively isolated portions of ethnic or religious groups into minority/majority regions that would form the basis of targeted persecution

The ottoman empire fell in 1922 &amp;lt; 100 years ago.  

Borders such as Iran/Iraq have been changed as recent as the 40's, and weren't accepted until the 90's.  Syria was part of the UAR until the 60's

Israel's current borders have only existed since the '79

These borders are hardly going to remain "static" for the next 100 years in such a way that will cause turmoil

&amp;gt;The discovery of massive oil reserves across the region which would turn some states into the massive economic powers

Oil wasn't even discovered until '36 and it wasn't until the '50's that it became such a large part of their economy.  

&amp;gt;The formation of the State of Israel, and subsequent dissimilation of Palestine (this one should be obvious..)

Israel didn't exist until '49, And its borders have been in a constant state of flux.  

&amp;gt;The growth of what would become an endemic trend of militia groups backed by states foreign or otherwise for purposes of fighting 

Can't really put a date on this one.   But isn't this true of pretty much any war at any geographical location throughout time.  

Who is to say some more unforeseen events will occur in the next 85, that will shake up the middle east?  Someone in 1850 wouldn't have predicted the nation of Israel existing

**TLDR** Claiming that a situation will stay the same for 85 years, when the circumstances causing it aren't even 85 years old is just pure over-extrapolation.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277941115.0" user="AssFaceKillaaa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But all your cited "reasons" didn't even exist 100 years ago.

Yeah, but the argument is that those factors will continue to have an effect of instability for the *next* 85 years. 

Borders being in flux is something that causes instability. See Israel/Palestine. The effect of changing borders causes territorial disputes and a change in the demographics of ethno-religious groups in turn inciting conflict or persecution of said groups.  

&amp;gt; Oil wasn't even discovered until '36 and it wasn't until the '50's that it became such a large part of their economy. 

That's exactly it though. Look at the role Oil plays in all of these economies. They will need drastic diversification to avoid economic calamity if/when Oil prices (which we've seen a few times including now) and global dependence on consumption drops off - Especially in the Gulf States, which is arguably the most stable region of the ME. 

&amp;gt; But isn't this true of pretty much any war at any geographical location throughout time. 

I would say no - It's definitely a more recent phenomenon, and though we've seen it in South/Central America, Africa, parts of East Asia, that doesn't take away from the fact that there have been a slew of Failed Nation States in this region, and that when that happens there are power vacuums that are filled with Rebel Groups or Dictators and the process starts all over again.  

&amp;gt; Who is to say some more unforeseen events will occur in the next 85, that will shake up the middle east?

Certainly not me. But I'm going off of the current state of affairs and how historically the policies of Regime Change, redrawing of Borders, arming or otherwise backing rebel groups, has had an adverse effect to stabilization. 

&amp;gt; Claiming that a situation will stay the same for 85 years, when the circumstances causing it aren't even 85 years old is just pure over-extrapolation.

again... not saying they will "stay the same," but rather that there will be a continued state of instability in the region for the foreseeable future. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
