<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43101594883.0" user="wasd12la" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  

So they give you a chance to remember why you did it and match it to the paperwork? If you really don't care enough to remember why you abandoned an animal, maybe you shouldn't have another one. That is probably the worst moment of that animals life and the person forgot. 
.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101677087.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. They will ask you what the reason was even if it was like 20 years ago. And of course, I agree the normal response is to be fully aware of what lead to that surrender, but I don't feel having a surrender on record in general, should be a disqualifier for a new adoption. If the people seeking shelter pets are told, "no you're not worthy" they'll just go to a backyard breeder or buy a stupid goldendoodle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101726964.0" user="wasd12la" delta="False">
    <text>But that same logic can be used with guns too. Why bother with background checks if criminals will just go buy black market guns if denied a legal one? Just sell guns to everyone. 

Just because people can and will bypass it, it doesn't mean we should give them a living creature if they have proven to be potentially irresponsible with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101835675.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Just because people can and will bypass it, it doesn't mean we should give them a living creature if they have proven to be potentially irresponsible with them.

I mean it's a bit of a catch-22 because the *really* irresponsible thing to do is to just abandon the animal without filling out the paperwork, and *this is what the shelter incentivizes*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102073863.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>And dumps/public landfills incentivizes illegal dumping. You can argue it’s dumb, but that’s the way our legal system works as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104590186.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>No, public landfills do the opposite: they provide a place where you can do your dumping legally, rather than risk leaving it on the side of the road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104854599.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>They cost money mate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105060271.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, they do. But they are cheap enough that the incentive is to pay the fee and dump there, rather than risk getting a huge fine for illegal dumping.

If public landfills cost *way more* money then they would incentivize illegal dumping. Fortunately, they don't!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102696873.0" user="Neshgaddal" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't all animals from shelters mircochipped? Shouldn't it be trivial to find out who the previous owner is and put people who abandon their animal like that on a super-shit list?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103316261.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>If you got it from a rescue, then, yes, most microchip. But only if they got the dog from a rescue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103922497.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>This. Microchips are administered by for-profit companies who have their own incentives and levels of competency. Even if I know my animal was previously chipped, I may not want to give that company a bunch of cash to make sure I’m never dragged through the mud with their previous owner. And people do not have direct access to the data enough to check the data were properly changed unless they have a chip reader of their own. People make mistakes, and there are systemic failures. I’ve tried to update my cat’s information *twice* and it still hasn’t taken properly.

Or, in the other role, I might be giving a pet to someone in an entirely ethical way, and they might never update it or face any of the above. 

Be very, very careful what data you use to make decisions that can be life-altering for others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103994040.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>You dont have to pay to update microchip information. The microchip will always work, if it doesnt move in the body where the person scanning cant find it. The money the companies ask you for is or other things they offer.

I volunteer at a rescue and we have gotten dogs that had microchips but couldnt find the owner because they never updated the chip. One dog made it across the country to our rescue before the owner was finally found and the dog was able to get sent back. It was at the shelter waiting for a while for some to claim it before it came to us.

Our microchips get updated automatically by the system once an adoption goes thru, but that was a recent change.

Always update your animals microships. It does not cost money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104130444.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe it depends on the company? There are definitely ones with transfer fees. And those that are free conflate registration with a sign up process for subscription services, which at the very least might confuse and dissuade people from doing it.

https://medium.com/@annhud/do-i-have-to-pay-for-this-getting-out-of-pet-microchip-hell-2ba61598d95a

I’m coming at this as a pet owner rather than, so I may have an incomplete picture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106749293.0" user="Charlea1776" delta="False">
    <text>I just looked at our adoption paperwork from 8 years ago because of your comment and am going to add our info today....luckily our number hasn't changed so it might have been OK. It was such an ordeal to drive to get this puppy because they were to be euthanized, I think I just didn't catch that in the rush!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106759472.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>So glad this comment helped remind you! You're not the only one to forget.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103726001.0" user="MissTortoise" delta="False">
    <text>What if those owners passed on the animal (responsibly) to someone else?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104595819.0" user="WovenDoge" delta="False">
    <text>Without actually seeing who left the animal there's really no way to be sure that they actually were the previous owner, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101887756.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>It's definitely not black and white. My husband feels that the *reason* for the surrender is very important; thus good record-keeping being vital. While I believe that there should be no requirement to surrender and no paperwork because it incentivizes dumping.   
People are sadly only as honest as their options. When given the option of being held accountable in some way for something that was essentially out of their control- or just passing the buck on down the line (aka dumping without recourse) most people will take the dumping w/o recourse over being held accountable for actually *doing the right thing*. Because people suck. But also because the world doesn't typically reward the *good*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103943712.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>I’d argue this is not because people suck, but because people have a reasonable interest in preserving themselves, their reputations, and their future options when the record-keeping mechanism is insufficient and the judgment that it enables is unpredictable or unjust. It’s not sucking for not wanting to step in shit unnecessarily. This is why we have Good Samaritan laws, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111266318.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that both- some people suck, *and* it's reasonable at the same time to have a sense of self-preservation and to not want to be lumped in with those that do unjustly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103880911.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not the analog though, really. The analog would be responsibly surrendering a gun you don’t want rather than disposing of it by other means. Or being added to a list because you responsibly surrendered an illegal unregistered gun, whether or not it even belonged to you, to avoid it circulating on the black market. The more important issue is that someone is dissuaded from good surrendering practices in the first place, not (just) that they can go get a pet elsewhere if denied the second time. 

Giving up an animal for adoption is also not the same as committing a gun crime (unless you decide to be an edgelord and equate surrendering an animal to a shelter as killing it, ignoring that they have no control over other people’s future decisions). Those are different levels of “irresponsibility.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102969801.0" user="DarkSoulCarlos" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you consider goldendoodle's to be stupid? Are they really less intelligent than other breeds? If that is the case, don't they still deserve a good loving home?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103748907.0" user="MissTortoise" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a breed, it's a mutt. "Goldendoodle" is just putting on airs. The concept of "designer breeds" is stupid, not the animals. 

There's absolutely nothing wrong with mutts, all my animals have been of no particular breeding, they're much sturdier and less prone to stupid medical issues caused by inbreeding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104980162.0" user="DarkSoulCarlos" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your point about designer breeds. I have always viewed the idea of it as petty and dumb.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104272380.0" user="diablette" delta="False">
    <text>They’re a fad/status symbol. They cost big $ and people like to show off how much disposable income they have. This encourages home breeders to pump out more of them and they are everywhere. It’s not the animals’ fault nor any reflection on the breed’s characteristics. The concept of encouraging home breeding is stupid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104961453.0" user="DarkSoulCarlos" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that. You make great points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104624295.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>But if they ask about it, then there is a chance to show that you've grown as a potential pet-owner.

If they're asking about it, it's not necessarily an instant-disqualification. It sounds like perhaps a bad answer to this question was given? Is that possible?

This is reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111414785.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I also don't feel like punishing someone for life

&gt; They will ask you what the reason

But if they're asking about it, then there is a chance to show that you've grown as a potential pet-owner.

If it were "instantly-disqualifying," there would be no need to ask anything about it; it would just be a 'no.'

This situation shows that surrendering a pet is *not* necessarily instantly disqualifying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103817997.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>You may not wish or think to share the entire details of your past, like a time you lost your job or went through some other hardship, with some new shelter who has access to this information, and who you may not even know has access.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106602408.0" user="ailish" delta="False">
    <text>I once had a roommate leave his cat behind, and I was moving into an apartment that didn't allow animals. It wasn't my cat, but I had to take him to a shelter. Should that prevent me from getting an animal from a shelter now, almost 20 years later?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107379913.0" user="wasd12la" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not. The micro chip on that cat is not registered to you, they can tell it clearly isn't your cat and you have no responsibility to take care of it. So this story is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107443541.0" user="ailish" delta="False">
    <text>This was 25 years ago and microchips weren't really a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107599185.0" user="wasd12la" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to go reread my first comment. They match your excuse with the one on file. If it lines up and they have common sense, you're fine. You clearly remember why it happened and it was a good excuse. I don't see how you would apply here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107604527.0" user="ailish" delta="False">
    <text>Well you're just one person so, yeah.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43144782870.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me like you’re putting a lot of confidence in “common sense” to sort through structural errors and bridge gaps that don’t need to be there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107994306.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43144773330.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>It’s absolutely not irrelevant. You’re the person who surrendered the animal, regardless of who is registered on the chip.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43119435597.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>...it wouldnt, just tell the truth that the cat was abandoned by its owner, which wasnt you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43119619782.0" user="ailish" delta="False">
    <text>They didn't believe me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43119637647.0" user="AveryFay" delta="False">
    <text>People find strays and drop them at shelters all the time, that is all you need to say. Just leave the cat and go if they absolutely want to make up something different...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43119640775.0" user="ailish" delta="False">
    <text>This was years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43144823249.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>This is the subject of the comment thread you are posting on: that they *do* make assumptions, in a process designed to address one problem, that have harmful impacts and cause others.

Have you ever tried to say the kind of thing you’re suggesting to someone and gotten an answer back like, “sorry, there’s nothing we can do” or “that’s what it says in the system?” For a range of reasons, whether because they don’t have the discretionary power to go against a policy, they are lazy, or have a hard on for the rules, individuals very often offload accountability onto whatever their computer screen says in front of them when in these positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107190476.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Its also a macro-problem not a micro-problem. People just letting animals loose is extremely common here as well as turning them back into overcrowded shelters where they basically just put them down. I guess form the perspective of the person who puts them down things are different. But I find it hard to believe they arent struggling with the morality of what they do on at least some subconscious level. 

Ultimately though if shelters want to survive in most of the US they need to keep these lists and make sure they aren't overcrowded. They do have to function and keeping those "shit lists" objectively maintains a higher rate of people adopting animals to homes for life vs adopting a kitten as a Christmas present and returning it when it hits adulthood. 

You belong on a shitlist for that and the other side of it is no one in their right mind would admit to doing that, yet we all know its incredibly common. Repeat offenders should be barred all together.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
