<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43102930633.0" user="UnderABig_W" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is very much dependent on your location and individual shelter rather than a universal thing.  Our experience dealing with our local shelter was different.

Our family found a kitten huddled next to the engine in our truck on a cold day.  We felt so horribly for the poor thing, but there was no way we could keep her because my daughter is severely allergic to cats.

We took her to the local shelter, and explained the situation.  They took her without a problem.  I didn’t even have to leave my address.  I asked them to at least take my phone number in case for whatever reason she wasn’t adoptable, so I could try to find a forever home for her myself.  They told me that wasn’t necessary because they’d have 0 problems adopting her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111118496.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>That's he way it should be done. But people in certain counties figure it out pretty quick when they go to their one shelter within 50-100 miles and find out their entire family is ineligible because maybe dad surrendered an animal years ago or something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111902508.0" user="UnderABig_W" delta="False">
    <text>That is crazy, especially if (like in my scenario) you do not even own the animal you are surrendering, just trying to help out a homeless, at-risk one!

I dunno, maybe it would have been different if we were bringing in an older animal that would be harder to adopt?  But this kitten was the cutest little thing—my spouse and I don’t even like cats, but we probably would have kept her if our daughter wasn’t allergic!

So maybe they thought our story was true, and that’s why they acted the way they did?  Whereas if we’d come in with an older animal, they would’ve thought we were lying and acted differently?

I really don’t know.  But I do think most of the employees at places like these honestly want to help the animals.  Do their policies always achieve that?   No, but I do think they’re trying the best they can.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
