<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43103913512.0" user="le_fez" delta="False">
    <text>I have volunteered at shelters for almost 20 years. None of them keep "shitlists" of people who surrendered animals unless the animal was obviously mistreated or the reason was "we got a kitten so we don't want this 10 year old cat anymore" because that is a huge red flag. We understand that sometimes life happens and you are doing the best thing for the animal by surrendering it to a reputable shelter.

I remember a man six or seven years ago whose wife died after a prolonged illness that chewed through their savings then had lost his job and couldn't find one that allowed him to keep his home. He had taken to living in his pick up and knew that was no life for his cat. This 50 plus year old sat on the floor sobbing like a baby and apologizing to the cat. He would check in on the cat often and, even though his hope was his life would even out and stabilize, was elated when the cat was rehomed. No shelter would punish this man for doing the right thing nor would it do so to other pet owners in less dire but understandable circumstances</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107964416.0" user="_-Logic-" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;He had taken to living in his pick up and knew that was no life for his cat. This 50 plus year old sat on the floor sobbing like a baby and apologizing to the cat. He would check in on the cat often and, even though his hope was his life would even out and stabilize, was elated when the cat was rehomed

Damn thats sad, atleast it had a happy ending.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43110655951.0" user="spezcanNshouldchoke" delta="False">
    <text>Widower rehomes beloved pet because their late spouses medical debt forced them into poverty is a happy ending? 

Another win for the orphan crushing machine I suppose...

I know you mean for the cat but even then. Cat looses one of their people and is left by the other in an unfamiliar setting where it lives nervously until adoption. I'm sure the cat lives carefree and has no residual issues from its life being completely upended for reasons it can never understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43112229622.0" user="_-Logic-" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I was hoping that the op would tell me more about the widower, I was really hoping he would make it out of poverty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43109793785.0" user="Mother_Attempt3001" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I was on my local humane societys shit list because when I moved here my car got put in the move and obviously didn't know the area. I put up signs but didn't even realize there was a local humane society that people being found animals to. When I did figure it out 5 days later, and went there, my cat was there, covered in fleas, and cost me 150x5 to get her out. It was awful and I was crying. Turns out they put me on their shit list and I only could adopt there ,(and I actually volunteered for 3 years) bc I changed my name after getting divorced 4 years ago and they didn't have my new name in the system. I am the most rescue loving person around but they did not give two shits because it took me 5 days to realize that she was at the shelter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111257843.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>This happens all the time. The shelter workers do judge you, and Haaaaarrrrrd.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
