<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="248893922.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/446ns2/cmv_the_middle_east_will_be_consumed_by_chaos_for/">
    <title>CMV: The Middle East will be consumed by chaos for the rest of the 21st Century</title>
    <original_poster>AssFaceKillaaa</original_poster>
    <original_post>Change takes a long time. Things happen overnight, but we don't see true effects until removed by a generation or two. There have been myriad of conflicts in the middle east for the entirety of my life, as well as most of the last century. Over the course of the last Century, The Middle East was thrown into Chaos due to many factors: 

-The redrawing of borders which effectively isolated portions of ethnic or religious groups into minority/majority regions that would form the basis of targeted persecution for regimes at later times (disbanding the Ottoman Empire/reshaping political landscape of the region).

-The discovery of massive oil reserves across the region which would turn some states into the massive economic powers (Saudi Arabia/Iran/Qatar/UAE... and on and on) that would drastically effect their relation to the rest of the world.

 -The formation of the State of Israel, and subsequent dissimilation of Palestine (this one should be obvious..)

-The growth of what would become an endemic trend of militia groups backed by states foreign or otherwise for purposes of fighting Proxy-Wars or affecting regional influence. (i.e. Mujahideen turned into Taliban turned into Al-Qeadea turned into ISIS...)

Because of these and many other reasons, I believe that the region as a whole will continue to see failing Nation States, massive civilian casualties, continued violent confrontations between Nations, Rebel groups, and civilians, and systemic corruption for *at least* the next 85 years. **I don't believe through supporting Regime Change, or diplomatically informed policy decisions will affect meaningful change in the region in this century.**

 Or to put it another way: *The damage has been done.* 

PLEASE CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28277825577.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No.  By 2050, oil will be dead.  Once the middle east has nothing to offer, people will stop caring about the middle east.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277850633.0" user="AssFaceKillaaa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; By 2050, oil will be dead.

I agree with you here. 

&amp;gt; Once the middle east has nothing to offer, people will stop caring about the middle east.

Couldn't agree less. It will have the complete opposite effect: The fact that almost every major economy in the region relies almost ENTIRELY on oil is exactly what will destabilize the region even more when global oil dependence drops mid-century as you predict. Imagine Saudi Arabia's and UAE's and Kuwait's, (all US allies) economies collapsing. Not to mention Iran. This is what's in store for the region. 

While I couldn't agree more with the first statement, the second part of your argument is a gross simplification. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277856996.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But then they'll just be like [insertcountryhere] in Africa.  We'll feel bad for them but they won't be politically important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28277961007.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>In fairness u/royalmayfair4 said "caring" not "stable".  I think the point is that once we don't need them for oil they can behave like death squads in Africa have been, and will get as much media attention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278018254.0" user="AssFaceKillaaa" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that totally makes sense. I could agree with that. But that doesn't remove the instability. Which is the whole argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278061995.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>Well yes.  But it is an interesting argument to say "while that is true, you won't care when it happens."  It is a bit like responding to someone who says we will eventually run out of oil with "yeah but by that time alternative energies will have totally replaced it, and it will be a smooth transition."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28279220988.0" user="Fimbulwolf" delta="False">
    <text>Out of all the states you just named, Iran will arguably be hurt the least by the vanishing of oil as a relvant resource. That country, in major difference to other gulf countries, has a big industrial tradition and a highly educated population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28278632530.0" user="uniptf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Once the middle east has nothing to offer

That won't happen until people wise up enough to ditch religion all together.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
