<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43101710420.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that more are dumped than people following protocol by going in and physically filling out the paperwork.

This is sound

&gt;I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time.

This isn't. If 56% of dogs and 71% of cats in shelters end up being euthanized, people are on lists for essentially killing their pets. We don't bring them up on criminal charges but saying hey, you probably got your last pet killed so we won't give you another is reasonable. No matter how people leave pets at shelters, most of them probably don't understand the consequences for the animals.

I think instead of making people fill out paperwork, they should just make copies of IDs and have the employees do the paperwork after they leave with reason and whatever else based on the conversation. It's so much easier to hide that the real reason for that is tracking. You need contact information if you have a question etc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101845095.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This isn't. If 56% of dogs and 71% of cats in shelters end up being euthanized, people are on lists for essentially killing their pets.

But what about the percentage of pets that would die regardless? As many are returned because of an unforeseeable accident or illness that owners end up not being able to foot?   
The biggest cost associated with owning a pet is emergency medical procedures, which often pop up with no advance warning giving people no time to save up. These are often the type of situations where owners panic and opt to surrender their pet rather than taking on the big medical expenses.  


Here's some statistics for people interested:  
[https://www.thezebra.com/resources/research/pet-adoption-statistics/](https://www.thezebra.com/resources/research/pet-adoption-statistics/)   


I mean, we don't even have universal healthcare for our *people*. A huge ass reason people have to get rid of their pets is the astronomical medical costs associated with injury or illness. (Sometimes, we charge 20x or more what something costs us at the clinic. We can get bags of lactated ringers for a dollar but charge people $50 for one bag to take home if they want to do their sub Q fluids at home for their pet.)   
One way or another, we get our money from you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101942646.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But what about the percentage of pets that would die regardless?

This is an argument that it doesn't matter what people do to pets because they'll just die anyway. In that case we might as well just leave them all outside to starve. If we're going to try to save them, that has to be done in some kind of ordered way.

&gt;As many are returned because of an unforeseeable accident or illness that owners end up not being able to foot?

People tend to stay in the same kind of financial situation unless you're talking about quite young people surrendering pets. Inflation is wild. Minimum wage is laughable. The average American can't scrape together a couple thousand in an emergency.

&gt;I mean, we don't even have universal healthcare for our people.

We also don't kill people just because there are 'too many'. Pets are really truly just an expense people get emotionally attached to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102000531.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We also don't kill people just because there are 'too many'.

My friend, this is true nowadays in most places.. scarily, in the past not so much. But aside from the fact that most people have no business having a child we seem to be more worried about *who has a pet*. It seems bassackwards and ridiculous. People that a shelter wouldn't trust with a mixed breed dog have 3 underfed kids. Two wrongs definitely don't make a right, but what does that say about our standards in society in general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102049022.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;aside from the fact that most people have no business having a child we seem to be more worried about who has a pet.

I truly don't think the average person cares. Pets are the topic so that's what I'm discussing. There's been no reason for me to randomly go off on a tangent about who should or shouldn't have kids.

&gt;People that a shelter wouldn't trust with a mixed breed dog have 3 underfed kids. Two wrongs definitely don't make a right, but what does that say about our standards in society in general?

That's not two wrongs. Someone with 3 underfed kids *shouldn't* have a dog. All it says is that the shelters have a decent screening system. People are arguably pressured to have kids with things like abortion bans/unreasonable restrictions, systemic issues with access to reliable birth control and a society that pretends like women's main job is still supposed to be child rearing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102078569.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That's not two wrongs. Someone with 3 underfed kids   
&gt;  
&gt;shouldn't have a dog.                                                 


We agree on this. But neither do I think that someone who fucked up in the past should be relegated to backyard breeders, or being denied the right to have kids, either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102261061.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Pets and children are not entitlements. It's really problematic to see another living thing as something a person deserves to raise or own. People regularly do way too much damage to both of these categories for us to just be like 'oh, well, they're remorseful so let's just give them another shot'. Pets not being taken seriously is why we have an overpopulation problem and so many die every year. Kids not being taken seriously is why child abuse is so common.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103557741.0" user="JUiCyMfer69" delta="False">
    <text>You realise this is a pro genocide position right? How would you enforce the policy so that people that “shouldn’t” have kids can’t, other than forced sterilisation and child removal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103597219.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Words have meanings.

&gt;gen·o·cide

&gt;/ˈjenəˌsīd/

&gt;ngen·o·cide

&gt;noun

&gt;the deliberate killing of a large number of people from a particular nation or ethnic group with the aim of destroying that nation or group.

If you hear genocide when someone says not everyone should have kids because some people are more prone to abuse them, that just means you have horrific morals and priorities. More than half of pregnancies are unintended. There are *so many* steps that can and should be taken before forced sterilization and child removal are even thought up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103635024.0" user="JUiCyMfer69" delta="False">
    <text>The definition you shared is unnecessarily limited and plain wrong. Forced deportations, sterilisations and child abductions are also means of conducting genocide. 

The targeted groups needn’t be solely national or ethnic, they can be sexuality based or political too.

The only part I might be wrong on is “intent”, but I’ll ask you, what does intent matter if the outcomes are the same. Especially if perpetrated by a large organisation such as a government instead of an individual.

If there are so many steps, why not list just one to start of with instead of gesturing vaguely?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103699635.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The targeted groups needn’t be solely national or ethnic, they can be sexuality based or political too.

Absolutely not. The whole reason genocide is so bad is because you're wiping out an entire nation or ethnic group. You literally can't wipe out a sexuality because that's how people are born. Political affiliation is just an ideology. It's impossible to wipe out an ideology in the age of the internet.

&gt;If there are so many steps, why not list just one to start of with instead of gesturing vaguely?

Because this is a horribly bad faith argument where you've made up a dramatic strawman that has absolutely nothing to do with what was being talked about. I'm not going to debate how something that is clearly, obviously and inarguably not genocide isn't genocide. You're just wasting time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103717678.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>Genocide is an incorrect term. Your position is eugenicist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107582367.0" user="raggedyassadhd" delta="False">
    <text>People are deemed unfit parents and have their kids taken away from them. Sometimes just because the other parent wants revenge and cares more about getting their revenge than the well being of their own kids. Some people definitely shouldn’t be allowed to care for children. For example, pedophiles. People who abuse kids. People who go out to the bar all night leaving a baby at home alone or in their car all night. None of this is related to genocide though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103376350.0" user="anewleaf1234" delta="False">
    <text>A pet is a responsibility. 

Not everyone can get a pet. 

Those who control animal shelters get to pick and chose those who are responsible and those who aren't. 

Pets aren't for everyone. If you aren't responsible enough to properly take care of a pet you shouldn't have one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43797172609.0" user="khhab3000" delta="False">
    <text>oh, yeah, they would better euthanize them than give them a chance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102079358.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>That children are property? And you can’t really means test sex rofl</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103354494.0" user="grandoz039" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; This is an argument that it doesn't matter what people do to pets because they'll just die anyway. In that case we might as well just leave them all outside to starve. If we're going to try to save them, that has to be done in some kind of ordered way.

If you adopt a dog and week later surrender the dog to the same shelter because of unforseen circumstances, in no way did you essentially kill the dog. I mean, the "problem" with returning the dog is not that you were supposed to keep it, but that you weren't supposed to adopt it in the first place. And in that case, the situation stays the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103511791.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;56% of dogs and 71% of cats in shelters end up being euthanized

Shelters are places where animals quite literally go to die. Leaving an animal at one means there's an incredibly high chance of it dying. Bringing a dog back to the same place in a week might make an irresponsible person feels better but it's not a harmleas action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103573960.0" user="grandoz039" delta="False">
    <text>If the alternative is not taking dog from the shelter in the first place, then the dog's fucked up either way. At worst, some other dog got adopted in the week he was away, instead of this one, but that's net 0 loss of life. Unless someone ends up not adopting at all, because this specific dog wasn't there, which is very unlikely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103628557.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Shelters...are...places...where...animals...go...to...die. If you leave an animal there, you're leaving it to die. 

You did not put the drowning person into the water to drown, they did that completely on their own. Unlike animals that can do literally nothing without a human to take care of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104045191.0" user="opeidoscopic" delta="False">
    <text>The statistic you cited for the percentage of dogs and cats in shelters which get euthanized seems kind of high. The source you cited was The Zebra, which is just an insurance website. It seems like they got the statistic from American Humane:

https://www.americanhumane.org/fact-sheet/animal-shelter-euthanasia/

However, they don't provide the actual study and instead link to petpopulation.org, which redirects to The Association for Animal Welfare Advancement. Both of these are nonprofit groups with an interest in portraying the plight of shelter animals in the worst possible light to maximize funding. I'm not suggesting they're nefarious by any means, since that's how all nonprofits work, but that's why it's important to consider all statistics in context.

Here are some sources I found which indicate vastly lower euthanasia statistics:

https://www.aspca.org/helping-people-pets/shelter-intake-and-surrender/pet-statistics

https://spots.com/animal-euthanasia-statistics/

These sources seem to put the number between 15-25%. Still too high, obviously, but it's also important to keep in mind that typical animals being euthanized at a shelter are feral, neonates, sick/injured, or behaviorally unfit to be pets. My whole point being that if you were to surrender the average healthy, friendly family pet then there's a good chance for it to be adopted. This is especially true in areas like the northeast United States where there's such a shortage of adoptable animals that they need to be imported from the south. At the very least, it's not a death sentence like you claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104047197.0" user="BlazingFiery" delta="False">
    <text>See, it's like this: the pet has to go, whatever the method, the pet has to leave the house. Would you want it to go to a shelter, or to be left on the street? 

Since, according to you, the pet is anyway going to die at the shelter, I'd leave it in the middle of nowhere so it can have a minor chance of living. How's that? Sounds shit, doesn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104156394.0" user="GoodellsMandMs" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Shelters...are...places...where...animals...go...to...die. If you leave an animal there, you're leaving it to die.

and if you bring one back youre doing the same thing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104745742.0" user="noodlesfordaddy" delta="False">
    <text>it's not that hard to understand the point he is making. stop being obtuse</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104488596.0" user="Angdrambor" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you're saying that trying to save a dog and failing is worse than not making the attempt in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43180405489.0" user="StormlitRadiance" delta="False">
    <text>Are you just blocking everyone who questions your viewpoint? roflmao, mad respect. Top tier redditing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43181971294.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>This post is 9 days old. So for cases like this where there's clearly something weird af going on? Yup.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104498440.0" user="fdar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The biggest cost associated with owning a pet is emergency medical procedures, which often pop up with no advance warning giving people no time to save up. These are often the type of situations where owners panic and opt to surrender their pet rather than taking on the big medical expenses

Not sure why do you think this is an acceptable excuse. Emergency medical procedures might pop-up without advance notice but the fact that pets will at some point need medical care shouldn't be an unexpected surprise. If you're unable to plan to provide that care when needed then you shouldn't have a pet. And I understand that it can often be a big financial burden, but yeah, pets are a big financial burden. If you can't afford it you shouldn't have one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105024665.0" user="CincyAnarchy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you're unable to plan to provide that care when needed then you shouldn't have a pet. And I understand that it can often be a big financial burden, but yeah, pets are a big financial burden. If you can't afford it you shouldn't have one.

Well then the statistic cited of 56% of dogs and 71% of cats dying in shelters would increase.  Is that a good outcome?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105072980.0" user="fdar" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe short term, but where do you think those animals are coming from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105176605.0" user="CincyAnarchy" delta="False">
    <text>In my experience at a shelter?

Backyard breeders; strays people find; and lastly people who's living circumstances (costs, prison, or otherwise) changed and they cannot keep their pet.

But I don't see the relevance.  Surely a lot of current adopted pets are adopted by people who cannot afford major medical expenses for those pets if they come up.  Is there a viable alternative to these adoptions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111283762.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Emergency medical procedures might pop-up without advance notice but the fact that pets will at some point need medical care shouldn't be an unexpected surprise. If you're unable to plan to provide that care when needed then you shouldn't have a ~~pet~~ kid.   


Curious as to how changing that one word at the end makes you feel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111351151.0" user="fdar" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people who are unable to provide medical care to a child should be able to adopt one either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43135000473.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>But what good does that do when they can just get irresponsibly knocked up for free?   
Same with backyard breeders which are the pet alternative for those 'not worthy' of adopting a dog. Irresponsible people will get what they want one way or another, often resorting to even worse tactics to get what they want. I.E. creating a whole ass new life to suffer in late stage capitalism collapse through generational poverty. (Which is objectively worse than providing a home for one that's already here that needs one.) Idk, people just suck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43135624717.0" user="fdar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; But what good does that do when they can just get irresponsibly knocked up for free?

They can do that anyway. When a child is in your care you have a responsibility for the well being of that specific child, you shouldn't put them in a bad situation to save another hypothetical child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104698685.0" user="disisathrowaway" delta="False">
    <text>Part of owning a pet is assuming costs for care. If you cannot afford to provide medicine for your pet then you can't afford a pet. It's a pretty simple concept.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105272513.0" user="lkattan3" delta="False">
    <text>This is classist. It’s a way to hand wave away the complex socioeconomic challenges pet owners face. You can go from being able to afford a pet, to not being able to afford a pet overnight. You can become disabled, have a death in the family, be evicted, all of which will impact your financial standing. Not to mention that 73% of the American population is currently living paycheck to paycheck. That’s a result of stagnant wages for four decades, inflation, the rising cost of housing and the cost of veterinary services rising 50% in the last two decades, outpacing inflation. Veterinary practices have been gobbled up by corporations and private equity, leading to an increase in cost passed onto the unwitting consumer, leaving the veterinary community to act as a third-party administrator between clients struggling to pay for their pets’ veterinary care
and the interests of the already wealthy. Rescues and shelters serve as cleanup crews for the pet’s who have “responsible” pet owners that rehome/relinquish because they can no longer afford them. The truth is the best policy is always strong pet retention policies. Pets’ best chance is if they can stay where they are wanted. It’s supporting struggling pet owners to help them meet their pets needs instead of deeming them unfit because they’re suffering under the same conditions so many are these days. These programs exist, they just aren’t often implemented/well-funded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106519413.0" user="disisathrowaway" delta="False">
    <text>I'm lower class.
But please, preach to me about my plight in the modern world and the evils that capitalism has inflicted on me and my community.

I love hearing this sort of thing from strangers on the internet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107007944.0" user="Criminal_of_Thought" delta="False">
    <text>By saying that the mindset is classist, are you saying it's bad that people have this mindset in the face of how the pet industry is right now, or just that classism is an unfortunate byproduct of how the pet industry is structured?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111303927.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>I responded and changed all the instances in his response with the word 'pet' to 'kid' and asked if that alters his point at all or if he feels we should have higher standards for owning a pet than having children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111297429.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Part of ~~owning~~ having a ~~pet~~ kid is assuming costs for care. If you cannot afford to provide medicine for your ~~pet~~ kid then you can't afford a ~~pet~~ kid. It's a pretty simple concept.

Do you hold to your position with these nouns changed in your sentence?   
If not, why do you have higher standards for the care of animals than children?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103405811.0" user="AndreasVesalius" delta="False">
    <text>“You brought a pet back and we killed it. You we’ll just keep this one and skip straight to the killing”

Maybe if you’re on the shitlist, you should just have to pick a pet from the bargain bin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103527524.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>You know who would love to pick animals from a "bargain bin"? Animal torturers. All deaths aren't equal. Euthanizing is more humane than torture or starvation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103559634.0" user="AndreasVesalius" delta="False">
    <text>But those animal torturers could just take from the normal stock. They wouldn’t be on the shitlist since they never bring the animals back. 

Besides, the people who previously voluntarily surrendered their animals would be less likely to be animal abusers, seeing as they had other, easier, and more abusive options than voluntary surrender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103614025.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>You cannot create a category of living things, call it "bargain bin" and expect it not to be targeted by evil people. 

Surrendering an animal has nothing to do with whether or not the owner abused it. There are a bunch of different kinds of abuse; not everything leaves scars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103910487.0" user="AntiObtusepolitica" delta="False">
    <text>Please also calculate for all the pets that are euthanized because they didn’t get homes. Each person you ban is a potential for a permanent placement. You are willing to eliminate  all those opportunities for an animal to find a home. A trial period or foster situation might help. Solutions your version of eternal judgment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104017874.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Each person you ban is a potential for a permanent placement.

...And a higher than normal potential for bringing the pet back to a shelter or otherwise abandoning it. 

&gt;Solutions your version of eternal judgment.

Animals are dying, Kathy. This isn't just about judgement. It's about the real world consequences for pets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104900868.0" user="TimmmV" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; This isn't. If 56% of dogs and 71% of cats in shelters end up being euthanized, people are on lists for essentially killing their pets. We don't bring them up on criminal charges but saying hey, you probably got your last pet killed so we won't give you another is reasonable. No matter how people leave pets at shelters, most of them probably don't understand the consequences for the animals.

They take their pets to shelters so that the pet can be looked after properly though? The problem is the shelter euthanises animals at such a high rate - which is something that is extremely preventable. You are treating this dynamic as a given when it doesn't need to be one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106933715.0" user="Account2436" delta="False">
    <text>I think this reasoning is flawed. My mother adopted a dog that tore my leg open trying to play with me. Me and the dog were bestfriends but it just couldn’t be gentle. It was a dog that needed just an adult and no children in the house. My mothers put him in a shelter because she didn’t want to risk the dog hurting me more. She wasn’t a bad owner or anything, the dog just wasn’t right for our home</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
