<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43101599740.0" user="GotAJeepNeedAJeep" delta="False">
    <text>Could you be letting the perfect be the enemy of the good? 

No one *needs* to be a pet owner, or has a right to be one. How many of the people on the "shitlist" are *bona fide* examples of people who made what was at the time a thoroughly responsible and well-thought out decision to adopt, but then faced wholly unpredictable circumstances rendering them incapable of caring for the animal and leading them to the equally responsible and well-thought out decision to surrender the pet?

I get that such a circumstance is possible, and it sucks for that would-be 2nd-time pet adopter. But isn't that a fair price to pay for protecting animals from the irresponsible, selfish, impulsive, shortsighted, or downright abusive people who take advantage of the adoption systems' comparitavely low entry barrier to pet ownership? Surely *returning a pet you adopted in a given timeframe* is a reasonably proxy for one's fitness for pet ownership? 

Sure, I'll grant you that it isn't fair for some people. But is your claim that this system is ineffective at its stated goal? If not, then can you elaborate on how *being fair* to this likely minority of "responsible pet surrenderers" is more important than protecting animals from those who'd do them harm?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101664416.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But isn't that a fair price to pay for protecting animals from the irresponsible, selfish, impulsive, shortsighted, or downright abusive people who take advantage of the adoption systems' comparitavely low entry barrier to pet ownership?

In my opinion it doesn't matter. Because people who are refused to adopt the shelter/rescue pets instead will go get a backyard-bred pitbull or mix breed for free or a doodle (depending on disposable income) and will still get a pet regardless from people who don't care and add to the pet problem by breeding backyard pets.   


Maybe being *fair* is still requiring info for surrender but having it 'drop off your record' after a few years or not having a prior surrender being a disqualifying factor for another adoption? I don't wish for irresponsible people to have pets, but why then don't we care when irresponsible people have kids? It seems so backwards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101746694.0" user="GotAJeepNeedAJeep" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Because people who are refused to adopt the shelter/rescue pets instead will go get a backyard-bred pitbull or mix breed for free or a doodle (depending on disposable income) and will still get a pet regardless from people who don't care and add to the pet problem by breeding backyard pets.

You're sort of being circular. You're arguing here that *because* of the shitlist, they'll go to the backchannels. Implying that if it *weren't* for the shitlist, they'd simply return to adoption shelters. Which means that the shitlist works for its intended purpose of keeping these people from abusing the adoption process. 

&gt;Maybe being fair is still requiring info for surrender but having it 'drop off your record' after a few years or not having a prior surrender being a disqualifying factor for another adoption?

Sure, I guess, but that's a different position than your original view, so if that's where you're at now I think I've earned a delta. 

&gt;I don't wish for irresponsible people to have pets, but why then don't we care when irresponsible people have kids? It seems so backwards.

Of course we care when irresponsible people have kids, but that's a different circumstance with different considerations. 

I and another consenting adult can't leverage our rights to our own bodliy autonomy to produce a puppy from nothing but our own biology.

Curtailing childbearing involves a host of ethical quagmires that just aren't present when considering pet ownership. And as you've incidentially pointed out yourself, our discussion is specifically about adoption from shelters; there are other channels to aquire a pet including breeding, purchasing and the black market. The shitlist is a regulatory tool for only one of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43101923027.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that there are multiple avenues to address the issue; and although I feel I have a pretty good grip on how to do that there may be better ways to keep more pets both housed *and* safe, while not denying people who could be good pet owners because of something out of their control years ago.   
Is the best way keeping the requirements and judgments on prior surrenders? Or is it better to eliminate the need to basically admit to society you're e a failure because you can't afford an enucleation on your proptosed pooch?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103529922.0" user="Phemto_B" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that it's the shelters letting the perfect be the enemy of the good. People can have good reasons have to surrender an animal, and people can "dispose" of an animals in very not good ways. 

You're focusing on the worst of humanity and letting it make you lash out at everyone. There are many reasons why a family may no longer be able to keep a pet. Do we reward them for dumping it and punish them for doing the responsible thing? All because we're mad about the really irresponsible people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103631022.0" user="No-Performance3044" delta="False">
    <text>If you never even adopted the animal but present it to the shelter, you still go on the shit list. It happened with my wife. Someone left their dog with us and refused to take it back claiming they have cancer all of a sudden, we would’ve kept the dog too but it was growling and attacking our dog, and peeing inside our house to mark its territory, refusing to make business outside. We couldn’t keep it since it was attacking our dog and making a mess, and we explicitly never agreed to adopt it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43103802024.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>This is an EXTREMELY good point. A big issue with databases like this is the potential negative impact to innocent people from categorical failures. It’s very similar to how algorithms applied to drug purchasing data flag people irrevocably as med abusers for getting prescriptions filled for (ironically, given the subject of discussion) their pets. Even in the event that someone disagrees with OP about whether a person who surrenders an adopted pet should be able to adopt in the future, there is unacceptable potential cost to other people. 

https://www.wired.com/story/opioid-drug-addiction-algorithm-chronic-pain/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43108136028.0" user="giantsnails" delta="False">
    <text>What? Clearly the shelters are the ones letting perfect be the enemy of good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
