<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43101984174.0" user="TikTrd" delta="False">
    <text>I really didn't read the entirety of your past because I stopped at....  Their records can go back 20 years, if you surrendered a pet in 2002....


Girl! That shit was on a floppy disc back then. Ain't no way a shelter is keeping records for 20 years. They'd need a spare fucking warehouse out back for all that paperwork. I get it. You're needlessly exaggerating to try to prove your point, but it's doubt it more of a disservice than anything. Their records probably go back *maybe* 5 years. 

Don't try to act like this is some sort of "No Fly" list that will automatically ban people for life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102054248.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Girl! That shit was on a floppy disc back then. When's the last time you saw a floppy disc (if ever). Ain't no way a shelter is keeping records for 20 years. 

Semantics.   
Also.... yes. There were definitely computer-based data bases as far back as 2000 and before that were widely used in government/state/county institutions, especially. Most county or city tax-payer funded programs have kept digital records since they were a thing-this includes animal shelters. Any written documents would have been input into digital databases upon crossover from written to digital record-keeping, whenever that was according to each individual location. But I am certain that *you* know better than a licensed vet tech who works and provides services to these rescues and shelters on a daily basis that there was no way of tracking people who surrendered animals 20 years ago..when I was older than you are now...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102070239.0" user="TikTrd" delta="False">
    <text>I know quite a lot about municipal databases and they cost for updating and the labor intensive process of uploading historical data, yes. I've done it many times. I guarantee you that if police departments, public works, public health, etc only have records from the early aughts scanned in as pdfs, then a shelter is going to be damn lucky to potentially have even that. They're probably using a freaking Excel spreadsheet for each year that they'd have to manually search for those years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102094621.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>How does a 20 -year old know better than someone tangentially related , though?   
And it's arguing disingenuously on semantics that are not the point of the post. The point isn't were records available 20 years ago, it was that they're available NOW and being used as a determinant factor in whether people are allowed to adopt shelter pets. It's a non-sequitur that doesn't matter at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43102103197.0" user="TikTrd" delta="False">
    <text>Who the fuck is 20? Girl..... if you're going to try to have an intelligent discourse, you have to meet the basic requirements. You seem far too emotional to have a conversation. You're not being coherent. Try that one again</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43109908328.0" user="Kp15324" delta="False">
    <text>What’s up with this chick hahaha tone the fuck down man OP has been nothing but respectful and transparent about his/her qualifications. 

You coming in cussing and claiming that you “know a lot about municipal database” makes you sound like an idiot lol. Not hating, just giving you the objective truth of how you come off.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
