<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43102684593.0" user="awokka" delta="False">
    <text>A "shitlist" is a very poor way to use the data, IMO. It's very black-and-white.

Having insight into a person's previous circumstances could be useful for reviewing whether they'd be equipped to adopt an animal now. If they did have to give up an animal before, was it in the context of particular circumstances? Have those circumstances changed? Did they act before any harm came to the animal? Can they explain how they can care better for the animal now?

Accessing background data helps you determine what's important to know _now_, to give the animal being adopted the best chances of a happy future. So although compiling data into a crude "shitlist" may be a bad idea, it doesn't mean that gather the same data - and perhaps even more data - and using it _differently_ should be prevented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43104037969.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>I mostly agree. However, I teach about data ethics and this is a significant subject of discussion. Without standardized data collection and ordering practices that deliberately anticipate potential misuses and misunderstandings of potentially-sensitive data, you are asking for trouble by collecting that data in the first place. It’s not just how those data are used, but how. More data isn’t necessarily the answer either, since that context on its own is not a silver bullet. What, for example, is judged to be contextual relative to the “primary” data of importance, and based on what assumptions? How are you representing and coding this data that doesn’t fit within the normed categories, based on what you envision they will be used for? Most importantly, who is making and overseeing those decisions, and what processes are in place to minimize recourse when they create unintended consequences?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105885024.0" user="awokka" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that any and all data collection is so riddled with issues that it's always morally preferable to collect no data?

I thought that organisations were held accountable to things like GDPR to achieve a practical middle ground, where the benefits of gathering and using data can still be gained while reducing the risks of misuse. I don't see why this kind of middle ground would be unviable for this specific example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43105925346.0" user="NotYourFathersEdits" delta="False">
    <text>No, I am extremely clearly not saying always. I am saying that in situations where extensive work toward these questions won’t or cannot happen, that the data should not be collected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106060534.0" user="awokka" delta="False">
    <text>It was a genuine question to try to understand what you were getting at. Thank you for explaining, I'm sorry I pissed you off.

I can see how, for some organisations, in some contexts, they might not be able to gather data responsibly, and therefore shouldn't do it. We're on the same page that we can't just collect data and cross our fingers that it'll all be fine.

But I think it's a stretch to apply that to every animal shelter in the world. I think we'd risk making the world a worse place by imposing a blanket rule that _no_ animal shelter could _ever_ keep _any_ data of this kind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111815528.0" user="arrrrarrr" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, how is this answer not more popular?? Fabulous job explaining the potential pitfalls and how complicated this all is. Thanks for sharing your professional knowledge!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107794897.0" user="awokka" delta="False">
    <text>I realised that this point could be extended for using the data to do other, actively good things, e.g.:

* identifying trends/factors that underlie people having to give animals up, and use this to inform social investment so it can have the biggest positive impact
* connecting individual people with direct support for the other aspects of their life that have led to them giving a pet up

Obviously it relies on having adequate data processing and investment available, and you'd still need to put measures in place to be careful to avoid the data being misused as a "shitlist."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107825972.0" user="horshack_test" delta="False">
    <text>What you describe is how the shelter I volunteered at used the information.  What OP describes is simply not the case with all shelters.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
