<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2488070394.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/155bzei/cmv_people_who_surrender_animals_to_the_shelter/">
    <title>CMV: People who surrender animals to the shelter shouldn't be required to do paperwork that identifies them or go on a 'sh*tlist' that prevents them from adopting from that shelter in the future.</title>
    <original_poster>ForsakenTakes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start off by saying that I'm a licensed and registered veterinary technician who has experience working in clinics that do 'bulk' reduced cost spays and neuters for local humane societies and shelters.   
Yes, the sheer numbers of unwanted puppies and kittens- especially in the spring and fall -are next to impossible to keep up with. I hate seeing animals come in and out of the clinic that have been returned to their respective shelters, neglected, abused, or needlessly pregnant or intact as much as anyone else, because in the end it IS irresponsible people that cause these situations...   


However, I do not think that these shelters should be keeping what we call "shitlists" on people who responsibly surrender their pets they can no longer care for and go through the proper channels to surrender.   
What any shelter or rescue is doing by having you sign paperwork or anything regarding your surrender is basically adding you into a database of "irresponsible pet owners".   


Sometimes, this information is shared with surrounding shelters and rescues to deny future adoptions to people who've surrendered an animal *anytime in the past*. As far as I can tell, these databases are *forever*. If you surrendered a dog in 2002 because you lost your job and had to move into housing that doesn't allow pets for a few years, for example, they keep that surrender -and your reason- on file. And if you go in to adopt a pet today from that same shelter, you could be denied adoption because you're flagged in the system as an "abandoner". If your recalled reasoning doesn't match the original paperwork for surrendering an animal in the past -they will automatically deny you and assume the worst.  


I feel like making people identify themselves during the surrender process is counterproductive. The reason for this is it encourages blind dumping or abandonment at these shelters. We have so many pets left outside of these rescues/shelters that have requirements to fill out paperwork and provide identification that *more are dumped than people following protocol* by going in and physically filling out the paperwork. Because people know that they're going on some shit-list they don't know whom it will be shared with if they go in and "do the right thing".   


Sometimes these abandoned pets are left injured in crates- during the weekend or at night in harsh conditions when no one is there, simply because they fear being identified and judged for abandoning a pet they cannot care for. That's a big reason people re-surrender their animal- they get sick or get into an accident and the owner cannot afford the veterinary bills and are embarrassed and heart-broken.   
Allowing a 'no-questions asked' policy and 'baby boxes' have worked wonders for fewer unwanted babies being dumped in trash cans or irresponsibly on hospital property. Why can't we apply the same mindset to pets?   


I also don't feel like punishing someone for life is fair when people's situations change and improve all the time. Just because someone hit a rough patch 10 years ago and had to bring their cat back to the shelter doesn't mean they'll always be some irresponsible pet-dumper. (I think this is the reason they're so worried about the nature of the surrender, and want the paperwork in the first place.)   


Their hearts (shelters and rescues) are in the right place, but they're making things more difficult than they need to be when housing all of the pets that need it. There are way too many pets in need of homes to scrutinize potential owners to the point some of these shelters do. Some of these requirements are higher than many people in society hold to be a necessary threshold for caring for their own children and are excessive and ridiculous.   


TL;DR: Don't make people ID and "tell on" themselves when surrendering an animal because it makes more people just dump them instead. Also, don't just assume someone's a pos dumper for life just because they had to surrender in the past.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43105333080.0" user="ockhams-razor" delta="False">
    <text>If you abandoned your newborn infant to the fire department (not anonymously), and then later on try to adopt a child... You're also going to be flat out rejected.  It doesn't matter the reason.

You've shown, in your history, that you did not make the well being of a another, life in your care, a priority.  You gave up.

Regardless of the reason, it's information that the adoption agency have to assess whether the candidate life is going to be fully taken care of by the prospective adopters.

In both human and animal adoptions, this is a HUGE red flag.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106208589.0" user="AntiObtusepolitica" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not true, if you surrender your baby, you would probably have a better chance adopting a child later in life than a pet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106751466.0" user="ockhams-razor" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstood me.

I'm saying, as an analogy, if you surrender your baby, you won't be able to adopt a baby later on.

If you surrender your pet, you will not be able to adopt a pet later on.

And this is reasonable, you have a history that puts the well being of the potential child/pet in question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107406374.0" user="AntiObtusepolitica" delta="False">
    <text>How did I misunderstand? Abandoning a baby on the side of the road is something that makes you not only a bad parent but a bad human. Surrendering a baby requires turning it in at a baby box, fire station, or hospital and putting it up for adoption. This action does not necessarily mean you will forever be ineligible to adopt. They actually look at the circumstances surrounding the surrender. I guess they realize that people do get their lives together and besides, we don’t euthanize children so we have to find them homes. 
With that said there are some pieces of sh&amp;t that adopt children as well. Despite all the hurdles they place to adoption. And yet we still assume adoption is preferable to foster care, group homes or death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43107813402.0" user="ockhams-razor" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree, but that's okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43106352774.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>If that be true, of which I'm not sure, than that is a bad idea.

Someone not in the financial or emotional capacity to raise a child is doing the right thing giving it up for adoption.

Are you honestly saying that a teenage rape victim who gives up a child for adoption should, when having a good job 7 years later wanting to adopt should not be allowed to do so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43109181872.0" user="zac79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If you abandoned your newborn infant to the fire department (not anonymously), and then later on try to adopt a child... You're also going to be flat out rejected. It doesn't matter the reason.

You really need a citation for a claim like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43111337339.0" user="ForsakenTakes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you abandoned your newborn infant to the fire department (not anonymously), and then later on try to adopt a child... You're also going to be flat out rejected.  It doesn't matter the reason.

Yeah, but you could just get knocked up instead and no one can tell you otherwise. The pet equivalent is going to a backyard breeder or Craigslist.  


But people clutch their pearls at the mere *mention* of keeping those unfit parents from *breeding* more kids they can't care for properly. In fact, in our society we INCENTIVIZE these people to breed more by giving them free food/housing/medical care. But only if they're a destitute *parent*. That same person if they responsibly used birth control and is both *childfree or childless* and destitute, though...they can go kick rocks, amirite??!!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
