<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2491044503.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1573q8n/cmv_the_us_is_on_the_brink_of_civil_war_2/">
    <title>CMV: The US is on the brink of Civil War 2: Electric Boogaloo.</title>
    <original_poster>Nailyou866</original_poster>
    <original_post>A bit of a doomer post, I know, but this is why I am here.

I think the trends in the US are terrifying and will have a catastrophic climax in the near future. Civil unrest seems to be at an all-time high due to a variety of factors. I am very left/libertarian leaning and I see right wing and liberal outlets promoting highly charged news, racial tensions on the rise, police brutality, class warfare, and identity politics taking center stage as major contributors.

The news. Headlines are what news outlets thrive on, and the more extreme or outrage-y drive traffic to the articles, meaning that positive and uplifting stories are either left in the dust or not written in favor of something more likely to increase engagement. This means that context and nuance are buried in favor of opinion pieces that cause people to be irritable or in despair. Reporting biases gear audiences to a place of discontent. I know this isn't necessarily a bad thing on its own, as this can be a catalyst for change, but given some sources and motivations, such as right wing media trying to cause change against "wokeness", this can ruin interpersonal relations as people begin to hate their fellow person. I know that politics has a massive presense in society, but when people see humans just existing as "political" or "woke", they can easily otherize humans into something not themselves, making it easier to hate.

Racial tensions. This is relatively self explanatory as white supremacists are pouring out of the woodworks to attack movements like BLM and policies like Affirmative Action. It makes it difficult to be a person like me, cis, white, male, and working in security. I know I make black people uncomfortable because without knowing me, they might be quick to assume I have white supremacist ideals or biases. Anecdotally, I had to pull aside a group of black kids at one of my posts because they were causing problems at the establishment, and I kept having to get onto them about what they were doing. I pulled them aside to explain how the actions they were engaging in were problematic for the establishment and why management kept having me get onto them. Basically a "look, people are paying for a certain experience, and are complaining because you are getting in the way and being disruptive. If you want to be here, that is fine, but you have to follow the rules." As I was talking to them, an older black gentleman walked by and stopped to listen to what I was telling them. He told me after they left that he appreciated the way I talked to them and handled the situation maturely, and he stuck by because he was a little nervous because he saw "a white rent-a-cop talking to a group of black kids" and he wanted to make sure that everything was on the up and up, which I totally get. We talked for a while about the state of police and race issues, and largely agreed on several positions.

Which brings me to my next point, police brutality. It is no secret that Law Enforcement is... problematic in the US. I know it isn't just the US, but my focus is here right now. Connecticut just had several hundred police busted for over 20,000 fake and falsified tickets over a several year time span. As phone footage and body cam footage is released we see a really dark reality for minorities in the US. People being murdered or beaten for a variety of reasons, dogs being released on people and uncontrolled, and militarization of the police force given budgets that far outweigh things like parks and recreation or mental health. These issues are felt nation-wide and the average citizen can do nothing to redress their grievances, or it further hurts them because the State backs the cops. Qualified Immunity has been abused to the point where cops can just violate your rights and get away with it because "they couldn't have known they were violating your rights". The average citizen is powerless against the police, which is by design. If a cop draws on me and I were to shoot in self-defense, I would have a greater degree of a burden of proof than a cop would if it were the other way around, or even if I didn't draw. We saw that with kids being murdered by police for toy guys or adults being murdered for a hairbrush that was assumed to be a weapon.

Class warfare. People are being kicked out of house and home due to wage stagnation and supression, while the rich just get richer. We can see a direct example of that concept with the Hollywood debacle. Streaming services are massively profitable, requiring next to no cost compared to the older ways of distribution, and yet shareholders are raking in profits while actors and writers are being paid less overall due to the elimination of residuals through the streaming model. Massive shifts in technological advancements result in more money being accumulated by those already at the top. While I can go on about the inherant flaws of a profit-driven economy, the real facts are that CEOs and investors are gaining net worth and value while every day citizens are struggling to get by. More and more Americans are living paycheck to paycheck because of these things.

Identity politics. For whatever reason, LGBT+ issues are now taking the forefront of the GOP's platform. "Wokeness" is something that they are now dedicated to fighting, with baseless accusations being thrown against these minority groups of grooming and pedophilia, with the rise of acceptance and more people feeling comfortable enough about coming out being used as evidence of a conspiracy to turn everyone trans and gay. Children taught that it is OK to be different are somehow being indoctrinated in to this cult of degenerate behavior. The falsified outrage against the minority groups is being used to motivate hate crimes against anyone who supports them. Are there discussions that can be had about the type of information and when it is appropriate? Sure, but this isn't their goal. It was not and never has been about "protecting children" evidenced by the anti-trans bills being passed nation-wide that are trying to ban or raise the age to 25.

There are other issues at play, like rising mass violence and conspiracy theories, but these are kind of my main focuses. I am terrified that we are going to see an unresolvable schism in American society that will lead to a civil war with a death toll higher than any war to date. The lines won't be as clean this time, since before, people were mostly aligned with their state. In this time period, I would be more likely to catch a bullet from my neighbor than someone from another state, as was the case in the Civil War we know from history. Please, restore my faith in our ability to avert this catastrophy and come to a better solution. Some of my positions, such as my ideology or views on minorities and trans, you will not be able to change, those aren't the focus of this CMV. I just don't want to be worried I wake up and hearing about the new Fort Sumter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43117240618.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Like, when was any of this stuff you're complaining about not true?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117252129.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't about the truth of the societal issues that I am concerned about, it is about the trend of American society to large scale violence in the near future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117259341.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Nowdays is about as peaceful as things have ever been. You think the current Writer/Actor strikes are bad? At least there's not literal gunfire. You think current race relations are bad? At least lynching is illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117290134.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>The point I was making with the strikes is about the growing disparity that will soon become unsustainable, not the steikes themselves. I am aware that no direct violence has occured over those strikes in particular yet. This is more about the potential for problems. If enough people get forced into homelessness and poverty, do you not think it can result in a large violent movement as people get fed up with their situation?


Race relations are a difficult topic on their own because sure lynchings are illegal, but that doesn't prevent race based violence from occurring. Take a look at the white supremacist that shot up the black majority supermarket in New York. It wasn't a lynching, but absolutely motivated by race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117305331.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>And the point I was making is that we have been through these scenarios before without ending up in Civil War. We've had growing wealth inequality and horrible race relations before. Why wasn't that the 'brink of Civil War 2' but this is? It's not any worse now than it was then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117434087.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>I will admit that my position here is largely vibes based, but I can't really point to any time when wealth inequality was worse than now. We had the Great Depression, sure but that did affect everyone. There was growing unrest, and FDR had to do the New Deal, which greatly helped the average person. Right now we have Republicans actively fighting tooth and nail to prevent helping the impoverished and Democrats largely not caring as much. With the Supreme Court stacked against progressive politics, it will be much harder to pass a real economic reform.

Racial tensions may have been at their peak in the 60's, but like I said, I think it is just one factor among many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117545263.0" user="GogurtFiend" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I will admit that my position here is largely vibes based

A basic tenet of [epistemology](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epistemology) is that one's perception of a thing ("vibes") doesn't necessarily reflect the actual nature of said thing.

In other words: you can't make accurate predictions based off "vibes". "Vibes" depend on how you're feeling at any one time, not on anything empirical. If I were to give you a bunch of dopamine and Adderall, you'd suddenly be a lot happier and I'm quite certain your prediction would change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117638476.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know what specific philosophical position I hold, as I am still learning, however I do agree with the concept that feelings don't reflect reality. What I mean here is that I am seeing all of these demonstable facts of reality, as stated in my OP, and I am worried about a large scale bloody conflict. I have now walked back the description of Civil War for it, but I think people are going to get fed up with how things are, and it will cause a massive conflict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44187190656.0" user="itsjoshtaylor" delta="False">
    <text>“Vibes” are intuition, and intuition is a powerful thing — ask my philosophy professor, who’s one of the best in the world. Don’t bother with the naysayers; you’re an insightful person. Trust yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117774790.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Homelessness has been either steady or decreasing in the last few years. Real wages have increased since the 1980s.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117805372.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>Underemployment is on the rise, wages are largely stagnant, and housing costs are growing. Since the end of covid protections eviction rates have been well over average. Without a redress of these issues, we are going to see some serious economic strain.

Racial violence has always been a thing but 1) that isn't a good thing, and we should be eliminating it, and 2) it seems to be getting to a point where people are more comfortable with committing racial violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43119362420.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Rising unemployment? We’re at 3.6 percent, which is still at historical lows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118177242.0" user="Careful_Candle_2617" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Race relations are a difficult topic on their own because sure lynchings are illegal, but that doesn't prevent race based violence from occurring. Take a look at the white supremacist that shot up the black majority supermarket in New York. 

Take a look at the 37 murders that were committed by blacks against White people in December 2022 alone. https://vdare.com/articles/37-black-on-white-homicides-in-gas-stations-parking-lots-and-living-rooms-december-2022-another-month-in-the-death-of-white-america

It's weird how you paint race relations as White people's fault when it's colored people committing the majority of murders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118425092.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I am not going to sit here and pretend your bullshit 13/50 arguments have any merit. Fuck off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118511956.0" user="Careful_Candle_2617" delta="False">
    <text>It's 12.5/60. As in the blacks are 12.5% of the US population and commit 60% of the murders.

Reported for hostility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118515688.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>Nazi-ism is a hostile ideology, I am just responding in kind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118821467.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118567504.0" user="wrongagainlol" delta="False">
    <text>Well, white people do tend to say things like

&gt; The negros love their fried chicken and rap music wherever they end up.

So in some cases, poor race relations *are* White's people's fault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118606603.0" user="Careful_Candle_2617" delta="False">
    <text>Which race commits the majority of murders and robberies in the US again?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118655721.0" user="wrongagainlol" delta="False">
    <text>The one you hate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117491779.0" user="Donny-Bandish" delta="False">
    <text>this isn’t really true. hate crimes are at highs that haven’t been seen since jim crow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117786380.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>Isn’t that a reporting issue? There’s no mandatory reporting of hate crimes to the FBI like other crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43127892944.0" user="Hot-Sale9294" delta="False">
    <text>There is no way that can possibly be true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43118557765.0" user="wrongagainlol" delta="False">
    <text>Please. America was WAY more violent than this in the 1990s.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
