<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="250195022.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/44yjpq/cmv_nuclear_power_should_be_widely_adopted/">
    <title>CMV: Nuclear power should be widely adopted until/unless renewable energy sources can catch up</title>
    <original_poster>LostInRiverview</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've had numerous debates with other self-described liberals (in the American sense of the word) regarding nuclear power's place in energy production and in combating climate change. During these discussions, I've held that nuclear power plants should be aggressively built in order to meet current and future electricity needs. We have agreed that non-renewable energy is a detriment to the planet, and that an ideal solution would be non-nuclear as well (e.g. solar, wind, and other as-yet-unknown methods of power generation), but they have argued that nuclear power in itself is inherently dangerous, devastating, and should not be part of our "energy portfolio" moving forward. I feel this view is based mostly on an emotional reaction to the idea of nuclear power, rather than one based in science and reason. I have pointed out that modern methods of nuclear power generation are much safer and more efficient than those developed in the mid-20th century, and many times safer than continuing to burn fossil fuels for energy. Additionally, while we are making strides towards improving our power generation through renewables, there's no guarantee that we'll ever be able to provide all the energy we need through those methods, especially if/when we transition from gas-powered to electric vehicles. Transitioning to modern nuclear reactors for electricity seems the most level-headed long-term solution to our energy problems, at least until such time as we can find better ways to generate green electricity. 

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28287812604.0" user="pasttense" delta="False">
    <text>And how long do you think it will take renewables to catch up? 10 years? If so there is no point in building nuclear plants as it will take that long to build if you order it today.

http://www.energypost.eu/will-new-nuclear-power-plants-built/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287831420.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>I have no firm numbers on-hand to say how quickly we could catch up with renewables, if we can even catch up at all. However, even if you had very aggressive construction of renewable energy generators, I doubt we'd be able to come close to meeting our current energy needs within the next decade, to say nothing of our energy needs in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
