<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="250195022.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/44yjpq/cmv_nuclear_power_should_be_widely_adopted/">
    <title>CMV: Nuclear power should be widely adopted until/unless renewable energy sources can catch up</title>
    <original_poster>LostInRiverview</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've had numerous debates with other self-described liberals (in the American sense of the word) regarding nuclear power's place in energy production and in combating climate change. During these discussions, I've held that nuclear power plants should be aggressively built in order to meet current and future electricity needs. We have agreed that non-renewable energy is a detriment to the planet, and that an ideal solution would be non-nuclear as well (e.g. solar, wind, and other as-yet-unknown methods of power generation), but they have argued that nuclear power in itself is inherently dangerous, devastating, and should not be part of our "energy portfolio" moving forward. I feel this view is based mostly on an emotional reaction to the idea of nuclear power, rather than one based in science and reason. I have pointed out that modern methods of nuclear power generation are much safer and more efficient than those developed in the mid-20th century, and many times safer than continuing to burn fossil fuels for energy. Additionally, while we are making strides towards improving our power generation through renewables, there's no guarantee that we'll ever be able to provide all the energy we need through those methods, especially if/when we transition from gas-powered to electric vehicles. Transitioning to modern nuclear reactors for electricity seems the most level-headed long-term solution to our energy problems, at least until such time as we can find better ways to generate green electricity. 

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28287813004.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>Don't get me wrong, nuclear energy is a wonderful technology. Thanks to containment, Nuclear Energy has exposed fewer people to radiation per unit energy produced than Coal, and the energy made is carbon neutral. It's great! But, it's not perfect, and you should be aware of the limitations.

1. Nuclear Energy production requires a large body of water nearby for cooling purposes. So, it's never going to be a good solution in places like Las Vegas that lack large bodies of water.
2. Right now, we have no permanent storage solution for nuclear waste generated through nuclear fission. The planned storage site at [Yucca Mountain](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yucca_Mountain_nuclear_waste_repository), which was supposed to store nuclear waste for the next million years, has become a nightmare for construction-- so each nuclear facility must store waste materials on site, indefinitely. These materials are going to continue to require containment for many lifetimes to come.
3. Natural disasters happen, and the events at Fukushima should be a wakeup call to anyone who wants to build nuclear not only in California, but on the east coast as well: [We are overdue for a major earthquake.](http://bigthink.com/dr-kakus-universe/the-east-coast-earthquake-is-a-wake-up-call-and-should-serve-as-a-warning-of-how-unprepared-we-actually-are) Fukushima was bad, but imagine how much worse it would be if even just a few of our nation's [~100](http://www.nrc.gov/info-finder/reactors/) nuclear reactors lost containment! We could face a disaster that would make sizeable portions of (especially the east coast) uninhabitable for millennia. 

Again, don't get me wrong-- I think Nuclear is a great idea-- but the sooner we can shut down these reactors, the better. And I would expect that if we successfully replaced all of our non-renewables with renewables and nuclear, the wind would be removed from the sails towards 100% clean/non-nuclear renewables before long.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287843807.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>I think the points you've raised are all valid concerns, but they don't make the overall truth any less valid: relying on non-renewables is not sustainable in the long-term, and causes very real problems for us in the present, and will continue to do so into the future. Even with the issues behind nuclear power, I feel it is the best approach of all the ideas we currently have. I personally doubt that renewable energy (at least, the methods that we currently have available to us) will ever be able to meet our energy needs. 

It's worth noting that there are more modern reactor designs, like thorium reactors, that create substantially less waste than the outdated reactors used in the United States. While nuclear waste will always be a reality of nuclear power, if we transitioned to more efficient methods of generation, we could make the resulting waste a minor problem at worst. Of course, the one caveat here is that we'd still need some place to store that waste, and I can't see many places being eager to take it. Still, on the whole that's a solvable problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287855316.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>Not immediately though. Right now, we have to measure which evil is least. Here are the options, as I see them:

1. Continue using fossil fuels, risk global warming catastrophe. Large swaths of the world potentially become uninhabitable due to rising sea levels. 
2. Expand Nuclear, risk nuclear catastrophe. Large swaths of the world potentially become uninhabitable due to radiation, and still cannot end fossil fuel usage in many areas due to unsuitability of the technology. 
3. Cut consumption to levels allowed by renewable technologies. Millions die to loss of electricity and services.

All three suck. But Nuclear offers (arguably) the greatest destructive opportunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287877551.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're overstating the likelihood of such a nuclear catastrophe occurring, especially if we replace outmoded nuclear generating methods. Thorium reactors and other modern reactor types/designs are designed to be passively safe - the nuclear reaction will stop on its own if some accident or incident should cause the operators to lose control of the reactor. This passive safety limits or eliminates the risk of long-term damage. Some designs are even considered inherently safe, meaning that even in a catastrophe, there's a low likelihood of real danger. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287923332.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>You're using a technology that, while promising, is not yet commercially viable to defend your position. Why not argue that Fusion energy has none of these dangers or problems?

No currently commercially viable reactor is immune to these concerns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287961944.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>Immune to concerns, no. But neither is any other viable form of power production. Even third-generation nuclear power plants - which are currently commercially available - significantly reduce risk below that of plants operating in the US. Even discounting all of this, the danger of even outdated nuclear power generation is, on the whole, less than that of fossil fuel-based power generation. 

Allow me to employ an analogy. If you asked a layperson which was more dangerous, airplanes or cars, they could be forgiven for assuming that planes are more dangerous. After all, whenever a plane crash occurs, it makes the news, sometimes even national or international news. But of course, the reverse is true, and the only reason plane crashes make the news is because of the large death toll often associated with such events. The same could be said for nuclear power vs fossil fuels. Whereas a major Chernobyl-scale event could occur and cause damage over a localized area (though this is again more unlikely with modern design), the damage caused collectively by nuclear power pales in comparison to the damage to health and climate caused by the burning of fossil fuels to generate equitable levels of electricity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287974029.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>And my point is that the potential for apocalyptic level outcomes is greater for the plane than for the car. Yes, its safer on the whole-- but there is still an unmitigable level of destructive potential that you are (rationally) disregarding. But you still need to acknowledge it as existent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28293685746.0" user="ygyfygy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; so each nuclear facility must store waste materials on site, indefinitely

\* so each **uranium** nuclear facility.

Thorium facilities are green.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28294240318.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>No such thing at the moment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28294367556.0" user="ygyfygy" delta="False">
    <text>Th facilities aren't 100% green, but they are much better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28294370060.0" user="sdneidich" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, they would be better. But they also don't exist yet commercially.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
