<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="250195022.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/44yjpq/cmv_nuclear_power_should_be_widely_adopted/">
    <title>CMV: Nuclear power should be widely adopted until/unless renewable energy sources can catch up</title>
    <original_poster>LostInRiverview</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've had numerous debates with other self-described liberals (in the American sense of the word) regarding nuclear power's place in energy production and in combating climate change. During these discussions, I've held that nuclear power plants should be aggressively built in order to meet current and future electricity needs. We have agreed that non-renewable energy is a detriment to the planet, and that an ideal solution would be non-nuclear as well (e.g. solar, wind, and other as-yet-unknown methods of power generation), but they have argued that nuclear power in itself is inherently dangerous, devastating, and should not be part of our "energy portfolio" moving forward. I feel this view is based mostly on an emotional reaction to the idea of nuclear power, rather than one based in science and reason. I have pointed out that modern methods of nuclear power generation are much safer and more efficient than those developed in the mid-20th century, and many times safer than continuing to burn fossil fuels for energy. Additionally, while we are making strides towards improving our power generation through renewables, there's no guarantee that we'll ever be able to provide all the energy we need through those methods, especially if/when we transition from gas-powered to electric vehicles. Transitioning to modern nuclear reactors for electricity seems the most level-headed long-term solution to our energy problems, at least until such time as we can find better ways to generate green electricity. 

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28288175239.0" user="200dronerush" delta="False">
    <text>I think the issue with (current) nuclear power plants is their economy. Not really safety or storage concerns.

They're hugely expensive to build and very expensive to decommison. Actual nuclear power plants really need to operate for a long time (quite often over the schedule) to get some sort of return of the investment. The reason why Germany phased off nuclear power plants wasn't really Fukushima hysteria (it just helped a bit), but because they were a huge hassle in economic terms.

I think there isn't really any strong reason FOR building additional nuclear plants at this time. Simply because renewables are quickly becoming more and more competitive as a clean energy source. A few wind farms cost a lot less than a nuclear facility.

I think there is a bright future in advanced gen IV reactors (especially miniaturized). But they aren't coming anytime soon. By that time even a somewhat efficient fusion plant may be feasible.

In conclusion, I think nuclear power plants aren't feasible as an intermediate solution. But they could well be the 'ultimate' solution to getting rid of fossil fuels for good, be it fission or fusion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
