<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2503391384.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15egd5k/cmv_either_every_recognized_genocide_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Either every recognized genocide should be illegal to deny, or none of them should be.</title>
    <original_poster>Tibbenator</original_poster>
    <original_post>This IS NOT about whether some genocide took place or not, nor is it an argument about freedom of speech on the matter. This is simply about application of law.

A country should not pick and choose which horrible atrocity is illegal to deny and which ones aren't. Every act of genocide recognized as such by that nation's government should be illegal to deny or none of them should be. The law should be applied evenly to every genocide.

What sense does it make to decide which atrocities are illegal to deny and which aren't? It seems to be giving a message that "We recognize all these terrible crimes against humanity for what they are, but some of them are worthy of more protection than the others".

Making only select genocides illegal to deny just adds fuel to fires of conspiracy. Racists, nazis, bigots, all of the above, and so on, tend to see these laws as some sort of warped justification for their views; they believe they must be right because it's only illegal to deny the specific genocide that they are focused on and not others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43185029892.0" user="sophisticaden_" delta="False">
    <text>What government recognizes a genocide, allows individuals to deny it, and recognizes another but forbids them from denying it?

I’m not being rhetorical; do you have an example of this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185052827.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>There are [several countries](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legality_of_Holocaust_denial) that have laws banning the public denial of the Holocaust.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185089418.0" user="sophisticaden_" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I’m aware of that. 

I’m asking what genocides those countries formally acknowledge the existence of but permit the denial of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185071125.0" user="Tibbenator" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, I should have included that in my post. 

Using Canada as that is where I'm from; the Canadian government officially recognizes eight (8) genocides, yet only one is illegal to deny.
I believe Germany recognizes over 12 genocides but only has laws regarding the denial of 3 of them (but I may be mistaken here).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185090959.0" user="sophisticaden_" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the clarification!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185142187.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>because making it illegal is a political move rather then a legislative one, apply enough political pressure and then can render the other 8 similarly,  but practically there is just no point,  

denying an officially acknowledged genocide is a political move or one made of ignorance, but most genocides no longer have value in denying so there is no value in expending political capital to prevent them from being used as political leverage</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
