<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2503391384.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15egd5k/cmv_either_every_recognized_genocide_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Either every recognized genocide should be illegal to deny, or none of them should be.</title>
    <original_poster>Tibbenator</original_poster>
    <original_post>This IS NOT about whether some genocide took place or not, nor is it an argument about freedom of speech on the matter. This is simply about application of law.

A country should not pick and choose which horrible atrocity is illegal to deny and which ones aren't. Every act of genocide recognized as such by that nation's government should be illegal to deny or none of them should be. The law should be applied evenly to every genocide.

What sense does it make to decide which atrocities are illegal to deny and which aren't? It seems to be giving a message that "We recognize all these terrible crimes against humanity for what they are, but some of them are worthy of more protection than the others".

Making only select genocides illegal to deny just adds fuel to fires of conspiracy. Racists, nazis, bigots, all of the above, and so on, tend to see these laws as some sort of warped justification for their views; they believe they must be right because it's only illegal to deny the specific genocide that they are focused on and not others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43185048294.0" user="GotAJeepNeedAJeep" delta="False">
    <text>You conflate two concepts in your post - a *government* formally acknowledging a discrete genocide, and a *law* prohibiting denial of specific genocide by the people governed. 

&gt;Making only select genocides illegal to deny just adds fuel to fires of conspiracy. Racists, nazis, bigots, all of the above, and so on, tend to see these laws as some sort of warped justification for their views; they believe they must be right because it's only illegal to deny the specific genocide that they are focused on and not others.

Talk more about the inconsistent laws that you take issue with? Can you give an example of a country where I can say aloud *X genocide did not happen* but cannot say aloud *Y genocide did not happen?*

Finally; in your hypothetical world, where all genocides are treated equally and anyone who denies one is shot dead in the street or thrown in jail for life - I assume, as you've not indicated what an appropriate punishment is for "denial" - is there no fear on your part of a government deemign this or that event a "genocide" to control speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185129203.0" user="Dennis_enzo" delta="False">
    <text>The Netherlands has a law making it illegal to deny the Holocaust. No such laws exist for other genocides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185133736.0" user="Tibbenator" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Finally; in your hypothetical world, where all genocides are treated equally and anyone who denies one is shot dead in the street or thrown in jail for life - I assume, as you've not indicated what an appropriate punishment is for "denial" - is there no fear on your part of a government deemign this or that event a "genocide" to control speech?

Personally I support freedom of speech and believe that none of them should be illegal to deny or question. I also think that if a government DOES decide to make it illegal, then they should apply the law equally and not choose which genocides are illegal to deny and which aren't. I also think it's quite the leap to assume I want people gunned down in the streets for speaking their opinion, especially given the sub I'm on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185187656.0" user="GotAJeepNeedAJeep" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I also think it's quite the leap to assume I want people gunned down in the streets for speaking their opinion, especially given the sub I'm on.

How is it a leap? You want people punished in *some* way for speaking a particular opinion. By all means, clear up for us what you feel the appropriate punishment is. Don't leave room in your argument for me to make that assumption. 

&gt;Personally I support freedom of speech and believe that none of them should be illegal to deny or question. 

Then why isn't *that* your posted view? Why this far more slippery argument about percieved double-standards? You're opening the door for us to all start bickering about which genocide is worse. 

&gt;I also think that if a government DOES decide to make it illegal, then they should apply the law equally and not choose which genocides are illegal to deny and which aren't.

See? This statement makes the assumptions that all genocides are, in fact, equal. Are they? Is that the discussion you're really looking to have this morning?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
