<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2503391384.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15egd5k/cmv_either_every_recognized_genocide_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Either every recognized genocide should be illegal to deny, or none of them should be.</title>
    <original_poster>Tibbenator</original_poster>
    <original_post>This IS NOT about whether some genocide took place or not, nor is it an argument about freedom of speech on the matter. This is simply about application of law.

A country should not pick and choose which horrible atrocity is illegal to deny and which ones aren't. Every act of genocide recognized as such by that nation's government should be illegal to deny or none of them should be. The law should be applied evenly to every genocide.

What sense does it make to decide which atrocities are illegal to deny and which aren't? It seems to be giving a message that "We recognize all these terrible crimes against humanity for what they are, but some of them are worthy of more protection than the others".

Making only select genocides illegal to deny just adds fuel to fires of conspiracy. Racists, nazis, bigots, all of the above, and so on, tend to see these laws as some sort of warped justification for their views; they believe they must be right because it's only illegal to deny the specific genocide that they are focused on and not others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43185227638.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; What sense does it make to decide which atrocities are illegal to deny and which aren't?

The sense is that they're crafting laws that address the problems they actually have and want to solve, and are less specific about problems that they don't have and aren't really trying to solve.

If Canadian legislators think they have a problem with antisemitism, it makes sense to craft a law that relates to antisemitism. It's worth noting that the Canadian law in question I think is:

https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/c-46/section-319.html

It has a section about "Wilful promotion of hatred" *and* a section about "Wilful promotion of antisemitism". The law *is* broader than just holocaust denial, but they just add a very specific section because that's clearly the specific problem they want to address and they want to leave no doubt about the key use case.

This is not really any different than consumer product design. You build a device that should work in all kinds of conditions, but you give extra consideration to what you think is the main use case.

I think it would be helpful for your view to assert a specific direction here that you think would be better than the Canadian law as written rather than the kind of wishy washy "should be all or none" position. If you're opposed to this Canadian law, just say so. If you think this Canadian law should be stricter, say so. But laws are written by multiple people and go through a legislative process and are often balancing multiple needs and interests, and it doesn't seem weird in principle that the final law represents a compromise between specificity on the most pressing issue vs trying to being concise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
