<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237132854.0" user="Fluffy_MrSheep" delta="False">
    <text>Aside from your otherwise weak argument. The hijab is not a religious symbol. Unlike others mentioned the hijab is a sign of modesty. You cover your hair because it's a feature that will attract men. It's been proven that girls who wear hijabs get less attention from men. This isn't a fact u can argue.

The purpose of a hijab isn't to highlight your religion. No girl wears a hijab to tell the world they are Muslim. It just so happens that Islam is the only religion which heavily promotes (not mandates) girls to wear a hijab

It's funny because the same crowd who argue that girls should be allowed wear what they want only use that argument when talking about a girls right to wear revealing or attractive clothing like sports wear and short skirts but when it comes to wearing hijabs, something worn to push away male attraction. The same argument doesn't apply. 

Going back to your main argument about schools being a secular institution. Just because they are secular doesn't mean they can't allow religions to be practiced there. As long as they aren't funded by specific religious institutions then they can remain secular while allowing all these religions to co exist. There's no need to target a specific demographic of people with this very regressive ban. The prayer rooms weren't harming anyone and they will continue to not harm anyone because no one is required to use them. Its a courtesy to the Muslim students. If you were to say for example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237241306.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Islam is the only religion which heavily promotes (not mandates) girls to wear a hijab

So it's religious</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238283173.0" user="ArCSelkie37" delta="False">
    <text>Most prayer rooms I know of are multi-faith anyway, anyone can use them for any religion. It’s the polar opposite of favouritism.

I’d have thought OP would love prayer rooms so that he doesn’t have to see the horrific sight of people being religious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238588933.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>Curious about your experience: I know one contention for not allowing prayer rooms was the practical ability to maintain it multi-faith/egalitarian. The example there was a dispute stemming from Muslim men not allowing women in to pray at the same time. 

It’s all pretty anecdotal, but I could see it being a bit of a challenge in which the school would have to weigh in, so I wonder what it’s been like elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
