<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="113" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43260019795.0" user="LebaneseDemonLobster" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to upvote this post, even though I disagree with it, because that is good for discussion which will stimulate people's thoughts. I hope this helps you refine or reconsider your view.

&gt;Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there

I think that is a fallacy. Hospitals are secular organisations. So what?

&gt;no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turban

We have a fair few muslims in our country. For reasons best known to muslims, many women and teenage girls would find it immodest to be coerced into not wearing a hijab. I don't know what they believe. I don't think non-muslims can really understand this. Same goes for Sikh turbans.

I don't deny that in theocracies like Afghanistan the hijab is an instrument of oppression for women. In the Netherlands, that is not the issue. Perhaps their parents make them. If so, that is bad, but that is not the school's right to mandate through this measure.

&gt;You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy

I don't want to have an "atheist theocracy" which bans the hijab. That would be *de facto* the same as enforcing the wearing of a hijab or a cross.

If I am religious, e.g. Christian, I might consider it my duty to live my faith. Of course, faith should show through outward works, but I should be allowed to wear apparel too. 

People are allowed to identify with other groups or subcultures such as punks through jewelry. 

&gt;School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there.

Nearly everywhere is a place for religion. Religion isn't a kind of mask you can where when you like. It is an identity. People do not shed it when entering "irreligious places".

&gt;nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.

Whose opinion matters? *I* believe motor cars ought to be banned, including EVs and motorcycles. You are probably a motorist. Why should my opinion matter over yours?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
