<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236551966.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, ***no jew hats.***

Nice.

You seem to be mixing up the SCHOOL with the PEOPLE in it.

&gt;. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy.

It's not religion in school. It's people in school practicing their own religion, not involving anyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236557007.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't they do that at home and at places of worship? School is not a temple.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236595650.0" user="SleepBeneathThePines" delta="False">
    <text>Because people believe in certain things and you crying about it doesn’t change that fact? 

Are you suddenly a Christian just because you step in a church? No? Religious people aren’t suddenly atheists ‘cause they step in a school. Simple as.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236783968.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why can't they do that at home and at places of worship? School is not a temple.

Why can't they pray in school? You know there's a First Amendment says they can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236788791.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes, the canadian first ammendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236847392.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>OK, You know Canada has a 2a, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237134414.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>You know Canada has the Notwithstanding Clause right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238949126.0" user="JR_Al-Ahran" delta="False">
    <text>And section 1 known as the limitation clause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237226910.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Why do they need to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237247712.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why do they need to?

Why do they need to justify it to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237264484.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Why do they need to demonstrate it?  

There’s plenty of time not in school</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237323209.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Why do they need to demonstrate it?

Why do they need to demonstrate what?

There's also plenty of time IN school.

You're not coming up with any answer as to why it should be ok to violate student's rights besides 'there's time not in school' which is not a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237354909.0" user="astro-gazing" delta="False">
    <text>Not op, but school time is for learning, just that. I'm not in favor of banning necklaces, hijabs and other things like that though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237617072.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Not op, but school time is for learning, just that

So no eating, no recess, no physical education, no art, no music, no clubs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237908066.0" user="astro-gazing" delta="False">
    <text>There's obviously gonna be *some* exceptions like eating, going to the bathroom, changing your diabetic sensor and other really important things. 

Recess is just a short break, if they want to pray during that time then sure. PE is good for the body, but I do think it should be optional. Clubs can teach kids some skills</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240297970.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>So someone’s most fundamental beliefs about the world and afterlife are irrelevant afterthoughts?  Lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241670256.0" user="astro-gazing" delta="False">
    <text>I personally believe they are, but that's not the reason I don't want religion in schools</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254930648.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>Several religions have specific times you are recommended to pray. By not allowing them to, you are essentially denying their ability to practice their religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256403877.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>I think I’m ok with those religions prescribing actually</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256593124.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>Alr u cool</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238946856.0" user="JR_Al-Ahran" delta="False">
    <text>What does Manitoba have to do with this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239081685.0" user="JR_Al-Ahran" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody said it is. Section 2(a) protects this under freedom of religion. Multiple SCC cases reinforced this. Freedom of religion is defined as 

“the right to entertain such religious beliefs as a person chooses, the right to declare religious beliefs openly and without fear of hindrance or reprisal, and the right to manifest religious belief by worship and practise or by teaching and dissemination”

Nowhere does it allow the state to discriminate against these people. Should we ban the pride flag? “This is a school not a gay bar”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239310345.0" user="PavWrestlinGifs" delta="False">
    <text>How is someone wearing a turban / yamaka effecting anything at school, wtf is wrong with u. It’s no different than a haircut</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
