<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236812542.0" user="CathanCrowell" delta="False">
    <text>Religion is not hobby. It's cultural, family and personal heritage for many people. It's fulfil spiritual needs what are same like our needs for entertainment or friendship.

Public Schools are supposed to fulfil this needs same like education, because it's big part of young person's life. Schools usually are trying to support social or fun events. If young people fulfill their basic needs, they are better students and better people.

Another reason is learning about diversity. Fact is that world is colorful and we all are different. If we seperate everything what make us special from public schools, what we will do after school? Why we should limited what is part of us? Why should everybody be same? This is not real, it's fake, and learning something what is not truth. 

Public Schools should not promote any religion, but it should be safe place for everybody without unnecessary restrictions what make them uncomfortable in place where they are 50% of their time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
