<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="78" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43240129277.0" user="bbrit89" delta="False">
    <text>I was raised an atheist. As an Atheist, I do not believe in a god nor practise a religion. I believe that forcing your views and customs on others is intolerable. 

But it goes both ways.

Forcing a child to remove their hijab or yamaka (that little hat thing you failed to google the name of) is just as bad as forcing a child to pray. 

True atheists practise something called "mind yo-business". If it does not affect you... Mind yo-business. How does a child wearing a hat or a cross negatively impact anyone? 

This decision is in line with the same bigotry and hate as any of the organized religions. "Those like me are bad and wrong and they must conform or change to be just like me". 

Frankly, atheists with an option such as yours I do not feel truly have a good grasp on the concept and are using just a different vehicle for their hate they would have otherwise used religion for. 

Hope you can let go of whatever hate is driving this opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
