<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237567876.0" user="KuttayKaBaccha" delta="False">
    <text>So you want authoritarianism. At one side, you people harp on about human rights and freedom to do XYZ but the second it’s something you disagree with you want a complete ban in schools which you know are required to have any chance of a career and where the majority of kids will learn, but since you don’t approve of their parenting it’s now on you to teach them into your neat cookie cutter minions.

Religious teaching has no place in public schools nor does teaching any ideology really. “Be nice to everyone and learn these things so you can have a successful career going forwards” is all a school is and should be. 

You think you’re better than everyone else but that’s precisely what every facist and dictator thinks as well. You think all the people in history that imposed their will on others thought they were bad people? Or they believed that what they believe in could be wrong?  No, just like you they believed what they know is objectively superior and what others knew was objectively inferior. And that’s fine on it’s own until you brute force it on to other people.

99.99% of religious people I’ve met are wonderful, non violent, friendly and humble people. Very sociable as well because they often find value in things besides money and showing off which I can’t say is as prevalent in less religious people. And this is regardless of religion, Sikh, Hindu, Christian, Jew, Muslim I’ve sat down and talked with them all and most are easily the most welcoming and affable people ever. And most of the religious people you’ll meet will not ever bother you or anyone else either. Just like most trans or LGBT people will not whip out their dicks and start waving it in people’s faces. These scare tactics are old as day and create more of exactly what they fear than there is in the first place.

You, me, nobody at all can actually objectively prove any ideology as inferior because the content is subjective in nature. People points to the success of the West while conveniently ignoring the fact that it was discipline, foresight and a whole lot of betraying and backstabbing every other country to steal that wealth that allowed it to be in this position in the first place. 

You’re free to talk about corporate behavior, governmental policies or certain political tactics as superior or inferior but bringing in ideology of any type other than corporate or economic ideology is a moot point because we all know the West didn’t rise to power by being morally superior, and it’s not staying in power by doing so either. If you do want to attribute the success to an ideology you’d have to choose Christianity since that was the dominating ideology when the West became what it is. 

It’s like a poker player stealing all the chips from all the other players then saying “the way I play is superior because you are poor and I am rich,” . Sure , it’s within your right because might as right, but all you people pretending it’s anything other than that is hogwash. If some country came in and took all of Americas money, military power and top minds and left only the dregs of society with a few installed leaders that only line their own pockets and don’t care at all about the success of their country, would you be willing to accept them as superior based on their ideology? 

I agree, religion should be private and the prayer room can be private, but pretending to go for an all out ban and controlling what people wear and then daring to ever pretend you have any kind of moral high ground again is peak Hypocrisy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237594891.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;you people

"they" "them" "the enemy" 

&gt;99.99% of religious people I’ve met are wonderful, non violent, friendly and humble people.

Thanks to secular, universal, public institution and tjought keeping their biases in check.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
