<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237333011.0" user="SomeRandomme" delta="False">
    <text>Secularism in this case is a red-herring. Secularism is not the reason for this law.

It's true that Quebec has a rough history with religion. The catholic church had a lot of power in Quebec historically; in the Mid-20th century, Quebec had the quiet revolution and the government distanced itself from the church by-and-large.

However, religious symbols were not a problem until recently. Hospital rooms, courts, even the government assembly featured crosses.

Religious symbols were never an issue until minorities started showing up. Especially minorities who tend to speak English.

As soon as we start seeing larger and larger numbers of immigrants from countries like India, Egypt, Pakistan, etc. who speak English, suddenly religious symbols are huge problem and need to be banned from public life. 

Francois Legault, the current premier of Quebec, is a separatist. The Quebec separatist movement is an ethno-nationalist movement. At the end of the last vote for separation which failed, the separatists publicly blamed it on "money and ethnic votes" which is a direct quote. Legault is the same guy who, in response to a video of Quebecois nurses ridiculing a native woman *as she died in the hospital*, said Quebec has no issues with systemic racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239441262.0" user="ge93" delta="False">
    <text>100%, laicite has to be analyzed in it’s unfortunately xenophobic context. 

Nothing to do with anyone’s personal antipathy on religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239528009.0" user="RaffiTorres2515" delta="False">
    <text>François Legault was a sovereignist but he is no longer one. The CAQ is not even for independence.

Quebec independence movement is way more complex than just ethno nationalist movement. Many immigrants group were pro independence, like the Haitian community for example. The money part of the Parizeau quote was about Jews, it was about the no side who cheated using illegal funds. It's a facts, I don't even understand why you want to twist it that way. Your comment is pure misinformation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239926268.0" user="ge93" delta="False">
    <text>The OP’s comment is a bit generalized and simplified, and yes Legault is not a sovereigntist. However, the roots of “religious symbols must be banned” arose from the so-called crisis of reasonable accommodations from 15 years ago, a quite frankly, Fox News-tier hate campaign against ethnic minorities as detailed in this doc:

https://www.lapresse.ca/debats/opinions/2022-06-02/nationalisme-quebecois/retour-sur-la-bataille-pour-l-ame-du-quebec.php</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243301198.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>No, the roots of it are the quiet revolution in the 60s. Both my parents were educated by catholic nuns/priests that were wearing full-on religious garbs: they lived through that transition where the Catholic Church was removed from educational institutions, and it was considered a good thing. 

You are telling people with that lived experience that the separation of church and state only started happening 20 years ago…. That’s what is making people from that older generation react. You are deliberately erasing their lived experience and collective achievements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243348198.0" user="ge93" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone is well aware of the Quiet Revolution. No one is advocating to make imans and rabbis as teachers or to re-establish the pre-Quiet Revolution Quebec theocracy. We are talking about personal decision taken by individuals which do not have an affect on third parties. The rest of Canada is secular with normal secularism 

One of the ironies of Quebec’s “laïcité a 2 vitesses” is that it essentially privileges Catholicism by “neutrally” targeting religious practices that are non-Christian. Nobody cared about the cross in the legislature or on Mt. Royal until brown people started wearing their own personal religious symbols and there was a freak-out (and Dumont nearly beat the PQ on this issue, resulting in the “Chartes Des Valeurs” etc.). Who cares if someone is wearing a religious symbol? There is the same obligation of neutrality and impartiality from judges, prosecutors, teachers in RoC.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
