<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="95" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43242528060.0" user="LowKeyBrit36" delta="False">
    <text>I think that while Quebec was right to close down prayer rooms, that having no religious effects is a bit too far. In the US, in the first amendment, we have protections for the freedom of religion. While this doesn’t mean a school should be forced to choose a religion to affiliate their school with, and instead schools themselves should be secular, people in school shouldn’t have their ideologies suppressed to fit a secular way of viewing things. Additionally, if children in schools were forced to be secular, then they would (most likely) have more issues with xenophobia or religion bashing (whatever it’s called there’s a term I’m forgetting) due to never having experienced religion or religious differences inside of school. Maybe the culture towards and around religion is different (such as you cannot have public effects like a cross, Star of David, hijab, etc) but as far as I know, religion is still open to be expressed in Quebec, so if that is the case, then it would definitely cause issue to never being exposed to it at a young age. I guess my point is that while it is good to maintain secularism of the school, the children of a school should still be able to keep personal religious affects and to be allowed to experience other children who are different than them practicing their own culture/religion. Additionally, I would also say (on a side note) that it would also be good for schools to teach about different world religious, but exclusively on an educational level to inform children of other religions and their beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
