<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="101" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43243629798.0" user="SeductivePterodactyl" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that there should be no established religion in schools.

But I suppose I more specifically disagree that you can't make reasonable accommodations for somebody's faith.

Particularly when certain things are basic requirements of the faith.  Example:  Having a room designated where Muslim students can go for their noon prayers isn't a problem to me (which I believe is the central thing OP is talking about).  They have to do this as a basic tenet of their faith, and its not unreasonable to ask for a quiet place to do so.

In the same way, Sikhs are required to have the five Ks, which effectively means the turban (uncut hair), an iron bracelet, a small blade, a comb, and specific undergarments.  I don't see any reason that schools cannot make accommodations for a Sikh student. (the one sticking point I would see is the blade, and I believe that their religious leaders have been reasonable about that, and that its not a requirement to have a sharp one, its symbolic in the modern day).

Hijabs, I'm a little more leery on, because its not a central dictate of faith, the requirement varies by sect, and its honestly more of a later cultural practice (and more Persian/Iranian than it is originally Arab).  I personally wouldn't choose that on my hill to die on, just because its not worth the storm and stress.

Same with yarmulke on Fridays for Jews (it is Friday, right?  Please correct me if I'm in error on this or anything).

I personally have no issue making reasonable accommodations for faith.  I would be up in arms if there was an established (officially or unofficially) faith in a school, that's what would get me fired up (because I effectively had that growing up, small rural town dominated by one particular Christian denomination).

For the record, I'm an atheist who wanders around between "quietly anti-theist" and "militant anti-theist".  I think that we would be better off getting rid of all of it, but in this modern world, I think making reasonable accommodations is the best way forward. (And I would be as opposed to the government pushing my atheism as much as I would be opposed to any particular religion being pushed.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
