<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="96" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43242587006.0" user="jnix01" delta="False">
    <text>Since YOUR opinion grossly violates the 1st Amendment of the Constitution, it is YOUR opinion that simply doesn't matter.

The 1st Amendment guarantees freedom OF religion, not freedom FROM religion. It forbids government from promoting one religion over another, BUT... most importantly, it forbids government from restricting the religious practice and/or expression of individuals.

It's that second part that the bible banners always seem to conveniently forget...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243628072.0" user="No1eFan" delta="False">
    <text>Quebec is in Canada. 

Do they have a similar constitution to the US? If not then your comment is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245539664.0" user="jnix01" delta="False">
    <text>Uh... why yes... yes they DO.

The Bill of Rights in the Canadian Constitution is very similar to the US Constitution with regards to freedom of religion, including the freedom of thought, belief, opinion, AND expression.

Of course Canada has already progressed far enough along that Castro Junior and his Marxist cohorts don't believe that they need to uphold the Canadian Constitution, and are acting accordingly. It is up to the people of Canada to take back their freedoms... if they want to. Or they can go the route of so many other countries, and submit to the slavery that is Socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245930906.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>You sound stupid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246177875.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/BeastPunk1 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20BeastPunk1&amp;message=BeastPunk1%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/-/jv7idui/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246788910.0" user="jnix01" delta="False">
    <text>Yes... Canada's Constitution is very similar to the US Constitution with regards to freedom of religion. If the current government in Canada is trying to restrict  religious expression, they are violating their Constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
