<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236611800.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that

why does your opinion matter more than theirs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237166673.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>In this case, because he’s right.

I am religious and can say religion has no place in school</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237462285.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>But a room for prayer is not religion having a place in school any more then any voluntary clubs like idk a Nintendo fan club are the school accommodating students for something they want</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238040953.0" user="mitchyboy" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn’t the prayer room would be a dedicated room though? And it would be a big issue if, for example, a student LGBT group asked if they could use the room for  their meetings in there. Whereas the Nintendo club would probably meet in a random class room and could easily share with other groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238316450.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>Idk I'm not familiar enough with Islam to know the specifics but I think it's just a room with prayer mats well nothing else disruptive or distracting in the room is going on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240590130.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>It was always just a random classroom for us (I'm Canadian.) A teacher who was marking during the lunch break/recess or otherwise not on patrol outside would just leave their classorom door open, any Muslim students that wanted to pray would bring in their prayer mats, pray, put them away and then go outside to play with everyone else. Sometimes it was a Muslim teacher, sometimes it was just whoever was free that recess. 

I literally have never heard of a school with a room dedicated to only religious observance. None of our school buildings have that kind of spare space!! The Muslim students kept their prayer mats and whatnot in their lockers, there was exactly zero disruption or additional expense to anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237678519.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>I am not religious and I believe people should be free to practice their religion freely wherever they wish, so long as it doesn't encroach on others. The idea that allowing people the option to pray at school or wear religious symbols in any way affects those not practicing the religion is absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238975562.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I am not religious and I believe people should be free to practice their religion freely wherever they wish, so long as it doesn't encroach on others.

Cool, except the very act of practicing religions like Christianity or Islam already encroaches on others when it's being practiced around impressionable youths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239191206.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>If you find me someone who converted to Islam after being around a woman in a hijab please let me know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239341296.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you find me someone who converted to Islam after being around a woman in a hijab please let me know.

There are millions of children who are forced into that hijab and "converted" into that religion after 18 years of being able to force it on their daughters unchecked.

Those children deserve to spend every day at school free of the influence of bullshit religions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239422717.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>What your advocating for would do nothing except harm the kids raised within their religion, and probably make the parents more likely to homeschool them and indoctrinate them further. This is not a solution, this is spite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239435887.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What your advocating for would do nothing except harm the kids raised within their religion

In what way is barring all schools from allowing religious implementations and forcing all children to attend school (homeschooling is a fucking abomination that should be abolished too) going to somehow harm the kids who are victims of religion?  How does giving them a time when they are free from the influence of religion and taught the fallacies and bullshit within each of those religions somehow indoctrinate them further?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239468382.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In what way is barring all schools from allowing religious implementations and forcing all children to attend school (homeschooling is a fucking abomination that should be abolished too) going to somehow harm the kids who are victims of religion?

Freedom good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239677389.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Freedom good.

Not super interested in the freedom to abuse children as it turns out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239798115.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>We're talking about whether children should be allowed to pray in school. You seem to have lost the plot a bit here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239818127.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We're talking about whether children should be allowed to pray in school. You seem to have lost the plot a bit here.

I know exactly what we are talking about. Indoctrinating children by brainwashing them with religion is child abuse.

The state should not condone or support that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239844667.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>This is called a motte and bailey, and I'm not falling for it. This argument is not about "brainwashing" children, it is about whether children who are already "brainwashed" should be persecuted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240068476.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; it is about whether children who are already "brainwashed" should be persecuted.

What you call persecuted, I call being given the freedom to exist free of that religion they were indoctrinated into.  If only for the school day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240112377.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom is being barred from what you would otherwise do? What a stupid thing to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240132791.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Freedom is being barred from what you would otherwise do?

Freedom is being allowed to exist as a child without being forced to wear or demonstrate a bullshit faith shoved upon you before you had critical thinking skills.

Freedom is being given the knowledge and the truth that religion is made up bullshit so they can decide for themselves what they want to believe as adults.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240146330.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>"Freedom is when people agree with me 😤😤😤😤😤😤"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240376235.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom is when children aren't subjected to indoctrination that poisons the logic and reason of our species.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240248465.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>This is better. Then they will be able to put the blame on where it lies...the parents. The parents are the ones who are putting their "religion" before their child. We have a huge portion who already homeschools so I don't think it would really make a difference. Besides if we want to EVER do anything about our absolute dismal public school education we will have to cut off all private and charter schools from public school funds...which will lead to many parents homeschooling anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240307917.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>Forced secularization of public institutions worked very well in Turkey and definitely didn't lead to a resurgence of embittered fundamentalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242730385.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>That's Turkey...this is a whole different ballpark. Religion is something that only of age people should consent to. 
Especially those high demand conservative religions... they really don't do as much good as they do bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245341074.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>If your just gonna handwave any contradictory information there's no point in arguing with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246053794.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>That's Turkey they don't have bat shit crazy religious fanatics threatening the other people they HAVE to share with. Does Turkey have an issue with public schools being robbed of their funds for non public schools? 

also google begs to differ... they don't have 100% complete secular schools.

 "While the state is officially secular, all primary and secondary schools have been required to teach religious studies since 1982, and the curriculum focuses mainly on Sunni Islam. The extent to which other religions are covered depends on the school."

https://www.google.com/search?q=Does+turkey+have+secular+schools&amp;rlz=1C1GCEA\_enUS1009US1009&amp;sxsrf=AB5stBjK1C-qYSaoBfXZeiuBW-ISfrrf9Q%3A1691441262567&amp;ei=bljRZMONIu-8kPIP2dy\_gAQ&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD\_PPctcuAAxVvHkQIHVnuD0AQ4dUDCBA&amp;uact=5&amp;oq=Does+turkey+have+secular+schools&amp;gs\_lp=Egxnd3Mtd2l6LXNlcnAiIERvZXMgdHVya2V5IGhhdmUgc2VjdWxhciBzY2hvb2xzMgUQABiiBDIFEAAYogQyBRAAGKIEMgUQABiiBDIFEAAYogRIoCVQAFiJJHAAeAGQAQCYAXqgAfsNqgEENy4xMbgBA8gBAPgBAcICBxAAGA0YgATCAgQQIxgnwgIFEAAYgATCAgYQABgWGB7CAggQABiKBRiGA8ICBRAhGKABwgIFECEYqwLCAggQIRgWGB4YHeIDBBgAIEGIBgE&amp;sclient=gws-wiz-serp</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246808420.0" user="skdeelk" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"While the state is officially secular, all primary and secondary schools have been required to teach religious studies since 1982, and the curriculum focuses mainly on Sunni Islam. The extent to which other religions are covered depends on the school."

This is the backlash I'm talking about :/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237250544.0" user="Jackolantern668" delta="False">
    <text>OP is just arrogant. If he thinks that no one whose opinion matters is upset about what Quebec is doing, why bother with this CMV?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238881065.0" user="shedont" delta="False">
    <text>I might be wrong but it might be just poor choice of word     for what OP think is people whose opinion he would value or consider.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258790469.0" user="LebaneseDemonLobster" delta="False">
    <text>I think he's referring to fundo nutjobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241198251.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP's position *can* be changed, but I don't think the approach of this particular comment thread will be able to help OP change their view.

This subreddit is about changing views, not about playing therapist and helping the OPs work through their glaring character flaws.

In my experience, the comment above yours

&gt;why does your opinion matter more than theirs?

will not lead to meaningful reflection on OP's part.

OP's *actual view* must be challenged.  I appreciate the approach of inviting reflection, but it's clear from OP's rhetoric that reflection simply isn't going to be prompted by a top-level comment without genuine substance addressing the view itself.

IDK why I took the time to write this, but I hope it was informative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237427629.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>Cause they're religious, and none should take religious extremists seriously</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237953727.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Like usual its an excuse to PC coat racism. Religion shouldnt be taught in school but banning hijabs is just insane. Not everyone who wears a hijab is muslim lol.  Some people just have fair skin and dont want to get sunburned. Its one of the most common pieces of clothing across the globe.

It really reminds me of the old reform schools where they would "acclimate" native Americans with US culture. Basically forcefully stripping away their culture and religion while trying to mold them into your preferred status quo. Hijabs, skull caps, cross necklaces and so on dont effect education. If a hijab is distracting you from learning long division youre just a moron.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238507949.0" user="Hour_Addendum_9691" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t know the USA also did reform schools I thought that was just a Canada thing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238701588.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>No it was mostly a US thing, but through a lot of those years saying American could mean Mexican, Canadian, or the US. You can read up on it here though.

The US is propagandized like any nation and I think the whole recent revelations in Canada were basically a big PR opportunity to shift the blame. Rough estimates for the native American genocide in the US are around 100 million. Id also look into Andrew Jackson and the Indian Removal Act. For some reason we still have a genocidal maniac on our $20 bill...because he ended duh fed! We worship money, its sad.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American\_Indian\_boarding\_schools#:\~:text=American%20Indian%20boarding%20schools%2C%20also,youth%20into%20European%20American%20culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238768694.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>It's capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239331734.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Whats capitalism? Im pretty sure the concept of violently creating ethno-states predates capitalism by at least 4000 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239346705.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine carrying on about the past in a Reddit board like it's relevant today</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240034111.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Lol yeah. When you were educated did you get raped then burried in a mass grave? Also thinking history is irrelevant to modern times is the most reddit thing imaginable. In reality reddits just a reflection of status quo so yeah.

I never get viewpoints like yours. Its almost like you see life as a video game and the backstory was just made up before you spawned in. Especially when policy written in this era still exists, as well as post slavery, white flight, segregation and so on. What do you think formed overal social policy? Fairies and magic lol? Or could it have been history?  Fucking hilarious considering most governmental buildings are modeled after classic architecture.

Literally denying pretty much all of history like viewpoints dont evolve and morph to fit modern PC definitions and expectations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240696627.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>OMG are you still going on?  Honestly I'm so sick of hearing about historical injustice like anyone can do anything to change the past.  Get over it.  Lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240807467.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>This has to be a troll post, you seem too dumb to live</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240916953.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing gets by you does it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247662080.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>It's spelled bayou, dummy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247666730.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>Okay screw you but also lol.  But also go to hell.  But also good one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247862020.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>:)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252704140.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>You are a genuine lowlife</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253060939.0" user="AdamicAtom" delta="False">
    <text>https://youtu.be/4lxINyZxbgU</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241104435.0" user="HippyKiller925" delta="False">
    <text>They did. Look into the Indian Child Welfare Act. After the US was finishing up with the orphan trains they switched to Indian children</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238570652.0" user="foladodo" delta="False">
    <text>op movin mad</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238719517.0" user="Yushaalmuhajir" delta="False">
    <text>This is exactly what it is.  I used to think like OP (well, I was probably worse, but I wasn’t afraid to admit it).  He’s trying to make this a “religion doesn’t belong in school” but I doubt he’d give a rat’s ass if a kid wore a cross necklace to school.  Him mentioning hijab multiple times tells me what I already know.  Every right wing idiot out there thinks they can make their hatred of Muslims PC as long as they make the “muh secularism” argument knowing full well that hijab is a requirement in Islam that he just doesn’t want Muslims in his country.

His country came and destroyed ours’ and now that they’re unlivable they don’t let us in as refugees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238746349.0" user="Midnightoclock" delta="False">
    <text>OP specifically mentions cross necklaces in their post. Cross necklaces are also not allowed to be worn with this law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238841823.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Such obvious propaganda...yeah these people are victims of a brutal and terrible regime...but we cant let them in as refugees. Doesn't add up. Refugees fleeing Cuba are all fine and dandy cause communism bad but if its right wing religious authoritarianism refugees are off the table.

They did the same thing in South America. Also sent Jewish refugees back to Europe durring WW2. IBM literally designed census machines to sort the Jewish population form the rest. Funny too Fords such a big company still when Henry Ford was literally a nazi.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239072130.0" user="AmongTheElect" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Every right wing idiot out there thinks they can make their hatred of Muslims PC as long as they make the “muh secularism” argument

Oh stop trying to make this some right-wing thing. I'm as right wing as they come and support kids being able to wear a hijab wherever they want including public school. I help moderate a Conservative sub and when Ilhan Omar wanted to wear her hijab in the House despite existing rules against it, the sub supported her on that, too.

Not to mention OP being atheist/"gender is a social construct"/anti-gun/pro-abortion doesn't exactly scream "right wing" to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239429859.0" user="Yushaalmuhajir" delta="False">
    <text>I also lean right (absolutely despise Ilhan Omar, I don’t consider her a Muslim because she’s said things that contradict Islam completely, she just wears a scarf on her head for some oppression olympics brownie points).  I have no issues with conservatives and in fact you and I would probably agree on a good bit but the white nationalist crowd (which I know are different than conservatives, I’m the kind of guy who would never live in a blue state) pulls this as well as the liberal types who hate Muslims too but feel the need to “white man’s burden” us with bombs and occupations.  Tbh liberals are probably worse because they pretend to be our friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241724653.0" user="NoVaFlipFlops" delta="False">
    <text>Your vacuum is working incredibly well for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239241311.0" user="FloraFauna2263" delta="False">
    <text>The idea of religion not belonging in school should only exist to make religious minorities feel welcome, same reason youre supposed to say "happy holidays" instead of "merry christmas." 

OP is not pro-secularism, OP is pro-enforced atheism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243127672.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>So, if the school had only majority religion believers and atheist's, it would be ok to push the religion as there would be no religious minorities present?

What's wrong with merry Christmas? I'm an atheist and to me Christmas is a very important celebration related to the culture I live in but has zero religious meaning to me. Happy holidays sounds silly as "holi" in holidays refers to holy which is exactly the thing that the cultural Christmas doesn't have.

I wouldn't want to enforce atheism to anyone, which is why I wouldn't support OP's view but I don't see why we should call Christmas something else than Christmas just because it has a word Christ in it. English (and many other European) language contains tons of expressions that are taken from Christianity as it was the dominant religion for hundreds of years. Why should try to wipe these things out of the language just because it's no longer that dominant? If these expressions naturally stop being used then they don't need to be carried either. We could call Christmas saturnalia but that would also refer to a God or Yule (which it's called in Swedish and Finnish for instance) but why would that make things any better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243655045.0" user="FloraFauna2263" delta="False">
    <text>It's because there are multiple holidays other than Christmas, and assuming others celebrate Christmas rather than Hannukkah or Diwali, etc, is kind of a dick move. We don't have to get rid of "merry Christmas," it's perfectly fine to say that to someone you know does celebrate Christmas.

I'd imagine you would be a little annoyed if everyone ever kept saying "happy Hanukkah" to you during the winter holidays season.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243858281.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's because there are multiple holidays other than Christmas, and assuming others celebrate Christmas rather than Hannukkah or Diwali, etc, is kind of a dick move. 

Diwali is in November. It would be real dick move to say happy holidays (and refer to Diwali with that) in December. 

What if you happen to be in the United States and say happy Thanksgiving in November and the person you're talking to happens to be a foreigner and doesn't celebrate that. Is that a dick move? If it is, what should people say? 

&gt;I'd imagine you would be a little annoyed if everyone ever kept saying "happy Hanukkah" to you during the winter holidays season.

Why would I be annoyed? If the person is a Jew that kind a wish wouldn't annoy me at all. Same thing if someone says "Xi nian hao" in February and I'm not Chinese. 

Have an open mind ffs and don't get annoyed so easily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243944279.0" user="FloraFauna2263" delta="False">
    <text>Diwali is in different times of the year each year due to differences between calendars.

The difference with thanksgiving is that there is no equivalent in other religions, and also the fact that Thanksgiving is not a religious holiday. (Also there are some groups of Native Americans who are not particularly happy with Thanksgiving celebrations).

The reason I assumed you would be annoyed is because many who dislike the cultural shift towards saying "happy holidays" also generally dislike religious minorities.

I probably shouldn't have used that analogy of being told "happy Hanukkah," as it's different when you are a religious minority that often faces discrimination. Which Christians are not, and neither are atheists such as yourself.

I do think it's kinda funny you think I should have an open mind, when you are the one refusing to change just one phrase in order to make religious minorities feel welcome. Especially after having the reason for it explained to you. This is a dictionary example of being closed-minded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244091661.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I probably shouldn't have used that analogy of being told "happy Hanukkah," as it's different when you are a religious minority that often faces discrimination. Which Christians are not, and neither are atheists such as yourself.

Ok, maybe we understand different things with discrimination. I don't think it's discrimination that in a country that has long cultural tradition to celebrate winter solstice and call it "Christmas" that this word is used for everyone. 

&gt;I do think it's kinda funny you think I should have an open mind, when you are the one refusing to change just one phrase in order to make religious minorities feel welcome.

What do you mean "welcome"? I'm not a Christian but I have lived in several countries that have had Christian past, which has then affected their language. I'm not keen trying to consciously change the language just so that some minority don't get upset. As I've said, I've lived in several countries. I've always felt that it's my job to assimilate to the culture in those countries instead of demanding people there to change their language to fit mine. So, when I lived in the US, I didn't get upset when people said Happy Thanksgiving in November and Happy 4th of July in July even though I was a foreigner and those celebrations didn't really mean much to me. 

But I don't get upset if someone who is in a minority religion wishes me Happy Diwali, Happy Hanukkah, Happy Ramadan, whatever. I don't want them to force them to lose their identity to some bland "happy holidays". 

Are you really that closed-minded that if a Hindu wishes you Happy Diwali, you get upset and demand that he has to say "happy holidays"? If not, then why would you be annoyed if someone says "merry Christmas"? 

Maybe try to live in another country and you'll broaden your mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244444460.0" user="FloraFauna2263" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between a Hindu wishing me, a member of the religious majority, a happy Diwali, and a Christian wishing, for example a Jew, a merry Christmas, is that I am not discriminated against, so being wished a happy Diwali does not cause me feelings of unwelcomeness.

Its still kind of odd that you're assuming that you have the moral high ground, when you are doing the following:

A: using your experiences as an atheist as evidence against a certain way to treat religious minorities ("I'm not a Christian but...")
B: openly saying that it is reasonable to expect foreigners to assimilate when living in a different country ("I've always felt that it's my job to assimilate..." fucking yikes)
And C: saying that you are unwilling to use a different phrase to be respectful towards vulnerable religious groups ("...just so that some minority don't get upset.")

As an atheist, you don't get to decide the wishes of religious minorities. Jews, Muslims, Sikhs, etc are groups that wish to have more cultural acceptance, and part of that is changing the way we speak to people. Saying that it isn't right to start saying happy holidays, and that we should be saying merry Christmas instead is very Christian normative and goes directly against the wishes of members of religious minorities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243659136.0" user="StaticEchoes" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're looking at it the wrong way. No one is saying "Call Christmas something else." Its more like "There are other holidays people celebrate during winter. Some people feel less welcome when you assume they celebrate Christmas."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243799742.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Well, depends on the country. For instance, in China people don't really celebrate any particular thing in the winter (until the Chinese new year in February). 

But that attitude sounds silly anyway. Let's say that you're in the United States and it's early July. Should you avoid saying "Happy independence day" in case the person happens to be a foreigner and doesn't celebrate the US independence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244574674.0" user="StaticEchoes" delta="False">
    <text>Do you distinguish between a holiday that directly relates to the country itself (Independence Day) vs one that directly relates to a religion (Christmas)? Culturally promoting July 4th is promoting America (in America). Promoting Christmas is promoting Christianity. I recognize that a ton of people celebrate Christmas non-religiously, but I don't know if that changes anything for the people who celebrate another holiday. Ultimately, its a pretty minor problem, but it does reinforce the idea that America is a Christian nation.

Your example would only be comparable if there was a holiday that was directly competing with July 4th, and that holiday was culturally significant to a big enough segment of the population.

At the end of the day, people are probably not going to be mad if you wish them a Merry Christmas, but whats the problem with trying to be more inclusive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250094508.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with you. Promoting Easter would be promoting Christianity (and interestingly Easter is much less celebrated in the more Christian USA than more atheist Europe). However, Christmas is more of a cultural thing. Christianity plays nowadays a small role in it compared to non-religious traditions. It is also a universal celebration of the winter solstice, which is why in some Christian countries (I mention already Sweden and Finland) it's still called by its pagan name.

Is it just the name of the festival that annoys you? If also in English it would be called Yule would it change your mind about it being a Christian festival if people celebrated it exactly the same way as they do now (some Christians go to church for instance)? If not, then what? You acknowledged yourself that most of the celebration has nothing to do with the religion.

I'm not sure what competing festival you're talking about. Christmas must be by far the dominant midwinter festival in all majority Christian countries. As I mentioned Diwali is in November, Ramadan timing varies, Chinese new year is in Jan/Feb. 

Regarding being inclusive, then you shouldn't wish people happy Thanksgiving either as in the US that might annoy native Americans or the 4th of July as it would annoy British.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241122783.0" user="HippyKiller925" delta="False">
    <text>You may want to be more careful about equating this to a left/right distinction. In the US there are a lot more Muslims and Christians who disagree with OP than you'd think, with a lot of US Christians teaming up with Muslims on trans issues in schools. It's a bit of "the enemy of my enemy is my friend" with both Muslims and Christians seeing progressives as their common enemy because they see progressives as promoting what OP is promoting</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242620516.0" user="jnix01" delta="False">
    <text>"right wing"??? Really??? You actually think that the OP is "right wing"?

How could you be that ignorant? It is the LEFT wing that is overwhelmingly atheist, and  has been trying to destroy freedom of religion in this country for over 100 years. The "Right wing" supports the Constitution, which guarantees freedom of religion and expression. Not for only one specific religion, but for all religions... yes... even including Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243154096.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Which country you're talking about now? The only country OP refers to is Canada as he mentions Quebec.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245492633.0" user="jnix01" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure that the OP was comparing the US to Canada, touting the fact that Canada is suppressing freedom of religion in their country and implying that it should be the case in the US.

 If that is not the case, well then I don't care much what Castro Junior does in Canada... it's up to them to get their freedoms back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243924028.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/Yushaalmuhajir – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Yushaalmuhajir&amp;message=Yushaalmuhajir%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/-/jv37ti5/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238962788.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Not everyone who wears a hijab is muslim lol. Some people just have fair skin and dont want to get sunburned.

No student is barred from wearing them after they leave school and no student is getting sunburned in class in France. 

&gt;Like usual its an excuse to PC coat racism

Nothing about this religious discussion has to do with racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239019198.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;No student is barred from wearing them after they leave school and no student is getting sunburned in class in France.

They dont have windows in France? Do they not let the kids outside lol? Id love to see your complexion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239080908.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They dont have windows in France? Do they not let the kids outside lol?

Most schools in most civilized nations have regulations about the UV coating required on windows just for this reason.  So that the handful of children who sit next to the window all day every day don't have to apply sunscreen on one half of their face and one arm every day just to sit in class without sustaining serious skin damage or getting cancer.

Additionally, plenty of non-disruptive and non-religious ways are present for children to avoid sun damage if that truly is their concern.

&gt;And even if French kids were locked in dark prisons why enforce an arbitrary rule? It doesnt make any sense. Maybe you could explain why they cant wear them opposed to the rule existing?

First off, all head coverings in class are detrimental and distracting.  They make it harder for a teacher to monitor the kids for cheating, harder for children behind others to see the board properly, and full body coverings make it much harder for teachers to identify things like bruises from abuse and lice.

Second, it's a religious garment and religion being taught to children is child abuse.  Giving them a place that they can escape the fucked up brainwashing influence of religion at home and enforce logic and reason over fairy tale bullshit is important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249827351.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Second, it's a religious garment and religion being taught to children is child abuse. Giving them a place that they can escape the fucked up brainwashing influence of religion at home and enforce logic and reason over fairy tale bullshit is important.

Define teaching religion, does it have to be direct or (pardon my exaggeration for effect) should a kid be taken away by CPS because their parents let them watch Good Omens instead of some dry left-brain scientific lecture</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241233419.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand how this could be considered racist.

From what I was able to find, about 60% of Muslims are white, 20% are black, and 20% are Asian. 

Which race are they being racist against, exactly?

If you think they have a bias against Muslims, that has it's own term Islamophobia. 

Even then, it can only be considered Islamaphobic when ignoring the rest of OP's post:

&gt;No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no caps that jewish people wear

Islam and Christianity are extremely diverse religions with adherents from all races, and both religions share a message of complete racial inclusivity.

Sikhs are overwhelmingly (&gt;95%) Asian and white, so I suppose one could make an argument for Sikhophobia being racially motivated.

Jewish people are overhwhelmingly white, but do have a substantial black minority. 

Essentially, I fail to see racism in OP's post.  Islamophobia is a more accurate term IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246282662.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I don't understand how this could be considered racist.

Ah young I see. Basically West Asians though. If you lived through the 9/11 era you know. Its hard to pin an exact race as islamophobias generally dont know the difference. For instance after 9/11 all the Indian kids at my school were getting harassed and called terrorists. Basically brown person from west Asia is what theyre being racist against but being racists theyre too dumb to know the difference.

I also dont know where youre getting these statistics? Most muslims live in 4 countries none of which have a white majority? Not only can I not find what youre referencing but everything I can find completely negates what you are saying. Id say the main racial hatred is directed at Persians and Arabs but also Indians because racists are dumb.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islam\_by\_country</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246784725.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most muslims live in 4 countries none of which have a white majority?  
&gt;  
&gt; Id say the main racial hatred is directed at Persians and Arabs

Persians and Arabs are white.

I suppose you could argue that they're Asian, but then we're being really fast and loose with "Asian" and would have to include white Russians other peoples of Caucasia as being Asian as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246861996.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most Persians and Arabs are white.

What? White describes light skinned Europeans? Specially western and central Europeans. They literally invented the modern usage of the term to describe themselves. Probably the most obvious example of this is popular depictions of Jesus vs accurate depictions. They whitewashed him. The only country that considered them white is the US due to the census bureau not having an option for Arab or Persian descent. A sort of modern example of revisionist history in action or maybe simple bureocratic oversight. Given the whole war on terror though Id guess its the first.

Its actually a big issue though so thats likely soon to be changed. Id by the next census most likely. Arab and Persian communities are demanding racial recognition as its often used as an excuse to descriminate and get away with it.

I know when I visited the middle east I was definitely referred to as the white guy anytime I left a tourist area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246918989.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, that *is* interesting. 

That puts me in a weird spot, too.

My family is African (Berber), but everyone assumes we're white.  In case you're unfamiliar, we're the indigenous peoples of super-Saharan Africa. 

In general, we're darker skinned than Persians.

So, I'm not white either?  Clearly I'm not Asian or native American or any other major race.

Does this make me African American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249489621.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;My family is African (Berber), but everyone assumes we're white.  In case you're unfamiliar, we're an indigenous people of North Africa.

Im familiar thats just a really small and particular ethnic group associated with the Mediterranean. Stemming from Roman conquest if I remember right, thats how people in your region became white. Mostly rape and pillaging and so on. Being white doesnt mean you make up a majority of the muslim population though? Im struggling to see a connection here. Maybe you can explain how you being an extremely small white muslim minority in a melting pot region also means white muslims make up the majority of the islamic population?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250063985.0" user="OnceNamed" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Stemming from Roman conquest if I remember right, thats how people in your region became white. 

No, absolutely not.  Read up on history.  The Berbers are indigenous to north Africa since before recorded history.

The Romans didn't even exist when my ethnic group formed. 

You've built and stuffed your own strawman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254470998.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>This is a recent photograph of a modern Berber? Uhhh....I get Berbers are of mixed ethnic origin. Ultimately race is a social concept invented by Europeans to justify the continuation of slavery post Christian conversion and it applies poorly to a lot of ethnic groups as it really has no scientific basis but yeah....

https://encrypted-tbn0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcTe-7WJlZOKF9TVOFhZc3Ujck9dtmQrkDCAEQ&amp;usqp=CAU</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43262660949.0" user="mehra_mora55" delta="False">
    <text>Well, for example, I am from Russia, and we perceive Arabs and North Africans as "whites", in the sense of "Europeans", although they are different from northern Europeans.  
But technically, if you're an African who came from Africa to America, are you really African American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242993357.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your second paragraph but your first paragraph is a very poor argument. People who wear a scarf just to protect themselves from the sun would most likely be willing to swap it to a sunhat with no problem but someone wearing it for religious or cultural reasons wouldn't. 

So, if hijabs were banned along with other religious symbols (I'm not saying they should be) then an excuse to wear one "because I need it to protect against the sun and there is no alternative" is a very bad one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246244911.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People who wear a scarf just to protect themselves from the sun would most likely be willing to swap it to a sunhat with no problem but someone wearing it for religious or cultural reasons wouldn't.

Some people value basic personal freedom and dont want arbitrary dress codes enforced upon them lol. Imagine being told you cant wear shoes and need to wear flip flops. Youd probably be like "fuck no I already bought these shoes, Im not going to go buy a pair of flip flops because you cant handle people wearing shoes." As a students its a bigger issue as obviously you cant work under a certain age and dont have your own money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258152211.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Personal freedom is a completely different thing. Some schools require a uniform that restricts the freedom of choosing your own clothes far more than a scarf ban.

And in any case your example doesn't make sense. If you knew that your school requires you to wear flip flops you would not buy shoes (meant for your work) but flip flops. Imagine going to a school that requires students to wear a uniform in jeans and then starting bitching that you already bought the jeans. The principal would laugh you (or rather your parents) out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258615813.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Eh depends. At least around here private schools expensive but the shcools themselves are broke. Generally if the parents just say the kids going to wear it or theyll leave the school they get their way.

Also dress codes make some sense, but still not much. Dress codes date back to the birth of the public school system which was basically designed to prepare students for incarceration or factory work. Generally better schools dont have strict dress codes as more intelligent people tend to stand up for themselves better. They tried at my highschool and it was just incredibly unpopular so they scrapped the plan. My shcool also had AP, legal departments, business departments, dual enrollment, even a technical school on campus. You could graduate as an electrician or plumber for instance.

Generally you see dress codes in bad neighborhoods.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258670094.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Everything you wrote is irrelevant. We're not talking if a school should or shouldn't have a dress code. That's a separate discussion. We're discussing your argument that if the school has a dress code and you show up wearing something else and then try to justify that by saying "well, I bought this already so have to be allowed to wear it instead of the clothing that I was supposed to buy". 

As I said, if you did that the principal would laugh you out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43263280059.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Personal freedom is a completely different thing. Some schools require a uniform that restricts the freedom of choosing your own clothes far more than a scarf ban.

You brought it up. Now Im wrong for addressing it? Also no principal is "laughing out" a parent and keeping their job. You seem to have a really silly idea of how the school system works. Dress code is proposed and either accepted or not. Parents can also go and voice their concerns to the school board during these meetings. School boards are elected but in the US the limitation is the Civil Rights act meaning you cant ban a piece of religiously required attire.

Then youll have a situation where your attorney is actually laughing the principle off. Because an attorney can do that without getting fired.

Taking these weird roundabout ways of saying children shouldnt have rights or agency is just too much. Speak plainly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43266649958.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>It's a completely different matter to discuss in the school board if the school in question should or should not have a dress code and unilaterally decide that the school dress code doesn't apply to you. 

And I'm not talking about the US but the UK. I didn't even know that the US schools have a dress code.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43271971396.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>So what lol? Dress code was such a big fight at my school they barely enforced it as it was just ruining the actual education aspect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43276380127.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean "so what lol"? Are you asking what are you laughing?

I don't care about your particular school. It's irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43281071039.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>You're asking what? What I'm laughing?

But yeah arbitrary dress codes and education obviously don't mix. You're literally supposed to be learning to think critically and think for yourself lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43286207700.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Yes , what do you mean by "so what lol"?

And what are you laughing now? Your own argument is laughable or what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43289357475.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Are you having a stroke? Youre not making any sense. What you are writing is literally illegible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43292064887.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not having a stroke. I'm worried about your obsessive laughter when there is nothing funny going on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43292744723.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Your grammatical mistakes are what's funny...you a bit slow there bud?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43300799948.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>What's so funny about grammatical mistakes?

And do you want me to go through your grammar? Do you think it's free from "funny" mistakes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43305506983.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And what are you laughing now?

WHAT ARE YOU LAUGHING!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43309291204.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Did you go completely nuts now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43309523633.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Im quoting you genius. Is English not your first language or is your brain broken? We'll call you Arny from now on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43309866445.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Your quote was correct but what was the rest of your comment about? I've not said anything about any army.

And who is this "we" you're talking about? Are you some collective behind the Reddit username?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43309915570.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>Arny not army. As in Arnold Schwarzenegger? We is us as in the two people talking right now. Youll be Arny. I'm not trying to be mean lol you seem really out there. Like you're having trouble reading and writing or something.

You really dont know who Arny is? Or "get to the choppa"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43310136817.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I have no idea who is Amy and I don't really care. And I have not agreed any of your "we" statements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43314595828.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>I see you're just hard of reading.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43318356656.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>What does Arny have anything to do with this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43318848237.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>You speak like him. What are you laughing?!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43320160215.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know how I speak? 

I only commented your laughing when there was nothing funny going on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243856412.0" user="Dennis_enzo" delta="False">
    <text>No one gets sun burned inside a class room though, so that's a poor argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245698164.0" user="Goblin_CEO_Of_Poop" delta="False">
    <text>What? Is no one up to date on dermatology lol?

https://sundoctors.com.au/blog/5-reasons-why-you-need-to-wear-sunscreen-indoors/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
