<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236569845.0" user="Jebofkerbin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Public Schools are secular organizations

Secular doesn't mean "religions are banned from this space" it just means that the space isn't affiliated with any particular faith.

Making reasonable accommodations for people who need it to help them participate is a good thing to do regardless of whether those accommodations are for religious reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236573725.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>It means that in France.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236630731.0" user="striped-rakkhun" delta="False">
    <text>good thing we’re not fr\*nch buddy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236670323.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>It’s called Laïcité in France actually. It’s a vestige of the French Revolution and the utter disaster that was. Nearly everything bad about the 20th century can be traced back to that shitshow (especially the Nazis and Soviets)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236965415.0" user="Emperormorg" delta="False">
    <text>Citation needed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237019222.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Easy. The French Revolution lead to Romantic Nationalism and directly influenced Marx and early socialists. Napoleon who was a direct product of the Revolution destroyed the HRE, which led to the creation of German Nationalism. German (and various Balkan nationalisms) nationalism lead directly to both world wars and the Holocaust.

The Revolution directly leads to the Paris Commune, which inspired Karl Marx to his ideas of a violent dictatorship of the proletariat (seriously, read about what he had to say about the Paris Commune. Lenin and Stalin were not great innovators, they were simply taking Marx’s statements to their conclusion) Incredible suffering and at least a dozen wars and genocides spring forth from this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237352799.0" user="Emperormorg" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a citation? Or is this just your theory?

So that is a very conservative way to analyse the French revolution. You can also analyse it was a revolt against tyrannical monarchy and aristocracy, and being a starting point in Europe for a concept of political pluralism, rule of law and democracy, which neither the Soviet or Nazi system upheld. If the absolutist ancien regime had attempted to moderate sooner into a constitutional monarchy and gave into the demands of the revolutionaries, that would have avoided full on revolution. So defending monarchy to attack nationalism doesn't really hold up when it was the faults of monarchy that led to nationalism in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237384801.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>[Nationalism and the French Revolution](https://www.google.com/search?q=nationalism+and+the+french+revolution&amp;rlz=1CDGOYI_enUS953US953&amp;hl=en-US&amp;sxsrf=AB5stBgqS3owQeVdU_0v7E7uW0SmGVBKdg%3A1691349869024&amp;ei=bfPPZOSDAa66kPIPqrSxGA&amp;oq=nationalism+and+the+french+revolution&amp;gs_lp=EhNtb2JpbGUtZ3dzLXdpei1zZXJwIiVuYXRpb25hbGlzbSBhbmQgdGhlIGZyZW5jaCByZXZvbHV0aW9uMgcQABiKBRhDMgYQABgHGB4yBhAAGAgYHjIGEAAYCBgeMgYQABgIGB4yCBAAGIoFGIYDMggQABiKBRiGA0iVIlDcEViKG3ABeACQAQCYAeEBoAHVC6oBBTAuOS4xuAEDyAEA-AEBwgIKEAAYRxjWBBiwA8ICBxAjGLACGCfCAgUQABiiBOIDBBgAIEGIBgGQBgg&amp;sclient=mobile-gws-wiz-serp)

Nationalism and the monarchism of the ancien regime were fundamentally at odds. Monarchical France was at its core a diverse realm while the project of nationalism started by the revolution was all about centralization and destroying diversity. This is why there was a genocide (the war in the vendee) and the systematic effort to standardize French as a language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237106926.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>Nazis are a direct consequence of the Christian religion, Soviets might have a link, but judging by your post not the one you meant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237128894.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Nazis are a direct consequence of the Christian religion, Soviets might have a link, but judging by your post not the one you meant.

They are obviously not a direct consequence of Christianity, otherwise they would have emerged in every Christian country long before the Second World War and many of the most prominent Nazis were not Christian at all, as they were pagans and atheists and agnostics. Nazism was a fundamentally German phenomenon caused by the First World War and romantic nationalism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237333255.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>They did. Every country had Jew hating extremists linked to the christian religion, i.e. nazis. The simple evidence for that is the amount of people in christian countries that colaborated with the nazis on their own accord, or the Vatican almost immediately approving and celebrating the nazis. Hell, the US held parades in honour of Hitler before they joined the war. 

The SS had beltbuckels that said "got mit uns" (god with us), they all had to swear an oath to the almighty god (not of Judaism or Islam) when joining the German army and their leader wrote a book dedicating his chosen path to his christian faith. nazism was present in every country, just like it is till this day in many forms, and it all stems from the christian religion. The Germans were just the most extreme of a big bunch</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237505917.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Anti-Judaism and racialist anti semitism were not the same things historically. Plenty of Muslim countries were anti-Judaic without being anti Semitic (since Arabs are semites after all). There were even muslims who were in the Waffen SS. 

Plenty of christians risked their lives to protect Jews. The Catholic Church worked to actually hide Jews and the confessing church in Germany organized resistance to the Nazis.

Hitler was popular in America not because of religion but because of racism. Eugenics was extremely popular amongst educated Americans at the time. Hitler even admitted to being inspired by Jim Crow laws and American sterilization of native Americans and the mentally ill. 

As for the belt buckle, there were in fact muslims, atheists and pagans in the ranks of the SS. The founder and leader of the SS; Himmler was a pagan, not a Christian. Goebbels was an atheist.

Nazism was a particularly German phenomenon that could not have emerged anywhere else. There are no Nazi movements today. There are Neo Nazis but they are fundamentally derivative of the singular German origin point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237708959.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what your point is? I never made any distinction.

There are nazis who protected jews (they liked), but there were a whole lot more exterminating the jews -just like there were more christians actively helping to exterminate the jews- does that make nazis good? Sorry that's a super weak argument, you'll have to do much better. 

Racism based on hating jews.... where does this jew hating come from....? Could it have anything to do with a certain religion that preaches hatred against the jews based on some old books? They were racist specifically BECAUSE they were religious. To prove me wrong you only have to point me towards the jew hating atheist organisation back in those days, should be easy right? 

OH wow, you found 2 people that were maybe not that deeply religious. I can name several thousands that were on a holy war against the Jews specifically because they were christians, not withstanding their leader who wrote down himself he did this because of his faith:  
"I believe today that my conduct is in accordance with the will of the Almighty Creator."  
\- Adolf Hitler, Mein Kampf, Vol. 1 Chapter 2  


It's time for you to sit down and study some more, you're making a fool out of yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237743657.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; To prove me wrong you only have to point me towards the jew hating atheist organisation back in those days, should be easy right?

Here’s one. https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/League_of_Militant_Atheists

&gt; OH wow, you found 2 people that were maybe not that deeply religious

Dude they were number 2 and 3 in the Nazi hierarchy. The actual founder of the SS and the guy who made the propaganda for the extermination of Jews.

&gt; Racism based on hating jews.... where does this jew hating come from....?

The Romans hated Jews long before Christianity. Stalin was an atheist who hated Jews.

Hitler hated both Christianity and Judaism. https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2019/04/20/hitler-hated-judaism-he-loathed-christianity-too/

&gt; It's time for you to sit down and study some more, you're making a fool out of yourself.

Dude you’re the one lying here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238638457.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>oh my god you could not get any dumber. It's obvious you're not intelligent enough to follow the conversation so I'll slow it down for you. 

We were talking about religious organisation (i.e. the nazis) following christian doctrine in their hatred towards jews, leading to the genocide against the Jews. We were talking about the USA supporting the nazis because they both felt the same way towards the jews, because they grew up with the same christian doctrine. I tell you to prove me wrong by just giving me one atheistic  organisation that hates Jews and could've caused the nazi hatred towards the jews. I assumed you would understand this organisation had to be from the US (I would've okayed Germany), and would have to hate the Jews without interference from christian doctrine. And what do you give me? A tiny Russian group that did not hate Jews, they actually disliked religion, which I can fully understand. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;The Romans hated Jews long before Christianity. Stalin was an atheist who hated Jews.

I so hope this was unintentional, but I think you're just really this stupid. Yeah, the Romans hated the Jews. Now tell me again, who edited the new testament? I seem to remember something about Milan, that's Italy, no? The romans? Oh my god. It's like the Romans hated the Jews, edited Jewish texts, made it official doctrine and then brought this religion to the whole of Europe by the sword, leading to most people in Europe disliking the Jews, cause the Romans, i.e. the christians, said so. 

I'm glad you agree the jew hate from the nazis comes from the Romans, or better said the christian religion, and the reason the nazis were so hateful was specifically because they were religious and followed christian dogma. 

Hitler also hated atheism. 

Please do yourself a favour and shut up, my abbs are hurting from all the laughing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239197338.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Of course you’re a conspiracy theorist. It’s not worth talking to someone who’s just going to ignore history and reality in order to be bigoted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239389755.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha, that's what defeat looks like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239482507.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>I’d say you’re soundly defeated on virtue of being proud to be a conspiracy theorist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239350432.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Now tell me again, who edited the new testament? I seem to remember something about Milan, that's Italy, no? The romans? Oh my god. It's like the Romans hated the Jews, edited Jewish texts, made it official doctrine and then brought this religion to the whole of Europe by the sword, leading to most people in Europe disliking the Jews, cause the Romans, i.e. the christians, said so.

The writers of the New Testament were all Hellenistic Jews. We have hundreds of surviving documents from every book in the New Testament that predate the Edict of Milan (an edict of toleration, not an edict of enforcing a particular religion) by at least two centuries. There is no evidence that Constantine or any other Roman Emperor edited the New Testament at all. Christianity was not primarily spread through the sword in Europe. In fact almost no religion has ever become popular through violence. Christianity, Islam and Buddhism spread widely primarily due to their influence as “civilizational packages”. Clerics brought literacy and organization to realms that lacked both previously. A good example is how the Goths became much more organized after their conversion to Christianity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239401398.0" user="Ilookbetterthanyou" delta="False">
    <text>Hahahahahahaha, who's lying now!? You know nothing about history. Just go hate some jews in silence while the rest of us figures out how to live together.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239475530.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Reported for bad faith and rude/hostile comments. You’re very bold to accuse others of lying and historical misrepresentation when you yourself are completely wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239489866.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239490961.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239495462.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239494043.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239492875.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236684997.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>No that's laicite, which is very different from secularism.  It's actually incompatible with secularism since it establishes a government religion somewhere between atheism and Catholicism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237338778.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>Laicite is literally the exact type of secularism that exists in Quebec. Considering Quebec started as a French colony, it isn’t exactly all that unheard of for a former French colony to adopt the same type of secularism as their ancestor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237425361.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>It's not unheard of for Quebec to adopt laicite any more than for it to adopt the guillotine.  Doesn't make them secularism or good</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237466532.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>Laïcité has been globally proven to be the most effective form of secularism that exists.

It’s supporters greatly outnumber you. And it’s a system that works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237735352.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>Surely theocracy is globally much more common and has many more supporters than laicite or any of the other alternatives to secularism.  And it works too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237426614.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>Quebec was a colony of the kingdom of France which had Catholicism is the official state religion Quebec was never a colony of any secular French government</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237526326.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>…And then France adopted Laicite when the Catholic Church tried going overboard. Quebec was having the exact same problem, and then decided to follow suit shortly thereafter.

In both cases, they decided on a system that works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237573527.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure it's working well for the government but I think religious people who desire freedom of expression would disagree about how well it's going

I'm an atheist but I believe in religious freedom and I would be very disappointed with my government ever try to adopt such unnecessary measures to ostracize religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237770167.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I’m sure it’s working well for the government

Don’t forget the secular-minded citizenry in Quebec as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238972716.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure its going great for them too but sadly for the majority, majority rule is not the only deciding factor of Politics there is also the factor of minority rights and the right to practice one's religion is amongst the most fundamental of rights</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237139858.0" user="Fluffy_MrSheep" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't mean that in France. It doesn't mean that anywhere</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237180344.0" user="ora_the_painbow" delta="False">
    <text>Secular means neutral or unrelated to religion. A secular institution doesn't need to ban expression of religion inside of it, just like how a public institution doesn't need to ban every privately-owned store or good inside of it (which would be silly).

By enforcing the absence of religion, you're implicitly forcing the institution to become atheist. Why is atheism a more valid belief to enforce on people than any other? (speaking as an atheist myself)

Anyways, should expressions of any belief system to banned as well? If not, why is religion any different from other belief systems (assuming that the person practicing isn't harming anyone else)? If so, should we ban all expressions of politics inside school as well? What about banning people expressing their favorite music artists? etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237595505.0" user="clar1f1er" delta="False">
    <text>google 'burden of proof'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237933574.0" user="ora_the_painbow" delta="False">
    <text>Burden of proof requires some clear baseline or expectation that is generally agreed upon, and I don't think there is a truly objective one here. In fact, given that most of the world is spiritual or religious in some way, most people probably think burden of proof lies with people who are atheist. I also don't think this is a sensible way to organize what should be allowed in schools, because then anything that is not basically a baseline cannot exist in a school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237991008.0" user="clar1f1er" delta="False">
    <text>Basically a baseline = everybody already accepts it, or you can prove it to be baseline. You got it. Since it has no proof, it has no basis for accomodation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237247538.0" user="jftduncan" delta="False">
    <text>I thought this was about Quebec.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237160146.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Making reasonable accommodations

There is no reason to accomodate religions in a general, public and universal institution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237239837.0" user="Jackolantern668" delta="False">
    <text>Why not if the accommodation doesn’t negatively impact anyone?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237322373.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>It fundamentally goes against the concept of a neutral, public secular institution. The only way it could work is if those social traditions get secularized and therefore more acceptable for and towards everyone else.

Just the thought of wasting money to build some shrine or office in a school and not something useful seems like a bad investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237416896.0" user="Yawanoc" delta="False">
    <text>Spirituality is part of human nature.  Nothing wrong with accommodating people who are more spiritual than others, especially in an often stressful environment expecting children to excel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237468458.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Spirituality is part of human nature

If you believe spirits exists. Spirituality has a million ways to be understood, you do not have a million ways to accomodate everyone in a club or with small monuments and so on.

So we know you cannot obviously give every single group a spotlight at school, We need grand general spaces to meet and know other students which are totally neutral to not play favorites, what do we call that? School. With its yards, places to eat, library and the like specially since im talking to first worlders here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237830568.0" user="Naturalnumbers" delta="False">
    <text>This is an extremely goofy and childish notion. OP is asking that religious people renounce their faith if they want to go to public school. Allowing a Jewish person to wear a yarmulke does not cost anything at all., Banning people from wearing traditional religious items has a cost in that it limits access.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237562589.0" user="clar1f1er" delta="False">
    <text>I need a strongly contemplative satanic room. I need a mindfulness room. Sure could use a meditation room now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237643381.0" user="Smee76" delta="False">
    <text>All those things would be permitted in the prayer room.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237700357.0" user="clar1f1er" delta="False">
    <text>Separate rooms, separate purposes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237929277.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>Then thats an unreasonable accomodation. Having a room set aside specifically for meditative and religious needs is reasonable, needing seperate ones is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238143327.0" user="clar1f1er" delta="False">
    <text>Having the room at all is unreasonable, and citing faith for it isn't reasonable either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238992537.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>I dont see why its absurd to have a space for people to meditate, pray, or whatever other practice a person might want to engage in that requires quiet and the expectation of a period of uninterupption. Why shouldnt Satanists not be allowed a place to meditate if they so choose?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249871221.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Is meditation a practice of Satanism or are you just trying to slash school budgets by using it to get what you want</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238376033.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It fundamentally goes against the concept of a neutral, public secular institution.




The issue is that a *neutral* secularism doesnt really exist. The Quebec flag has a religious symbol on it but now its "cultural".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238899187.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>And Iran has popular ancient pre-Allah rituals popular among the people even though its an Islamic republic, some things do trascend religious meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239836681.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; And Iran has ancient pre-Allah rituals popular among the people even though its an Islamic republic just to give an example, some things do trascend their original spiritual meaning and just become " a thing we all do".


Yes, the issue is that the boundary between the religious and the secular cultural practices is and has always been blurry.




&gt; but in fact shows how trying to accomodate every aspect of spirituality is so subjective and unsutainable you need to keep your government institutions neutral and separate from it to not get bogged down. 


Thats assuming that every aspect of spirituality needs its own super specific accommodations. They dont, there's a lot of overlap, a prayer room can be a room for just about any activity. 

Furthermore, being bogged down by the cultural intricacies of the society, is arguably part of any governments job.



&gt;It doesnt mean Quebec or Italy can have crosses in schools out of tradition either(in fact im suprised uncivilized things like that happen there)

You are? Really? France privileges the Catholic Church. The Fleur de lis is on the Quebec Flag. Christmas is a national holiday in almost every Western secular country. 

We have **always** picked and chosen what aspects of religion to keep in government and which to discard, for one because you cannot really completely separate religious practice and culture, religions are cultural practices as well as spiritual beliefs.

And for another, because members of the dominant religious group whether pious, or non-believing will bias themselves towards their own religious and cultural backgrounds, and treat minority religions as purely a matter of belief, and not culture. 


Thats why some people are uncomfortable with the idea of more strict interpretations of secularism. It privileges the nonreligious and the religion of the dominant group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237361728.0" user="eloel-" delta="False">
    <text>Is there unlimited funding and building space?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237384590.0" user="Jackolantern668" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not. But if insufficient funding and space is the problem, then why not just say it instead of adopting a “no religious expression in public schools” rationale?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237613131.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>It'd be diverting resources to religious use whether they're plentiful or short. That can be objectionable regardless of whether those resources are plentiful or slim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238531055.0" user="Historical-Panic-820" delta="False">
    <text>What extra funding is needed to allow someone to wear a hat inside?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243258445.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>??? No one is preventing students from wearing religious garbs. This thread is about providing a private prayer space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239015493.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why not if the accommodation doesn’t negatively impact anyone?

Teaching children that believing in religion is acceptable and encouraging children to practice their religions in school negatively impacts everyone though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241118916.0" user="HardlightCereal" delta="False">
    <text>Children should be taught about a wide variety of religious beliefs in a non judgemental setting, but should be forbidden from participation outside of what's directly necessary.

Also BTW the belief that an objective world exists beyond human perception is religious</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237264586.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>There's no reason not to do that as well, as long as every religion is welcome and not just a specific one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239006406.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;There's no reason not to do that as well, as long as every religion is welcome and not just a specific one.

Sure there is. Teaching kids that it's okay or acceptable to believe in fairy tale nonsense is harmful to the human race.

There's no reason for logical human beings to support those ridiculous delusions or enable that form of child abuse in schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239146953.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah, I was expecting this kind of completely reasonable, intelligent, open-minded and not at all conceited response sooner or later. Reddit never disappoints.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239349979.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry that I'm not interested in coddling the silly superstitions of the world or treating them with reverence enough for you.

Religion is a cancer on humanity and fuck treating it with kid gloves just cause some people feel like it's important to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239555947.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I'm sure you must be a super nice, level-headed and easy person to talk to, not to say very fun at parties. Keep up being the incredible person you are, and have a good day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239673179.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I know when talking about making policy that affects children the number one thing I want from the people making those decisions is "must be fun at parties."

I'm sorry that pointing out religion is nonsense and that teaching kids nonsense as if it were fact should be treated as child abuse.

I'm sorry that the fact that religion is fucked up and has caused the deaths of millions and the suffering of billions is a hard truth to face for you.

But under no circumstances should any rational, logical human being ever give an inch of ground to religious beliefs that aren't backed up with scientific evidence.  Nor should we make any accommodations in law or policy that respect those religious beliefs in any way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239827666.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>Dully noted and disregarded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240071246.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>I think you might want to look at what subreddit you're in.  Your comments are very, very poor faith efforts here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240214743.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, the irony...

This is r/changemyview, not the "act discourteously and still expect others to engage in civil discussion with you" subreddit.

If you really want to discuss, then you might want to change your approach. I hate to break it to you, but from your first comment you just sound like the usual angry reddit atheist, and unfortunately this kind of thing never goes anywhere.

I'd be happy to dialogue with you if you drop the edgy tone, and further expand your views rather than just keep ranting that "religion bad". There's not much I can work with here since until now you just gave your own opinions with nothing really to back them up. Like, why is it child abuse? Why is religion worse than anything else? Why can't kids pray at school? "Because I think so" is not a valid reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240401296.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;. Like, why is it child abuse?

Why is lying to children and indoctrinating them into believing nonsense without any objective evidence to back it up abusive?

Seems pretty self evident. 

&gt;Why is religion worse than anything else?

Who said it was worse than anything else? 

&gt;Why can't kids pray at school?

Because schools are for teaching children the objective facts of the world and how to use logic and critical thinking skills to become educated adults.

Introducing fairy tales and rain dances into that environment for any reason other than to point out how silly they are to believe in is counterproductive to that goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240567983.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why is lying to children and indoctrinating them into believing nonsense without any objective evidence to back it up abusive?  
&gt;  
&gt;Seems pretty self evident.

Look, it's truly ironic that you call me out about the subreddit we are in, and yet your arguments boil down to "it's self-evident to me!". How exactly do you expect to change my view with that? Sorry, I couldn't let that pass.

No, there's nothing that's self-evident about it. As long as there no actual abuse going on, like violence or any kind of psychological abuse, there's absolutely nothing wrong in parents raising their kids teaching them what they think is right. That's literally how any kind of upbringing goes, and different parents have different ways of doing that. Even in a secular family, there's no guarantee that kids are being taught the "right" things. That's just the way it is, and this is not child abuse in the slightest.

The only reason you see it as self-evident is because you disagree with it, and I see no reason to agree with you in that.

&gt;Who said it was worse than anything else?

You say that it's wrong to teach kids about religion, and that's harmful to the human race. At its core, religion is just a set of values. Why are those values any worse than literally anything else that parents might teach their kids?

&gt;Because schools are for teaching children the objective facts of the world and how to use logic and critical thinking skills to become educated adults.  
&gt;  
&gt;Introducing fairy tales and rain dances into that environment for any reason other than to point out how silly they are to believe in is counterproductive to that goal.

And how does having a separate space for kids that might be religious to congregate getting in the way of that? How is it counterproductive to that goal? Does not having a space like that in school will suddenly make them lose their religion? Would having that space *really* harm the learning environment of a school? Do you have anything to back any of that up, or are we still working just with informed opinions here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240883644.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Look, it's truly ironic that you call me out about the subreddit we are in, and yet your arguments boil down to "it's self-evident to me!". How exactly do you expect to change my view with that? Sorry, I couldn't let that pass.  No, there's nothing that's self-evident about it.

Okay, well then lets take a step back if lying to children and teaching them to believe in nonsense isn't a self evident harm to you.

Do you think lying is a good or a bad thing?  Do you value honesty?  Do you think we should teach our children to lie or be honest?

&gt;The only reason you see it as self-evident is because you disagree with it, and I see no reason to agree with you in that.

I see it as self-evident because I see that teaching children to lie and to believe in nonsense with zero proof or evidence is harmful.

It's cool that you think there would be no problem teaching children, "All people with black skin are possessed by the devil and are evil that should be purged from the world" and have no problem lying and making shit up to indoctrinate children with I guess.  But I would have a problem with that personally because lying to children and teaching them to believe in that nonsense would be harmful to the children and lead to a worse society to live in.

You, however, seem to think that we should not just allow but encourage that belief and any other wacked out and fucked up belief like the absolutely insane shit in the Bible and Quran (which btw is far worse than that) and give kids a place to spread that to other children or amongst themselves with our tax dollars.

Hard pass.

&gt; At its core, religion is just a set of values.

At its core religion is lies.  It's made up bullshit and it has nothing to do with values.  Nothing about God killing every firstborn son in a murderous genocidal rage has to do with teaching anyone values, I promise.

Religion is worse than most other things that parents might teach their children because religion affects the entire way of thinking for that person for the rest of their lives.  People who believe in religion also are far more likely to believe in aliens, conspiracy theories, hoaxes, outright lies, and fake news.

https://www.psypost.org/2018/10/study-religious-fundamentalists-and-dogmatic-individuals-are-more-likely-to-believe-fake-news-52426

And that's before we factor in all of the anti-LGBT bullshit that indoctrinates them with hatred.  Before the systemic child abuse conspiracy that their religions fund and that indoctrinating them into early makes them far more likely to fund when they themselves grow up.

It's a harmful cycle from a system of "values" that has killed countless millions of people and abused billions more over the centuries.

And it has no place in our schools, being coddled by our laws or our policies, and no reason to ever be funded or supported with our tax dollars anywhere on Earth.

&gt;And how does having a separate space for kids that might be religious to congregate getting in the way of that? 

How is using our tax dollars to fund a place for children who have been brainwashed to get together and repeatedly reinforce that brainwashing a bad thing?  To potentially expose other students to that illogical, harmful thinking and damaging rhetoric?  To condone that line of nonsense fantasy thinking in our education system in any way is to undermine the entire concept of our school system.

&gt;Does not having a space like that in school will suddenly make them lose their religion? 

No, but not giving them any public places to practice those things makes it far less likely that they will be exposed to them as much.  Which is the end goal.

&gt;Would having that space really harm the learning environment of a school? Do you have anything to back any of that up, or are we still working just with informed opinions here?

Like, say, allowing students to pray after school during sports until oops, everyone starts pressuring and indoctrinating all the kids and forcing them to either demonstrate they believe the same or ostracizing them?

https://www.houstonchronicle.com/opinion/outlook/article/Opinion-I-was-a-Katy-High-football-co-captain-17290739.php

Shit like this happens ALL OVER schools that allow that bullshit and has for decades. It's now getting even worse thanks to our corrupt ass Supreme Court ruling that it's totally legal to do this kind of shit.

And stories like this are exactly how the poison of religion keeps spreading its influence and why it should be absolutely stamped out in schools in every way.  Both public and private.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241260529.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Okay, well then lets take a step back if lying to children and teaching them to believe in nonsense isn't a self evident harm to you.  
&gt;  
&gt;Do you think lying is a good or a bad thing?  Do you value honesty?  Do you think we should teach our children to lie or be honest?

Religious parents do NOT believe they are lying to their children, nor teaching them nonsense, though. They are just a set of values and truths to them like any other, and therefore there is no abuse or lies intrinsically involved. 

That said, you seem to be very strongly opposed to telling lies and nonsense that can't be proven to children. Do you think parents who teach kids things like "being kind will be good to you" are also being abusive, since that is just a very subjective and non-demonstrable thing, as "being kind" might end up being harmful to the child?

Do you think parents who tell their kids they can be whatever they want, which every parent knows to be a lie, are being abusive?

Why? Why not?

&gt;I see it as self-evident because I see that teaching children to lie and to believe in nonsense with zero proof or evidence is harmful.

I'm sure there are people who think exactly the same about the things you believe, and their view is just as valid since it's all just "self-evident" to them.

&gt;It's cool that you think there would be no problem teaching children, "All people with black skin are possessed by the devil and are evil that should be purged from the world" and have no problem lying and making shit up to indoctrinate children with I guess.

That's just a straight up strawman. Keep the dishonesty down a bit.

&gt;At its core religion is lies. It's made up bullshit and it has nothing to do with values.

"I don't agree with its values, therefore it has nothing to do with values".

Do I need to explain why this is fallacious? Values don't stop being values just because you disagree with them.

&gt;People who believe in religion also are far more likely to believe in aliens, conspiracy theories, hoaxes, outright lies, and fake news.  
  
https://www.psypost.org/2018/10/study-religious-fundamentalists-and-dogmatic-individuals-are-more-likely-to-believe-fake-news-52426

That study is NOT saying that "People who believe in religion" are more likely to believe in fake news. It also has NOTHING to do with aliens. It's saying, specifically, that religious FUNDAMENTALISM, along with dogmatism, delusionality, and reduced analytic thinking is linked to belief in fake news.

This might be the same thing as "People who believe in religion" to someone who didn't even take their time to read the study, but it isn't.

&gt;Like, say, allowing students to pray after school during sports until oops, everyone starts pressuring and indoctrinating all the kids and forcing them to either demonstrate they believe the same or ostracizing them?

It's a nice thing that we are talking about a *private, designated* space for personal prayer, and not at all about a public demonstration of faith that might lead others to feel pressured to follow in. I don't know why you brought that up as it is just vaguely related to what we were talking, but let's keep it in topic, shall we?

Back to the matter at hand, why is a *private*, *designated* space for prayer a bad thing? You said it's bad because it might "potentially expose other students to that illogical, harmful thinking and damaging rhetoric, and to condone that line of nonsense fantasy thinking in our education system in any way is to undermine the entire concept of our school system."

Well, since this is still all just your opinion, my opinion is still that you're full of shit and unnecessarily paranoid and worried about a harmless thing, and you still hasn't said anything to change my view about it. 

I'll end this with an anecdote: at my old work, which was a **government** **scientific research facility**, that also had a school and we always had university students doing work there, we had an "ecumenical chapel", which served as our prayer room. It housed buddhists, christans, muslims, etc, anyone could go there to pray, or even conduct masses and other religious rituals if they wanted.

And we were fine, and they are still fine today. Outside of the chapel there was no religious presence in there. The "entire concept of our school system" wasn't undermined just because of it, the university students didn't pressure anyone into prayer, and our scientists and engineers weren't brainwashed by their religious peers (hey, a lot of them even went there often).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242861671.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Religious parents do NOT believe they are lying to their children, nor teaching them nonsense, though.

Racists don't believe that they're lying when they tell their kids that black people are inferior too.  Should we also provide pro-racism belief spaces in schools?

&gt; Do you think parents who teach kids things like "being kind will be good to you" are also being abusive, since that is just a very subjective and non-demonstrable thing, as "being kind" might end up being harmful to the child?

Yes.  Teaching people to be kind and teaching people that being kind will reward you are two different things and yes, teaching the second one is a pretty fucked up lie that is also pretty abusive and can lead to kids developing a lot of anger and bitterness that they were lied to about that.

&gt;Do you think parents who tell their kids they can be whatever they want, which every parent knows to be a lie, are being abusive?

Depends entirely on if they are lying or not when they say it.  But yes, in general, lying to the children and telling them they are capable of something they aren't is also abusive parenting behavior that can fuck a kid up.

&gt;I'm sure there are people who think exactly the same about the things you believe, and their view is just as valid since it's all just "self-evident" to them.

They are welcome to think that.  But the things I believe are backed with evidence and logic and theirs are based on "faith" so it's a different situation.

A parent is more than welcome to think that evolution doesn't exist and I'm lying to the children about it when I teach them.  But it objectively does so fuck that parent.  I'm not lying.

Meanwhile, a parent telling a kid they will burn in hell if they feel attraction to the same sex is lying.  They are making shit up and have zero evidence to back that up.  There are objectively lying to those children and making claims they cannot support.

We live in a world with objective truths and pretending like we don't, especially in regards to education systems, is silly.

&gt;That's just a straight up strawman. Keep the dishonesty down a bit.

It's not a strawman, it's an example of a horrific personal belief based on nonsense.  It's the same as any other religion that teaches horrific shit like Christianity or Islam.  Just a more clear example that can hopefully get past your own biases which allow you to overlook the horrific shit in those religions hopefully.

So again I ask, would you be okay with parents teaching that belief to their kids?  With giving kids a place to share that belief?  Protecting that belief in our laws and disallowing us from challenging or singling out those who believe that?  Using our tax dollars to promote that belief?

If not, then why is it cool to do the same with any other fucked up beliefs people hold with no basis in reality that are harmful to our society and our species?

&gt;That study is NOT saying that "People who believe in religion" are more likely to believe in fake news. It also has NOTHING to do with aliens. It's saying, specifically, that religious FUNDAMENTALISM, along with dogmatism, delusionality, and reduced analytic thinking is linked to belief in fake news.

Uh huh.  That's religion my man.  You don't get religious fundamentalism without religion.  Some portion of people exposed to the fucked up beliefs of religion won't be able to dissociate like the majority of religious people.

These are people who BELIEVE in religion, not people who just blindly say, "I'm a Christian!" who were indoctrinated as children into this shit, never actually think about or examine their beliefs, and don't actually internalize the teachings of these religions.  Fundamentalists are just, "people who actually believe and follow a religion as its taught" instead of the majority of religious people who live with cognitive dissonance.

And those people who actually believe religion are harmful to our society.  So we should be looking to prevent that from continuing to happen to our children.  Which is accomplished by shielding them from religion as much as possible.

&gt;This might be the same thing as "People who believe in religion" to someone who didn't even take their time to read the study, but it isn't.

It's entirely what I just said.  Religious fundamentalists are people who believe in religion.

If you'd rather a source of people who just identify as religious though, they are also objectively dumber and believe more dumb shit.

Here's a simple study showing that people who attend church once or more monthly are almost twice as likely to believe QAnon (violent, racist, genocidal conspiracy theories) as those who never go to church.  As well as showing that White evangelicals are also way more likely to believe in shit like the Jan 6 conspiracy, COVID vaccine microchips, and vaccines causing autism than everyone else:

https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2021/07/27/what-drives-belief-in-conspiracy-theories-a-lack-of-religion-or-too-much

It's not a coincidence that almost 100% of people who still support a fucked up rapist con man for President, one who tried to literally end our Democracy itself here in America once and for all and install himself as Supreme Leader, call themselves religious.

https://www.kwtx.com/content/news/Trump-voters-very-religious--443162893.html

&gt;It's a nice thing that we are talking about a private, designated space for personal prayer, and not at all about a public demonstration of faith that might lead others to feel pressured to follow in. I don't know why you brought that up as it is just vaguely related to what we were talking, but let's keep it in topic, shall we?

Speaking of people who didn't read...from the article I linked:

&gt;Players would sweep through the field house calling for those not already in the room to join them in the **prayer room.** Coaches would encourage those who were unaware the player-led prayer was about to begin to join the **prayer room.** It did not matter whether a player was getting his ankles taped or just relaxing by his locker, there was always an urgency to gather in this room and hold hands in prayer. I never felt I had a choice, I just knew to fall in line. This was especially true while I was a co-captain. I believed I had to set a good example by joining the majority of players and following the coach’s example.

It's cool that you think that somehow these "private, personal spaces" (which are actually public spaces any student can go into and that are widely advertised in these schools which seem the opposite of personal and private) won't ever bleed into the rest of school life but they very clearly and very often do.  And it's fucked up.

&gt;I'll end this with an anecdote: at my old work, which was a government scientific research facility, that also had a school and we always had university students doing work there, we had an "ecumenical chapel", which served as our prayer room. It housed buddhists, christans, muslims, etc, anyone could go there to pray, or even conduct masses and other religious rituals if they wanted.

Cool.  This is also fucked up and should be dismantled.  No government facility should respect or coddle to religion and our laws and policy should stop giving them any kind of consideration of any kind.

&gt;And we were fine, and they are still fine today.

See above re: Trump was our fucking President for 4 years.  Then reconsider this statement about how "fine" we are with religion in our public sphere and poisoning our species.

&gt;The "entire concept of our school system" wasn't undermined just because of it, the university students didn't pressure anyone into prayer, and our scientists and engineers weren't brainwashed by their religious peers (hey, a lot of them even went there often).

It's cool that you're comparing a government facility full of adults to prayer rooms in public schools full of children and all, but it has nothing to do with the conversation at hand other than, "hey look, another waste of tax dollars spent to give consideration to the group of grown ass adults who believe in the tooth fairy."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242939347.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Teeklin – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20Teeklin&amp;message=Teeklin%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/-/jv40si6/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242938311.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/ToranjaNuclear – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20ToranjaNuclear&amp;message=ToranjaNuclear%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/-/jv3pqwb/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237417527.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>The reason is that people want to be accommodated? You could argue that it's that's an insufficient reason but to say there's no reason at all is categorically wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237525720.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;people want to be accommodated

Accomodating people means explaining to kids what other cultures are like, or core tenants of anti-discrimination against other people.

What people are talking about is making religions as a concept and organization feel cozy at public, universal institutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237557892.0" user="LordJesterTheFree" delta="False">
    <text>No we are talking about religious people being made to feel cozy wich is a good thing since public institutions exist just as much for religious people as secular people

Religion is not getting endorsed it is simply religious students being authorized to use a space for a religious or non-religious Reason same as my community college having an anime club isn't them endorsing anime or making anime feel cozy they don't care about anime they care about making students happy and enabling them to set up whatever Club they want (within certain obvious parameters of safety and code of conduct)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241111909.0" user="HardlightCereal" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, let's stop accommodating the religious belief that the world exists in professional spaces</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237415676.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>Need what??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237558832.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>"Reasonable accomodations" is a word regularly used to say that people with certain beliefs should have exceptions to the rules, so long as they deeply and truly believe them.

I'm of the stance that the rules should simply not hinder those people in the first place. An inclusove environment should never require that reasoble religious people should need exceptions.

Example: Hats in ID photos. If it's okay for Muslims to wear turbans, then it's okay for everyone. I'm open to a discussion on exceptions here. I don't think there are any.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237694185.0" user="sinocarD44" delta="False">
    <text>For IDs, I think the expectation is to be pictured as you would be in a typical daily situation. Wearing a hat can change with your daily preference. A turban, I think, I central to the religious tenets. A turban is something that is expectes to be worn daily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238449013.0" user="goodr14" delta="False">
    <text>An ID is used for the purpose of identification. You should be pictured in a way that shows your unique features as to make identification possible. Headgear that makes you not able to be identified makes the ID just a card of anybody wearing particular headgear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239365464.0" user="Harag4" delta="False">
    <text>If the turban is worn correctly. You are more likely to find a Sikh with his turban than without. I would say it's more accurate to include their turban in their ID.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243885219.0" user="Dennis_enzo" delta="False">
    <text>People with poor eyesight also wear glasses most of the time, and yet for an ID picture they need to take them off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239681840.0" user="FountainsOfFluids" delta="False">
    <text>My mom was forced to take off her eyeglasses for her DMV ID photo. It's absurd. It makes her look like a different person, and she needs to wear glasses to drive. 

For 99% of ID use, it is during the course of normal operations. So this type of ID should match what the person is going to look like during a normal day. 

You're never going to see a Sikh on a normal day without their turban, so requiring a photo ID without it is *opposite* of the purpose of a photo ID.

Especially considering that the turban doesn't block any facial features like a beard does. But they don't require men to shave their beards. Why? Because the assumption is that the man is going to have a similar beard when using the ID day-to-day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240855021.0" user="Lisentho" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; . It makes her look like a different person, and she needs to wear glasses to drive.

If she needed to be ID'd she could just take her glasses off, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241069319.0" user="FountainsOfFluids" delta="False">
    <text>It’s really not relevant that it’s easy to take off glasses. She shouldn’t have to. If her photo had her with her glasses on, she’d look like herself normally, because she wears glasses all day every day.

And it’s so much worse for a Sikh, who would have to remove their turban for an ID check. That’s not a simple hat that can be removed and replaced in a second.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241684103.0" user="MrsMiterSaw" delta="False">
    <text>With exceedingly fee exceptions, a sikh will have their turban on, making a picture with the turban more identifiable than without.

That's the whole point of the exception.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242089499.0" user="miarsk" delta="False">
    <text> O it isn't and you know it. For example hair color is missing from pictures with head gear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245678960.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243167080.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>And yet I was required to put my hair behind my ears for the picture but I never ever ever have my hair behind my ears, which I imagine is quite a common situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250248673.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine being forced to cut your hair, or shave your beard.


To someone with sincere religious beliefs, taking the turban off feels invasive and a lot more like being forced to cut their hair than simply put it behind thier ears.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250863534.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps so, but that's an entirely different argument than that it's supposedly about taking the picture how one ”normally looks” which was the original one.

And if safety apparently not be compromised enough if a Sikh do it, then everyone should be able to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251384802.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>It's a combination of two factors.

1: the fact that it doesn't impact safety much. (Also applies to you)

2: the fact that doing so invokes a significant cost on the person. (Doesn't apply to you)

Taken together, it's just not worth it to force a Sikh to take off their turban to take a picture.


You don't want someone to get the idea that the State hates them. It's the fastest possible way to radicalization.


Now, if either factor were different, things would be different. If a Muslim woman is wearing a full face covering, taking a picture of that is essentially useless. In that case as the DMV or whatever you would have to come to a solution that ends with you taking a picture of their face. Maybe having a woman take the picture?


In any case, leaving people with the impression that the state cares about them is VERY important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251639973.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Taken together, it's just not worth it to force a Sikh to take off their turban to take a picture.

Indeed, but why is it worth it then to force everyone else to take off hair dress or put their hair behind their ears?

As you point out, it doesn't impact safety much, so why does the rule exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252646327.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Because for you it is a VERY small sacrifice.


So the small safety gain is worth it, not because the security gain is large, but because the loss to you is so small.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237700419.0" user="ghostmacekillah" delta="False">
    <text>just a quick correction but Muslims wear the hijab, a turban is more of an Indian / Sikh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237724428.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're trying to weave a unified thread of logic on something that's more of a compromise or priority conclusion between separate threads of logic, not a reconciliation.

There's one argument for headwear to be disallowed in identity photos for security reasons. There's another argument for why some religious people should be allowed to always wear their headwear. It's been decided, above and outside those two individual arguments, that the religious need supercedes the security one, not because the religious factors affect the security argument or that there is no security argument, but they're allowed to be "wrong" in the security-risk logic to be "right" in the religious one.

The exception isn't "okay" by the risk covered by the rule. It does undermine and weaken the cause of the rule. It's just allowed by compromise or exception because there are (in the view of the people making the rules) greater issues at issue. If that undermining is spread to everyone, that's spreading the problem that does exist but was contained.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237917393.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>Additionally, ID photos are meant to identify you: if you always wear a turban due to your religious beliefs, then chances are any time that your ID is used to identify you, youll be in a turban. So is it more effective security wise to have an ID photo that reflects how you look day to day, or one that does not reflect your typical depiction?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238326073.0" user="RogueNarc" delta="False">
    <text>In this case it's not a matter of religious belief but habit. An atheist could provide a compelling history of persistent head covering as any religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238981025.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but its a lot easier for a sikh to prove a dogmatic following than an atheist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244002891.0" user="SonOfShem" delta="False">
    <text>yes, but also a Sikh is going to be wearing their turban &gt;99% of the time.  Most people who do not have a religious requirement to wear such a covering will not be able to demonstrate a similar frequency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240517551.0" user="gothicaly" delta="False">
    <text>Okay but anyone could wear a turban for the photo and then not wear turbans day to day or vice versa. From a purely security standpoint it makes sense to have a photo of purely someones face completely bare. Screening at airports make you take off glasses to match passport photos. Its not just something made up to inconvenience certain people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240747100.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, anyone can, but Sikhs don't. From a "purely security standpoint" you're virtually never going to see a Sikh without a turban or headwrap, so what good does it do having an ID that doesn't really resemble you very well? 

&gt;Screening at airports make you take off glasses to match passport photos.

I mean, that's never happened to me as a glasses wearer, but who knows. Every airport seems to have different protocols they follow. Denver's airport hasn't even made me take off my shoes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240765027.0" user="gothicaly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Sure, anyone can, but Sikhs don't. From a "purely security standpoint" you're virtually never going to see a Sikh without a turban or headwrap, so what good does it do having an ID that doesn't really resemble you very well? 

I addressed that in my first sentence. Sikhs dont? Religion isnt a mark branded into your skin. Anybody can say theyre anything.

&gt;I mean, that's never happened to me as a glasses wearer, but who knows. Every airport seems to have different protocols they follow. Denver's airport hasn't even made me take off my shoes.

You have to for canada atleast and many other countries. Domestic flights maybe. Im sure there are countries that dont but how can it be argued that someones bare naked face isnt preferable for an identification photo. Never mind finding a fugitive or something that dramatic just an unconscious john doe person in a hospital setting. Even just putting your thumb over the head on the i.d. where the turban would be. Its not rocket science. Im just talking about someones bare naked face. Im not trying to argue pedantics or what ifs and exceptions. Like ofc a bare face is preferable to a partially obscured one for a identity card?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242432585.0" user="brutinator" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Like ofc a bare face is preferable to a partially obscured one for a identity card?

And I'm trying to explain that it's a perfectly rational school of thought for security to choose to identify individuals by how they are most likely going to look instead of a sterile photo that is never going to resemble themselves. 

It's the same reason why they used to take mugshots of people in their suits, hats, and other streetwear instead of in a prison jumpsuit because people don't tend to wear a jumpsuit in public. Or the reason why I've never been asked to shave my beard for a photo, which obscures my face far more than a turban ever could. 

The only advantage a sterile naked face offers is facial recognition software which..... tbh not really crazy about, and not something I'm going to defend, but that's a different story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245310472.0" user="gothicaly" delta="False">
    <text>That is not a rebuttal to my points. Anybody can say they identity as whatever religion and cover up for photos and then commit crimes without head covering. Just because someone is likely to wear a suit or head covering on a day to day basis has no bearing on the needs of an identification card.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237921566.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Following the logic: The people in charge of that rule decided that religion should come before security. My belief is firmly that you can never reasonably be proven to have sincere religious beliefs of any kind, and that any requirement to testify of those beliefs is an infringement on them in the first place. Either security is more important than religion and nobody gets to wear their caps, or religion is more important than security and therefore all people should be able to wear headgear without proclaiming that their religion says so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238023948.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; My belief is firmly that you can never reasonably be proven to have sincere religious beliefs of any kind

Someone else's inability to verify doesn't mean you do or don't have them _in fact_, and the possibility that someone might lie about their religious beliefs in order to wear a hat doesn't mean that you ought to throw up hands and abandon the no-hat requirement and the benefits it brings entirely. You can accept that some people might lie about hat religions and you take those acceptable losses, or, if you're more heavy-handed or it becomes an epidemic issue, apply some scrutiny and make people prove the applicability of their hat necessity to some standard, and you take acceptable losses on the other side of the matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238408365.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Beliefs are subjective. Measuring them against others isn't just impossible, it's immoral, not just because you'll inevitably tell someone their actual beliefs are invalid (which is also true), but because you're by necessity telling people that they must behave in certain ways *because* of their beliefs. "You are not Sikh, and therefore here is your list of rules that you would not need to follow otherwise" is discriminatory and wrong. Any scrutiny at all applied to the legitimacy or sincerity of someone's professed beliefs is shitty.

I get that your response was focused only on the first part of my sentence, but the existence of that inevitable failure to catch liars and accuse the truthful of lying, when it comes to emotionally vulnerable beliefs like this, is still significant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243661222.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; You can accept that some people might lie about hat religions and you take those acceptable losses,

Well, if you set the rules so that 

a) you can wear the hat if it is for religious purposes and 

b) we have no way to verify your beliefs so we are forced to believe whatever you declare about them,

then in effect you have abandoned the no-hat policy and done it in a way that punishes people who are honest (as they alone would abide that rule). What's the point of such rules?

We don't make laws such. Or we make it so that in some cases we trust people say (we make binding agreements based on what people say) but then punish them heavily (the criminal punishment for fraud is pretty serious) if we find out that they in fact lied. In your system there is no punishment for deceit, which then teaches kids that deceit is fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250261258.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Pragmatically though, the law works.


We don't teach people with sincere religious beliefs that the State hates them, and most people don't wear hats in photo ID.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258171826.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't understand your point about hate.

In particular why should we care about "sincere religious beliefs" any more than anything else people believe? And how do you even determine "sincerity"? I'm an atheist now but was a Christian when I was a kid. At some point my belief degraded over time from "sincere" to "not at all". At which point would I have been allowed to break rules based on my belief and at which point that right would have stopped?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43261297228.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>If you as a kid felt you were being persecuted for your beliefs, you would either stop believing, or more likely, dig in your heels and believe even harder.

It could go either way, but creating religious extremists is not really a risk I want to take, if there is no good reason to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43262381273.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Not allowing to wear some religious symbols in school is not persecution. That would have had zero effect on my beliefs staying or fading away if I were allowed to wear a cross or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43263242507.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Your religion doesn't mandate wearing a cross.

These things are fundamentally different because of that.


It's like banning Lords Supper out of concerns of attempted cannibalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43266638473.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean "mandate"? We're not talking about Saudi Arabia. If you don't like your religion, then change. The point is that you can't make the rest of the society bend to your will just by labelling it a religion.

I'm not sure what your last point is. Even if some people believe that they are literally eating the body of Christ, they really aren't and there isn't any reason to ban Eucharist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43267374299.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If you don't like your religion, then change

I'm talking about the people that DO like their religion.

My point was that to them their religious clothing is as important to them as the Lord's supper is to most Christians.

&gt;The point is that you can't make the rest of the society bend to your will just by labelling it a religion.

In this case, you actually get less rights because it's a religion. I can wear any clothing I want to a Quebec school as long as it is not a religious symbol.

So technically I could wear a turban, as just a practical article of clothing, but my Sikh coworker could not, because to him it's a religion.



And in any case, if Quebec really cared about Laïcité, they would take the damn cross out of their flag. 🇲🇶 (Not technically the Quebec flag, but it looks similar from a distance. Instead of snakes, the Quebec flag as fleur de lis, which is a symbol associated with St. Joan and the French monarchy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43267917099.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really care if something is "important" to someone. Seeing all the matches of the team they support is very important to the ultra fans. So what? That shouldn't allow them to skip school/work. The point is that in your own time you're free to do whatever you like about your religion or your sports team and wear whatever clothes you like, but in school or work you need to adhere to rules there no matter how important you think the thing that you really really want to wear is to you.

The point I'm trying to make is that in secular society we shouldn't raise religion on any higher pedestal than all other things that people may have inside their head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43268625809.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The point I'm trying to make is that in secular society we shouldn't raise religion on any higher pedestal than all other things that people may have inside their head.

But the banning of wearing religious symbols DOES that.

There is no law preventing students from wearing symbols important to their sports teams. Or fashion brand they like.  But religion is treated differently. 


Again, until they take the cross off the flag, I cannot believe that they are being sincere about wanting to remove all religion from public space. They just want to effect certain religions. Ones that aren't the Catholic majority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43269295230.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about religious exceptions. If a religious scarf is allowed on the basis that "it's really really important" for that person while all other headgear are banned then that is wrong. That was my argument for your "important" argument. If want to move goalposts on that, then feel free to do so but I'm not going to go there. If not then address the point why religion should be treated as more "important" to people than other things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43270114256.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, I thought you were agreeing with the law. Which as it stands, bans religious symbols specifically and says nothing about other symbols.


Here is the reason I'm that I oppose religious symbols bans. 

1: I think that the government exists to serve the people, not the other way around. I think that anytime you ban something you have to have a good reason for it. This would apply to everything. I would question it everytime. 


2: Religion is something that you cannot decide to change your mind on. And it's not something we can prove in any direction. What if Allah is God, and Mohammed is his messenger? I can't disprove that. Neither can you.

3: Religion is EXTREMELY important to people in ways that other beliefs are simply not. 

4: I think that by showing a basic level of respect to people's beliefs, they are going to like you more. Personally, that doesn't really matter, someone will just think you are a dickhead. But when someone feels that the State hates thier beliefs, *very bad things* happen.


So in summation, I think that the government should make reasonable accommodations to religious people. A Sikh is going to have his turban on all the time anyway, so forcing him to take it off for a photo ID makes no sense. However, if a Muslim woman has her face fully covered, her photo ID would be completely useless. So in that case the DMV person should work with them to find something they are reasonably happy with. But that picture is being taken with the face visible, no two ways about that.

As long as it seems like you are making a good faith attempt to accommodate, I think you are in the clear. 

You don't leave the person fucking hating you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43270953607.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding your point 2, I can't change the sports team I support any more than a religious person can change their religion. For 3, for ultras supporting their club is everything life. On the other hand most Western people are so called cultural Christians which means that the religion plays almost no role in their every day life.

My point is that people can have strong beliefs that are not religious. If you put the religious beliefs on a pedestal, you're trampling these other strong beliefs that people may have. 

I have no problem respecting whatever people think is important to them but I have no reason to lift type of a belief over others. Do you agree with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43271968131.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't met any Ultras, but I don't think they feel like they have done something bad if they take off their teams hat in public. Maybe they do though?

If so, that is kind of the same.


The reason that Religion is the exemption is that it there are much fewer of them and they are more centralized in beliefs. 


There is also an element of bias too for historical reasons. People have been oppressed based on religion a lot in our country's history, so laws were written to prevent that.


I take it you oppose France and Quebec's vision of Laïcité ? If so I think we are fully in agreement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43276408805.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>What does it matter that religions are centralized? At the end of the day they are all social constructs like everything else (such as the sports teams). They should not get any privileges based on history. Rather the opposite. Historical precedent shows how religions put oppression on people who don't belong to the religion, including affecting their private lives. The opposite is not true. Secular societies do not limit religious people's religious practices as long as they are done in private.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43276441045.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>It's a lot easier to make accommodations to 1 million people of 10 different groups, then 1 million people of 10 000 different groups.

&gt;Secular societies do not limit religious people's religious practices as long as they are done in private.

We can do so much better though. Having the right to practice your religion so long as nobody sees it is was defacto possible in Nazi Germany. 

I see no good reason to ban people from wearing religious symbols when in public.

It doesn't effect anyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43270939451.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Actually you have a really good point, and I have changed my view slightly.

Yes, religion is in category of beliefs I will call "totalizing" because of how important they are to the believer 


But they are not the only beliefs in that category.


A paranoid schizophrenic has a totalizing belief. 

So does a "aliens are trying to prove my butthole" conspiracy theorist.

If someone wants to keep their tinfoil hat on so that the aliens don't come and probe them, if there is no REALLY good reason for them to no wear it, then sure, why not. Obviously if they are getting an MRI, it would have to come off.

Similarly, if they made demands for action from other people, it would be fine to reject that. But if it is just things they are doing, who cares?




I don't think it's very common that all headware is banned. The only example I can think of is photo ID. In that case making an exception for things that someone wears "religiously" (lol) makes sense, because it will aid identification.

Yes, someone can disguise themselves, but that was always an option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43276461354.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding your last point, niqab and burqa are probably the best possible ways to disguise yourself. They are on the same level as the masks we wore 2 years ago and at that time people were asked to remove the masks when identification was required.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43276540533.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>That would be one of the cases where yes, you do actually have to see the person's face, and it is justified to demand they take them off to verify ID.


But like the face masks, you can still have them on at all other points in time.


I think I've only had to verify my ID 3 times in the last year, and two of those times were to buy alcohol, and once at the request of US people in order to get on their boat to look at it.

So I could have had a face mask on 24/7 if I really wanted to. (And pass on the booze and boat)

That means that someone has the same right to a niqab.

(Unless they live in Quebec, where they have less rights)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238283617.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Either security is more important than religion and nobody gets to wear their caps, or religion is more important than security and therefore all people should be able to wear headgear without proclaiming that their religion says so.




This is a false dichotomy. Getting peoples pictures in how they normally look is good security. As such getting a picture of a Sikh guy with a turban or a hijabi Muslim woman is good security practice its what they normally look like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238419830.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Therefore I should be able to wear a hat in my photo, because I normally wear hats, this is how I normally look.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238523394.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>If you normally wear hats *at every occasion* while out in public, without fail, and do not remove said hat, even in situations where removal of headgear in a social setting is the norm, e.g. formal events, job interviews, etc, and the hats you wear are relatively uniform in appearance....


Then I would say you have a decent case to appeal to the highest court in your country that from a security standpoint, it is prudent to take any identification photo of you with your particular headgear on.




If its just a case of "Nah bruv, I just like wearing hats a lot", but you'll take it off when you want to and the circumstances demand it, then no.


Because we are dealing with two different levels of adherence here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238888654.0" user="PsyPup" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;even in situations where removal of headgear in a social setting is the norm, e.g. formal events, job interviews, etc, and the hats you wear are relatively uniform in appearance....

The point is that, if it's okay for one group to wear a hat because of their religious groups, then this shouldn't be an abnormal thing for anyone. 

Religion isn't something you're born with, it's something you're taught, it is a choice people make. It should not be considered any more important than "Nah bruv, I just like wearing hats a lot"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239643867.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The point is that, if it's okay for one group to wear a hat because of their religious groups, then this shouldn't be an abnormal thing for anyone. 



And my point is that, the reason why not wearing a hat is needed in identification photos does not apply to individuals who wear it for religious or deeply cultural reasons. The purpose is identification, and it is unlikely that they will forgo that item of clothing in their daily life, in any aspect of their daily life. 


If you want to be legalist fine, but that now belies the practical reasoning behind the concept in favour of "everyone needs to do it, because"

&gt;Religion isn't something you're born with, it's something you're taught, it is a choice people make. It should not be considered any more important than "Nah bruv, I just like wearing hats a lot"



In theory yes. In practice no, religion is generally instilled from an early age, and considered to be akin to deeply held cultural practices, where concepts like viewing it as an elective choice are limited.  




You can take the world as it should be, or take the world as it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240866949.0" user="Lisentho" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; you have a decent case to appeal to the highest court in your country that from a security standpoint, it is prudent to take any identification photo of you with your particular headgear on

Never gonna happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244042335.0" user="SonOfShem" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Because we are dealing with two different levels of adherence here.

I think this is something most people are glossing over.  A muslim woman may literally refuse to go out without a hijab.  A random man who "never goes anywhere without his hat" probably only actually wears it 80% of the time.

But there's an additional consideration: what is the 'cost' to the person to remove their head covering?  For anyone, a turban will have a higher cost (in terms of time) for removing than a baseball hat. Plus there may be an emotional or spiritual cost tied to the person's religion.  A random guy who likes hats does not have the same emotional cost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238307681.0" user="RogueNarc" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's just allowed by compromise or exception because there are (in the view of the people making the rules) greater issues at issue. The exception is a compromise with detriments. It doesn't justify making the exception universal. If that undermining ability is spread to everyone, that's spreading the detriment.

Arguably fairness is a justification for equal application. That there exists an exemption for religious belief should permit an exemption for secular belief unless a state wants to start justifying beliefs on a basis other than the people who hold them. In that case, the government has stepped into the field of trying to prove religion. What's the difference between a sincere religious belief about headwear and a sincere secular belief about headwear?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238316205.0" user="RogueNarc" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's just allowed by compromise or exception because there are (in the view of the people making the rules) greater issues at issue. The exception is a compromise with detriments. It doesn't justify making the exception universal. If that undermining ability is spread to everyone, that's spreading the detriment.

Arguably fairness is a justification for equal application. That there exists an exemption for religious belief should permit an exemption for secular belief unless a state wants to start justifying beliefs on a basis other than the people who hold them. In that case, the government has stepped into the field of trying to prove religion. What's the difference between a sincere religious belief about headwear and a sincere secular belief about headwear?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237758158.0" user="shhhOURlilsecret" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Muslims to wear turbans,

Muslims don't wear turbans. Sikhs wear turbans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237868950.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Oops. Editing.

The point remains, and is actually accintuated by the fact that I didn't know the specific needs of the religion in question. We shouldn't need to have a list of beliefs and their specific exceptions, to check and see whether a person has the appropriate belief system that warrants the exception. If a Muslim wanted to wear a turban and told me it was part of his religion, even though it's not, how would we determine whether that accomodation is acceptable? The answer should just be the same for everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241663040.0" user="Kiwilolo" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of Muslims wear turbans. There are different styles of turbans all over the place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237962593.0" user="Green__lightning" delta="False">
    <text>My religion categorically bans photography, as it considers any permanent image of the self to be a form of idolatry, as well as being magically powerful, being a potential focus of curses back towards the user. How do you suggest I get a driver's license?  

Admittedly this religion doesn't exist, as much as I'd like to found a religion specifically to fight the surveillance state, but this is hardly more restrictive than some existing religions, such as anyone wanting to have their ID photo taken in a full burqa or similar. 

Secondly, there are perfectly valid secular reasons to do much of the same things, like specific clothing and food choice, taking regular extra breaks, and refusing to do things based on some level of dignity, and yet doing so isn't treated as valid. I propose starting a religion that's basically a human rights union, so you can say anything that breaks those rights is against your religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238471613.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>I'm with you on all points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242716352.0" user="AlonnaReese" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, there are Christian sects that disallow photography because it's considered a violation of the biblical law prohibiting the creation of graven images. Some governments do make an effort to accommodate those individuals. For example, the state of Indiana will issue photo-less IDs to people who have a sincerely held religious belief against appearing in a picture ([Source](https://faqs.in.gov/hc/en-us/articles/360040514231-How-do-I-obtain-a-photo-exempt-identification-card-from-the-BMV-)).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255748789.0" user="Iceykitsune2" delta="False">
    <text>Except that the link you provided states that a photo is still taken, just not printed on the ID.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238580772.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>That's why it's called "reasonable accomodation" and not just "accomodation". It's making a small exception to a rule to accomodate certain people. Like if you just want to wear a hat in your ID, no you can't. You could change your hat or not wear it to look like someone else. If your specific religious beliefs mandate that you always wear a turban of a certain style, we can make an exception because your circumstances are a bit different from the typical person.

Basically, we need rules in general to maintain order. Many, many people cannot comply with every single rule exactly as written for various reasons, but providing them a small exception won't cause problems. Providing everyone an exception if one person gets the exception would be chaos.

You say an inclusive environment is hindered by exceptions, but it's quite the opposite. Failure to make small accomodations will instead deter interactions between cultures. If you won't let Muslims pray during their prayer times, they'll just not work for that employer. They'll stick to working for other Muslims, and it'll cause divides in society. Same with governments not making such accomodations. If Sikhs can't wear turbans, they'll stay out of that country and go somewhere where they aren't persecuted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239577945.0" user="Natural-Arugula" delta="False">
    <text>It's more like the opposite, everyone can wear a hat, except a turban, or a yarmulke, or a hijab.

The effect is that I'm allowed there as a practicing Satanist, or whatever religion that doesn't require head garb, where all other religions are banned just because they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239612251.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. Hence my stance that rules like that shouldnt exist in the first place. Either ir applies to everyone, or to no one, or it's a shitty rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241983229.0" user="Fickle-Area246" delta="False">
    <text>You’re demanding uniformity in a world that is not, and should not be, uniform. Creating successful culturally diverse societies requires adapting to actual facts. Which includes the different needs of those different cultures. Compromise is important all the time. And being exclusionary is counter to being respectful of different cultures. If anything, though, the fact that religious people need exceptions to a rule shows that perhaps the rule is too authoritarian to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243231312.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>All societies becoming a diverse mosaic of parallel cultures can also be seen a step towards uniformity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243352212.0" user="Angdrambor" delta="False">
    <text>"Reasonable accommodations" also gets used for ppl with disabilities. 

As an autistic kid, A quiet room in school would have solved a lot of my problems.  I would be practicing mindfulness and resetting and calming myself down in there. 

A quiet room is a completely reasonable accommodation, irrespective of why the student needs it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243482945.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed that it's reasonable. Disagree that they should be exceptions, instead of just the standard available to everyone.

I mostly have a problem with the idea that there would be a system in place to determine whether someone "needs" that special accomodation. How would you prove you were autistic (or religious) enough to warrant that special exception? Why is it not more equitable to simply have a room that is quiet, neutral, and available to anyone who wanted to meditate or pray or disassociate or whatever there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243550818.0" user="SonOfShem" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'm of the stance that the rules should simply not hinder those people in the first place. An inclusove environment should never require that reasoble religious people should need exceptions.

This is silly.  Rules have goals, and they are designed to achieve those goals.  But in a diverse society, those rules may not produce that same goal for everyone.

The purpose of an ID law is to be able to ID people.  If it's easy to remove the head covering (like a hat) and it is only sometimes worn, then it is better to remove because you can remove it when being ID'd if necessary.

If the head covering is harder to remove (either from a religious or practical perspective), is always worn, but it only covers the hair, then the purpose of identification is fulfilled better with the covering than without it.

But, even if the head covering is harder to remove, and even if it is always worn, if it completely blocks the face, then it completely defeats the purpose of identification to be able to take the photo with it.  So wearing that is clearly not ok.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238314059.0" user="catfacemcpoopybutt" delta="False">
    <text>If your religion requires a prayer room in the school for you to go there then it's notreasonable, it's psychotic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249860495.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that it requires a prayer room in the school it's that it requires prayer at certain specific times of day and there's people who deemed a prayer room more reasonable than forcing all people of that religion to homeschool or make them waste more class time traveling back and forth to pray at home but still go to school</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252797676.0" user="catfacemcpoopybutt" delta="False">
    <text>Which is psychotic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238586790.0" user="Budget-Razzmatazz-54" delta="False">
    <text>If schools had specific Christian Prayer rooms in the US, millions  people would lose their minds and scream aboit separation of church and state. 

And I would agree. 

We could also go down a rabbit hole of what constitutes a reasonable accommodation or what even constitutes a religion or belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241301078.0" user="MIGHTY_ILLYRIAN" delta="False">
    <text>Not giving concessions to any religion is a way of preventing the school from being affiliated with any religion, which is the point of secularism. The opposite of that, i.e. giving concessions to every religion, is the opposite of secularism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241544807.0" user="NorthernerWuwu" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, in Quebec it does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241980655.0" user="No_add" delta="False">
    <text>He might be coming at it from a french secularist standpoint or "Lacïté", which is closer to "freedom from religious influence", than "freedom of religion".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243585986.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Making reasonable accommodations for people who need it to help them participate

Could you elaborate what exactly you mean by this. I mean, if someone has legs broken, it makes sense to let that person bring crutches to school. If someone is extremely vulnerable to common colds, it makes sense that they are allowed to wear a mask in the classroom.

But if someone thinks that a magic fairy really really wants them to wear pointy hat in the classroom where otherwise headgear is banned, should they be allowed to do so? 

All religious reasons are of the latter and not the former kind. 

I'm fine making rules such that religious people can participate, but then those rules have to apply to everyone equally as the religious reason is no different than "I really really think that I should do X".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
