<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237296786.0" user="Hairy_S_TrueMan" delta="False">
    <text>You have to be mindful about how your "neutral" religious policies affects different religions. Schools often *do* allow religious jewelry to accommodate Christians. Even if your position is blanket application across all religions, that's not necessarily what the actions you're defending are. 

Western society is already built to accommodate Christians in sneaky ways. Christians will never have school on Sunday. Extracurriculars that span into the weekend will generally go to Saturday instead. Every Christian always has Christmas off without having to make up any work or excuse their absence. Easter they have off because the school schedule is based on their religious calendar. 

If nobody gets any conscious accommodation, the majority religion wins out and minority religions get snubbed. It seems fair to give everybody nothing, but it's not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250350985.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Also conveniently, Christianity is one of the few religions that doesn't mandate religious clothing.

I find such actions from a province with a cross on their flag highly suspect.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
