<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="84" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43240670666.0" user="GlassPeepo" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not against having a "prayer room" in schools for the kids who actually want/need to use it throughout the day. And I'm not against religions clothing or jewelry. Regardless of religion. I'm no expert, I don't know the ins and outs of every religion or when and how they pray. If you, 10 years old, need to go pray for a minute at lunch time, that's fine. The rooms should just be there as an option for anyone who might need it, but it should never be used in a "okay kids, follow mrs smith to the prayer room to learn about Jesus" type of way. Let students have access to their own personal religions and whatever accommodations they may need, and leave it at that. Schools should be a safe space for kids of any religious background, but schools do not need to be *teaching* religion in any way. Let it happen, and try not to influence it one way or the other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
