<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237176886.0" user="Atticus104" delta="False">
    <text>There is a difference between enforcing religion and barring reglion. As a secular organzation, it should not be enforcing relgious beliefs or practices on in't staff or students by requiring them to paritipate in relgious rights and rules.   


However, the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms garentess everyone the freedom of reglioin, meaning they should be allowed to practice their beleifs so long as their means to do so does not infringe on the rights of another. Personal religous garb like necklaces, hijabs, turbans, and  yarmulke are protected under the charter.   


The logistics may prevent a facility from having a dedicated prayer room, but students should not be barred from praying, as again it would violate the charter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250372762.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms

Notwithstanding clause go brrrr.


Honestly not sure why we have a constitution (insofar as we have one) if we can just blatantly ignore it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
