<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237630968.0" user="Dedli" delta="False">
    <text>"France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that."

Disagree here. Youre disregarding an awful lot of opinions as "doesn't matter" for no discernable reason.

Secular doesn't mean religion is excluded, but that all (and lack thereof) are included. No one is forced or pressured to say Praise Jesus, and nobody is forced or pressured not to.

If any logos are allowed on clothing, religious symbols should be allowed too. If any headgear is allowed, then it shouldn't matter whether someone has a deep and emotional connection to it. Why force them to admit it one way or the other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238269915.0" user="ArCSelkie37" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of people were upset about it at the time and now. Same as when they were planning to ban hijabs in public a while back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250345574.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Mfw the province with the cross on the flag says that they are sincere in thier beliefs of secularism 🤨🤨🧐</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
