<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="68" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43239019562.0" user="sisnitermagus" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing to argue. It's should never be aloud in schools</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254895314.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>My brother in Christ, why are people so anti religious on this thread? You are literally attempting to block people from their religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255464020.0" user="sisnitermagus" delta="False">
    <text>Religion is a personal matter. Keep that shit at home and stop trying to force your Religion on other people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255831388.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>Allowing someone to practice their religion is not equal to forcing them to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256497821.0" user="sisnitermagus" delta="False">
    <text>Prayer in school and promoting one religion over another is it being forced on people. You can practice your religion all you want in your home and churches. Keep it out of the public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256589834.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>Praying in school is forcing it upon someone? I'm going to try and understand that logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256682326.0" user="sisnitermagus" delta="False">
    <text>If a kid is paying on their own, no problem. Once the school gets involved in the payer in any way. It is indoctrination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260033625.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't a thread about indoctrination. It's a thread about the right to practice your religion</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
