<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237481002.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of the public education system is not to "educate" but to make healthy members of society.  Its why public education systems spend time discussing sexual health, family relationships, playing sports, and having social clubs. 

* People that practice diet and exercise live healthier lives. 
* People that practice a religion have more stable and healthier lives. 
* People that feel apart of a community have more stable and healthier lives. 
* People that are educated in sexuality and safe sex live healthier lives. 

Banning religion is the equivalent of banning gay people. It doesn't work and you look bigoted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245690183.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People that practice a religion have more stable and healthier lives.

Proof?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43246482056.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>There’s endless resources and studies reaching this conclusion. (Point of clarification: I’m not religious.)

https://www.pewresearch.org/religion/2019/01/31/religions-relationship-to-happiness-civic-engagement-and-health-around-the-world/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253165468.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>What I got from this is that religious people are happier, might live longer according to some studies but don't have better physical health:

The exact nature of the connections between religious participation, happiness, civic engagement and health remains unclear and needs further study. While the data presented in this report indicate that there are links between religious activity and certain measures of well-being in many countries, the numbers do not prove that going to religious services is directly responsible for improving people’s lives. Rather, it could be that certain kinds of people tend to be active in multiple types of activities (secular as well as religious), many of which may provide physical or psychological benefits.5 Moreover, such people may be more active partly because they are happier and healthier, rather than the other way around. (For more information about what may be causing these links, see this sidebar.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253429886.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>Yep.

&gt;People who practice religion have more stable and healthier lives.

* "A large volume of research shows that people who are more Religious/Spiritual (R/S) have better mental health and adapt more quickly to health problems compared to those who are less r/S. These possible benefits to mental health and well-being have physiological consequences that impact physical health, affect the risk of disease, and influence response to treatment. ([3](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3671693/))
* “Religion gives them hope, meaning, and a sense of purpose. (1)” 
* "Religiosity and country level of development play a significant role in shaping people’s subjective well-being. ([2](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6182728/))"

&amp;#x200B;

Every scientific study has returned results showing religion contributing to a healthier and more adaptable (stable is the word I used) individual. 

Sure, religious people get drunk and do crazy stuff like the rest of humanity but statistically its less likely and they're more likely to be healthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253465014.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>They may be more mentally healthy (because delusions like religion are designed to do that) but not more physically healthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253821772.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;delusions 

I'd hesitate to call them delusions. Unless you think all of human culture is a delusion? I hesitate to call anything other people do with their personal time delusional or wrong, especially if it doesn't harm me. 

Humans have been religious creatures since the start and they will continue to be so long-long-long after you're gone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253858867.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>Believing in a magical sky daddy is delusional, period.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253942278.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>No more of less delusional than thinking all of existence happened due to a "big bang" or any other human explanation.  

Either God created something, all of existence was created from absolutely nothing, or [nothing is real](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solipsism).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253975531.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;No more of less delusional than thinking all of existence happened due to a "big bang" or any other human explanation.

We have scientific evidence that points us in that direction at the very least. What do you have? 2000 year old texts written by Jewish men with heatstroke or Arabs who loved diddling kids? Or maybe some Hindu bullshit written by old people who discovered mushrooms and drugs?

&gt;Either God created something, 

Then who created sky daddy?

&gt;all of existence was created from absolutely nothing, 

Likely.

&gt;or nothing is real.

Likely too. Maybe the universe is like Minecraft where you are the main character and everything loads around you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254066859.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What do you have? 2000 year old texts written by Jewish men with heatstroke or Arabs who loved diddling kids?

Religious people have a set of principles and guiding practices refined over thousands of years that set a healthy and productive life. All religions carry  commonalities that make people's lives more productive, healthier, and happier (as supported by my earlier scientific studies). It also gives people a moral compass that is good for society. Further, it gives them a social group of people who can care and support each other. 

**Again, as I disclosed earlier, I'm not religious.**  

I'm not about to call religious people feeding homeless people and not drinking their face off on Saturday night so that they can get to Church on Sunday a problem or delusional.

If I'm hiring someone to take care of my kids or to work on my house, **I'll take the church-going person over the atheist people everyday.** 

Whats funny is that most atheist turn their political opinions into their religion and they end up being the most crazy and jaded people you find in society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254379578.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Religious people have a set of principles and guiding practices refined over thousands of years that set a healthy and productive life. All religions carry  commonalities that make people's lives more productive, healthier, and happier (as supported by my earlier scientific studies). 

While I can't technically disagree, I do wonder how these studies were conducted, what sample size was taken and what the scientists consider happier and more productive. 

&gt;It also gives people a moral compass that is good for society. 

How has it been good for society exactly? Religion has been the cause for countless wars and genocides. If you need an ancient fantasy fanfic to be a good person, you aren't.

&gt;Further, it gives them a social group of people who can care and support each other.

That is likely the reason why they're happier. Loneliness is a killer and cults like these tend to make people socialize more amongst the cultists. 

&gt;Again, as I disclosed earlier, I'm not religious.

Good for you, though I doubt out.

&gt;I'm not about to call religious people feeding homeless people and not drinking their face off on Saturday night so that they can get to Church on Sunday a problem or delusional.

That part I have no problem with and isn't delusional.

&gt;If I'm hiring someone to take care of my kids or to work on my house, I'll take the church-going person over the atheist people everyday.

So you're discriminating against potential employees due to religion or lack thereof? Isn't that illegal? And stupid considering atheists are smarter than the religious?

&gt;Whats funny is that most atheist turn their political opinions into their religion and they end up being the most crazy and jaded people you find in society.

I don't think atheists are the ones beheading people in the Middle East pal. Nor are they the ones killing LGBTQ people in Africa and the USA. I'm starting to think you're either lying to me about being religious or you're just an idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254792066.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;...what sample size was taken and what the scientists consider happier and more productive.

One of those studies retained over 44,000 people in it. Each from reputable scientific sources. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;So you're discriminating against potential employees due to religion or lack thereof? Isn't that illegal? And stupid considering atheists are smarter than the religious?

I was making a point.  If someone is part of a moral organization that I'm familiar with then I will consider that a benefit. To me, its the same as any other character filtering criteria. You vet people based on their history, affiliations, and their current network (references). And I don't consider church to be better or worse than a mosque, temple, etc.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;I don't think atheists are the ones beheading people in the Middle East pal.

Sure, the Christian or Muslim-run countries do plenty of violent stuff. And the non-religious countries do violent stuff. The self-declared atheist China is currently committing genocide on the Uyghurs. There's no correlation between religion and violence. People are violent - full stop.

People always retort "the Christian crusades!" but those wars were for the same reason everyone fought wars: expansion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255040874.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;One of those studies retained over 44,000 people in it. Each from reputable scientific sources.

Did they capture different economic factors, racial factors, gender etc? I don't think that 44,000 (as you claim with no evidence) would be enough of a sample size to make that bold statement about atheists in general.

&gt;I was making a point.  If someone is part of a moral organization that I'm familiar with then I will consider that a benefit. To me, its the same as any other character filtering criteria. You vet people based on their history, affiliations, and their current network (references). And I don't consider church to be better or worse than a mosque, temple, etc.

So it's basically "you belong in my cult so I'll choose you over others"? You do realize that's one of the main criticisms of religion right?

&gt;Sure, the Christian or Muslim-run countries do plenty of violent stuff. And the non-religious countries do violent stuff. The self-declared atheist China is currently committing genocide on the Uyghurs. There's no correlation between religion and violence. People are violent - full stop.  
&gt;  
&gt;People always retort "the Christian crusades!" but those wars were for the same reason everyone fought wars: expansion.

Nope, religious people tend to be more violent. Again I don't tend to see atheists burning buses in Sweden over one person threatening to burn a ~~fanfic~~ holy book. I also don't tend to see atheists pass laws against LGBTQ people. And as for the Chinese that's a political not a religious based genocide. The Chinese want to control Uyghur territory by any means necessary. There is no anti-religious intent really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260078520.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Did they capture different economic factors, racial factors, gender etc? I don't think that 44,000 (as you claim with no evidence) would be enough of a sample size to make that bold statement about atheists in general.

The studies I provided were from the National Institute of Health (NIH) and UC Berkeley. If you think their efforts were outside of scientific study procedures then I'm happy for you to provide conflicting scientific studies from reputable sources.

Simply stating "religion has caused endless wars" or inferring a-religious people are happier without evidence or support isn't helpful. Worse, saying people are "delusional" because of your perception of events is akin to a child's ability to debate ("everyone is stupid but me!"). You're making statements based on your opinions and beliefs without any supporting evidence.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;basically "you belong in my cult so I'll choose you over others"? You do realize that's one of the main criticisms of religion right?

Correct. Humans look for people that are in their clan (standard stuff in sociology). In addition to their history, affiliations, and their current network, I also filter people based on language, nationality, locality, and level of education.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Nope, religious people tend to be more violent.

Proof? Please site scientific sources. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;The Chinese want to control Uyghur territory by any means necessary. There is no anti-religious intent really.

You do realize that the Uyghurs are a primarily Muslim group?  And that China [banned all practice of Islam](https://www.hrw.org/news/2018/09/12/chinas-muslim-ban)?  But even if you were to say "no, they only care about their ethnicity - that's what they want to erase" (which is not true), I'd point to the Tibetan people. [China invaded](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_rights_in_Tibet) and destroyed Temples and any form of religion along the way. [Chinas problem](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annexation_of_Tibet_by_the_People%27s_Republic_of_China) with Tibetan people is that they are Buddhist and listen to the Dalai Lama, not that they're another ethnicity. 

&amp;#x200B;

You're handling of this conversation is akin to the ignorant politician trying to convince someone of something because you "feel" its true. What evidence do you have for anything you say?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
