<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237130968.0" user="vanoroce14" delta="False">
    <text>The main purpose of school is for students to learn material that will help them develop their potential AND for them to learn how to exist peacefully and productively in their society. 

Based on this, forbidding *the students* to wear religuous symbols and not reasonably accomodating religious or philosophical practices goes against the purpose of school. I would *much rather* my kid learn that muslims, christians, jews, sikhs, and so on exist, and how to interact with them. I would much rather *that* be a lesson taught in school. 

No, what has no place is the endorsement of any religion, or the imposition of any religion by the school. That I vehemently oppose. 

Also, quick note. You say: 

&gt;France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.

This is, quite frankly, disgusting. You're essentially saying French muslim's opinions don't matter. While I don't necessarily understand the practice of wearing hijab, and would support anyone not wanting to do so out of their own volition, forbidding it / forcing people to not wear it crosses a line. And European anti hijab laws aren't even fair in how they are written or enforced. They have a clear anti inmigrant and anti muslim bias.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
