<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="65" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43238737704.0" user="The_Intolerant_One70" delta="False">
    <text>There are private religious schools, so on the one hand, I could say you have a point, BUT then a number of things would have to be in place to make it fair across the board. Those choosing a private education should have the school tax removed from property taxes so they can put it towards the private school costs. Another thing is, as you say, religion should not be promoted or forced  in the public sector. Fair enough, but that same standard should be applied from the other end where secular curriculum (IE gender ideology) should not be forced or promoted in the religious schools. The one area, both public and private schools, should have a core common agreement with any province is in the area of educational curriculum that will benefit the children for future adulthood. That would be the obvious,  Grammer, reading, arithmetic,  history, language arts, etc. This way, religious schools will not have to incorporate themes such as Halloween or Pride week, and public schools can cancel Christmas and Easter. Then, hopefully, everyone will be one big happy clam!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
