<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237117779.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>What problem are you trying to solve by banning all expressions of religion in school? You are proposing impinging on many people's personal freedom (freedom to practice their religion, freedom to dress how they want), so I presume there is a compelling reason? You have not identified what benefit you are trying to achieve, or what harm you are trying to prevent.

&amp;#x200B;

The idea of laicite is that if we pretend no one is religious then we won't have any problems with religion. But pretending doesn't make it so, people will still be religious. This means there are 2 major consequences with this approach:

1. Students or teachers who are part of a religion impacted by this will feel like they aren't welcome by the school, by the provincial government. If they aren't welcome, then why should they care about the school or government or society, when it just makes their lives hard for no reason? 
2. People will not realize how many religious people of different religions they know in their community, and makes it easier to "other" religious groups - after all people think they don't know any because people don't necessarily feel comfortable disclosing their religion in that environment.

These both work to increase conflict and reduce societal unity.

In contrast, multiculturalism works on the idea that there are core values of respect, tolerance, and human rights everyone needs to follow, but outside of that we should celebrate our differences and diversity. In a multicultural society you personally know many people of different religions, and know they attend your school, work in the government, and live in your community. As a result they are less likely to be viewed as "other" because they are seen as being part of other social groups. 

Laicete thinks different religions can't get along so we need to remove religion everywhere, while multiculturalism thinks different religions can get along if you are part of the same community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237486970.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>How's it freedom if you're being brainwashed since you were literally born?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237639079.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;How's it freedom if you're being brainwashed since you were literally born?

Freedom to practice your religion. Being prevented from doing something is obviously a reduction in freedom. The reason for someone's religious beliefs doesn't change that. 

Could you define how you are using the term brainwashing? Because if you are saying any religious belief is the result of brainwashing, then so are all social norms, a huge portion of morality, and belief that the earth is round. Just telling your children what to believe isn't brainwashing. 

I would note that preventing people from any religious expression at school will reduce the amount of exposure to other religions and viewpoints children get, by making religion a taboo topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237684253.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>Religion should be a taboo topic, it's useless and it belongs to the past. And it is brainwashing, people would take issue with it if it was a cult, but when it's a religion, it is sadly still normalized. social norms, morality, etc that benefit children and society are different from religions and all the other made up fairy tales that do nothing other than harming the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238046045.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; social norms, morality, etc that benefit children and society are

Most social norms don't have a benefit outside of group cohesion, and could be swapped out with other norms. For instance shaking hands is a social norm, but you could replace that with doing the chicken dance with very little impact. Wearing clothes is a social norm which has no clear benefit when walking down the street. Needing a shirt in many establishments is a social norm with no clear benefit. Is teaching our kids they can't run around the neighborhood naked brainwashing? The only reason we need to teach them that is because of social norms. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt; religions and all the other made up fairy tales that do nothing other than harming the world.

The church my mom went to also operated a soup kitchen, ran a thrift store which hired people who needed job experience to get employment. They organize meal prep for people in the church who are going through health issues. They did that because of religion, and I think you would agree that providing food to low-income and people experiencing homelessness is good. If religions only cause harm, then by definition you think soup kitchens are bad. My sister donates 10% of her income to charity (not churches, things like MSF, sponsoring children in developing countries to go to school), because of her religious beliefs.  If religion only harms the world, donating to charity is also bad according to you.

&amp;#x200B;

You can have your own beliefs, but in my opinion a framework which claims soup kitchens, aid for people in developing countries, and creating a community where people give each other meals when in need is "harming the world", is a morally bankrupt framework. 

For what it's worth I'm an atheist and also gay, so don't come at me claiming I just think that because I'm religious or not the target for many people with religious beliefs. I just don't have religious trauma because my family has always been very supportive and kind, so I have no problem recognizing the positives of religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238079022.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>Your mom could do all of that without a church, my mom is an atheist and she does volunteering Jobs and other charities, you can't ignore all the bad religions have done, cause it far far more outweighs the good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238333184.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but she does it with religion. "Your mom could do all that with religion, my mom is a Christian she does volunteering jobs and other charities."

You see how ridiculous that sounds? People can do good a million different ways, you can't just dismiss the good people do because it wasn't the specific way you want them to.

Also, I can't  help but note you attribute anything good someone does to them being a good person, and anything bad someone does to be because of religion. That is an obviously terrible way to do it, and can make any group of people wou want be terrible.

Finally I don't at all think the religion has done more bad than good claim is at all clear, and is entirely dependent on the location and time period you are measuring, and how you attribute actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238238625.0" user="TheSavior666" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; if you think religions are bad, by definition you think soup kitchens are bad.

Religions did not invent soup kitchens nor are they inherently religious in any sense.

So no, you can hate religion while having no issue with charity - because religion is not a requirement to have charities or support for the poor.

None of that is a positive of religion unless you can demonstrate these things wouldn’t exist without religious people.

That’s an obviously ridiculous assumptions, so the examples of religious people doing good things is totally irrelevant to if religion itself is good. 

Do you think your mother and sister would entirely ignore and scorn poor people if they weren’t religious?  Of course not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238473034.0" user="DRB_Can" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I should have quoted them exactly there. They said "religions and all the other made up fairy tales that do nothing other than harming the world.".

If religions do nothing other than harming the world, then everything a religion does harms the world.

If a religion tells people to wave hello, that harms the world according to them. If religions tell people to not litter, then telling people to not litter is bad according. Even more fun, if one religion tells people to support LGBT rights and another tells people to oppose them, then both supporting and opposing LGBT rights is bad according to them. Their statement is an absolute that is absurd to apply, and results in completely nonsensical conclusions.


Religious people running a soup kitchen is just as good as non-religious people running a soup kitchen. You can't say that religious people would still be nice without religion, but religious people who do bad things are only doing bad things because of religion. Either religion doesn't matter to what people do (good and bad), or it does matter to what people do (good and bad).

They wouldn't scorn people, but they probably wouldn't  do as much. Their religious moral framework makes direct intervention the primary directive. If their moral framework was replaced with a random one from society (Canada), it's likely their moral framework would prioritize themselves much more based on the behaviour of the general population in Canada. For instance only 25% of tax filers donate to a registered charity in Canada. If they had an "average" sense of morality they would not donate to charity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239429020.0" user="ge93" delta="False">
    <text>Well-said. 

As well, in Quebec’s context the discussion of laicite is explicitly rooted in xenophobia and is targeted towards minority religions (“a 2 vitesses”. )The biggest proponents, Drainville and Legault, talk about how “Quebecois are catholics” and Drainville mocked the idea of taking christmas trees out of schools. Not that I personally mind Christmas trees in schools, but the hypocrisy is the issue.


Really, Quebec society isn’t super xenophobic, but this form of xenophobia has become a core part of Quebec soft nationalist values as a manner of distinguishing their values from other Canadians (by trying to be more like France). Who gives a shit about voluntary prayer rooms in schools, schools which have “Holiday Pageants” and “Holidays trees” and are closed Christmas and Easter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250354395.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Also they have a cross on their flag.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
