<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236578529.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>This discriminates against a minority religion that is supposed to have mandatory prayers at certain times of day during school hours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236587082.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the school's problem, pray at home. Why should a public institution care about religion? If a religion says gay is bad, should schools let students beat up gay kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236625873.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>If you're a government employee, you get time to pray. Why should schools be any different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236639996.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>You shouldn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236649559.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>So, you realize you're banning members of a minority religion from participating in public schools and official government offices, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236660771.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>And members of a majority religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236715286.0" user="I_Hate_The_Demiurge" delta="False">
    <text>How? Presumably you mean Christians? You've added no barriers or conditions onto them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236729908.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Christians don't have mandatory times to pray. They can 'just wait until you're home'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237441296.0" user="ArchWaverley" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a Christian, and sometimes I pray at work by taking a moment of silent reflection. To an outsider it looks like I'm sitting at my desk with my eyes closed for 20 seconds. Is this allowed? Should someone ask what I'm thinking about if there's a risk I might be praying on company time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238431603.0" user="ColdJackfruit485" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re ok with discrimination?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236643172.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>Same reason we make reasonable accommodations for those disabled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236646514.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Unlike religions, disabilities are real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236668553.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>Lol religion is as real as democracy, human rights and anti-discrimination laws. 

Religion is a protected class and will be protected by the Canadian supreme Court.

It's the same rationale that requires Canada to provide all govt services in both English and French.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236671941.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>That court upheld the ban iirc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236704135.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>The Quebec court. This will likely be appealed to the supreme Court and evaluated there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236710967.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>And I believe Québec has some degree of autonomy from the rest of Canada, and either way won't obey what the anglophone courts say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236739712.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>You clearly don't understand Canadians political system. Quebec is bound by federal laws, including if schools (provincially managed) infringes on federal rights (protected class). 

This case must go through the provincial system before it will be appealed up to the federal supreme Court. 

Quebec can complain but it cannot infringe on the rights of Canadians. The supreme Court will decide if they must provide dedicated prayer rooms or not. 

They can still pray at school according to the Quebec minister who passed the law so doesn't really agree with your overall argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236947829.0" user="jupiterslament" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Quebec can complain but it cannot infringe on the rights of Canadians. The supreme Court will decide if they must provide dedicated prayer rooms or not.

I'm not saying I disagree that the law should be overturned, but... there's the whole notwithstanding clause. Provinces can basically do whatever the fuck they want as a result of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237161773.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>I've yet to see a provincial law that allows it to violate federal law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237218418.0" user="jupiterslament" delta="False">
    <text>It's happened on numerous occasions... most of them in Quebec. In this case, protected class (religious) rights would fall under section 2 of the charter of rights and freedoms. The [notwithstanding clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Section_33_of_the_Canadian_Charter_of_Rights_and_Freedoms) applies to that, and can allow the law to operate despite the charter. It was used in 2019 by Quebec for their religious laws already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237302074.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>Oh shit you appear to be right. Apparently we wouldn't get any rights without the provincial govt being able to override them. 

Makes the provincial elections much more important than I thought. 

Quebec just fucking whomever they want apparently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236991449.0" user="Mother_Sand_6336" delta="False">
    <text>Either way, it would be illiberal to do so. The Francophone world is more comfortable with the  role of state authority in social matters. It wouldn’t fly in a more Lockean liberal view.

So, I won’t try to debate whether Quebec was within its legal right; that’s for the courts. But there’s good reason for the United States’ separation of church and state. 

As secular institutions serving the public, to me that means they should only consider educationally relevant matters. And even then I’d prohibit them from a policy that leads to such de facto exclusion of some members of the public.

But I value the freedoms of conscience and free expression.

Just because YOU don’t believe in religion doesn’t mean that other fellows with whom we are all trying to liberally coexist don’t take it quite seriously. And since metaphysical debates cannot be settled by empiricism, we leave such to the realms of freedom of conscience. 

So, to me, such a ban seems needlessly authoritarian on the surface. I get it as a reactionary gesture to an influx of Muslims in French society. But, in terms of political science, it uses state power to trample on the freedoms of conscience and expression that I, as an atheist, highly value. 

And I think you should too. Prohibiting one’s citizens from expressing religious beliefs might make governing easier, but I think you prefer freedom of expression and conscience to either the Soviet Union or Catholic France. 

But, if you really just want one of those, then just say so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237482707.0" user="Zestyclose-Bar-8706" delta="False">
    <text>Quebec bypassed the Canadian human charter of rights to pass this law</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236683124.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Religions are self evidently real, otherwise you wouldn’t be making this post. The truth claims within the religions however are separate and may be true or false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236717000.0" user="acquiescentLabrador" delta="False">
    <text>A better take is religion is chosen, disabilities are not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236747785.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Psst.

If you want to make the argument that you're not discriminating against religious people, maybe don't say stuff like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237313870.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Who said I wanted to make the argument that I'm not discriminating against religious people? 

I am, and I don't care. I also discriminate against people that claim to believe in Witchcraft. It's not safe to let crazy people or liars (every religious person is at least one of the two) make policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237402390.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, yes, enlightened by your own euphoria or whatever.

You're in the minority, and making claims like this just makes you look just as irrational.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237884781.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Is there some sort of argument here? I'm right, you just don't like my attitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238460124.0" user="MunMur" delta="False">
    <text>It’s comments like this which is why no one takes your opinion seriously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237479059.0" user="Zestyclose-Bar-8706" delta="False">
    <text>And this shows your true intentions behind the CMV</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258807607.0" user="LebaneseDemonLobster" delta="False">
    <text>Not trying to be rude but are you saying religious people are disabled or purely making a comparison? Because I've seen hardline "Evangelical Atheists" say they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260427666.0" user="Kazthespooky" delta="False">
    <text>No, the point is about making reasonable accommodations for peoples protected classes, including religion. 

The easiest form of accomodation that society generally agrees makes perfect sense is making reasonable accommodations for the disabled. If OP agrees with reasonable accommodations for the disabled they must agree with the concept of reasonable accommodations for all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236932152.0" user="arkayuu" delta="False">
    <text>Praying is an individual act that harms no one else. You can't compare it to beating up kids at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238460922.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; That's not the school's problem, pray at home. 




It is the schools problem, they exist to educate students. The "take it or leave it" mentality can interfere with their education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240301425.0" user="OpeningChipmunk1700" delta="False">
    <text>It is the school’s problem because the school is forcing students to violate their beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249850859.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Islam says you have to pray at certain times of day, meaning if you're not going to allow them means to pray at school you have to either make them be homeschooled or take up even more class time with them shuttling back and forth to spend ten minute or w/e stretches of the day praying at home

Also most religions I know of that say hate gays say hate gays not beat up gay people; so regardless of the morality of either practice you're falsely comparing one where a practice is delineated in the holy book to one where a belief is delineated and practice perhaps assumed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236832941.0" user="Oplp25" delta="False">
    <text>Im pretty sure thar Islam recognises that praying at the specific times is not always feasible, and allows you to "catch up" on prayers whennit is feasible. Yhis seems to gwt around that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236846483.0" user="AAPgamer0" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if most muslim agree with me but if you can't do prayer because of school. It's a good enough reason to miss them and since i couldn't pray at school. I would just catch up on those prayer at home. And this would affect only the Duhr/noon prayer (although you could do it at home if  you're home is close enough to school) and Asr prayer (which doesn't always happen in school hour so sometime you already do it at home anyway).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239696709.0" user="Shmurdaszn" delta="False">
    <text>School is not a good enough reason to miss prayer, it’s the second pillar of Islam and it is even an option of many scholars that abandoning prayer takes one out of the fold of Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241448958.0" user="AAPgamer0" delta="False">
    <text>It would mean missing two prayer which you can still catch up on them at home. Not all of the five prayer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244357279.0" user="Shmurdaszn" delta="False">
    <text>It’s the majority opinion that if you willingly miss a prayer (not by accident or due to genuine inability) then you can not make up the prayer at a later time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244374301.0" user="AAPgamer0" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but in this case it is genuine inability since you can't pray at school. Of course if you could pray then you should (for exemple if you're home is close to school and that the school let you go home to eat then you should go home to pray)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243645006.0" user="aymoji" delta="False">
    <text>Fo you have a source from quran or hadith that says you MUST do the prayers at their time? Not muslim just curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244350350.0" user="Shmurdaszn" delta="False">
    <text>In Quran and Hadith one can find these sources, see Surah Rum and Hood and Hadith mentions more about details of timings I believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250363251.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Many Muslims disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237391134.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>Why should a religion allow some kids to get out of class time? What if I declared that my religion of the god against homework said all homework was a sin? And that failing me for not competing my homework was discrimination against my religion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238651110.0" user="nubpokerkid" delta="False">
    <text>I Mean you think these kids want to pray at school? Religion should be kept at home instead of forcing kids to carry it t school. People have suggested having a single room for all religions but we all know it starts with that and each religion demanding their own. School is a place of study, not worship and it’s a little ridiculous to demand public or private money to provide you a separate room.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249839827.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I Mean you think these kids want to pray at school? Religion should be kept at home instead of forcing kids to carry it t school.

So are they supposed to be homeschooled (and potentially even more radicalizable if you really hate their religious teachings that much) just because it says they have to pray at certain times of day or just take up even more school time going back and forth between home and school

&gt; People have suggested having a single room for all religions but we all know it starts with that and each religion demanding their own. 

Not every religion needs one, do you think they'll all want one because literally "you have to give me the exact same thing even if my religion doesn't require it or it's not equal</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250367305.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Are you opposed to the Hijab ban in schools that Quebec has done?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
